Water collects into stagnant pools.
I've always loved watching it spill out all at once.
Breaking free, liberated, rushing out.
The energy stored up during
its stagnation bursts forth.
Everything springs into action!
Tamaki Mari-san, it's already noon.
I... I had the scariest dream!
What was it?
I dreamed you put a wet towel on
my face in an attempt to kill me, Mom.
That does sound scary...
I told you yesterday to tidy up your room.
Do not open
without permission!
-Rin
Wait!
Ow...
Huh?
Things I want to do in high school
Keep a diary
Skip school just once
Go on a journey without a plan
"Things I want to do in high school."
"Keep a diary."
"Skip school just once."
"Go on a journey without a plan."
Get the most out of youth.
What are you talking about?
What?
A Place Further Than the Universe
One Mwillion Yen For Youth
3 Likes
1 Comment
#OneMwillionYen #Tanuki #Youth #Antarctica
So?
Well, I just realized, I'm in my second year
of high school and I haven't done anything!
You didn't do anything in
middle school either, Kimari.
Exactly!
Student Activities
I knew I had to start doing stuff
when I got into high school!
That it isn't good sleepwalking through life...
Youth
Doesn't
Come to
Those
Who Wait
Act Now or
Regret Later
Seize
the
Moment
Nothing Begins
Without One
First Step
I Want to
Protect
Your Smile
Pudding
is a Drink
Class 2-2
Tamaki Mari
You Can
Do It!
Courage,
Enthusiasm,
Energy
I only have so much time, so I'm wondering,
where did all that determination go?
So, what are you gonna do?
I decided...
Get the most out of youth.
I'm gonna make it happen!
Expressions to offer advice
(Why don't you ____)
Tokyo?
Yeah. First I'll go to Tokyo,
then I'll start my journey from there.
Drifting from place to place on a whim!
When?
Ouch!
Enjoy your trip.
Tomorrow?
Yeah. I'm g-gonna ditch school.
Well, that sounds fine.
I'm skipping school, though! Playing hooky!
Yeah, and it's not that big a deal.
Not that big a deal?
Hey, Kimari... have you never ditched before?
You mean you have, Megu-chan?
Sure I have. Everyone has.
Incredible!
Don't look at me like that.
So, ever gone on a journey without a plan?
I guess not.
Then... then... then...
I'm not going with you.
How'd you know that's what I meant?
It was obvious.
That's just the way you think, Kimari.
But it's meaningless, unless you
go by yourself, in my opinion.
I see...
Just go.
I'll help you.
Okay!
Tamaki
I'm back!
So excited!
Tomorrow, I'll get changed in
the bathroom at the station!
And then...
The beach, the beach!
Crap. They'll know I'm from Gunma...
What are you doing, Sis?
Nothing!
Heading out already?
What's the big bag for?
I had to borrow gym clothes from a friend.
Again?
See you later!
Don't call me.
I had to!
You don't have to worry.
I already called the school.
With my mimicry skills.
For real?
If you have to stay overnight,
I'll back up whatever story you use.
Stop worrying and go.
Sure!
I'm heading out on a journey.
I'll change clothes in the bathroom.
I'll get on a train that goes
the opposite direction from school.
While everyone goes to school like normal,
I alone will burst free.
I'll go on a journey without a plan.
To a place I've never seen before...
No loose pants!
Lift them higher!
Both your pants and your grades!
What are you doing here?
Well... I mean, it was raining.
And I started thinking,
"you can't just skip school"...
Isn't there anywhere you wanted to go?
Sure, there is! Lots of places!
Kyoto, Okinawa, Hokkaido...
Then why didn't you go there?
Well... you know...
A plane could crash.
A shinkansen could explode...
And a meteor could fall at any time.
I know that! I know!
Then why didn't you go?
You got scared?
You know. It's the thing I've always done...
Rin
When I try to join clubs,
when I try to learn new things,
when I thought about taking the entrance
exam for a really good school...
I always chicken out at the very last minute.
When I'm about to try something
I've never done before,
I start thinking,
"What if it doesn't go well?"
"I really don't want to fail."
"What if I end up regretting it?"
When the moment comes, every single time...
Rin
Hurry!
Want to eat
Well, I don't think that's
necessarily a bad thing.
I hate it, though.
I'll be back by curfew
I made the usual
I really hate that part of me.
See you.
Sure.
Next time, want to hang out somewhere?
Sure!
Hey, you dropped this!
Yen
Are you kidding me?
How much is there?
I counted... it was exactly one million!
A million?!
Why did you keep it? Why didn't
you take it to the police?
I freaked out!
Sure you did...
I'm serious! I seriously freaked out!
And I think... the person who dropped
it was wearing a uniform for our school.
What year?
I'm not sure...
I only caught a glimpse of her from behind.
See her?
I don't... think so.
Her hair was about as long as that
girl's, and I think she was pretty.
Anything else?
She smelled good. Conditioner, maybe?
Not much to go on...
Well, it's okay.
I don't think there are many
girls with hair that long.
I'm going to check the first-year classrooms.
Okay...
Ethics
I need to calm down...
That smell...
A million...
A million... yen.
Yen!
Open and
close doors
QUIETLY
What do you want?
Year 1 Class 1
Oh... actually...
Um...
That's...
Uh, Yesterday, I...
No, I didn't steal it! I just happened to—
Thank you.
Thank you!
Closed
Antarctica?
A Place Further Than
the Universe
Kobuchizawa Takako
My mother wrote this book.
She was a member of an
Antarctic research expedition.
She went missing when
I was in middle school, though...
I see.
They never found her,
and she didn't leave much behind for me,
so I'm going to go and find her.
To Antarctica?
Can you even do that?
That's what everyone says.
Year 2 Class 2  We're All In This Together
My grandma, my friends,
my teachers, my upperclassmen,
and my neighbors...
New Club Formation Application
Club Name: Antarctica Club
Primary Purpose: To go to Antarctica
Club Activity Details: Train and study to go to Antarctica. Go to Antarctica.
Member names: President: 2-2 Kobuchizawa Shirase  Vice President: 2-2 Kobuchizawa Shirase
(Must have 4)  2-2 Kobuchizawa Shirase  2-2 Kobuchizawa Shirase
"You really think they'll
let a child do that?"
"Don't you realize how much that would cost?"
And that's what the million was for?
I've been working part-time jobs.
I'm going to go.
I'll go, then rub it in the faces
of everyone who said I couldn't.
After I finished my entrance exams and
got into high school, I made up my mind.
Antarctica, she said! Antarctica!
Don't you think that's amazing?
The furthest ends of the Earth!
That will be 566 yen.
Kobuchizawa Shirase?
Yeah! You know her, Megu-chan?
The girl in class 2 who they
call "Antarctica," right?
Antarctica?
Coming Nationwide This Winter!!
Anniversary Collaboration Campaign
She's pretty famous, you know.
Ever since she got to high school,
she's talked about nothing
but going to Antarctica.
That is what she said...
There's no way she's going, though.
But she has a million yen!
And she said she was totally going!
She can't, though.
Come on, it's Antarctica.
You'd need to be part of an expedition to go.
Then, why?
I dunno...
I mean, that's why people call her a weirdo.
She doesn't make any friends.
She spends all her time after school
working and saving up money.
Wanna hang out somewhere?
Oh... not today.
A Place Further Than
the Universe
There it is!
Social Sciences
400 Natural Sciences
410 Math
420 Physics
430 Science
440 Astronomy
450 Earth Science
460 Biochemistry
Excuse me, that's my bike.
Oh, is it?
The Antarctic Express?
Where's our payment?
We were making sure no one stole it.
We hear you've got some money on you.
Could you lend us a little? Just a little...
E-Excuse me!
K-Kobuchizawa-san, the teacher's calling you.
They gotta ask some
questions about the money.
Really?
Way to spoil the fun...
You were lying?
Don't scare me like that...
I thought the teacher really
found out about it!
But I gave you a knowing look!
How was I supposed to know?
But why were you there?
Just happened to be passing by?
Actually, I happened to see you,
and I wanted to talk to you.
About what?
I want to encourage you!
I wanted to do something
when I got into high school.
Something I'd never done. Something amazing!
But I never did anything,
and whenever I try,
I end up getting scared and quit.
So... I think it's really amazing
to work hard at something,
even when everyone discourages
you and makes fun of you!
Just let people say what they want.
Wanting to show them up
just fires me up even more.
I think it's for the best.
Isn't there any way I can help you?
Just say the word!
Will you go with me, then?
People have said that to me in the past.
But they all go away before long.
They decide it's impossible,
their friends get them to stop...
Or they get scared.
I think that's normal.
We're in high school, after all.
They have classes to get to, and friends.
I'm not like them! My feelings
about this aren't that frivolous...
I'm checking out boats.
Come here this Saturday.
If you do, I'll believe you're serious.
Antarctic survey ship coming to Kure Port!
Icebreaker Shirase Public Exhibition
"Icebreaker Shirase, public exhibition"...
Kawaraishi Station
Please use public
transportation to arrive!
Venue:
Tsukijicho, Kure, Hiroshima Prefecture
Kawaraishi South Pier, Kure Port
Hiroshima
Prefecture
Hiroshima...
Or they get scared.
I think that's normal.
There's no way she's going, though.
Will you go with me, then?
Icebreaker Shirase Public Exhibition
A Place Further Than
the Universe
Sis!
I know it's Saturday,
but you can't sleep in forev—
I'm going on a journey.
This time, I am going on a journey.
I'll get on the train that goes
opposite the usual way,
so that I can see things
I've never seen before...
I'm scared; it's true...
I want to call it off...
It might all turn out to be pointless...
But...
I'm finally going on a journey!
I got a picture of Mt. Fuji!
Wow, it's so big!
Shirase
Crossing the equator,
weathering storms,
breaking through ice...
14,000 kilometers from Japan.
To that place further than
the reaches of the universe,
Passed 55 Degrees South!
12 December 2015, 12:27:58
that unapproachable place...
How do you plan to get there?
You want to know?
The corners of her mouth
curled up in a smile.
Get the most out of youth.
My youth sprang into action!
The Place Further Than the Universe
Miyake-san, come over here!
Okay!