I could just die right now.
A Place Further Than the Universe
The Follow Backs
Don't Stop!
2 Likes
0 Comments
#IFollowEveryoneWhoFollowsMe
High school students. Antarctica.
3rd annual middle-high school polar science contest
Seriously doubt we'll find anything.
Here you are.
Thanks!
That's hot!
Why would you serve it hot?!
My grandma says it's only May, so...
Even if it's only May, it's still hot out!
I want cold tea.
And some sweets with it, too!
I request something of the pudding variety!
Don't you think this is a bit bizarre?
Bizarre?
This, from the girl who
came up with our last plan?
Yeah! Don't you realize
how embarrassed we were?
What was I supposed to do?
It was our only option.
Even so...
What? What?
High school girl!
"High School Girl Goes to Antarctica!"
A high school aged celebrity will be going on a
three month trip to Antarctica with the civilian expedition.
Likes: 29
Goes to Antarctica!
"The planned civilian Antarctic
expedition team has announced plans
to send a female high school
student with its news crew"?
"The accompanying student will
be celebrity Shiraishi Yuzuki-san...
She'll be doing online streams
about the trip to Antarctica
and conditions at Syowa Station."
Someone beat me to it!
I didn't know about this!
The expedition members didn't
mention a thing about it...
They probably realized the
trouble it would cause.
See?
Reporter... journalist... where?
Um... um... um...
Shiraishi Yuzuki
Shiraishi Yuzuki.
Her agency is... Call this place right now!
And say what, exactly?
Ask them if I go along with her.
I'm the daughter of an Antarctic expedition
member and a girl in high school.
I know everything about Antarctica!
Call her yourself.
But... I'm not cut out
for that sort of thing...
They're all strangers, after all...
I'm gradually starting to
understand how this girl works.
Same.
Beep!
No way, no way, no way!
Talk! You want to go
to Antarctica, don't you?
Um...
How dare you push this on me?!
Same to you!
Hello?
What are you doing?
Um...
You're Kobuchizawa Shirase-san, aren't you?
Yes?
A pleasure to meet you.
My name is Shiraishi Yuzuki.
Shiraishi...
...Yuzuki?
Huh? Isn't that the name of...
She's on wiki!
A child actress who started in
commercials at the age of five.
38,000 followers?
Made her singing debut with
"The Follow Backs Don't Stop."
Shiraishi Yuzuki's 1st Single
The Follow Backs Don't Stop
I could just die right now.
I'm so embarrassed.
Shirase-chan!
Take a picture!
Uploading my image to SNS without
permission is a violation of likeness rights.
Then can I get an autograph and a hand print?
She's not a sumo wrestler!
But what are you doing here?
Well... I wanted to talk to you.
About what?
Would you go to Antarctica in my place?
Huh?
Antarctica.
You want to go, don't you?
Where did you leak it?
A message board? Twitter? Your timeline?
I didn't leak it!
Oh, no...
Orange
Reserved Today
Antarctic Expedition Informal
Meet-up
Sexy Delicious!
Meat Festival
Do you remember the meet-up
in Shinjuku before?
I had been invited, too.
I heard about you there.
I see.
But what do you mean, in your place?
Put simply, I don't want to go.
TV Program Outline
High School Girl Goes to Antarctica!
I'm originally from Hokkaido, so I'm
sick of the cold, for one thing.
I think any high school girl going would
fit the requirements of the project, so...
You...
You're sure?
Shirase!
Shirase-chan!
You did it!
Yes... Yes!
Yes!
Well? Told you, didn't I? I told you
that my plan would work perfectly!
But...
Impossible, you said? Ridiculous, you said?
Was this... part of the plan?
It worked, didn't it?
I've done it, Antarctica!
At last, Antarctica!
Wait for me, penguins!
Wait for me, auroras!
I bet that hurt.
Sorry, she's an idiot.
That's all right...
Is this the only way out?
Yes, but...
I'm borrowing your sandals.
Excuse me.
Wait!
Hello there.
New Dosanko Promotions
Producer, Manager
Shiraishi Tamiko
I am Yuzuki's manager.
My name is Shiraishi Tamiko.
Shiraishi?
I am also her mother.
Thought so.
I keep telling you, I'm not going.
But you have to go.
It's your job, remember?
I told these girls they could do it instead.
Do you really think it's
your place to decide that?
TV Program Outline
High School Girl Goes to Antarctica!
Pardon me.
What is it?
Well... you see...
She just has to report on Antarctica, right?
I think she can do it!
She's beautiful, see?
Just like a famous actress!
Can she perform?
O-Of course!
I'm c-currently... in...
Antarctica... the weather...
Hello! Can't hear you!
Hold it! I can perform! I'll handle it!
Hello! I'm in Antarctica!
People of Japan, are you seeing me?
Can you be attractive?
She didn't sugar-coat it!
Shut up! Okay, in that case...
Helping Hands Class 2-3 Tamaki Mari
How about this?!
I'll be going now.
Huh?
What are we even doing?
Yeah... I want to go, but...
Aina: Can't do that either?
H-Hey...
Yeah?
Th-This might be coming
out of nowhere, but...
Would you be my friends?
Yuri-chan: How about next Sunday?
Sorry...
I don't know just yet...
I told you before, didn't I?
When you reach your second year,
you'll get more real time off.
Can't you just bear with it for one year?
No.
You don't have to worry. I'll make
sure you're in time for entrance exa—
I don't care about entrance exams.
I'm not going to high
school for entrance exams.
And here I thought we'd found a miracle.
Too bad Shirase can't
talk in front of people.
But, Hinata-chan, you also couldn't—
You don't have to rub it in!
That scarred her more than I thought!
Welcome—
We have it!
Have what?
New Dosanko Promotions
Producer, Manager
Shiraishi Tamiko
Convince her?
Yes. Apparently the girl is refusing to go.
If you can convince her to go,
I'll recommend to the production
company that you go as her companions.
What do you think?
In other words, if we can get her to go...
I see!
But Yuzuki-chan left, didn't she?
Actually, she has a job in Tokyo on Sunday,
so she'll be staying in
a hotel until Saturday!
Friday, Saturday... two days?
Which means there's no time to waste!
Let's go!
It's after ten.
Then tomorrow morning,
before we go to school. Five o'clock?
Wait, wait. Are we gonna film her waking up?
Six, then? Seven? When should we do it?!
Calm down.
If she's that set against it,
she must have a pretty serious
reason not to want to go.
I thought she just said
she didn't like the cold.
She said that pretty bluntly.
That means she probably has a
deeper reason not to want to go.
Hinata-chan, you're so mature!
So, what's the reason?
Well, I don't know that yet.
But asking about that should
probably be our first task.
A reason, huh?
Uh-oh! See you later!
Sure!
See you tomorrow!
What's wrong?
Self-loathing.
I was just thinking,
you're probably right, Hinata.
At the end of the day, I've mainly
been prioritizing my own feelings.
I haven't been thinking about anyone else.
You're just realizing that?
Just kidding.
As they say, it's a thin line between
self-assertion and selfishness.
Who says that?
Me!
Working today?
Nope!
Want to grab a bite, then?
Antarctica, huh?
Did you work that all out?
Well... We're not sure yet, but...
Sorry. Another time.
Here?
Room 305.
What should we do? T-T-Tail her?
What good would that do?
A coincidence.
Just pretend it's a coincidence.
Huh? Were you staying here?
Where are you off to?
Um...
Math I
Studying?
Yeah. I need to catch up
on the classes I miss.
This place has free refills,
and it's open late.
You're so responsible...
It's about Antarctica, right?
I'm sorry, I haven't made any more progress.
Y-Yeah, we know that, but...
There's something else we wanted to ask you.
What is it?
Why don't you want to go?
Is it strange that I don't?
Well, c'mon! Antarctica has penguins!
Icebergs, too!
And you can see the aurora!
My mother got to you, didn't she?
Does she want you to convince me to go?
Stare...
Yes.
Spineless!
But I still want to know the
reason you don't want to go.
Why should I tell you?
Well, it's okay if you don't want to...
I doubt you would understand.
I don't have any friends.
Not just now.
I never have.
Not once.
Shiraishi Yuzu-chan
Congratulations on
your TV appearance!!
I've been a child actress
since I was four years old.
But because I was so busy, I hardly
had any time to play with friends.
Then it kept happening and happening.
I've never had a fight with friends.
My mom's the only one I fight with.
So once I got into high school,
I decided I had to make
friends, no matter what.
I'd go to clubs, get a part-time job,
buy sweets with my friends after class,
do karaoke...
But...
Thanks, you guys!
Sure! Let's go hang out some time.
Really?
Sure thing.
Also, can we get a picture together?
Yuzuki-chan's a celebrity,
so people want to see pictures.
Take one with me, too!
Sorry...
Oh. Bye, then.
First impressions are important, aren't they?
I need to start working hard
to form them right now.
Proper relationships and groups...
You're basically establishing who you are.
Wh-What?
I just wanted to hug you suddenly!
I can't breathe!
I totally understand you!
I always hate new school terms and stuff, too!
You don't understand!
Yes, I do!
No, you don't!
Because you're all best friends, aren't you?
Best friends?
Aren't you?
We haven't even known each other a month.
We've never even hung out together.
We're just all trying
to go to the same place.
For now, at least.
Right?
Yeah.
Yeah!
Sorry to keep you out so late.
I hope your mother understands.
Not at all. I feel a little better,
having gotten to talk about it.
Well, bye.
Bye-bye!
So... where does that actually leave us?
What do you mean?
Have you forgotten?
We came here to convince her!
Oh! That's right!
Huh? But if Yuzuki-chan refuses,
Shirase-chan can go in her place...
If we convince her, we can go together...
Huh?
Wait, but if Yuzuki-chan refuses,
Shirase-chan can go in her place...
I'm so confused!
It's not that hard!
If she refuses,
they'll get some other
entertainer to go in her place.
I see!
Convincing her was our only chance.
But...
Well, I think this is okay.
Aina: Can't do that either?
Yuri-chan: How about next Sunday?
Sorry... I don't know just yet...
Sorry. Maybe next time.
It's the first time anyone's done that to me.
Having friends... Is that what it feels like?
Kimari-san!
Let's go to Antarctica!
What are you doing? They'll yell at you!
Come on, let's just go!
Come on, the wind is really strong!
Hurry up!
But I...
Hold out your hand!
What a strange dream.
Today
Good morning!
You guys...
I told you it was too early!
She's still in her pajamas!
It was Shirase-chan who said it!
What was I supposed to do?
We're going all the way to Tokyo.
Tokyo?
Yeah! We heard you had a job in Tokyo,
so I figured we could go together!
Sorry to jump on you like this!
It's all because she didn't
ask for your contact info.
Me?!
Do you have time?
Yeah.
Really?! Then, then...
We can go to the Tokyo... Polar...
Wh-What's wrong?
Kimari!
What did I do?
It must have been you!
But you're the one who said
we should go together...
I'm saying I'll go if I can
go with the three of them.
And I won't go without them.
Okay, Yuzuki-chan! Let's go!
Okay!
P-Penguins!
Aren't they nice and fluffy looking?
Yeah...
Hey!
Wow, it's long!
Hey, we can go inside this!
Really?
It's pretty cramped in here, huh?
I believe they use newer models of
snowcats nowadays, of course...
Full speed ahead, and keep 'er steady!
I don't think it's a boat.
This bunk bed only has a top bunk!
It says they keep the rooms
over twenty degrees Celsius!
Nice to hear it!
Because it'll be negative
ten degrees outside!
I bet my nose would be running...
Come a little closer!
I bet the real one is a lot more beautiful!
Yes, I've heard it's very beautiful.
My mother said it brought her to tears.
Most people don't get to see
the aurora, though, do they?
I've heard that.
Then if we really do get to see it,
we might be the only high school students
in the world to see the aurora from Antarctica.
Really?
In that case...
I could just die right now!