It's not a dream.
It's not a joke.
Comprehensive Summer Training Documents
It's not a misunderstanding.
That's what goes through my mind,
every day, after I confirm it.
At school, at home, at my job,
Ray of Hope For Civilian Antarctic Expedition?
Shichishin-ya to Sign Contract to Sponsor "Challenge For Antarctic"?
We got some tickets for this,
so if you're interested,
come see management.
I say it over and over again.
We're going to Antarctica!
She actually said Antarctica!
You don't care?
No.
It's not as if they'd believe
me right now anyway.
I'll say it after I've really gone,
"In your face, in your face, in your face!"
You're kind of a jerk, you know.
I certainly am.
You mind?
Nope!
A Place Further Than the Universe
Four Caterpillars
5 Likes
4 Comments
#ShutUp #InYourFace #Compasser
Always check the lower door before
and after closing the freezer door
You're serious about this?
You need two days off for
this "summer training,"
and then you'll be taking time
off beginning in December?
Yes.
What do your parents have to say?
We have their permission.
I hereby grant permission as guardian of your student
(Kobuchizawa Shirase) for them to take the following time off:
(Student's Class) Year 2 Class 2
(Student Name) Kobuchizawa Shirase
(Guardian Name) Kobuchizawa Koumi
To join the Civilian Antarctic Expedition
"Challenge For Antarctic" team and...
Tamaki-san?
Um...
What do you think, Rin?
Seems pretty normal.
She didn't slam the refrigerator door,
and the rhythm of her
chopping seems normal...
Okay!
Wait!
I'm suspicious. It's too normal.
Like it's all a front, to trick us...
Mari-chan.
Y-Yes?
I bought some bath salts.
Could you take them to the bathroom?
Sure!
Feels Like Antarctica
Medicinal
Bath Salts
Mint
Limited Time
They started selling those recently.
Does she already know?
No, it might just be a coincidence...
If I jump to conclusions,
I might be digging my own grave.
But what if she knows?
If she does, then trying to hide
it might make the situation worse!
Maybe I should be just come clean, and—
Mari-chan.
Is something the matter?
Or is there something on your mind?
Antarctica, perhaps?
H-Hey, Mom!
The truth is, I've decided
to take a trip this winter...
Oh, that's a done deal, is it?
I simply hadn't heard a thing about it!
Not until a neighbor told me today.
Gosh, was I embarrassed!
W-Well, I meant to tell you...
I hereby grant permission as guardian of your student
(Tamaki Mari) for them to take the following time off:
(Student's Class) Year 2 Class 3
(Student Name) Tamaki Mari
(Guardian Name) Tamaki Yoko
To join the Civilian Antarctic Expedition
"Challenge For Antarctic" team...
It was just an issue of t-t-timing,
and we needed to be sure it was happening...
Who filled this in, now?
And who stamped it?
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
At least put down the weapon!
It's not a weapon. It's a cooking utensil.
Though I could use it to dish out something
to a certain idiot daughter of mine...
That's a terrifying thing to say!
I'm ho—
Dad!
Dad! Dad!
Forgive me, my daughter...
Dad! Da—
Social Studies
Terminology
This is pretty much all on you, Kimari.
You don't have to sum it all up like that!
Now I can't go unless I pass every single test!
And even without that, I won't have any
time to study during our training camp...
You're really taking time
off next week, then?
Yeah, it's four days, including the weekend,
so I'll be off through Tuesday.
Are you sure about all this?
I read that they're not even sure
if the boat will leave the harbor.
Well, it's not like I can
do anything about that...
I gotta get to my job!
Rough life, huh?
See you!
Don't overwork yourself, okay?
If you work too hard and it doesn't go
through, you're really going to regret it.
Right. See you!
Standardized Test Guide
High School 2
English
I request your assistance!
No dice.
Why not?!
Look, going to school means
you're taking classes, right?
That means you've got tons of time
allotted every day just for learning.
If you still can't do it, you're probably
just not putting in the work.
Academics aren't like sports.
Anyone can pick this stuff up if they try.
She's right.
Traitor!
I'm not a traitor.
Hinata's right, that's all.
Fine, whatever. I'll ask Yuzuki-chan!
She's younger than you.
I'm outside the gate.
She's here, she says!
Good morning!
You seem different today...
I was at work last time.
I had to dress that way.
You had to?
I just look awful in that
cutesy stuff, anyway.
It's really not "me."
Really?
I thought you looked cute...
I can't stand that "Look at
me, I'm a girly-girl!" junk.
Why's she in such a bad mood?
Well, her job being what it is,
she probably deals with
some complicated stuff.
Is this the place?
Yeah, definitely.
Sorry I'm late!
Sorry that it wasn't
the easiest place to find.
Go on, get in.
Oh, don't worry, I'll tidy it up!
Sorry, sorry!
This isn't quite what I was expecting...
Not quite what you were expecting, huh?
Yeah, I guess it wouldn't be.
An Antarctic expedition
is a very big project.
Even if we are civilians, you wouldn't
expect a junky old minivan.
How are we supposed to respond to that?
Like I'd know!
But I never thought you'd manage
to end up coming with us.
What happened to your million yen?
I still have it.
You don't need it, do you?
As I'm sure you've read,
we don't have any money.
Do not
insert tape!
DANGER!
So we're doing a whole lot to raise
the funds to get to Antarctica.
That also means we're trimming
every bit of fat that we can.
We won't let it be canceled. Don't worry.
Civilian Japanese Antarctic Expedition
"Challenge for Antarctic (2nd)"
Sponsor Recruitment
You girls might not know this,
but we've been hearing the same thing
over and over since the project started.
Icebreaker Shirase
Recruiting naming
rights partners!!
Your name here!
Pins
"You don't have the money.
Won't it be dangerous?"
We're used to it.
You are?
Any time one of those reports comes out,
the rest of the team and I
all shout together...
"Shut up, idiots!"
You know?
We do that, too!
Really?
Yes!
The mountains, huh?
Feels nice out here!
Though we won't be going out
there until two days from now.
Hundred Mountains Lodge
Altitude [3026M]
Today and tomorrow, it's all lectures.
Go on, get in.
Check these documents!
Wow! A station handbook?
Internal Documents
Handle with care
Station Handbook
"Internal documents... handle with care."
Syowa Station
Construction of new station
Wow, a snowcat!
This is so exciting!
Discovery of large numbers of meteorites
The collection of meteorites across the world...
17,100 discovered. The world's largest collection of meteorites.
Among them, we've located nine Mars meteorites and nine Moon meteorites.
(Reference) America: 17,301 China: 9,826 Korea: 21 Other (including Europe): 869
Mars Meteorite
How meteors accumulate in Antarctica
Based on that documentation,
I'll be giving you a condensed version
of the summer and winter
training the others get.
Antarctica is the only continent in the
world with no permanent inhabitants.
Unlike Japan,
Joint International Expeditions Under the Antarctic Treaty System
Primary Base Distribution
Countries participating in Antarctic expeditions: 29
Wintering stations: 20
Ross Sea
Dome Fuji
Mizuho            Asuka
Queen Maud Land
Antarctic Treaty System
Antarctic Peninsula
Prydz Bay
it has many rules surrounding its use.
I want you to be sure to memorize them all.
Got it!
You're not like this in school...
You aren't in my class!
Well, let's meet the team captain!
I am this Antarctic expedition's
captain, Todo Gin.
Captain...
It's a woman?
I'm going to start by saying this:
Whether the members of my team are
researchers or just accompanying us,
I will treat you all the same.
We have many things to accomplish.
Just because you're in high school doesn't
mean I won't ask you to do everything,
from laundry to hard labor, as necessary.
Keep that in mind.
Yes ma'am!
The ABCs of Antarctic Expedition
A: Always follow procedure
B: Be alert at all times
C: Common sense!
These are the ABCs of
an antarctic expedition.
A: Always follow procedure.
B: Be alert at all times.
C: Common sense.
I want you to keep these in mind at all time.
1. I want to live
2. I want to know
3. I want to keep my team together
All of these apply on an Antarctic expedition.
No matter what, you must survive and come home alive.
Eagerly pursue knowledge and new experiences.
Lastly, never leave a member of your team behind.
She sure did sound like a real captain, huh?
If you dozed off around her,
you'd have chalk coming your way, for sure.
If we had a test, I bet she'd fill
it with all the hardest questions.
We're surveying a route tomorrow, right?
Yeah, we'll be going outside.
It'd be a waste not to, being up
here in the mountains and all!
Still, this all looks pretty tough.
How did it go?
How did what go?
Seeing her again after so long.
I told you, didn't I?
I'm going to treat her like
any other member of the team.
Yeah, yeah...
Did you go against my wishes on purpose?
No, I didn't have any part of this.
That girl really got here
through her own efforts.
Though I must admit,
I had a feeling she would...
Since the first day she told
me she wanted to come along.
She's Takako's daughter, after all.
What's this?
A transceiver, I think.
This is a compass, and that's a GPS...
And then we've got flags.
Hinata-chan, do you get it?
Yeah, she taught us most
of it to us yesterday.
But why do we have to do this?
Antarctica's flat, isn't it?
We can get along fine without
marking a route, can't we?
Totally wrong.
The landscape's white as far as you can see,
so it's easy lose track of
your direction in a blizzard.
That's why you need to create
a route to walk along.
So we set up the flags to
serve as landmarks, huh?
But where do we put them?
Figuring that out is the
point of the training.
Communication station
Route Creation Start Point
This is our current location.
And this is our destination.
Route Creation End Point
Route Creation Course
So we just have to get there?
But we can't just go right there.
We have to go here, here,
and here on the way,
and set up flags at each point.
I see!
Okay, let's do it!
That way, right?
Wait, wait!
We can't just run off willy-nilly.
Do you even know where the points are?
There... ish?
"Ish"? Come on!
We'll need to keep precise
track of our location.
I'm getting the feeling
this is gonna be hard.
Forty-eight, forty-nine, fifty!
Right here!
Check the angle.
Which should I look with?
Left eye or right eye?
Your dominant eye, probably.
Which eye is that?
I think you go like this...
Are you done yet?!
168 degrees.
More to the right!
Right?
Right!
Correct!
There!
Um, the latitude is...
And the longitude is...
It seems further away than
the last one, doesn't it?
If the instruments are right,
we should be right here, I think.
That's where they are, huh?
They've gotten pretty off-track...
This reminds me of the first time
I took part in one of these.
What's the story on the other three?
Well, the one is the girl we were supposed
to bring along from the start, right?
They seem to have become
friends at some point, but...
Oh.
She said the other expedition members
would compete on time, but...
I think precision is more
important than speed.
Safety first, right?
Okay, here I go.
One, two...
398, 399, 400.
Okay, here!
Two steps left!
Yes, there!
That was fast.
I'm impressed you could tell, though.
Kimari must be good with the compass.
She does seem cut out for it!
Just call me a compass expert.
A compasser, for short!
First comes rock! Rock-paper-scissors!
Okay, I'll take this one!
Feels like we're on a field trip!
Anyone bring any playing cards?
We're not here to play around!
Sleeping in a tent will
be good training, too.
But it's not even 8:00 yet!
Come on, the captain said they'd always
socialize at night during their training camps...
Less talk, more sleep!
Hey, let's talk!
Don't look at me.
Wanna tell scary stories?
I could just kill you right now.
Yuzuki-chan, do you not like scary stories?
Please shut talking now.
What does "shut talking now" mean?
You're my senpai, so I self-corrected!
You knew what I meant,
so please leave me alone!
Please shut talking now.
Knock it off, Kimari!
Shirase-chan, are you asleep?
I was wondering about something...
Do you know the captain?
How could you tell?
Just had a feeling.
She and my mother knew
each other in high school.
She went to Antarctica with my mother.
She came home.
My mother didn't.
That's all.
Because... my mother is waiting there.
What a big sky!
Where's the North Star?
Um, were supposed to trace something
from the Big Dipper, aren't we?
I thought it was Cassiopeia.
What's the South Star?
South Star? Is there one?
There is, but you can't see
it as clearly, I've heard.
Which is it?
You can't see it from here, duh.
"Never think the stars you see
are all the stars there are."
Another of your sayings, Hinata-chan?
Yeah, that one kinda sucked, huh?
This is Syowa Station.
Aurora Team, do you read me? Over.
We got it!
This is Aurora Team, Miyake.
We read you loud and clear. Over.
This is your regular check-in.
Is everything all right there? Over.
Four members of Aurora Team.
All personnel and equipment
accounted for. Over.
Understood.
It gets cold around dawn, so
watch your body temperature.
This concludes your regular check-in.
Be safe.
Be safe!
She really did contact us!
I almost forgot!
New Message
To: Mom
Subj: Dear Mom
Mailbox
Receipt
Favorites
So cold...
Hey...
Is there something there?
What was Shirase-chan's mom like?
All I can say about her is
that she was very strange.
Was she like Shirase-chan?
I don't know. I don't know
her daughter very well.
But in stubbornness and conviction,
she's her spitting image.
She's trouble.
Isn't trouble just the best?
A personality like yours
will do well in Antarctica.
Really?
Why do you want to go to Antarctica?
Did she invite you?
Yeah...
But I'm the one who made the decision.
That I wanted to go with her.
That I didn't want my high school
years to end the way they were going.
That I wanted to go
somewhere that's not here.
I see.
But then I met Hinata-chan and Yuzuki-chan,
and I got to hear how the
members of the expedition felt,
and I learned stuff about you
and Shirase-chan, and now...
It's not just "somewhere" to me.
It's Antarctica!
I'm gonna go to Antarctica with all of you...
Everyone, wake up!
What is it?!
I'm not a morning person...
Just get up already!
You, too, Shirase-chan!
Hurry! Hurry!
I wanna go with all of you.
I wanna find the South Star with all of you.
I wanna see auroras, eat shaved ice,
and take pictures with penguins!
We've got to go!
Yeah!
Kimari