Watch Duty
Tamaki
Miyake
Himi
Good morning!
You're late.
Being late for watch duty
makes trouble for everyone.
Yes ma'am!
Today's menu, if you would.
Food Waste
"Leftover special."
That's too honest!
At times like these,
we go with you-know-what!
Today's Menu
Antarctic Style Pork
Eat your dried sardines, too!
Pork-on-rice and pork soup sets available!!
Cleaning duty: Team B
That's it for the watch report.
Is there any other business to address?
Um, I was thinking the premade
Calpis is too thin...
It's too strong, isn't it?
Poor man's Calpis.
Don't call me "poor."
Person on duty there?
Well, the person on duty
yesterday made it, not me,
but I'll do what I can.
It's cold!
They did say it would be windy...
What are we supposed to do after this?
Clean the bathrooms!
The summer team leaves
in 3 days!
I told you I hate hijiki!
Just eat it.
I'm told you've been a little
anemic lately, Honami-san.
Meanie!
Those high school girls
were so cute at the start.
They weren't doing anything then.
Want some tea?
After so much time in Antarctica,
you'll never reintegrate into society.
Like that.
Chisou, ron.
Riisoku, jyunchansanshiki, dora dora...
Sorry... with uraura, that's a sanbai man.
I told you not to rely on the suji!
I think that's a different thing, actually...
Doesn't the sound of a vacuum cleaner
just make you think of home?
Where have you been?
They invited me out,
so I did some interviews.
Island Stroll
Grotto
Oh, the island stroll?
Yes.
They took Shirase-chan and I
out for that yesterday.
Yeah!
Why didn't you tell me?!
Because you were on watch duty today!
Odd man out!
Shut up!
Ow!
Who cares about some island stroll?
I'm going out on the ice operation later!
That's right! I gotta hurry!
It's almost time for the meetup!
Hey!
We're all going on the ice operation.
Island Stroll
Grotto
Really?
The four of us will be heading out
to join the ice operation. Over.
Roger that. Be safe.
Which should we take?
Hi!
I could just die!
Wow! Glaciers!
You're shaving from these big blocks of ice?
It's forbidden to remove
things from Antarctica,
so it's the only souvenir
we're allowed to take freely.
This ice is full of air that's
tens of thousands of years old,
so as it melts, it pops.
Want to eat some?
Yeah!
So this is how thousand-year-old air tastes!
You can distinguish it?
When I grow up, I've gotta
drink alcohol with this.
I bet you'd be a loud drunk, Kimari.
You think?
When this starts up, it really hits
home that summer's almost over.
Really?
Soon, it'll be autumn, then winter...
The winter team!
What do you do during winter?
All kinds of things.
We play games, drink booze...
Soumen
Of course, research and
investigation is important,
but when we hit June, it's nighttime all day.
I see...
"Polar night," right?
During the day, there's a faint
brightness around the horizon,
but that's the only change you see.
Otherwise, it just stays
night for a long, long time.
Perpetual night, huh?
But that just makes the stars
all the more more beautiful!
You can see the aurora, too!
The aurora...
That's right, we never saw it!
Because we only get a tiny bit of night.
We got a photo with penguins,
ate shaved ice...
we haven't gotten the aurora
or the Antarctic stars!
Because the sun doesn't
go down, like I told you.
Help!
But I'm happy! But they stink! But I'm happy!
What's she doing?
But they stink! But I'm happy!
I need to get back to work.
You guys take it easy.
But they stink! But I'm happy!
This'll be your last day
on the frozen sea, right?
But they stink!
That's right...
But I'm happy!
I told you to help me!
Sorry, I can't get within
five meters of them...
Do something!
Sorry, I can't!
We've really gotten used
to it all, haven't we?
This scenery, too...
Hey, just hypothetically...
Hypothetically...
Well, no one else needs the rooms.
And we can keep sending
video from here, right?
So there's no reason we have
to leave right now, is there?
You're going to hurt me!
I'm not, I'm not.
Liar!
What did you think? If we don't go
back now, we're stuck here all year.
I know that. It'll be fine.
I bet that once it gets
dark I could sleep forever.
What about school? By the time we get
back, everyone will have graduated.
Well...
What about our families?
And Yuzu's drama?
Well, I do understand not
wanting to go back...
You'll come back, then?
What? Sure...
For the winter stay. All four of us!
Fine.
You'd better mean it!
You'd better not let me down!
Yeah, yeah...
I'm asking seriously.
I'm answering seriously.
Okay, then!
But... what are we going to do?
Remember what the captain said?
If there was anything we wanted to do
before we leave, we should tell her.
Before we leave, huh?
Are you sure that's all you want?
Yeah. Before we leave, we want
to play with everyone here!
Hey! Let 'er rip!
You can do it!
Let's do this!
Captain! If I hit it out of the park,
will you consider my offer?
Sure.
I'm holding you to that!
He still hasn't given up?
Can he hit it?
I doubt it. Gin-chan is known as
the "Antarctic 19-in-Pinstripes."
Her pitches are first-rate.
And...
No one can dodge them.
No way...
Don't worry.
Takako could still hit them.
Takako...
You're watching, right?
Hinata-san!
Lavatory | Bath
Washroom
What, now?
If you were gonna cut it, you should
have done it when we arrived.
I just got the urge to cut it.
Should I do it?
Kimari-san, please stand back.
Aw...
Up to where?
Seriously?
Yeah!
Farewell, Summer Team!
You can't keep putting it off.
She's really going, you know...
Farewell, Summer Team!
Challenge for Antarctica
High School Girl Reporters
Remember us when you're home
There.
Is this flag handmade?
The guests of honor are here.
Come on, line up here!
Okay!
Huh?
Well? Does it look good on me?
You really are your mother's daughter.
You look just like her when you smile.
What happened? Broken heart?
No.
But maybe, in a way...
In a way?
Use your imagination.
I don't get it!
Normally, we'd be changing
places with the winter team,
but there's no one swapping in this time,
so it's just a farewell party
for the departing summer team.
Well, Captain?
You've done an excellent job, everyone.
This morning, the weather is nice.
It's an excellent morning for a departure.
In particular, I'd like to talk about
Japan's first high school-aged
Antarctic research team members.
This was a major experiment.
I'm sure they were all nervous.
We were all very, very nervous, too.
But they did an excellent
job as expedition members.
The male team members' internal wishing
for them to stay has been
so loud, it's audible.
But they are going home.
It's time to give up on them.
Lastly...
Thank you for everything.
Even after you go home, I hope
you'll occasionally think of us,
here in the darkness, far over the horizon,
silently lasting through the winter.
Let's meet again here some day.
Now, as a representative of the summer team,
Kobuchizawa Shirase-san.
Yes ma'am.
Everyone.
Good morning.
As you all know,
my mother was a member of
your Antarctic expedition.
She loved Antarctica, and left
our house in her obsession.
When I looked at her,
to be honest, it was hard for me to have
positive feelings about Antarctica.
I think wanting to change that
feeling was the reason I came here.
A place further than the universe.
Mom... rather, my mother called it that.
It's a place that strips everything bare.
Time, life, hearts...
It's a place with nothing to
protect you and nowhere to hide.
It's an environment that exposes
everything we're embarrassed about,
and everything we want to hide,
and so naked and crying, we're forced to
come face-to-face with who we really are.
We've overcome trial after trial together.
And from that, I think I now understand...
the reason my mother loved this place was
not just this scenery, this sky, this wind,
but also the time she spent here,
overcoming things with her team.
She loved this atmosphere,
where you have no choice but to
overcome things with your team,
with nothing else to get in the way.
I love this place.
Good luck over the winter.
I'll be back again, I swear.
Are you crying?
Here.
You made these for us?
With leftovers, of course.
Um...
Wow, thanks...
Could you take this back to Yu-kun?
He's waiting in Japan?
What?
Don't go!
You smell of alcohol...
Of course I do! I've been drinking!
Don't worry. Have this.
Shirase-san, thank her! Thank her!
Just go already!
The Follow Backs Won't Stop
So that's your signature, Yuzuki-chan?
Looks like an idol's.
How many of these did you sell?
Would you please cease your babbling?
Here.
Um...
Yes?
I'm looking forward to your drama.
Though I won't get to see
it until I get back...
Okay...
How'd it go?
There really are people
looking forward to it...
Of course there are!
You'd better work hard!
Okay!
It's time to go!
Take care.
Thank you!
Actually, I should be thanking you...
Do you remember what we talked
about in the van that first day?
Talking with you then really
gave me a lot of courage.
When I saw your faces, I realized I
couldn't let our plans be canceled.
You were thinking they might?
Yes.
For adults, there's a moment
when you shouldn't be honest.
Take care of the captain.
You heard her.
Well, listen to you.
Go on, get in!
Okay!
And take this.
I think my mother would be mad if you
didn't let her stay for the winter.
But...
I don't need it anymore.
Understood.
Let's go.
They're gone.
The average age here just jumped.
Ouch!
Well, we've got a lot of time ahead of us!
Inbox
Kobuchizawa Shirase
Dear Mom
Kobuchizawa Takako
Inbox (1483)
Saved Drafts
Sent Mail
Trash
Outbox (1)
When we first came here,
it seemed so far away...
Well, that's what a journey is.
It's not over yet.
There's still the 60 degrees,
the 50 degrees, the 40 degrees...
Screaming!
I'll probably throw up again.
It's okay.
Barfing and barfing,
thinking "I'm so sick, I'm gonna die..."
That's fine. That's part of the journey, too.
Do you think we've gotten a little stronger?
Or maybe we've gotten sloppier...
It's because everything is bigger here.
Is this what we're wearing?
It's the last one!
We need to make it special!
Let's see... This will be my final
catchy, witty, sensational report...
Maybe you should put down the script?
Okay, let's go!
Wait! It's the last one!
I need a little more time!
The aurora!
You're right!
Oh, no! I can't get it to show up!
It's okay.
If that happens once in a while.
Mail          Now
Mom
The real thing is ten thousand times more be
Mom...
No way!
Mail          Now
Mom
The real thing is ten thousand times more beautiful
I know.
That's it!
That's the South Star! I'm calling it!
I don't think it's that bright...
Hey.
Let's say goodbye here.
Kimari...
Does that mean we won't
be together anymore?
The opposite. It means that even when
we're not together, we can be together.
After all... we're still who we are.
Who's that a quote from? Hinata-san?
It's not bad, though.
Right?
We still have a lot we have to do, right?
Yeah. When we're done doing that,
let's go on another journey.
The four of us.
The four of us, yes.
Well, Shirase still has her million yen.
I've got my savings, too...
That's gone now.
I left it there.
Treasure
In the place further than the universe.
When you go on a journey, there are
things you learn for the first time.
That this scenery is indispensable.
That people change, the world changes,
even when you're not looking.
That there's no such
thing as a "nothing" day.
That your house has its own smell.
If you want to learn those things,
you've got to get moving.
Then just keep moving until you see
something you've never seen before.
Offerings
No matter how far you go,
the world is so big...
You'll definitely find something new.
It's a little scary,
but I know you can do it.
Because...
Off to the airport
Almost home
I'm back!
Megu-chan
I'm home—
Oh, too bad.
Megu-chan
Right now, I'm in the Arctic
Why?
People who feel the same way
will find you right away.
Why?!
We'll Go On Another Journey Someday