What's wrong?
I see your eyes.
It's the same color as your eyes.
When I saw it,
I felt something.
What is this feeling called?
To Major Gilbert,
Today marks the 120th day of my hospitalization.
I have regained nearly all bodily function.
I still have some difficulty moving,
but not enough to impede a mission.
Requesting immediate return to duty.
Somewhere in Enchaîné,
Capital of the Enciel Kingdom
The girl's existence was kept tightly under wraps.
Somewhere in Enchaîné,
Capital of the Enciel Kingdom
Anyone who knew of her referred to her as a weapon—
as a wannabe human that fought whenever ordered,
a tool without a mind of her own.
Colonel Hodgins?
Over here.
Right.
Sorry about that.
Violet!
You okay?
Are you hurt?
Where's the major?
Where's Major Gilbert?
He's not here.
Might I ask where he is?
Is he back home on leave?
How are his injuries now?
I believe he was gravely hurt as well.
Is he still alive?
He's...
You can be discharged now.
Colonel Hodgins came all the way to pick you up.
Well, there you have it.
Pardon me,
Colonel Hodgins.
Stand at ease, Violet.
I'm terribly sorry to report that I
couldn't remember your name and rank.
It's fine. Now take a seat.
But you recognized me, huh?
We met twice before—back at the training
barracks, and the night before the final battle.
Yeah, we did.
What were you doing?
Writing a report for Major Gilbert.
I was also told that putting pen to
paper would help with my recovery.
So, what about the major?
Relax, Violet.
I'm here because he asked me to come.
So he's alive and well.
The doctors told me we won the War.
What's his current assignment?
When should I regroup with him?
First things first, get dressed.
I'll get us a ride in the meantime.
Here are your belongings. They finally arrived.
They were apparently shipped
by mistake to a faraway army base.
The brooch...
Where's the emerald brooch?
This was all they found by
your side and in your quarters.
If it's not here, then I must look for it.
Violet!
It was a gift!
It was a gift from the major!
Very well.
I'll find it for you.
I promise.
But...
Anyway, you are to accompany me.
Those are his orders.
Orders?
Roger.
When will the major give me my next assignment?
I'm afraid some missions
might be beyond me in this state.
Violet.
To celebrate your discharge.
I didn't know which you'd like, so I bought all three.
Which'll it be?
None of them.
Well, uh, let's say the world
will end if you don't pick one.
Pick now! Three... two...
The puppy, then.
Here you go!
Why the puppy?
The major's older brother once said I was "Gilbert's dog."
This journey will take a while.
The railroads in this area were
rendered useless by enemy bombings.
Have you ever been to Leiden?
No.
Violet...
You must live on...
and be free.
From the bottom of my heart...
There you are.
Colonel.
We can see the port of Leiden now.
Port City Leiden,
Capital of Leidenschaftlich
Gilbert was really worried about your life after the war.
So he said he wanted to leave you
in the care of the Evergarden family,
the relatives he most trusted.
Once they were contacted, both Mr.
and Mrs. Evergarden agreed to take you in.
Welcome.
Come, Violet.
This is Mrs. Evergarden.
Say hello.
Uh, a polite bow would be enough.
What does it take, three days from Enchaîné now?
Yes. Normally, I'd be back within a day.
The War did last four whole years.
The infrastructure will take
a while to get back up to speed.
Come on, Violet.
Drink up.
I'm so sorry! Don't push yourself!
Oh no!
You'll get a burn!
No need to worry.
I don't feel heat.
But we must cool your bandages off.
Bring us some ice, Oliver!
Right away, ma'am!
These arms are made from adamantine.
Uncouth as they may look, they're just as sturdy.
I'm not used to them yet, but I believe
they'll eventually feel like part of my body.
Could you come with me for a moment?
I used to wear these back when I was young.
Good idea.
Try them on.
They look great on you.
Truly.
I'll take my leave now, then.
I must get back to the office.
Oh?
Violet,
be a good girl and listen to Tiffany, okay?
It's fine.
No need to be so uptight.
Think of us as your real family.
You can talk to us about anything, all right?
I've never had a family,
so I don't need a new one.
Don't be like that.
We had a son, but we lost him in the War.
I can't be a replacement for your late son.
Violet.
Gilbert wants you to lead a life of happiness here.
So please...
You understand, right?
Why?
Why is Major Gilbert putting me here?
Is it because I've lost my arms and all value as a weapon?
With some training, I can fight again!
Violet, the war is over.
I'm the major's tool.
But if he no longer needs me,
I should be disposed of.
Please cast me aside.
Dump me somewhere.
Colonel Hodgins...
Oh, I forgot to tell you.
I quit the military.
I'm not a colonel anymore.
Then how should I address you?
"Boss," maybe?
I run this company here.
I bought an old mansion and renovated it some.
The ground floor is the reception.
Sir, if you could write down the
destination and the sender's address.
We'll need three days or so to complete the shipment.
The first floor has the office
and the ghostwriting department.
Ghostwriting?
Oh...
It's where we write letters and
the like as per the clients' requests.
Many people still can't write.
I couldn't either.
Not until the major taught me.
Is that so?
I was thinking of starting a business once the war ended,
and the government's postal
service isn't available to civilians yet,
so I figured this could work.
Anyway...
Here are your orders, Violet Evergarden.
Gilbert left you in my hands,
so I'll give you your orders in his stead.
You can still serve a purpose.
You can still work.
Right here.
Benedict.
The hell d'you want, Boss?
"What can I do for you, Boss," you mean!
Well? The hell d'you want?
Ow! What was that for?
You did that on purpose!
This is Benedict, a postman.
Sadly for me, we've been joined at the
hip since before I founded this company.
And, Benedict, this is Violet.
She'll be joining you as postman from today.
What? A kid like her?
Her ability to see a mission through is unmatched.
I have to hit up the banks,
so you show her the ropes.
Your stuff goes in here.
Understood.
Your uniform.
Get changed.
Understood.
What are you—
Wait! Hold up!
Kinda baggy.
No problem.
Shouldn't you take your gloves off?
Would sorting the mail be hard for you?
No. It shouldn't pose a major problem.
Sort them by the street names written here
and put them in that shelf.
We always have a ton of packages to
go through, but you don't have to rush.
Also, there's a break room on the second floor.
Roger.
Later.
I'll be done with my assignment shortly.
You were at it the whole time?
Without taking any breaks?
I'm used to operations with long hours.
Then... Wanna try going on a delivery run next?
Delivery?
You take the mail to the address on the envelope.
Anyway, I'm leaving.
See you tomorrow.
"We'll consider an investment
depending on your results," huh?
Some company's running nighttime deliveries too?
We're nowhere near that yet.
Violet!
What are you doing?
A delivery run.
When I said a delivery run next, I meant tomorrow!
Also, please make sure to take breaks during work.
You just got out of the hospital.
It's not a problem.
Look, it is a problem.
Violet.
You may eat.
I will, thank you.
Once we're done here, I'll walk you to the office.
Only the attic's available,
but I set it up so you can sleep there.
Also, uh, the Evergarden family say
they're still willing to be your guarantors
until you become an adult.
But as for letting you live with them...
That part hit a snag, huh?
That hurt!
Come on! I was trying to break it to her gently!
Why should I care?
See you tomorrow, then.
Let me walk you.
What were the last orders Gilbert gave you?
"Run away and live free."
Also... "I..."
Ever since you were little,
you'd spent your life in the military,
focusing only on completing your missions.
From now on, you'll broaden your
horizons and learn many new things.
But it might be easier to live a life of blissful ignorance.
You haven't realized that everything
you've done so far has sparked a flame
that is now burning you up.
But I'm not on fire.
Oh, you are.
No, I am not. You're not making any sense.
You are.
You most definitely are.
And yet, I looked the other
way and pretended I didn't see it.
So when Gilbert left you in my care,
I saw it as my chance to make amends.
You'll understand what I'm saying one day.
And, for the first time, you'll notice all your burn marks.
A Doll?
No, I'm Violet.
Well, uh, Miss Violet,
I'd like to request a ghostwriting.
A ghostwriting?
Yeah.
I can't write, you see.
So I'd like you to write a letter for me.
What should I write?
You want me to tell you here and now?
Is that a problem?
Well, er...
It's a letter to my childhood friend out in the country.
I heard there'll be marriage
talks between her and another man.
So...
I want you to tell her...
"You were the first person to ever be nice to me."
"You meant the world to me."
"For you, I was willing to do anything and everything."
Go!
"I want to know how you feel."
"I want to understand your thoughts."
"We may be far apart now,
but I..."
"I love you."
Is that all right?
Y-Yes!
"I love you."
Now, take this to the reception on the
ground floor and complete the mailing paperwork.
Thank you very much for using
our Auto Memoir Doll service, sir.
And?
Who might you be?
How could you tell?
Hm?
How could you understand that man's "I love you"?
You want to work with the Auto Memoir Dolls?
Yes.
I still have difficulty holding a
pen, but I am able to use a typewriter.
No, that's not it. I'm asking you why you want that work.
I want to know.
I want to know what "I love you" means.
After giving his final orders,
the major uttered those words to me.
That was the first time I had ever heard him say it.
I don't understand what state of mind it refers to.
I can't understand it.
Generally speaking,
understanding that is what makes an Auto Memoir Doll.
But...
Very well.
After doing nothing but
following Gilbert's orders for so long,
she spoke for herself for the very first time.
The girl they called a tool without a mind of her own
wanted to know what "I love you" meant.
I swear... I swear I won't let you die, Major!
Stop it.
That's enough!
You must live...
Violet...
You must live on...
and be free.
From the bottom of my heart...
I love you.
"I Love You" and Auto Memoir Dolls