Four Years Ago
Port Stimmer,
Leidenschaftlich
Colonel Dietfried Bougainvillea,
your younger brother is here to see you.
Hey, Gil.
Have you been well? I see you still
have that stodgy look on your face.
You look just like Dad.
You haven't changed either, Brother.
Father would never have approved of that hairstyle.
He'd probably have lopped it off with his sword.
Anything but that.
You're always like this.
I'm glad he died.
Sorry.
Don't look at me like that.
I have a wonderful gift for you
tonight, to celebrate your promotion.
Listen.
This is but a weapon.
Use it without mercy or compassion.
Open it.
Hey, get up.
I found her on the northeastern front.
Her name is...
Violet Evergarden.
She'll be working as a trainee
Auto Memoir Doll from today.
Show her the ropes and the tricks of the trade.
Sure.
The blank-faced girl before me
looked just like a doll—
like the namesake of the job she performed.
Like a mechanical doll.
Uh, first off,
how much do you know
about an Auto Memoir Doll's job?
It entails writing letters and
the like as per the clients' requests.
Colonel Hodgins—
I mean, the boss told me.
Precisely.
I can't say I fully understand it yet,
but I should be able to carry out my missions.
This job ain't that easy!
And what do you mean, missions?
Iris, just focus on your work.
Okay.
Oh, right. I haven't introduced
you to the other Dolls yet, have I?
By the way, "Doll" is—
The short-form address for "Auto Memoir Doll"?
I realized that the other day.
Precisely.
The girl from before?
She's Iris, a rookie who just finished her training course.
And this is Erica.
She and I have been in this business for ages,
but since this company wasn't founded too long ago,
we're basically all newcomers here.
I don't think that's even close.
Violet, how are you with a typewriter?
I've never used one.
Let's begin with typing practice, then.
And she wants to be a Doll?
Iris, could you get us the manual?
Right away.
Uh, take a seat.
Roger.
You should take off your gloves.
Right.
Will you be okay?
No problem.
I see.
Give it a shot, then.
You place the paper like this,
and then you turn the knob to wind it around.
Place your index fingers on F
and J and press down on them.
Okay.
Yes, like that.
That's the way.
Next, memorize the finger placements for each letter.
Try following this manual.
H-Hey, Violet?
Violet, stop!
Could you, er,
keep it down?
Thank you very much!
That's 1.2 libre, so it'll be 10 colis.
Thank you very much.
Finally lunch!
Nerine, Lilian.
Let's eat together.
I bought noodles. There's enough for you guys too.
No thanks.
And don't show up at the counter all sweaty.
What the heck was that?
A man pours his blood, sweat,
and tears into his work, and he gets no praise?
And "don't show up"? What the hell?
Why are women so calculating these days?
And all that perfume!
I bet they're trying to reel in a
couple rich guys at the counter.
Let it go, boy.
Forget it. I've had it with working women.
Hey, you fellas want noodles?
No. And stop calling us fellas.
I'll gladly share your noodles.
Aw, another day of typing addresses?
Both afternoon bookings personally requested Cattleya.
You okay?
I-I'm fine.
I come all the way to Leiden and start working as a Doll,
but each and every day, I'm either writing addresses
or letters seeking information
about people who went MIA.
Nothing but that crap.
Yeah.
That reminds me. Apparently,
that newbie was in the army too.
But she's just a kid.
Oh, so that's why.
Why appoint her as a Doll?
She's so aloof, and I bet there's
not a tactful bone in her body.
There's no way she's cut out for this.
Man, I wanna write something exciting!
For a celebrity! Like an actress's secret love letter!
But Cattleya takes all of those.
How's Violet?
I asked her to lunch,
but she said she needed no "replenishment."
She's glued to the typewriter, practicing.
I see.
Sorry for all this.
Then you can make it up by taking me out to dinner,
Claudia!
Don't call me by that name!
I know your parents wanted a girl,
but that was just cruel of them.
I couldn't handle calling out a woman's name in bed.
Stop it, please! I'm sorry!
I can't treat you anytime soon.
No pay for me this month.
I'm done writing the addresses.
Good work.
I'll send them over to Deliveries.
Please do.
You should call it a day too, Violet.
Let me see.
My, you've improved a lot.
Impressive.
This weapon is what's impressive.
"Weapon"?
I guess. You could say it's a weapon that lets
us working women fight in the wider society.
You can accompany a Doll
and see how they work tomorrow.
I'm going on a house call now.
If a client requests it, we even visit their
home or workplace to ghostwrite for them.
May I take one with me as well?
A typewriter? Where?
My quarters. For training,
and also...
Gilbert's address?
Yes.
I wish to report to him that
I've assumed a ghostwriting post
and have begun training for it.
The major must still be busy.
I can't see him yet, can I?
Yeah...
Got it. I'll send this out for you.
So, how is your training? Going well?
It is.
No problem.
As you know,
I'm having a hard time getting
through each day as it comes.
"As you're aware, I require more funds..."
You spelled that incorrectly.
Also mention that I'll repay it at two clore per month.
"Every month..."
At two clore per month,
it will take about 120 years to repay the sum in full.
Will either of you live that long?
He's normally a very good boy.
But he does lose his temper at times.
"We apologize for the harm your dear child suffered."
Did I not raise him right?
"We promise to discipline him more firmly..."
Where?
Where did I go wrong?
Uh...
You're stalling the work,
so please cease crying immediately.
Wha—
What the hell is this?
"I know this is a selfish request"?
What do you mean, selfish?!
I'm sorry.
And "I have no excuse for the delay"?
Why are you making it sound like it was all my fault?!
Who do you think you are?
She's Erica.
I wasn't asking for her name!
Anyway, I don't like this letter!
I ain't paying for it!
Withholding payment for a service
because you don't like it is against the law.
What is it that you don't like, and why?
Out of my way.
We need a clear, precise explanation.
Please be prompt.
I've received quite a few complaints from customers.
Was there a problem?
Well, uh...
Are you okay?
There are no issues with my health.
I mean, how are you adjusting to Doll work?
I am devoting myself to my training.
I-Is that so?
If I may...
We have no more bookings for the day.
The Chamber of Commerce and
Industry's roster needs to be prepared,
but I'll work on it with her.
Type out the company name,
address, and industry sector.
Roger that.
Hey.
Why did you choose this line of work?
I...
Oh.
Nobody home?
Welcome, ma'am.
Are you looking for a ghostwriter?
Why else would I be here?
Pardon me.
If it pleases you,
we would be honored to write anything you request.
The Auto Memoir Doll service—
Is the Doll named Cattleya Baudelaire here?
She is currently out on a house call.
Really? I'd heard that she was the best one for the job.
Oh, well.
Someone asked me out, you see.
He's a man who founded an automobile company,
saying the age of personal vehicles was upon us.
I see...
But I'm not that easy.
I don't want him to think I'm a loose woman.
I'm not sure I follow.
Well, he's not that special,
and I don't have any feelings for him.
But I may consider it if he shows that he truly loves me.
I want to send a refined, romantic letter.
Write it for me.
Um...
Oh? Will you write it for me?
Roger.
What was with that letter?!
Please calm down, ma'am.
Iris!
Get her some tea!
R-Right away!
I wrote it according to your request.
Like hell you did!
He got angry and sent it back to me!
Why don't you read out what you wrote for us?
"I read your letter, but I currently feel nothing for you.
Also, you're lacking in affection and sincerity.
Keep in mind that I happen to
be a complex and dignified woman
and try again once you've
acquired enough funds and presents."
What is the issue?
I'm terribly sorry!
That was a bit too straightforward.
I wanted to be with him.
But if I accepted right away, he'd think I was too easy.
Doesn't every woman want
to make her man pursue her?
I loved him too, you know!
What will you have?
Water, warm or otherwise,
will provide ample hydration.
Two floral teas, please.
Certainly.
We shouldn't have let you
take up that job right off the bat.
I fail to understand.
I wrote the letter that best reflected the client's wishes.
There are two sides to words.
What's spoken isn't necessarily all there is to it.
It's a human weakness.
We tend to test others to reaffirm our worth.
How contrary, right?
I think I'll visit the addressee and apologize to him.
Major?
Major!
Major Gilbert!
Hup.
Hey!
What's up?
You alone?
You look out of sorts. Are you eating properly?
There is no problem with my nutrition intake.
Did you mess up at work, then?
You should just come back to Deliveries.
Deliveries won't do.
You should drop that obsession with
Doll work and look for something else.
I should think about it too.
Hodgins was complaining about no pay this month.
Our company might be in trouble.
May I ask you a question?
Huh?
Am I not suited to being an Auto Memoir Doll?
You could say the same about me.
I'm not asking about you.
Then no, you're not.
Why did you want to do this in the first place?
I want to know what "I love you" means.
That's it?
That's it.
I'm aware that it is an
expression of a particular emotion.
But I don't know why the major suddenly said it to me.
And I want to know.
Even if I'm not suited to this work,
I want to continue with it.
We have towels in the dressing room.
Either way, I don't think Violet can be a Doll.
We're still a new company,
but Cattleya is crazy popular.
We can't afford to tank our reputation
when things are starting to look up.
You should let Violet go.
Nah. Give her some more...
Excuse me!
Erica?
And Violet?
What happened to you two?
I... I don't think there's any need to fire her!
Violet, she...
Her typing is quick and precise,
so she can handle basic tasks like
writing addresses and preparing rosters.
She'll eventually learn more things,
and one day she'll be capable of ghostwriting letters.
Please,
don't fire her.
That's contrary.
You said yourself I wasn't suited for this mission.
You're being contrary.
I'm the one who isn't suited
to being an Auto Memoir Doll.
That's why I got so worked
up and spoke out on her behalf.
The instrument that would later become the typewriter
was invented by Professor Orland,
a leader in the field of letterpress printing.
He made it for his author wife Molly
after she went blind and became unable to write,
but he called it an "Auto Memoir Doll"—
the term that now symbolizes the ghostwriting business.
Meeting that girl brought it all back to me.
The dream that I nearly forgot,
and the feelings that had been buried deep inside of me.
Just like how Mrs. Orland's novel touched my heart...
I'm closing up shop. That okay?
Oh, sure.
I pray that I too...
will one day be able to write
letters that can move people's hearts.
All done!
What do you think?
Stand up, Violet.
Okay.
Great.
You look wonderful.
I knew it would suit you.
Oh, also...
One last thing.
Sorry it took so long.
Open it.
I'm opening it.
This is it.
This is the brooch the major gave me!
I found it for sale on the black market.
Somebody must've stolen it from your belongings.
I know!
Violet,
would you like to join a Doll training course?
They have intensive ones for newcomers.
Iris went to one, too.
The teachers were crazy strict, though.
I'm sure it'll help.
Ah, so that brooch was where
your pay for this month went?
Thank you so very much!
So who is this major she mentioned?
Gilbert.
A friend of mine from officer school.
One of the Bougainvillea.
Like the marquis?
Man, for a pampered rich kid,
he had real character.
"Had"?
He's...
"Never Coming Back"
anata no koe ga michishirube
Your voice is my guiding light
ichiwa no tori ga naiteiru
A sparrow cries out
namae no nai sora ni watashi wo sagashite
Looking for me within a nameless sky
yasashisa de amitsuzuketa yurikago de asu e yukou
I will head for tomorrow in this cradle woven from kindness
hare no hi mo ame no hi ni mo
Be it a day of rain or a day of sunshine
anata wo mamoru tame ni
I will be there to protect you
kakegae no nai takaramono
A treasure more valuable than all
namae no nai hana wa
A nameless flower
shizuka ni nemuru yo
Lies in peace