Leiden sure is huge, isn't it?
It really is! It has so many streets
compared to my hometown that I got lost!
Apparently, getting this school's
brooch makes it easier to find a job.
I wanna graduate and go back home right away.
Are you sure you're not just after the brooch?
Oh, come on!
Silence, please.
I welcome you all to the
Auto Memoir Doll Training School.
Sorry I'm late!
Know that repeated tardiness is
counted as absence without leave.
Yes, ma'am.
With the War now over,
the demand for Dolls grows by the day.
Of course, you can become
one without attending this school.
However, our goal is not to produce just any Dolls
but to produce the very finest.
The brooch that symbolizes graduation
from this school also symbolizes excellence.
That said, those of you I do not deem worthy Dolls
will find it entirely out of your grasp.
Are you all ready?
Roger!
Violet Evergarden.
Her demeanor was completely
divorced from her doll-like appearance.
She was more like a soldier.
Each time I learn a new word
shiranai kotoba wo oboeteyuku tabi
The fog begins to clear
omokage no naka te wo nobasu no
But there may well be words
dakedo hitori de wa wakaranai kotoba mo
I cannot understand alone
aru no kamoshirenai
"Goodbye" is a bitter pill to swallow
sayonara wa nigakute
And "I love you" is strangely distant
aishiteru wa tooi nioi ga shita
This indescribable emotion welling inside
tatoeyou no nai kono omoi wa
Scares me to the bone
totemo kowakute
But also feels very dear to me
dakedo totemo itooshikute
Why am I crying?
watashi nande naiterundarou
What reason do I give my heart?
kokoro ni nante kotaetara ii
Words don't always tell the whole story
kotoba wa itsudemo kataru demo nakute
Sometimes, they are simply there
soko ni aru bakari
Building up rapidly
tsunoru bakari
And making me miss you
watashi wa anata ni aitakunaru
To be a first-rate Doll,
you need the typing speed to
transcribe the words as they are spoken.
Please begin.
What is the matter, Ms. Evergarden?
You haven't specified a required speed.
Ah.
If I do, you will be able to match it?
Two hundred characters per minute, then.
Roger.
I'll start now.
Go ahead.
Aren't you going to eat?
I've been trained to
minimize my intake during a mission.
But...
Want some of mine?
No, thank you,
Miss Luculia from Leiden.
You remember what I said in my introduction?
I remember what everyone said in theirs.
The letter-writing skills required of a first-rate
Doll include grammatical perfection, a rich vocabulary,
and detailed knowledge of the various types of letters.
That's it for today.
I shall now announce today's grades,
Starting with grammar.
Violet Evergarden, full marks.
Next, vocabulary.
I have returned from my mission.
How was school?
I bet you got yelled at.
No, I didn't.
Welcome back, Violet.
Boss, I have here Instructor
Rhodanthe's daily evaluation of my work.
Okay.
What's it say?
Wow, great grades for the first day.
Oh, you're back?
How long are you going to keep that up? Be a man!
Right back at you!
Huh? No, you!
What are they doing?
Those two are always at loggerheads.
Huh? No, you!
Forget it.
Those two are always at loggerheads.
I'm amazed you got them to work together
long enough to form this company with you.
Your exercise for today will be an actual ghostwriting.
Let's do this.
I'm in your hands, Miss Luculia.
So, who will this letter be for?
You are asking who I want to send a letter to?
Simply pick someone close to you to
whom you wish to convey something.
Someone close to me?
Please address the letter to Claudia Hodgins.
Claudia?
A friend? Family?
My boss.
That is all for my report.
Yours, Violet Evergarden.
Is that it?
On second thought,
"When will I receive new orders from the major?"
Add that to the end, please.
This feels more like filing official
paperwork than sending a letter.
Now it is your turn to dictate a letter, Miss Luculia.
R-Right.
Uh, to my bro...
Actually, I think I'll address it to my parents.
Roger.
You see, I haven't really thanked my
mother and father for everything they've done.
Hmm... Now that I'm actually
sending a letter, I can't find the right words.
There's so much I want to say about the places
we went, and the places I wish we could've gone,
that I can't fit it all in.
Talk to you again soon.
Please don't worry about me.
Yours, Luculia.
Violet, read this out for us.
Sure.
"Dear Father, Mother,
I know I haven't written to you in
some time, but I have nothing new to report.
It is a matter of great concern to me that I
haven't expressed my gratitude for what you did.
As for the places we went,
and the places I wish we could've gone,
I have no information to give you.
I am carrying out my duties in a diligent manner
and am sound in both body and mind.
I haven't run into any problems.
That is all. I ask that you don't concern
yourself with my wellbeing. Yours, Luculia."
You call that a letter?
U-Uh, maybe I didn't make myself clear.
That isn't the issue here.
Letters are an instrument for
communicating a person's feelings.
A first-rate Doll should
understand the words the client is speaking
and take from them the
feelings they truly wish to express.
Violet, your grades are good across all subjects,
and your typing is truly fast and precise.
But what you have ghostwritten can't be called a letter.
It can't be called a letter?
Um, we can try again—
That's it for today.
Please give the letters you have written
to the people to whom they are addressed.
Don't worry. You just weren't at your best today.
Something similar happened previously.
Really?
Hey, let me show you the
most beautiful view in this city.
Here we are.
The stairs are steep, so watch your step.
Isn't it amazing?
I've loved this view ever since I was a little kid.
Violet...
I hope that one day,
you'll get to see that beautiful view in Leiden.
Well, I'm going this way.
See you.
Miss Luculia.
Just call me Luculia, Violet.
Go home already.
Don't be like that, man. What's the problem?
Brother! Have you been drinking again?
I haven't.
Welcome back.
This guy won't let me, so I haven't—
Brother!
Are you okay?
Damn it!
Luculia...
Thank you.
Violet, I'm happy about the letter,
but this is more like a report.
The instructor also said that what I
ghostwrote couldn't be called a letter.
Will I...
Will I ever be a worthy Doll?
I'm home! I'll get cooking right away—
Dad, Mom...
Bluebell Junoa.
Yes, ma'am.
Iberis Konoue.
Luculia Marlborough.
Yes, ma'am.
The aforementioned nine will graduate from this class.
May you all be exemplary Dolls.
We did it! Where are you going to work?
The post office back home.
I think I'll look for something here in Leiden.
And you, Luculia?
Uh, I haven't decided yet.
What? But you're graduating top of the class!
Really? That's too bad.
I'm terribly sorry.
Don't worry.
It's not like you have to graduate to be a Doll.
But then...
Why did I go to school at all?
I'm aware that graduating isn't everything,
but if I can't understand the words the client is speaking
and take from them the feelings they wish to express,
I don't serve any purpose as a Doll.
I knew you would come here.
Luculia.
School has ended. Why are you here?
Because I thought I might be able to see you again.
Say, Violet.
Who is this major of yours?
You always asked after replies
from the major in each of your letters.
Aren't they the one you really wanted to write to?
Why don't we try writing to them today?
Not one of your usual reports,
but a letter packed with how you really feel.
I'll be with you all the way.
Major...
I'm sorry.
I don't know what I want to tell him either.
I haven't even understood the words he said to me.
What made you want to be a Doll?
I want to know what "I love you" means.
What "I love you" means?
It's difficult to tell someone how you feel, isn't it?
The truth is, my parents are dead.
My brother's the only family I have left.
And I don't know what I can say to him.
When the War broke out, he went to fight in the army.
But the western front, where he
was stationed, saw next to no combat.
The War was always being fought somewhere far away,
so we never really felt its true impact.
But when Dad and Mom went to Herne for trade talks...
...the western front was breached?
Nothing was left, not even their belongings.
And then, the War ended.
C'mon, just one drink!
My brother came home.
Knock it off!
I wanted to be happy that he at
least came back alive, and I was.
What the hell, man?
But...
Shut up!
He was filled with regret about
not being able to defend Herne.
He'd convinced himself that it
was his fault that our parents died.
Don't show your face 'round here again.
But all that doesn't matter.
I'm really just glad he's alive.
All I want is to thank him!
But I've never been able to.
Luculia, write a letter.
A letter where you put all the
feelings you wish to express into words.
But I can never find the right words to say.
I've tried many times before, but I just can't do it.
And I don't know if I ever will.
Thank you for hearing me out, Violet.
I'll help you write that letter
to the major some other time.
"A first-rate Doll should
understand the words the client is speaking
and take from them the
feelings they truly wish to express."
Brother!
Wait, Brother!
Come on.
Thanks.
Hurry up. Get over here.
You were right! It's so pretty!
A woman?
Aren't you Luculia's...
What's that?
My mission—
No, my duty.
Or rather, a letter.
From Luculia to you.
From Luculia?
"Dear Brother,
I'm glad you're here for me.
Thank you for everything."
Welcome back.
Where have you been?
You were out awfully late.
School.
By the way, where's the boss?
A union get-together, apparently.
Wait, weren't you already through with school?
That's correct, but I wrote a letter today.
I don't know if I managed to
convey my client's feelings, though.
Is that so?
Weren't you two fighting?
Oh, right! Can you believe what this moron did?
He left a wet cup on top of a letter I'd ghostwritten!
You're the moron!
Your fault for leaving a letter there!
Seriously, what is with your attitude?
Oh, for crying out loud!
Violet!
Luculia?
What's the matter?
Good morning, Violet.
Instructor. I thought the course was complete.
Sorry. I barged in and asked her.
Luculia showed me this letter.
This letter from her to her
brother, which you ghostwrote.
I'd never been able to tell
my brother how I felt about him,
but Violet, you helped me finally express it.
"A first-rate Doll should
understand the words the client is speaking
and take from them the
feelings they truly wish to express."
You have just taken that first step.
Violet...
May you be an exemplary Doll.
Violet!
Congratulations!
Luculia...
And thank you so much!
Letters don't always have to be
filled with lots of flowery language.
Sometimes, it only takes a
sentence or two to express one's feelings.
I think that's one of the most important things
for a Doll to understand, and she taught it to me.
She was a bit doll-like in appearance,
a bit like a soldier,
and a bit strange,
but she was a truly wonderful girl.
"May You Be an Exemplary Auto Memoir Doll"
anata no koe ga michishirube
Your voice is my guiding light
ichiwa no tori ga naiteiru
A sparrow cries out
namae no nai sora ni watashi wo sagashite
Looking for me within a nameless sky
yasashisa de amitsuzuketa yurikago de asu e yukou
I will head for tomorrow in this cradle woven from kindness
hare no hi mo ame no hi ni mo
Be it a day of rain or a day of sunshine
anata wo mamoru tame ni
I will be there to protect you
kakegae no nai takaramono
A treasure more valuable than all
namae no nai hana wa
A nameless flower
shizuka ni nemuru yo
Lies in peace