What? A personal request?
For me?!
I'm happy for you, Iris.
You will be making a house call to Kazaly.
Kazaly? That's my hometown.
Oh, right.
So, who's the client?
Sara Florent, a woman in her forties. Do you know her?
Hmm... No, can't say I do.
All right.
To celebrate Iris's first request,
let's all go out for lunch today.
My hometown's way out in the
country, and I'm the only Doll from there.
The client must've heard about me from someone.
Not that I mind. I can go home and show this off.
Man, my friends and family
aren't going to leave me alone!
Try not to get carried away.
Behave in a manner befitting a Doll of C.H. Postal—
I know! I get it!
That's the kind of "I get it" that
means you don't get it at all, isn't it?
Excuse me? What did you just...
Each time I learn a new word
shiranai kotoba wo oboeteyuku tabi
The fog begins to clear
omokage no naka te wo nobasu no
But there may well be words
dakedo hitori de wa wakaranai kotoba mo
I cannot understand alone
aru no kamoshirenai
"Goodbye" is a bitter pill to swallow
sayonara wa nigakute
And "I love you" is strangely distant
aishiteru wa tooi nioi ga shita
This indescribable emotion welling inside
tatoeyou no nai kono omoi wa
Scares me to the bone
totemo kowakute
But also feels very dear to me
dakedo totemo itooshikute
Why am I crying?
watashi nande naiterundarou
What reason do I give my heart?
kokoro ni nante kotaetara ii
Words don't always tell the whole story
kotoba wa itsudemo kataru demo nakute
Sometimes, they are simply there
soko ni aru bakari
Building up rapidly
tsunoru bakari
And making me miss you
watashi wa anata ni aitakunaru
Nothing but letters canvassing votes lately.
Well, it is the first post-war election,
and the Lords are making all kinds of moves,
so the Commons candidates must be getting desperate.
Will those two be all right?
Of all the rotten luck...
I lost the perfect opportunity to
show off my awesome typing skills.
No need to worry. I'll type in your stead.
That's not the point.
Kazaly is a village midway up the mountains,
and its principal industries are
dairy farming and agriculture, yes?
It's a fairly new settlement, so it has no
other features or specialties to speak of.
Well, excuse us for having nothing going on.
It isn't a bad thing.
Anything of value will be fought
over, forever in the eye of the storm.
In North Leidenschaftlich,
the rich iron and copper reserves led
to its invasion by the Gardariki Empire.
Yeah, that's what kicked off the War.
My uncle was full of bluster, yelling
that he'd enlist, but my aunt was against it.
In the end, he never did.
Thanks to that, he didn't get hurt.
Sorry.
What was that apology for, exactly?
Well, uh, you did get hurt.
But why would you feel responsible for my injuries?
I don't, but...
An apology is the act of asking for forgiveness
when you feel responsible for a wrongdoing.
All right, all right! I get it!
From the moment I first met her, all the way up to now,
I never was able to wrap my
head around Violet Evergarden.
I just couldn't understand her.
Kazaly,
Leidenschaftlich
Yeah, it really is sticky here compared to Leiden.
Aren't you hot in those clothes?
No problem.
I'm used to temperature swings.
Are you, now?
Iris!
Welcome back.
Welcome home!
I'm so glad you could make it.
Dad, Mom! And Uncle and Aunt too!
What's with your arm?
What happened to it?
Oh, it was a flight—
A slight miscalculation. I overworked and hurt myself.
That statement is not factual.
I get a lot of personal requests, you see.
Nor is that one.
Ow!
Ouch! Crap, it started hurting again!
Work must be rough.
Especially for a star Auto Memoir Doll like you.
Ow, ow!
"Star"?
Jeez, Dad. Tone it down.
But if you're hurt, how are you going to ghostwrite?
Oh, that?
That's why she's here.
If a client requests it, we shall go anywhere.
Representing the Auto Memoir Doll service,
I am Violet Evergarden.
Like a toy doll?
Nah, "Doll" is their job title.
That took my breath away for a second.
I guess that's a city Doll for you.
Hey, I'm dressed as a Doll too!
Huh? Oh...
You look good, Iris. The very image of a career woman.
What the heck? Jeez...
Oh, right. Do you know Sara Florent?
She's the client. She's supposed to be here to meet me.
That was your late great-grandma's name.
The request was from me.
I figured I could see you by requesting a ghostwriting.
That's messed—
That makes your request invalid.
As the contract states, we don't accept
requests made under anonymity or pseudonyms.
Have a nice day.
H-Hey, Violet!
If you make a new request, I can accept it here and now.
Please write your legal name on the form.
What kind of invitations would you like me to write?
Invitations for Iris's birthday party.
Mine?!
Your birthday's the day after tomorrow, remember?
I totally forgot.
We're going to invite a lot of
people and throw one heck of a party.
If it's for the day after tomorrow, I must
start writing immediately to make it in time.
I'll need time for the deliveries, too.
So pretty!
What happened to you?
Stop that.
There's no need for concern.
Do you have a guest list?
Yeah.
Here you go.
Let me take a look.
Is it just me, or are there a lot of guys on this list?
Well, you're all grown up now.
And?
Don't you think it's time you got married?
What's that supposed to mean?
You're our only daughter.
We want you to come back home and settle down.
Quit your Doll work and live here with us.
This is why you called me back?
This is why you lied to me?!
You're lying to us too!
We know you're not "Leiden's most popular Doll."
Just quit already.
Either way, we're throwing this party.
Violet, please address the envelopes too.
Roger.
See this "Emonn Snow"?
Don't send him an invite.
Even though he's on the list?
Yeah.
Why is that?
Doesn't matter why.
Your parents selected this guest list.
I don't believe you have the
right to remove any names from it.
Look, just don't send him one.
But...
This request was for me.
You're only here to help me out. Got that?
Thanks a lot.
I'm done delivering my share.
I've finished as well.
Well, let's head back and have dinner.
We can't offer you anything
special all the way out here, though.
No problem. You don't have to.
Huh? I meant...
Besides,
while I don't have a clear reason why,
this scenery strikes me as
"something special" all on its own.
Here you are.
Thank you.
Happy birthday, Iris.
Thanks.
Is your arm okay?
Yeah, it's fine.
You became a Doll in Leiden, right?
Really? That's awesome!
Well, yeah...
Iris.
Got a moment?
We'll talk to you later.
Yeah.
Sorry to interrupt.
Remember him?
Montgomery. I hear he
passed the teacher's license exam.
And apparently, Hans is training to be a shoe craftsman.
Emonn!
Long time no see.
Sorry I'm late.
Happy birthday, Iris.
Why are you here?
Uh, because I got an invite.
You sent him one?
I checked with your mother,
and she said I should send one after all.
Iris?
Iris!
You did this by sending him that invite.
How is that related to your
sudden downturn in condition?
I told you not to send him one.
Why'd you have to go and do that?
I only carried out my mission.
I didn't want to see him.
Why is that? I won't
understand unless you give a reason.
Because he rejected me!
Do you mean you made advances
toward him, but he turned you down?
You showed your affection
for him, but he pushed you away?
Yeah.
That's right!
I can't believe Iris.
Sorry.
Oh, Violet. How was Iris?
She's crying.
Crying? Why?
Did something happen to her?
Iris?
Are you okay, Iris?
Cheer up.
We'll find you someone better—
You're still going on about that?!
This is all your fault for throwing that stupid party!
I never should've come back!
Food for you.
You told them?
Told them what?
About Emonn!
I did.
Why would you do that?!
It didn't seem like classified information,
and they were all worried about you.
That doesn't mean...
You really don't understand
how people feel at all, do you?
I'm sorry.
I thought I'd come to understand them a little,
but people's emotions are
extremely complicated and delicate.
Not everyone puts all of their feelings into words.
People can be contrary
or at times, untruthful.
I can't decipher them accurately.
It's proving all too difficult for me.
I'm truly sorry.
You don't need to apologize.
I know you had good intentions.
It's not like I understand
everything about how people feel either.
Really?
Yeah, really.
I've known Emonn since we were kids.
He was always sweet and kind to me.
I'd had a crush on him since forever,
and I'd convinced myself that the feeling was mutual.
I always wondered why he wouldn't make the first move.
So right before we graduated school, I told him.
I said, "I love you."
But...
Sorry.
I only see you as an old friend.
I wanted to crawl into a hole and die.
I couldn't stay here after that.
Writing was never my
strong suit, but I worked hard at it,
left for Leiden, and became a Doll there.
It seems "I love you" requires a lot of courage to say.
So much so that you want to
run away when it isn't reciprocated.
When the major said it,
did he feel the same way?
"The major"?
My commanding officer.
I became a Doll because I wanted
to know what his "I love you" meant.
Violet had been a complete enigma to me,
but right then, I understood her a little.
The major came into her life when
she knew nothing outside of the army
and showed her love.
And now, she's trying to find out what it truly means...
in her own way.
Say, Auto Memoir Doll.
Would you write some letters for me?
What kind of letters?
Apology letters for everyone who attended the party.
Sure.
Make them thoughtful and heartfelt, okay?
Do you want to send one to Emonn as well?
Talk about rubbing salt into the wound...
But yeah, send him one.
And your parents?
Why don't you try telling them how you really feel?
A letter can help you express it.
If you're having trouble speaking from the heart,
a letter can help you do it.
"Dear Dad and Mom,
I'm sorry for ruining the party.
I'll send apology letters to all the invitees.
Also, thank you for making a personal request for me.
In truth, it was my first.
So it made me really happy.
Work is a real handful at times,
but I chose this path for myself,
so I'll give it my best shot.
I'm sorry for making you worry so much over the years.
But I ask that you give me a little more time
and watch over me.
From the future most popular Doll in Leiden
in her first-ever letter to her beloved Dad and Mom—
one that will be remembered for years to come.
Sure you haven't forgotten anything?
Yeah.
If you ever need anything, let us know at once.
I'll be fine.
Also...
Thank you for that letter.
Uh...
She's the one who typed it out.
That's right. I'll hand you the invoice later.
What? You're going to charge me?
Ghostwriting is my job.
How about I buy you lunch for three days?
That isn't enough to cover the fee.
Give me an employee discount!
The train's about to leave.
Iris.
Happy birthday.
Take care.
Did that letter...
Did it help your feelings get through to your parents?
Couldn't you tell by looking at them?
It was a fine letter.
The words you wrote got through to them.
It was a fine letter, okay?
I... wrote... a good letter?
Why are you talking like a machine?
What flowers are those?
Oh, irises.
Take a look.
You see,
I was born when these flowers were in full bloom.
That's why my parents gave me this name.
What's your name?
Oh...
Can I give you one, then?
Violet...
Your name is Violet.
I'm sure you'll grow into a
woman just as lovely as those flowers.
"You Won't Be a Tool, but a Person Worthy of That Name"
anata no koe ga michishirube
Your voice is my guiding light
ichiwa no tori ga naiteiru
A sparrow cries out
namae no nai sora ni watashi wo sagashite
Looking for me within a nameless sky
yasashisa de amitsuzuketa yurikago de asu e yukou
I will head for tomorrow in this cradle woven from kindness
hare no hi mo ame no hi ni mo
Be it a day of rain or a day of sunshine
anata wo mamoru tame ni
I will be there to protect you
kakegae no nai takaramono
A treasure more valuable than all
namae no nai hana wa
A nameless flower
shizuka ni nemuru yo
Lies in peace