Leidenschaftlich
Army Department
Excuse me.
Want a drink?
Not now, thank you.
Is that so?
Well, I suppose you're not military
anymore. You're a private entrepreneur now.
Business is booming, I hear?
Thankfully.
But what if another war breaks out?
With the north?
That's right.
There are some powers within the
Northern League led by the Gardariki Empire
who haven't come to terms with the peace yet.
I assume you've heard of Drossel's public love letters?
Drossel? The kingdom that's
part of our Southern Federation?
Yes.
Drossel and Flugel, two enemy nations,
will be entering a marriage of happy convenience.
This ceremony has the distinct aim of proclaiming
the end of the War to the neighboring countries.
I'll be on my way, Boss.
The Kingdom of Drossel
Violet.
I know this is no easy task,
but you've completed a great
many jobs over the past few months.
Believe in yourself. You can do this.
This is the royal palace.
Goodbye.
May you write a fine letter.
This is Miss Violet Evergarden from C.H. Postal,
requesting an audience with
Princess Charlotte Abelfreyja Drossel.
It is a pleasure to meet you.
If a client requests it, we shall go anywhere.
Representing the Auto Memoir
Doll service, I am Violet Evergarden.
Your Highness?
Your Highness,
I believe I told you that you had an appointment today.
What, is the ghostwriter here?
It is a pleasure to meet you.
Representing the Auto Memoir
Doll service, I am Violet Evergarden.
I am Charlotte Abelfreyja Drossel,
arranged to marry Prince Damian Baldur
Flugel of the neighboring Kingdom of Flugel.
I have need of you to write
me a public love letter to him.
Your Highness...
Your current slovenly appearance entirely
undermines the refinement in your speech.
Our public love letters are defined by
how beautifully they express one's love
and establish the wedding in
people's minds as something to celebrate.
It all rides on your skill, ghostwriter.
I am perfectly aware.
I won't betray your expectations.
Why do I feel like I'm not speaking to another person?
You really are like a doll.
By the way, ghostwriter, how old are you?
I'm sorry to say that, as an orphan,
I do not know the precise year of my birth.
However, I have been told
that I should be around fourteen.
Sorry about that.
Would you please accept my apology, ghostwriter?
You needn't apologize.
If I may ask, is there a problem with my age?
Not at all. I simply wish to hear the
opinion of someone close to me in years.
Er...
How much older can a man be and still be kosher?
Kosher?
Her Highness refers to suitability as a romantic partner.
I have never been involved in romance.
But through reading a wide variety of literature,
I have been able to compile a statistical analysis.
My conclusion
is that there are many examples of
couples with a substantial age difference.
Socially speaking, age is no barrier.
Even if there is a ten-year gap?
Prince Damian is twenty-four.
I don't believe that would be a problem.
Even if there is no love?
Well?
"Love"...
That is a concept which has been weighing on my mind.
Be it love,
or a loveless marriage,
I do not possess sufficient
knowledge or understanding of the topic
to answer your query.
What is with you? What sort of life have you led?
You can hardly call this a conversation!
It's making me more worried
about your future than mine!
Also, could you please show some kind of emotion?
Please give me a moment.
It is complete.
"Dear Damian Baldur Flugel,
If I were to say that simply saying your
name out loud, or writing it out like so,
makes my heart race, how would that make you feel?
Every happening in this city
of flowers reminds me of you,
leaving me to spend every day sighing endlessly.
One such example is when I
gaze up at the moon in the night sky.
The waning moon strikes me as
much like a petal swaying in the wind.
The Kingdom of Flugel
Which then brings me to my next thought:
how do you feel when you gaze upon that same moon?
You've written about flowers
and the moon as instructed.
Wow...
You're really good at writing love letters!
Hey!
Yes?
Oh, "The Wedding Draws Near," huh?
Looks like things might work out.
"Dear Charlotte Abelfreyja Drossel,
the beautiful princess of White Camellia Castle,
You are my love story, the object of my passion,
and I can hardly contain my desire for you.
How dreamy.
You are my love story, the object of my passion,
and I can hardly contain my desire for you.
My dear, I want to touch you as soon as I can."
Excuse me.
An exquisite letter, as you would expect.
Is she feeling overwhelmed by the letter?
No.
It wasn't that kind of tears.
That's how she cries when
things don't go the way she wants.
I can tell because I've known the princess
ever since she was still in the queen's womb.
Your Highness, hiding is futile.
I can find you in a heartbeat.
Your Highness.
If I were your future mother-in-law,
this would lower my opinion of you.
You have a bad habit of forgetting
who you are when you get too emotional.
Once you marry into Flugel,
you won't have me by your side.
How could you say that, Alberta?
I am a court maid.
I serve the royal family, not you.
No, you're mine!
You brought me out of my mother's womb!
You raised me!
If nothing else, I'm yours!
First the letter, and now you.
Why is everything going wrong?
Get out!
I said get out!
No.
I shall stay right by your side.
Princess Charlotte, how would you like the next letter?
I don't really care anymore, to be honest.
Write whatever you want.
I bet a Doll's writing his letters too, anyway.
And Prince Damian is a busy man.
He likely isn't even reading these.
It doesn't matter what we write.
You aren't satisfied with his replies?
That's not it.
It's just...
I've met Prince Damian once, and he wasn't
the kind of man who would speak like that.
Say, may I put the Princess of
Drossel thing aside, just for now?
And Violet, could you also forget about being a Doll
and listen to me as the person you are?
Just hearing me out would be enough.
Sure.
The day I turned ten,
Drossel threw a grand party to celebrate.
For royalty, marriage arrangements
officially begin when we turn ten.
Every single person I was made
to meet was a prospective husband.
It felt like nobody was there to celebrate my birthday.
My own feelings didn't matter.
Or so everyone seemed to think.
Hey.
Did no one come looking for you?
Go on and cry.
Cry all you want.
I'm trying to stop crying here!
Don't say that!
Back at the party, you came across as a sassy little brat,
so it's a relief to see you can cry too.
That was the worst birthday bash I could imagine.
Even I had to hightail it out of there.
Of course the birthday girl would want to cry.
See you.
He spoke to me plainly, from the heart.
That's all it was.
But it left an impression on me.
It made me really happy.
Soon after, the War grew in scale,
putting all the marriage talks on the backburner.
But as soon as it ended,
I received a proposal out of nowhere.
I didn't want to let this chance go to waste,
so I studied up on all the benefits a marriage
between our countries would bring to Drossel.
I also laid the groundwork
with my father and the cabinet.
And while I don't know if that was the direct cause,
Drossel chose Flugel.
I'm incredibly happy about this marriage.
But what about him?
Maybe he has someone else he loves?
And we're ten whole years apart.
We might not click with each other.
I mean...
I'm nothing but a crybaby.
I'll be in a new country without Alberta by my side.
What if I do something to make him hate me?
That letter was all hogwash.
It had no heart.
I want to know how he truly feels.
You want to know how he truly feels...
Princess Charlotte.
Violet?
We Auto Memoir Dolls are our
clients' ghostwriters, and nothing more.
We don't do anything that they don't ask for.
So please understand that
what I'm about to do is out of line,
and that C.H. Postal will not be held responsible.
What are you thinking?
I want to stop your tears.
You see, I recognize his Doll's prose somewhat.
Violet...
What is she going to do?
Your Highness.
"Dear Charlotte Abelfreyja Drossel,
do you remember meeting me that moonlit
night in the White Camellia Castle's garden?"
Hey, that letter's handwritten!
And is that all? What the heck?
This is unprecedented. What's going on?
Violet!
I met with Prince Damian's Doll
and laid out a plan for future letters.
Now, you write a letter
in your own words.
Dear Damian Baldur Flugel,
I remember you very well.
You laughed when you saw me crying.
That really got on my nerves.
But I can never forget your voice as you told me to cry,
nor the kindness you showed me back then.
I laughed because it was cute
to see you finally act your age.
I didn't mean to offend you. Forgive me.
I may be a prince in name, but I'm not
the kind of guy everyone wanted me to be.
Don't expect me to be a mature man.
We only met once, on that night,
so I don't know you well. What kind of girl are you?
Oh my god!
It's like a real love letter!
I'm a crybaby with a short temper,
not the kind of girl who would make you go crazy.
That's not true!
Put her at ease, prince!
I have a little sister, so I'm used to crybaby girls.
I'm not much of a great guy myself.
I can't make you go crazy for me either.
What are you even saying?
If you're a man, be one and tell her to walk with you!
You're wrong. I'm already crazy for you!
Because of the first letter I sent?
A first-rate Doll wrote that one.
I don't mean the person in that letter.
I mean the one who patted my head
on that moonlit night four years ago!
Why? All I did was give you a shoulder to cry on one time.
To me, that one time has been a
precious memory, a shining jewel in my life.
I'm a thoughtless guy who doesn't understand women.
I'll go on hunts and stuff and leave you behind.
I know I'll disappoint you.
I'm sure you'll find a much better,
far more wonderful man as you grow up—
If I may ask, what makes a wonderful man?
Looks? Riches?
In my mind, a wonderful man is one
who is willing to be himself with me.
Among all the men putting on airs,
you are the only one I know who says he's not a great guy.
That's more than enough! That's what I want!
If you go hunting, I'll go with you!
Don't make light of a Drossel princess!
I've had the education to be a fine match for any man!
I'm confident I'll be a faster rider than you!
I never should've written those things!
He must think for sure I'm a rebellious, sassy brat now!
If I'd known this would happen,
I would've made you write everything!
Alberta should've stopped me too!
Princess Charlotte...
You have a reply.
What does it say?
"I'll be waiting in the moonlit garden tonight."
Hey.
Prince Damian?
I brought you my reply.
It seems my future bride is a
smart, tough, and intriguing person.
You'll be an amazing wife.
Let's get married, Charlotte.
Will you marry me?
Yes.
Their love came true.
Your Highness?
It's time to get ready.
Rise and shine.
Your Highness?
Alberta.
I'm over here, Alberta.
Good morning.
Your Highness, you mustn't poke fun at grownups.
Oh, but I'm all grown up too.
Come.
It's time to get ready, Princess Charlotte.
Say, Alberta.
Where do you think Violet is right now?
She must have left the country already.
You're beautiful.
I wish I could've showed Violet this wedding dress too.
Are you not worried anymore?
I am worried. Of course I'm worried.
Even now, I'm this close to crying.
You mustn't.
Not on this auspicious day.
I'm happy about marrying Prince Damian.
Right.
But leaving the country makes me sad.
But forget everybody else.
What really makes me sad is leaving you,
Alberta.
Princess...
I wish you all the happiness in the world,
Princess Charlotte.
Alberta...
You owe me one, Violet.
Convincing Prince Damian was hell.
I'm truly grateful.
I could go for some meat.
Is that how I should pay you back?
Precisely.
Roger.
It's a truly beautiful day, don't you think?
Yes.
It's the perfect day for a wedding.
anata no koe ga michishirube
Your voice is my guiding light
ichiwa no tori ga naiteiru
A sparrow cries out
namae no nai sora ni watashi wo sagashite
Looking for me within a nameless sky
yasashisa de amitsuzuketa yurikago de asu e yukou
I will head for tomorrow in this cradle woven from kindness
hare no hi mo ame no hi ni mo
Be it a day of rain or a day of sunshine
anata wo mamoru tame ni
I will be there to protect you
kakegae no nai takaramono
A treasure more valuable than all
namae no nai hana wa
A nameless flower
shizuka ni nemuru yo
Lies in peace
Port Leiden,
Leidenschaftlich
You...
Naval Captain Dietfried Bougainvillea...
It seems the rumors were true.
You really have become an Auto Memoir Doll, huh?
You, of all people?
You, who killed so many of my men,
are writing letters?
With your bloodstained hands
that have taken countless lives,
"You Write Letters That Bring People Together?"