Justitia Province,
Nation of Astraea
Hey, Leon! Look!
Women from all across the
continent are headed our way!
They're just ghostwriters.
You mean Auto Memoir Dolls.
Beautiful women who write
beautiful prose for their clients alone.
Hmph. They're dolled up for one reason:
because it's a profession full of women
who hope to one day marry into money.
If called upon, these women will go anywhere in the world
to hawk their so-called ghostwriting skills.
At first, I despised that Doll
profession for no discernible reason—
so much that I was taken
aback by how much it annoyed me.
Each time I learn a new word
shiranai kotoba wo oboeteyuku tabi
The fog begins to clear
omokage no naka te wo nobasu no
But there may well be words
dakedo hitori de wa wakaranai kotoba mo
I cannot understand alone
aru no kamoshirenai
"Goodbye" is a bitter pill to swallow
sayonara wa nigakute
And "I love you" is strangely distant
aishiteru wa tooi nioi ga shita
This indescribable emotion welling inside
tatoeyou no nai kono omoi wa
Scares me to the bone
totemo kowakute
But also feels very dear to me
dakedo totemo itooshikute
Why am I crying?
watashi nande naiterundarou
What reason do I give my heart?
kokoro ni nante kotaetara ii
Words don't always tell the whole story
kotoba wa itsudemo kataru demo nakute
Sometimes, they are simply there
soko ni aru bakari
Building up rapidly
tsunoru bakari
And making me miss you
watashi wa anata ni aitakunaru
Violet.
Long time no see!
You doing all right?
Miss Bluebell, Miss Iberis...
Luculia.
Hey, Violet. The letters you ghostwrote for
the Princess of Drossel were simply magical.
They really were.
I read the news articles too. I'm proud
to count you among my acquaintances.
What's up?
Nothing. Thank you.
Are you all right?
You seem rather down.
Violet...
Uh, ladies.
I'm Le Verrier, chief of the Shaher
Astronomy HQ in Justitia Observatory.
It's a pleasure to meet you, sir.
Our Shaher Astronomy HQ,
as you can see, also has a library housing
astronomy literature from all eras and places.
Our Manuscript Department spends
each day keeping every book in tip-top shape,
and if any get too worn out, they
make a fresh copy for preservation.
It is a highly important task.
Now, if that were the only work we
faced, they could handle it all themselves.
But last month, we received a great number
of extremely rare but poorly maintained books.
Some of them threatened to crumble
if you turned so much as a single page.
We have here eighty of you Auto Memoir Dolls
and eighty men from the Manuscript Department.
You will form pairs with one member from each side,
dictate the contents of the books, and write new copies.
You have two weeks.
These books are irreplaceable
and are of great worth to us
and many generations to come,
so your assistance is greatly appreciated.
Uh...
Next, Kyle Zoenig
and Miss Iberis Konoue from Fujimi Postal.
Looking forward to working with you, sir.
Y-Yeah, likewise.
Next, Leon Stephanotis
and Miss Violet Evergarden from C.H. Postal.
It is a pleasure to meet you.
If a client requests it, we shall go anywhere.
Representing the Auto Memoir Doll service,
I am Violet Evergarden.
Sir?
What's wrong, Leon?
U-Uh...
Nothing, really.
Next...
Don't bother. Just stay seated.
Pardon me.
It's fine.
First off,
we'll go with this book, written
in a common classical language.
It begins with records of a
sighting of Alley's Comet 400 years ago.
Alley's Comet?
That's right.
It's a periodic comet that
appears around once every 200 years.
We estimate that it'll be
visible from this observatory soon.
Understood.
Let's begin, then.
Okay.
Just so you know, I dictate very quickly.
If your typing can't keep up,
you won't be of use—
I am perfectly aware.
Th-Then let's see what you've got.
"An arrow of light in the great dark sky,
its long tail slicing Barbarossa's neck in two.
According to Ariadna, an astrologist,
'The arrow of light is an ill omen.
Once its shining light passes,
disease will abound, and the
king's demise will rock the country.'
Likewise, the arrow of light
also pierced through Barbarossa,
and it was almost as though his
body and soul were ripped apart...
If Ariadna is to be believed, the
arrow of light has appeared before.
And it signifies the Fairy King, Reinhard, taking a wife.
Of those fortunate enough to die beneath its light,
the women become Reinhard's consorts,
and the men become
offerings for the celebratory banquet.
As such, that parting is not a tragedy.
In the fairy kingdom, a land of eternity,
they will be bestowed new vessels in
which their souls will live on for all of time."
Please keep going.
R-Right. I guess you can keep up.
"However, the deaths of those fortunate
ones still cause panic among the populace.
All who see the arrow of light..."
Let's call it a day.
144.
Sir,
we completed about three days' work today.
You are an exemplary scribe.
Oh, really.
You all have done splendidly today.
We even have a pair who have made
three days' worth of progress already.
Please keep up the excellent
work for the remainder of the job.
Say...
How can you be fine after all that writing you did today?
It isn't all that exhausting compared to the travel.
It is our job as Dolls to go
anywhere, any time a client calls upon us.
Most of our year is spent on all
kinds of travel, suitcase in hand.
Then why are you working such a hard job?
Because it is a role I can fulfill.
At first, I thought of it as a mission.
But now I believe that this work—whether it
means expressing the feelings and desires of my clients,
or even taking in and transcribing the
thoughts of authors from days long past—
is, in these and many other ways,
a very special and wonderful thing.
I guess.
Am I really fit to have such a wonderful job?
What are you trying to say?
That we feel sorry for you, having Leon as a partner.
He has a real annoying personality, doesn't he?
He's an orphan who couldn't even
work here if not for Shaher's donation funds.
A lovely girl like you is wasted on him.
So come see us once you're done with work.
I'm an orphan too.
Also...
I haven't lived the kind of
proper life you seem to have assumed.
I only learned to read and
write in the past few years, too.
If one's birth or upbringing places a
restriction on who they can speak to,
then I believe you should stay away from me.
Well, it's different for you. Right?
Yeah. You know, his mother...
I don't even know what my parents look like.
You're sticking up for him
because you're his partner, right?
No.
I am merely stating the facts.
Let's go. We're not getting through to her.
Sir, did you find the book you were looking for?
Yeah, I did.
Are you upset?
I'm not upset.
This is just how I look.
I...
I'm often told I'm expressionless.
This is just how I look.
We're somewhat alike, aren't we?
What do you think she said then?
"You're a cute one."
How can I not ask her to stargaze with me?!
Hey, you listening to me?
Leon?
Let's both do our best.
For the four days they're still around.
It's lunchtime.
Why don't you eat with everyone else?
It's a habit.
You are most defenseless when eating or sleeping.
You don't react as quickly to enemies.
Enemies?
I used to be a soldier.
A soldier?
Is that strange?
I-It is!
You're clearly an ordinary girl!
Ordinary?
Yeah.
An ordinary... girl.
Don't you want to see it?
It's a 200-year cycle, so you won't
get another chance in your lifetime!
Uh, I mean Alley's Comet.
The comet covered in that book from the first day?
That's right.
D...
Don't you want to see it?
I...
It's an extraordinarily beautiful sight!
Yes, I would love to.
Really?!
Then I'll pick you up in front of the
quarters at 2 AM, three days from now.
Wait for me there.
Sit down here.
That's Alley's Comet.
A comet's tail is most clearly
visible in the eastern sky before sunrise.
Sir?
It's fine.
Don't be shy.
Have some soup.
You're a really nice person.
D-Don't be stupid! I'm not nice!
Also, I'm not good with women.
I'm always cold to them, and you're no exception.
Do you remember all those
things they said in the library?
Yes.
They were telling the truth.
Both about me and my family.
My mother was a traveling performer.
She toured the world, putting her
singing and dancing talents on show.
And then, she fell in love with a man
of this town and had a child with him.
That child was me.
Looking back, I think it was a good, happy family.
But one day, my father vanished.
He'd been in charge of Shaher's manuscript acquisition,
and he would travel across the
continent collecting rare books.
It wasn't unusual for his work
to take him to dangerous places.
And in the midst of one such trip,
we lost all contact with him.
Two years passed, and the search was called off.
Mom!
Leon!
Just wait, Leon! I promise to come back with Dad!
No!
Don't go, Mom!
Mom!
Mom...
She loved my father more than anyone,
so it must've been an easy choice for her.
I don't know if my wellbeing
never crossed her mind or what.
I learned back then that love
reduces people to bumbling fools.
That's why I...
Your mother was very important to you, wasn't she?
What about you?
I don't have any blood relations.
But there was one man who
took care of me for a long time.
We're separated now, though.
Being apart from him must make you lonely.
I don't understand how it feels to be lonely.
Even if I know what the emotion entails,
I can't tell if I'm feeling it.
Are you serious?
I don't lie.
Then...
Do you sometimes think back to him?
Always.
I always do.
Does your heart feel heavier
the more days you spend apart?
It does.
That's loneliness.
That's loneliness?
So being away from him made me feel lonely...
What if, while we're still working together,
you receive word that he's in serious danger?
Even if you go, there's no telling if you can save him.
Would you still rush to his aid?
Sorry. I guess I put you on the spot.
No. That isn't what gave me pause.
I wouldn't even have a choice in the matter.
I just wasn't sure how I'd apologize to you.
He means the world to me.
I would rather die than lose him.
Man, that's a shocker.
I didn't think you were the type to say such things.
Is that so?
That's like...
Almost like...
I see now! You love—
Look. I think that comet's tail has grown longer.
Well, Violet? Can you see it?
I can.
I've never felt the stars so close to me before.
Forget the stars! The comet!
We'll never see it again.
It's a once-in-a-lifetime encounter!
Yes, I am watching it.
It's marvelous.
"That parting is not a tragedy.
In the fairy kingdom, a land of eternity,
they will be bestowed new vessels in
which their souls will live on for all of time."
Thank you all so much!
Thanks!
Take care on the way back!
Thanks for having us!
Come back sometime!
Sir, it wasn't for long,
but thanks for having me.
Sure.
Violet.
Yes?
I...
I'm in the Manuscript Department now, but I actually
always wanted to work in Acquisition like my dad.
I felt that as long as I waited here,
my mother would come back with him one day,
and so I grew up holed away in here.
This place made it possible,
and that's what I wanted.
But I've changed my mind now.
I'm going to tour the continent like you.
I may run into danger.
I may even lose my life.
But that's the path I want to walk.
Right.
And then,
one day, we might meet again
somewhere, under a starry sky.
We're fellow travelers, after all,
Violet Evergarden!
Right.
When we do, would you gaze at the stars again with me?!
Would you, Violet Evergarden?
I don't know what the odds are
of seeing her again on my travels.
Are they as astronomical as the
odds of seeing that comet again?
Even if they are, I won't hesitate anymore.
Because she gave me the courage to take the
first step beyond the door that had locked me away.
anata no koe ga michishirube
Your voice is my guiding light
And one day, for sure...
anata no koe ga michishirube
Your voice is my guiding light
"Somewhere, Under a Starry Sky"
anata no koe ga michishirube
Your voice is my guiding light
"Somewhere, Under a Starry Sky"
ichiwa no tori ga naiteiru
A sparrow cries out
namae no nai sora ni watashi wo sagashite
Looking for me within a nameless sky
yasashisa de amitsuzuketa yurikago de asu e yukou
I will head for tomorrow in this cradle woven from kindness
hare no hi mo ame no hi ni mo
Be it a day of rain or a day of sunshine
anata wo mamoru tame ni
I will be there to protect you
kakegae no nai takaramono
A treasure more valuable than all
namae no nai hana wa
A nameless flower
shizuka ni nemuru yo
Lies in peace