You will not talk me down!
All I did was punish him for his act of folly!
Your virtuous facade doesn't fool me, you devil!
Sink to the depths of darkness where you belong!
Taking my life makes you no better.
You will burn in the flames of your sin.
I know. I'll have to bear this cross...
for the rest of my life!
Last night's play was incredible.
You should've come with us, Violet.
If you're referring to The Red Devil,
I'm reading the screenplay right now.
Ah, lucky you.
I'm so envious that you get to
ghostwrite for Oscar Webster.
I mean, that means you'll be
the first to read his new work.
It's going to be his first new production in a while.
"I know. I'll have to bear this cross...
for the rest of my life."
Each time I learn a new word
shiranai kotoba wo oboeteyuku tabi
The fog begins to clear
omokage no naka te wo nobasu no
But there may well be words
dakedo hitori de wa wakaranai kotoba mo
I cannot understand alone
aru no kamoshirenai
"Goodbye" is a bitter pill to swallow
sayonara wa nigakute
And "I love you" is strangely distant
aishiteru wa tooi nioi ga shita
This indescribable emotion welling inside
tatoeyou no nai kono omoi wa
Scares me to the bone
totemo kowakute
But also feels very dear to me
dakedo totemo itooshikute
Why am I crying?
watashi nande naiterundarou
What reason do I give my heart?
kokoro ni nante kotaetara ii
Words don't always tell the whole story
kotoba wa itsudemo kataru demo nakute
Sometimes, they are simply there
soko ni aru bakari
Building up rapidly
tsunoru bakari
And making me miss you
watashi wa anata ni aitakunaru
Here.
Ghostwriting requests.
All of these?
Ever since the public love letters,
Violet's been getting a lot more requests.
Say...
Have you told her about that major yet?
No.
The thing is, lately there have been times
where it seems like her mind is far away.
Roswell Province
Nation of Genetrix
Who is it?
The Auto Memoir Doll service.
The heck's that supposed to be?
It is a pleasure to meet you.
If a client requests it, we shall go anywhere.
Representing the Auto Memoir Doll service,
I am Violet Evergarden.
There stood a girl.
Not the one I wished I could see again, the one
whose very name is too painful for me to utter,
but a girl with hair the same shade of gold.
This is a surprise, though.
I didn't expect a child to show up.
If I am not to your liking,
we can arrange a replacement Doll.
Nah, it doesn't matter as long as you can type.
I'm not exactly in the best of health right now.
I know it isn't my place to say, but I'd like to
ask you to refrain from drinking during work.
Please.
I can't write unless I drink!
I'll be the one writing.
Let's start work tomorrow, then.
I see you're quite the handful.
Are we going to work here?
It's either here or out on the terrace.
I do have a study, but it's cramped and suffocating.
Then I know what I must do today.
What happened to your arms?
I lost them in the War.
But rest assured, it won't affect my work.
Right.
Sir.
I've cleaned things up so that we may work comfortably.
I've brought my own typewriter.
Do you have blank paper?
Nope. There's a store that sells it by
the port, so pick some up from there.
Also, I'd like carbonara for dinner...
Sir, I'm your ghostwriter, not your maid.
Quite the handful indeed.
Here, all the ingredients you
need for the dish you asked for.
Thank you.
What's the matter? Is there something on it?
No. How exactly do I cook this?
Huh? You crack the shell and take just the yolk...
Yolk?
What are you doing?
Trying my hand at cooking.
Well...
It's pretty good for your first time.
Aren't you going to eat?
I will, later.
I see.
What are you doing?
What'd you do with the booze on the shelf?
I hid it.
It will hinder our work, and...
it isn't good for you either.
I trust you don't mind me holding on to this.
Next, Olive's dialog:
"I must cross this valley of fire
if I am to obtain the sword I need to slay the beast."
Direction: "A water sprite appears."
The sprite's dialog:
"I'll extinguish this fire for you.
Then you can cross the valley."
So she'll be able to cross it? Thank goodness.
Direction: "The raging fire disappears."
How does it disappear?
Pull in the red cloth fluttering on stage,
and it'll look like the fire disappeared.
I see. Understood.
Hey, what do you think?
Is this interesting?
Well...
Well?
It's a fictional story, but I feel
like I'm experiencing it myself.
Together with this girl called Olive,
I'm finding joy, feeling sorrow,
and growing anxious.
Why is that?
It means you're putting yourself
in the shoes of the protagonist, Olive.
You're empathizing with her.
I'm relieved to hear you feel that way.
You see, this is my first time writing a play for kids.
After this, Olive will cross the
valley of fire, obtain the sword,
and slay the beast, yes?
Yeah, but at a price. She'll lose
her sprite-summoning powers.
What? No... How does she return home, then?
Her boat was damaged beyond repair.
I haven't figured that out yet.
But you must.
If you don't,
she won't find her way back home to her father.
Have you figured it out now?
It's a beautiful day.
Too beautiful, almost.
Sir.
What is this?
Oh, just a parasol.
Why do you ask?
I found it very pretty.
I need a break.
Leave me alone for a while, please.
One day...
One day, I'll show you. I promise!
Knock it off!
Please, stop.
I'm sorry for not asking—
Forget it.
Just... forget it.
Leave.
But the play would be left incomplete.
Olive's story wouldn't reach its conclusion!
Sir, are you hiding something deep down in your heart?
Unfortunately, I lack the ability to understand what it is.
I'm truly sorry.
I...
I can't write anything anymore.
But I realized I need to fix that,
so I decided to complete the
story I told her. The story I told Olivia.
Olivia?
Yes.
My daughter.
When my wife succumbed to illness,
I moved here, to what used to be our
summer vacation home, with my daughter.
I'm sure she was sad and lonely without her mother,
but she never let it show, not for one moment.
In fact, she was always helping
out so I could focus on my work.
And her favorite things were
her frilly parasol and the swans here.
How nice.
I wanna cross this lake too.
Do you think I can walk atop those leaves?
If you hold up your parasol and catch the wind,
you might be able to.
Olivia!
I'm okay.
I'm going to walk across this lake, no matter what.
One day, I'll show you. I promise,
Dad!
But then...
After a series of pointless arguments with the doctor,
I decided to bring my daughter back here so
she could spend her remaining days in peace.
For the first time in a long while, she smiled.
Those were gentle, peaceful days.
But...
I lost my only hope in life.
How many things I hold dear
must God take away from me?
I never knew parting with someone dear to you,
never getting to see them again,
was so sad
and so painful.
I'm sorry about earlier.
Oh, no. I lost my composure when you were in pain.
I should be the one apologizing.
I'll complete it...
Olive's story.
She'll return home and reunite with her father.
No matter how difficult the adventure
may be, it must have a happy ending.
Both the protagonist and the
audience deserve to be happy—
No, I'll make sure that they are.
The beast crumbles to the ground. Olive's dialog:
"I have finally slain the beast."
Water sprite: "You did well."
Wind sprite: "We must return to the world of the fae."
Fire sprite: "This is goodbye."
Olive stands still, lost for words.
Now...
How do we get Olive home from here?
Her boat is broken, so a plane?
I'd like something more magical.
A bird would be able to fly back home.
How about using her parasol to fly?
You can't fly with a parasol.
She can. The wind sprite
shows up one last time and says...
"Olive, open your parasol wide."
Could you open that one for me?
"That parasol will be your wings. If you
fly too high, the wind will carry you astray.
So ride the waves over the
ocean, step on the rocks in the river,
walk on the leaves floating atop
the lake, and find your way home."
That's a wonderful idea.
Right?
Once she gets back, she'll see her father again.
And after crossing the ocean to return home,
what do you think she'll say to him first?
"I'm home"?
No, "Dad"?
Are you stuck again?
Could you go over there and walk this way?
I want to picture the scene.
Do you just want me to walk?
If possible, walk on the leaves floating atop the lake.
Understood.
Uh, I wasn't serious about that.
How nice.
I wanna cross this lake too.
Do you think I can walk atop those leaves?
One day...
One day, I'll show you. I promise,
Dad!
I wanted her to keep calling me
that thousands upon thousands of times.
I wish she hadn't died.
I wanted her to live on... and grow up...
How I wish it were so!
Did you see that?
I'm sure I managed three steps across!
Sir?
What is the matter?
Do you feel ill?
After she made that miracle happen, I said to her,
"I was sure there was no God,
but if there is one, it must be you."
Are you sure?
Can I really have this parasol?
Yeah.
I thought I could jump farther than I did...
That was more than enough.
You fulfilled the promise my late daughter made to me.
The promise... she made to you?
Well, then.
Thank you for using the Auto Memoir Doll service.
No, thank you,
Violet Evergarden.
With your bloodstained hands
that have taken countless lives,
you write letters that bring people together?
You haven't realized that everything
you've done so far has sparked a flame
that is now burning you up.
But I'm not on fire.
You most definitely are.
You'll understand what I'm saying one day.
And, for the first time, you'll notice all your burn marks.
Major...
You must live...
Do I have the right to?
...and be free.
Do I have any right to after I
killed so many people as a weapon?
I must have prevented them
from keeping promises of their own!
Promises they made to loved ones of their own!
I'm not on fire.
I am!
No, I am not.
I most definitely am!
Everything I've done so far has
sparked a flame that is now burning me up!
Oh?
If it isn't Violet!
Mrs. Evergarden... I'm terribly sorry
for my behavior the last time we met.
I can't apologize enough for the hurt I caused.
Violet... Oh, it's fine.
There's no need to apologize.
I'm so glad to see you've grown up.
Now the late Gilbert's soul can rest in peace.
"Late"?
You told me he was alive, didn't you?
The major is all right, isn't he?!
That's...
Please tell me he's still alive.
I'm sorry.
I didn't have the heart to break it to you.
After the final battle at Intens,
you were found lying alone outside the church.
He must've pushed you out in
the moment before it got bombed.
We couldn't locate or identify his body,
but we did find his dog tag in the rubble.
And so, he was considered killed in action.
So we don't know?
But given the situation...
I'm sure the major is alive and well.
Violet...
He's fine!
Please understand, Violet.
He's not...
I don't understand. I don't understand it at all.
Why was I the only one found? That makes no sense!
He was right beside me, and he told me...
Violet, as painful as the truth is, you must accept it.
Violet!
anata no koe ga michishirube
Your voice is my guiding light
ichiwa no tori ga naiteiru
A sparrow cries out
namae no nai sora ni watashi wo sagashite
Looking for me within a nameless sky
yasashisa de amitsuzuketa yurikago de asu e yukou
I will head for tomorrow in this cradle woven from kindness
hare no hi mo ame no hi ni mo
Be it a day of rain or a day of sunshine
anata wo mamoru tame ni
I will be there to protect you
kakegae no nai takaramono
A treasure more valuable than all
namae no nai hana wa
A nameless flower
shizuka ni nemuru yo
Lies in peace