Hey, get up.
I found her on the northeastern front.
Her name is... nothing yet.
I've just been calling her "you."
Come on. Say hello.
Don't be rough! She's just a child!
Gil, that's no child.
That's a weapon.
A weapon?
A tool of war, nothing more.
Got it. I'll take custody of her.
Really? I'm glad you accept my gift.
I've already cleared things with the army.
Each time I learn a new word
shiranai kotoba wo oboeteyuku tabi
The fog begins to clear
omokage no naka te wo nobasu no
But there may well be words
dakedo hitori de wa wakaranai kotoba mo
I cannot understand alone
aru no kamoshirenai
"Goodbye" is a bitter pill to swallow
sayonara wa nigakute
And "I love you" is strangely distant
aishiteru wa tooi nioi ga shita
This indescribable emotion welling inside
tatoeyou no nai kono omoi wa
Scares me to the bone
totemo kowakute
But also feels very dear to me
dakedo totemo itooshikute
Why am I crying?
watashi nande naiterundarou
What reason do I give my heart?
kokoro ni nante kotaetara ii
Words don't always tell the whole story
kotoba wa itsudemo kataru demo nakute
Sometimes, they are simply there
soko ni aru bakari
Building up rapidly
tsunoru bakari
And making me miss you
watashi wa anata ni aitakunaru
Leidenschaftlich
Navy Department
I really must meet with Captain Dietfried Bougainvillea!
Like I said, he can't see you!
There is something I must confirm with him at once!
Give it a rest!
What's going on?
Captain!
We're terribly sorry.
That girl refuses to leave without seeing you.
You're dismissed.
If you don't want to die, leave.
What are you doing here?
Captain.
Of course.
Still a weapon, nothing more.
Captain!
Is the major... Is Major Gilbert...
Is it true that he was killed in action?
You didn't know?
Gilbert is no longer...
It's a lie! I refuse to believe it!
I'm sure he's all right!
What's with that look on your face?
You were nothing but a tool to him.
You're nothing but a heartless instrument of war!
How could you possibly feel sorrow?
Why would you tell her?!
Well, I thought she was ready for the truth...
Are you stupid?!
You're always such a terrible judge of things!
And you still haven't learned
how a woman's heart works!
In any case, you'd better go look for her right now!
Yeah, I know.
Oh...
Young Master, and... who might that be?
Before we get to that,
get her a bath and change her clothes.
If I may ask, does the madam know?
She's over at the Leiden mansion now.
No need to tell her.
I'll simply be taking this girl in for a while.
This way.
Come on.
Ow!
S-Stop that! It hurts!
Cut it out!
Young Master, I did what I could with her clothes,
but she wouldn't sit still.
It's fine. Don't worry about it.
Feed her and then take her to the guest room.
Please.
You'll catch...
You'll catch a cold. Use a blanket.
Tomorrow will be even colder.
Hold it! Don't!
You mustn't go outside!
What's the matter?
I'm terribly sorry.
She's been looking for you ever since she awakened.
She didn't even eat.
I'm not bringing her to the frontlines.
She's too unstable.
Why are you against it?
You do realize this is an order from the brass?
You watched her at the
training barracks too, didn't you?
Manslaughter is all she's good for.
Just take her with you.
But...
Don't get so worked up.
She's a girl with no family or friends.
Use her for all she's worth,
and when she no longer serves a purpose,
simply abandon her on the battlefield.
She's still—
Enough! Spare me your holier-than-thou attitude!
This is an order!
That is all.
The Gardariki Allied Army
began marching toward Bociaccia.
We immediately set up a defensive
line at the river before Capria, its capital,
and now we're locked in a battle of attrition.
Our troops number 30,000; the enemy's, 60,000.
They're holding out somehow,
but the enemy has now sent cannons to the frontlines.
The artillery fire has hurt command and control,
and there's a real chance our front may fall apart.
As such, Major Bougainvillea...
Sir?
I want you to lead a company behind
enemy lines and destroy their cannons.
Yes, sir. I'll make sure this mission succeeds.
You stay here.
Don't move until I return.
Understand?
Everything's ready, Major.
I'll be right there.
Major.
Enemy patrol.
What the hell?
What's going on?
Enemy attack!
Alert Command!
Leidenschaftlich is attacking!
Send for reinforcements!
Captain! The enemy's drawing near!
Charge!
Yes?
You're...
Is... Is the major in?
The major is here, isn't he?
Young Master is...
"Gilbert Bougainvillea"...
It has the major's name.
Violet...
Your name is Violet.
You won't be a tool, but a person worthy of that name.
V... Vio... let?
You understood me?
May-jor. Vio-let.
That's right. You're Violet, and I'm the major.
May-jor?
May-jor.
I read it.
Good. You should learn how to write now.
Major. The re-port.
Right.
You did well to write this.
It'll serve as good practice,
so submit a report to me every day.
Got that?
I'll submit a re-port every day.
We couldn't locate or identify his body,
but we did find his dog tag in the rubble.
Young Master is...
Now the late Gilbert's soul can rest in peace.
And so, he was considered killed in action.
Gilbert is no longer...
It's Thanksgiving.
This city was under Gardariki
Army control for three years
and was only recently liberated.
Violet,
this is all down to you.
Thanksgiving here in Machtig customarily
entails giving gifts to those you're grateful to.
Violet...
Is there something you want?
Something I want?
That's right. Ask for anything.
I will, if that's your order.
It's not an order.
I want to show you my gratitude.
Gratitude?
Yes. You always fight so bravely...
Never mind.
Shall we walk?
Major.
What is appropriate for me to want?
Let's see...
A girl of your age might want a dress or an accessory.
Understood. I want a dress or an accessory.
What's wrong?
I see your eyes.
It's the same color as your eyes.
When I saw it,
I felt something.
What is this feeling called?
What do you think? It's a beautiful brooch, right?
Beau...
...tiful?
Indeed.
I didn't know that word.
Is it similar to the word "pretty"?
That's right.
Are you sure you didn't want one
the same color as your eyes instead?
Yes, this was the most beautiful.
I didn't know the word, so I haven't said it.
But I've thought your eyes are
beautiful from the first time we met.
Major?
May I have the brooch?
Yes.
Thank you.
Oberberg,
Western Front
Leidenschaftlich Army
Frontline Command
I heard the Gardarikis retreated
from their western base too.
Think we can go home by spring?
Let's all go home together.
Gilbert!
Long time no see!
Colonel Hodgins!
Don't call me that.
You know I have to. You're a superior officer.
There's that standoffish manner again.
It's strange how it seems almost
likeable when you haven't seen it in a while.
I see you haven't changed either, even as a colonel.
Well, I've been assigned to
fronts we could win without a fight.
Your family is a major contributor of war funds.
It's only natural that Army
HQ would take that into account.
That's why I don't exactly
feel great about my promotions.
Anyway, how've you been doing?
You eating okay?
Hope you've been getting enough sleep!
He's just messing around. Stand at ease.
He's older than me, but we were
in the same batch at officer school.
Is she the one from the training barracks?
You're still keeping her around?
It was her who charged in and drew
first blood during the battle at Capria, right?
People have started gossiping
about how she's "your weapon."
Aren't there other things you could have her do?
Wait, sorry. Er...
Violet.
She didn't have a name, so I gave her one.
Are you taking her along for the Intens liberation?
If this operation succeeds,
the enemy will fall apart once and for all.
This will likely be the final battle of this war.
Yeah.
You know, I'm thinking of quitting the army
and starting a company once this war ends.
A company?
I don't mind hiring you.
Can't say I enjoy the thought of working under you.
Then maybe I'll hire Violet instead.
Yeah...
That might be a good idea.
Assemble!
Major.
What is it?
Am I not needed anymore?
What are you talking about?
Will I be disposed of and transferred
into Colonel Hodgins's custody?
Will you not give me orders anymore?
You haven't done anything wrong.
The final battle is only a few hours away.
Let's talk about this some other time.
I'll detail the operation.
The enemy army's general HQ lies here in Intens.
It's a natural fortress surrounded by cliffs on all sides.
It'll be hard to breach their defenses from the front.
As such, we'll have a special unit open artillery fire first.
We'll take that chance to sneak into
Intens through the underground waterway,
charge into the cathedral,
and secure the enemy HQ.
Then we'll send up a signal flare telling our
allies to attack, and our mission will be complete.
Understood?
Yes, sir!
T-minus five minutes to artillery fire.
Move out!
Commence artillery fire.
Commence artillery fire!
Fire!
Follow her lead!
All squads, sitrep!
Squad One, we lost three!
Squad Two is pretty much unhurt!
Squads Three and Four have
lost about half their members!
We're in bad shape!
All right!
Squads One and Two, secure the area
and keep enemy reinforcements at bay.
Everyone alive in Squads Three and Four
will come with me and take over the cathedral!
Let's go!
Yes, sir!
Fire!
Do your best, Gilbert.
Major!
Circle around to the right!
All troops, charge!
Major?
anata no koe ga michishirube
Your voice is my guiding light
ichiwa no tori ga naiteiru
A sparrow cries out
namae no nai sora ni watashi wo sagashite
Looking for me within a nameless sky
yasashisa de amitsuzuketa yurikago de asu e yukou
I will head for tomorrow in this cradle woven from kindness
hare no hi mo ame no hi ni mo
Be it a day of rain or a day of sunshine
anata wo mamoru tame ni
I will be there to protect you
kakegae no nai takaramono
A treasure more valuable than all
namae no nai hana wa
A nameless flower
shizuka ni nemuru yo
Lies in peace