Major!
I'm... okay...
Run away.
Leave me... and run!
I can't do that! I'm taking you with me!
Forget me...
I won't! If you're staying here, I'll stay with you and fight!
If you want to run away,
I'll take you with me and run away!
Violet!
I swear... I swear I won't let you die, Major!
Stop it.
That's enough!
You must live...
Violet...
You must live on...
and be free.
From the bottom of my heart...
I love you.
"Love"?
What is that?
What is...
What is love?
I don't understand!
I don't understand it, Major!
I knew you'd be here.
It was a truly horrible battle.
After your unit sent up the signal flare,
the rest of us charged in.
Sensing defeat, the Gardariki Army
bombed their own HQ before retreating.
You were found at the foot of that staircase.
He must've pushed you down to save
your life right as the explosion happened.
While I was hospitalized,
everyone I asked said that the major was fine.
We couldn't tell you.
You were more concerned about him than yourself.
Let's go,
Violet.
Where to?
I will only go where the major is.
We're heading back to the office.
You're one of our Auto Memoir Dolls, remember?
Fine, then. I'll stay here too.
I'm not leaving until you come back with me.
He entrusted me with you, after all.
Right before that battle, he came to visit me and said...
Should anything happen to me, take care of Violet.
Take her to the Evergarden
family in Leiden after the war is over.
Gilbert?
Please.
He definitely didn't see you as a tool of warfare.
He was worried about your future as an ordinary girl.
Hey, uh...
Sorry I dragged you into the car.
You okay?
You are okay, right?
Around the time you got discharged,
I wasn't sure if things would work out.
But you learned how to work as a Doll,
and you put everything you had into it.
You're fully capable of living
now, even without his orders.
Will you not give me orders anymore?
You haven't done anything wrong.
Let's talk about this some other time.
The road's blocked off.
Colonel!
I've quit the army...
Never mind. At ease!
Sir!
Did something happen?
The town of Caisseclaire was
attacked by Gardariki's anti-peace faction.
I'd heard that the opposition had
grown stronger, but I didn't expect this.
What's the situation?
We suppressed the attack, but the town and
its surroundings still have to be on high alert.
Let's take another route.
Got it.
Violet's back, right?
Seems like it.
She'll be coming back to work too, right?
Go see how she's doing.
Why don't you go?
Someone of your kind would be better.
What's that supposed to mean?
I'm preoccupied here!
Benedict.
Could you go look around District 12?
I'll try District 14.
Is something wrong?
A new delivery boy dumped the
letters he couldn't deliver on time.
So we have to go find them.
Don't worry. We know where to look, more or less.
Violet. I know you're in there.
Could I see you? Just for a bit.
I'm sorry to have worried you.
How's your health? Are you eating all right?
I'm leaving some snacks for you here, okay?
Do you think you can come in to work tomorrow?
Everyone's waiting for you, and we've got
tons of requests with your name on them.
I...
As President Hodgins said, I'm burning up
in the flames of what I've done.
You'll understand what I'm saying one day.
And, for the first time, you'll notice all your burn marks.
Why would you say that to her?
Considering her circumstances,
what else could she have done?!
Regardless of the circumstances,
regardless of how it happened or why,
the things she did can never be undone.
Then she can forget about it and start over—
You know she won't be able to forget.
She's not the only one burning up.
So are you and I.
Even the burns that may seem to
have faded have left a mark deep down.
Then what is she to do?
That's for her to decide
after she faces up to her burning body and accepts it.
But she lost her major.
She lost everything.
It's okay.
She hasn't.
She hasn't lost anything.
Now Cattleya's not coming back.
I'll go check on Violet tomorrow.
We should probably leave her be for a while.
But...
I want to know what "I love you" means.
I became a Doll because I wanted
to know what his "I love you" meant.
Should we really just leave her be?
What if she quits being a Doll?
I'd like to request a ghostwriting.
Major...
What's the matter?
Violet.
Major... Major!
You're all right!
What's with your outfit?
I'm currently working as an Auto Memoir Doll.
You are?
Yes. I ghostwrite letters.
Letters?
With your bloodstained hands
that have taken countless lives...
Major?
...you write letters that bring people together?
Major... Major...
What am I supposed to do?
Your orders... Please give me your orders!
Letter delivery,
Violet Evergarden.
It's for you.
Erica and Iris asked me to deliver it.
The letter has been duly received. See you.
You have more deliveries this late?
Yeah. We found a bunch of
letters that'd been thrown away.
What about Benedict?
He sprained his ankle.
Serves him right for wearing those boots.
Sheesh, what is wrong with you?
O-Ow!
I'll go around Kraft Street, then.
You handle the next street.
Each and every one of those letters
is filled with someone's heart and soul.
No letter deserves to go undelivered.
A letter!
Mom!
Letter from Dad!
Finished with deliveries?
Good work.
Thank goodness! They all found their homes!
"Dear Violet,
are you all right?
I thought about coming to see you, but Iris and
I discussed it, and we decided to write this letter.
Dolls writing a letter to
another Doll might be a strange idea,
but we wanted to let you
know that we're worried for you,
and that we're...
waiting for you."
We know you probably don't want
to come back to work at all right now,
so take a nice, long break.
But call for us anytime if you ever need anything.
Both Iris and I believe that you will come back to us.
Also, someone named Spencer came in
today with a ghostwriting request for you.
He said he wanted to give his sister a
letter expressing his apologies and gratitude.
He wants you to write it.
He insists that it has to be you.
Will this do?
Yeah.
It feels embarrassing giving my little sister a letter,
but thanks to her,
I found a job.
She's the one who made me want to get back on my feet.
Sorry to have you come over.
I'd heard you were taking time off, though.
My coworkers let me know with a letter.
It was the first letter I'd ever received in my life.
And it helped me realize that receiving a letter
makes one very happy.
I'm sure Luculia will be overjoyed too.
Thank you.
"Just as lovely as those flowers"...
"A person worthy of that name."
Violet?
Violet!
You trace your dreams back to their origins
tsuzurareta yume wo sakanobotta
You were right. I was covered in burn marks.
You trace your dreams back to their origins
tsuzurareta yume wo sakanobotta
Holding your heart that doesn't know how to cry
nakikata sae shiranu kokoro daku you ni
Is it really all right?
Holding your heart that doesn't know how to cry
nakikata sae shiranu kokoro daku you ni
Is it really all right for me to be an Auto Memoir Doll?
Your memories are dyed
kioku ni shimiwatatteku
Is it really all right for me to live—to live on?
In mistakes that can't be undone
ayamachi wa kienai
In wounds that even time can't heal
kisetsu ga megutteitte mo
They may ache and throb at times
seotta kizu wa tokini uzuku kedo
The things you did can never be undone.
They may ache and throb at times
seotta kizu wa tokini uzuku kedo
But the warmth won't fade either
nukumori mo kienai
But...
But the warmth won't fade either
nukumori mo kienai
It lives on in your memories
kioku to tomo ni ikiteru
Along with countless loves that provide your heart salvation
musuu no ai ga kokoro wo sukuu deshou
So don't forget to keep walking toward the future
dakara wasurenaide ashita e mukau koto
You have the courage to embrace everything
subete dakishimeru yuuki wo
But...
You have the courage to embrace everything
subete dakishimeru yuuki wo
Believe in it
shinjite
Everything you've done as an Auto Memoir Doll
Believe in it
shinjite
will never go away either,
"Violet Evergarden"