What are we gonna play today?
Dunno.
I'm bored of playing house.
Me too.
When are Mom's guests gonna leave?
I wish they'd leave already.
Right?
What's going on there?
A doll came walking toward us.
A really big doll.
And for some reason, it felt like bad news.
Each time I learn a new word
shiranai kotoba wo oboeteyuku tabi
The fog begins to clear
omokage no naka te wo nobasu no
But there may well be words
dakedo hitori de wa wakaranai kotoba mo
I cannot understand alone
aru no kamoshirenai
"Goodbye" is a bitter pill to swallow
sayonara wa nigakute
And "I love you" is strangely distant
aishiteru wa tooi nioi ga shita
This indescribable emotion welling inside
tatoeyou no nai kono omoi wa
Scares me to the bone
totemo kowakute
But also feels very dear to me
dakedo totemo itooshikute
Why am I crying?
watashi nande naiterundarou
What reason do I give my heart?
kokoro ni nante kotaetara ii
Words don't always tell the whole story
kotoba wa itsudemo kataru demo nakute
Sometimes, they are simply there
soko ni aru bakari
Building up rapidly
tsunoru bakari
And making me miss you
watashi wa anata ni aitakunaru
Mom! Mom!
Miss, you mustn't!
I understand what you're saying...
...but this is important.
Yes, but...
Mom!
Anne, how many times must I tell
you to knock before entering a room?
Also, say your greetings.
Welcome.
Pardon me, Mother.
My...
Good.
So, what is it?
Did you find another strange bug?
Please don't show me, though.
Not a bug!
A doll came walking!
A doll?
Milady.
She's here.
Oh, that kind of doll.
I forgot the appointment was today.
Show her in to the living room.
Certainly, milady.
Hey!
I'm sorry, but we'll have to
talk about this some other time.
"Some other time"? What are
you going to do about this mansion?
It's too big for her to live in alone.
That's why we're offering to...
Please leave for today.
Wait!
Anne.
Be a good girl, all right?
Sorry to keep you waiting,
and thank you for coming all this way.
Please don't mention it.
It talked!
If a client requests it, we shall go anywhere.
Representing the Auto Memoir Doll service...
I knew it!
You are a doll!
Anne!
Excuse her.
It's okay.
I am Violet Evergarden.
Come, take a seat. Tea will be served soon.
I hope you like it. Please help yourself.
Thank you.
It drank!
What happens to the tea after it drinks it?
Anne...
It will soon be discharged from the
body and eventually return to the ground.
Anne!
Where are your manners?
Shall we begin?
I have been told our contract is seven days in length.
Yes. Let's begin right away.
Certainly. Where will we be working?
Well, shall we take it to the
sunroom? It's nice and bright there.
What are you doing?
I'm having her help me write some letters.
I could've done that for you!
But you can't use big words yet, can you?
I can, too!
Besides, Miss Violet here is
famously exceptional at writing letters.
Who are you writing to?
Well...
Someone very far away.
Far away?
Yes.
These are very important letters.
Don't disturb us in the sunroom, all right?
Shall we, Miss Violet?
Certainly.
I've brought this typewriter with me.
That will do.
Understood.
I knew she was bad news!
Wow! She really is a doll!
Milady!
Mom...
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
I'll be better right away.
Really?
Really.
I know! I'll sing you a lullaby!
Thank you. But I'm a grown-up, so I'll be fine.
Hmm... Can I sleep with you, then?
Oh my. Didn't you grow out of afternoon naps?
Today's special.
Instead of that, Anne, could you entertain our guest?
I hate guests.
They take you away from me.
I'm sorry, Anne.
But please bear with it for seven days.
Be a good girl, all right?
Mother will be resting for a while.
Is that so?
She says she's a bit sleepy, is all.
While she's resting,
I'll entertain you.
I hate guests,
but you're okay since you're a doll.
And how will you entertain me?
Well, we could have a chat, play a game, or something.
Those aren't in the terms of my contract.
But...
I don't mind if it's just for a little while.
Let's play with this doll, then!
Sure.
A doll playing with a doll? Isn't that funny?
What do I do with this?
Talk or tend to it, obviously.
Start by saying hello.
Hello!
Hello.
Oh, good day!
That was the doll talking!
I see.
I understand now.
Oh, you're a doll, so you've
always been the toy and not the player.
No, I...
I'll teach you!
We'll play house next.
There's a table on the lawn.
Excuse me.
Your room is ready, so allow me to show you there.
Sure.
See you later, miss.
The room is on the second floor.
What could they be talking about?
Eris!
I'll take it to them!
No, you won't.
This is my job.
Please don't take it from me.
Sheesh.
Why must nothing in life ever go right?
Yes?
It's me, Anne.
Please come in.
Is something the matter?
What are you doing?
Tuning my hand.
Tuning?
Yes, tuning it to work as it should.
Does that mean you'll be
writing letters again tomorrow?
Yes.
And the day after that?
You're here for seven days,
so the day after that and the day after that?
Yes.
Who are you writing to?
I'm afraid I cannot tell you.
Why?
Client confidentiality.
Confiden...?
Stop using big words all the time!
Forgive me.
It can't be Father.
I mean, he's gone.
Remember that huge war?
He fought in it and died an honorable death.
Tell me. Who are you writing to?
Miss, didn't you come here for a reason?
A reason?
Eris left, and Mom's asleep now...
Shouldn't you be going to bed too, then?
Why?!
Staying up late is a lady's worst enemy.
That's what Cattleya told me.
Who?
Another of our Dolls.
There's another one?
Yes.
We have others too. They're called Erica and Iris.
Wow! Are there really so
many dolls that move by themselves?
That's right.
Miss?
Fine! I'll go to bed!
You'd better do the same, or Mom will yell at you!
Besides, if you stay up late,
evil ghosts will come to get you!
Good night, miss.
Good night!
What a weird doll.
"Then, the thief screamed, 'Whoa!'
And he ran away in fear."
You're pretty good at reading.
Violet!
What kind of pancake is
really hard and impossible to eat?
They're all edible once doused in syrup.
Violet!
Until Mom gets here, solve riddles, dance, play house,
and catch bugs...
Miss.
Please sort them in order of priority.
Violet.
Read to me.
Violet!
Will this do?
Yes, it's perfect.
I'll write along these lines, then.
Thank you.
Anne.
N-No, I just wanted Violet to tie my ribbon.
I see. But save it for later.
Madam, may I have a short break?
I'm sure the young miss would
prefer her ribbon tied right away.
All done, miss.
It wasn't really you I wanted to tie my ribbon.
Right.
I really wanted Mom to do it.
It's the same for reading,
solving riddles, and playing house.
Mom hates bugs, so I'll give up on that.
Stop taking away the time
Mom and I spend together, Violet!
I'll be gone in a few days.
Then tell her I can be there
while you're writing the letters!
I wanna be by her side!
I just wanna be there and hold her hand tight! Please!
I'm sorry, but I cannot accept your request.
But why?
Excuse me, miss.
I must return to work.
Do you think we can finish today?
If we maintain this pace, yes.
Please review this, Madam.
Madam?
I'm fine.
Milady!
But...
Please keep going.
That's enough!
Miss?
Mom!
Please stop already!
Anne?
I'm fine, so could you stay inside?
Why? Why must you write these letters?
Who are you writing them to?
Dad's gone!
They're very important letters.
They're for someone I don't know, right?
Someone who doesn't even visit when you're sick!
There's nobody out there who's truly worried about you!
Are these letters more important than me?
Nothing's more important to me than you, Anne.
You're always full of lies.
I'm not lying.
Then why aren't you getting any better at all?
You said you'd be better right away!
I will.
I know that you're...
I'm going to be all alone when you're gone!
How much longer do I have with you?!
If I'm going to be left all alone forever soon,
then forget about the letters
and spend this time with me!
Be with me!
Mom!
Miss.
Miss!
I'm taking the time you can spend
with your mother away for a good reason.
Please don't be angry at her.
But... But...
It's only natural that this would be painful for you.
You're already carrying the burden of
your mother's illness on your frail body.
You're a wonderful girl.
I'm not!
I'm not...
I made Mom cry!
No, you are a very gentle girl.
You're wrong.
I am not.
You're wrong!
You're wrong! You're wrong!
Mom fell sick because I'm a bad girl!
You had nothing to do with it.
You're wrong! You're wrong!
You're wrong!
There was nothing anybody could have done.
Just as nothing can ever make my
arms have skin and be soft like yours,
nothing can be done about this.
Mom... Mom...
Why do you write those letters?
Because everyone has feelings
they want to deliver to someone.
Who cares about that?
They don't have to be!
No letter that could be sent
deserves to go undelivered, miss.
And then, the doll that embraced me
finished writing her letters and said goodbye one day.
Violet.
Miss.
Huh?
You're warm.
Wait, are you...
Then what happens to the tea you drink?
As I said,
it will soon be discharged from the
body and eventually return to the ground.
She was no doll.
She wasn't bad news either.
She was a kind and gentle person.
I wish I could've read the letters she wrote.
I wonder who they were for.
Anne.
Come, let's have tea.
Mom, let's play with this doll!
Sure.
And then read books, play house...
Anne.
My dear Anne.
"Dear Anne,
happy eighth birthday.
I'm sure there are many things that make you sad.
You may be crumbling under
the weight of your responsibilities.
But don't give in.
Even if you're so lonely that it makes you cry,
please don't forget
that Mom loves you always."
"Dear Anne,
happy tenth birthday.
You must have grown up and gotten much taller.
But I'm sure you still love
reading and dancing just as much.
Have you grown out of the riddles and bugs yet?"
"Happy eighteenth birthday.
You're a lady now.
Have you fallen in love with someone?
I'm afraid I can't give you any relationship advice,
but I'm sure anyone you choose would
have to be a truly wonderful person."
"Happy birthday, Anne.
You've lived twenty whole years now! That's incredible!
I hope you know that it's okay to
cry once in a while, even as an adult.
Whenever you're anxious or afraid,
remember that I'll always be here.
Anne,
I'll always and forever be watching over you."
Welcome back.
That's a lot of letters.
They're letters set to be delivered to
Anne Magnolia over the next fifty years.
You wrote fifty?!
And you hadn't been on a house
call in a while, too. Were you all right?
It wasn't a problem.
But this is a wonderful idea.
I'm already excited to see them be delivered every year.
I am too, but...
By the time they are,
the mother will be gone,
and her daughter, still so young,
and so quick to get lonely,
will have been left behind by
the mother she loves so much.
She'll be all alone in that huge mansion.
I...
I was fighting back tears the entire time I was there.
Yeah?
But, Violet,
she will receive the letters you wrote.
Besides, no matter how far apart they may be...
"Loved Ones Will Always Watch Over You"
anata no koe ga michishirube
Your voice is my guiding light
ichiwa no tori ga naiteiru
A sparrow cries out
namae no nai sora ni watashi wo sagashite
Looking for me within a nameless sky
yasashisa de amitsuzuketa yurikago de asu e yukou
I will head for tomorrow in this cradle woven from kindness
hare no hi mo ame no hi ni mo
Be it a day of rain or a day of sunshine
anata wo mamoru tame ni
I will be there to protect you
kakegae no nai takaramono
A treasure more valuable than all
namae no nai hana wa
A nameless flower
shizuka ni nemuru yo
Lies in peace