Can I leave this request to you, then?
Sure thing.
That leaves us with this...
Ctrigall's Menace base? That's one
of our former enemies to the north!
Did we really get a ghostwriting request from there?
There's much demand for
Dolls among garrisoned soldiers.
And I have been publicizing CH Postal all over. But...
Is there a problem?
Civil war recently broke out over there.
The radicals want to reignite the War,
and the moderates want to keep things as they are.
Right when they finally had peace
again. I don't even know what to say.
I suppose some people can't live without war.
Yeah.
And the Menace base lies on
the front lines of that civil war.
I understand why they'd want to
send a letter, but it's too dangerous.
It's a bit unfortunate, though.
That soldier must've asked for a Doll because
he had a message to send from the battlefield.
But I can't send one of our Dolls to a war zone.
Menace Base
Ctrigall
Maria...
Our squad will hereby go into battle.
Each time I learn a new word
shiranai kotoba wo oboeteyuku tabi
The fog begins to clear
omokage no naka te wo nobasu no
But there may well be words
dakedo hitori de wa wakaranai kotoba mo
I cannot understand alone
aru no kamoshirenai
"Goodbye" is a bitter pill to swallow
sayonara wa nigakute
And "I love you" is strangely distant
aishiteru wa tooi nioi ga shita
This indescribable emotion welling inside
tatoeyou no nai kono omoi wa
Scares me to the bone
totemo kowakute
But also feels very dear to me
dakedo totemo itooshikute
Why am I crying?
watashi nande naiterundarou
What reason do I give my heart?
kokoro ni nante kotaetara ii
Words don't always tell the whole story
kotoba wa itsudemo kataru demo nakute
Sometimes, they are simply there
soko ni aru bakari
Building up rapidly
tsunoru bakari
And making me miss you
watashi wa anata ni aitakunaru
The envelope with the request is gone!
The one you said you would turn down?
Where's Violet?
She left this morning, saying she had work to do.
I think she mentioned going to Ctrigall,
and that's a week-long trip each way.
Crap.
I hear you, but we still can't.
Please.
Like I said, that's outside our delivery area.
What's all this ruckus?
Boss, this woman wants us to deliver her to this place.
The Menace base?
And you're from Leidenschaftlich?
No wonder you're dressed so lightly.
Now look here, missy.
This is the Menace base, where you want to be delivered.
And over here, there's an internment camp.
Or well, there used to be.
Did they run away?
Looks like they had some outside help.
And we have a faction that
wants to continue the War, too.
They handed weapons to the
Gardariki stragglers in the internment camp,
making a mess of everything
and throwing us into civil war.
The Menace base is barely hanging
in there as our last line of defense,
but the roads around it have been
blockaded, cutting off reinforcements.
Get it now?
The place you want to go is a bona fide battlefield.
But isn't that exactly why the soldiers there
would want to express their feelings to others?
Yeah, but not even an ant could
crawl into that base in one piece.
No.
This mountain is steep and
extremely difficult to cross on foot.
As such, neither army will be keeping close watch on it.
B-But crossing that mountain is...
Possible.
Given a plane and a skilled pilot.
Not happening. Even if you got over the
mountain, you'd have to be airdropped in.
You're an amusing lass.
I like ya.
Oh, you're a Doll?
Yes. If a client requests it, we shall go anywhere.
Then I guess a postman's job is to
deliver anything anywhere, anytime.
Say, the transcontinental
railroad will be finished soon, right?
Yeah, meaning it'll take no time to get to the south.
They say the girls down there are all beautiful.
We'll start receiving a lot of good food too.
The south, huh?
Hey, Yale.
Sir.
Message for the company commander.
Platoon Two will be circling around from this point.
Circling? Got it.
Our ETA to the mission point will be—
Sergeant Major! Yale!
Enemy ambush!
Damn it! I'll get them!
Get down!
Shit!
Aiden...
Please don't leave me here.
Why would I?!
We're going home alive.
No! I don't want to die!
I don't want to die either!
No... Aiden...
Don't leave me...
Yale!
No!
I don't want to die!
I have to come home!
Maria!
I have to come home...
You can see the battlefield now.
The Menace base has fallen too.
There's no way you can go
down there. We're heading back.
The Ctrigallan Army is so frail.
The moderates are just a bunch of cowards.
That's why we must show them the way once again.
Shall we continue the hunt, then?
A plane?
Aren't our allies grounded right now?
A child?
Get her!
Quit it.
I recognize you,
Leidenschaftlich's girl soldier.
Why are you here?
I'm sorry to ask,
but would you please fall back?
Fine. I get it.
Let's go. We're no match for her.
Are you Mister Aiden Field?
How do you... know my name...
I'm sorry to have kept you waiting, sir.
Aren't you going to play, Aiden?
Nope. Can't think of anything I'd use the money for.
Then why not send a letter home?
A letter? From the battlefield?
Yeah.
I've never written a letter in
my life. I don't even know how.
Take a look at the poster.
It says a lovely lady will put
your feelings into words in a letter.
Hey, Aiden.
Make sure I look good, okay?
Aiden...
Maria.
Sir.
We'll hide here for a while.
Someone will come pick us up in the morning.
I feel hot right now.
This is to prevent hypothermia.
Will you write a letter for me?
I must focus on treating you.
I'd rather you wrote the letter.
I think I'm going to die soon.
So please.
Understood.
Pretty.
I'm ready, sir.
Address it to Dad and Mom.
Certainly.
"Dad, Mom...
Thank you for raising me all these years."
Are you writing the letter?
I'm memorizing your words with my fingers.
I see.
"This might be my final letter to you.
If you two are reincarnated
and marry in the next life too,
then please have me as your son again.
Please.
Things weren't supposed to end this way.
I was going to find happiness
in life and show you that I had.
So please pray a lot so that I can be your son again.
I beg of you."
Was it okay to use such unrefined language?
Yes. I think it's better this way.
Hearing you say that makes it sound true.
Sir!
Sir, is there anyone else you'd like to write to?
Maria... To Maria.
Miss Maria, yes?
An old friend from the neighborhood.
We'd been together since we were kids,
and she was like a kid sister to me.
She said she loved me, and
the feeling was probably mutual.
But I came here before I could do
anything a boyfriend would do for her.
We didn't even kiss.
I'll put those feelings of yours
into words in a letter.
”Maria, are you doing well?
Do you remember when you said you loved me?
I was really, really happy.
Maria... Maria...
I want to come home to you.
I don't want to die.
I want to come home... to you...
Wait for me."
I can't open my eyes anymore.
Are you writing this down?
Yes, I am.
Violet, please make sure my letters are delivered.
And thank you for saving me.
I...
I'm not alone.
I'm right here. I'm right by your side.
Please touch me.
I'm holding your hand, sir.
Oh, now I feel kind of cold.
Dad, Mom...
Maria.
Maria,
kiss me.
Thank you.
Everything will be all right now, sir.
I promise to deliver your letters for you.
"From the Vandal Postal Service.
We've recovered your item.
It'll be returned to you intact."
Thank goodness.
So, when will she be back?
They say they're taking a detour on the way, though.
Maria! Letter from Aiden!
I bring you this letter from Mister Aiden Field.
No...
Aiden!
Thank you.
Thank you so much for bringing our son back to us!
No, I didn't...
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
No...
No. I'm sorry I couldn't protect him.
I'm sorry I let him die.
I'm so sorry!
"I Don't Want to See Anyone Die Ever Again"
anata no koe ga michishirube
Your voice is my guiding light
ichiwa no tori ga naiteiru
A sparrow cries out
namae no nai sora ni watashi wo sagashite
Looking for me within a nameless sky
yasashisa de amitsuzuketa yurikago de asu e yukou
I will head for tomorrow in this cradle woven from kindness
hare no hi mo ame no hi ni mo
Be it a day of rain or a day of sunshine
anata wo mamoru tame ni
I will be there to protect you
kakegae no nai takaramono
A treasure more valuable than all
namae no nai hana wa
A nameless flower
shizuka ni nemuru yo
Lies in peace