The anti-peace faction that gained traction in
Ctrigall has been almost completely suppressed.
However, some remnants managed to escape
and are likely looking to meet up with other powers.
As such, we're requesting the assistance of your squad,
Naval Captain Dietfried Bougainvillea.
Why ask me and not the army?
I belong to the navy.
As you're aware,
the future of the continent rests on the
upcoming peace treaty signing ceremony.
We want to take all possible
measures to prevent any interference.
In addition, the army's special task force has disbanded,
leaving us shorthanded in case of an emergency.
But fortunately, your squad is still active,
and the navy is perfect for this operation.
Now that the man who used to clean up
your messes is gone, you ask his older brother?
The radicals are certain to
try and disrupt the peace talks.
Do you have some idea what they may be planning?
In three days, an ambassador and a civilian
Doll will be taking the transcontinental railroad
from Distery to Gardariki as envoys of peace.
This is a risky move.
We can't have another war breaking out.
You may use the troops in the area as you please.
Foil their plans, no matter what.
"Peace," huh?
Each time I learn a new word
shiranai kotoba wo oboeteyuku tabi
The fog begins to clear
omokage no naka te wo nobasu no
But there may well be words
dakedo hitori de wa wakaranai kotoba mo
I cannot understand alone
aru no kamoshirenai
"Goodbye" is a bitter pill to swallow
sayonara wa nigakute
And "I love you" is strangely distant
aishiteru wa tooi nioi ga shita
This indescribable emotion welling inside
tatoeyou no nai kono omoi wa
Scares me to the bone
totemo kowakute
But also feels very dear to me
dakedo totemo itooshikute
Why am I crying?
watashi nande naiterundarou
What reason do I give my heart?
kokoro ni nante kotaetara ii
Words don't always tell the whole story
kotoba wa itsudemo kataru demo nakute
Sometimes, they are simply there
soko ni aru bakari
Building up rapidly
tsunoru bakari
And making me miss you
watashi wa anata ni aitakunaru
Are you sure you only want to be delivered to Distery?
If I can resupply, I don't mind
taking you all the way to Leiden.
I mean, you had a hell of a time back there.
Well, let me know if you change your mind.
You can feel the tension in the air.
Shows how important this mission is.
We're accompanying that ambassador to Gardariki,
where we'll help him with the
public peace correspondence?
Yeah. And if it goes well,
the War will be over for good.
E-Excuse me! You're from C.H. Postal, yes?
Yeah.
I'll lay out our schedule for you.
Our ship left Port Leiden at 1100 hours.
From Nahalar, we'll sail up the River Rentler,
then use the canals from Machtig,
and arrive at Distery in
Eckstreme at 1200 hours tomorrow.
There, you will board a
special train with the ambassador.
The reason we're sailing partway is to ensure your safety.
Thank you.
Is your boss not coming?
I can't believe he retired the moment the War ended.
Who are you?
C-Captain Bougainvillea.
Bougainvillea?
Wasn't that Violet's major...
I'm his older brother.
What do you want?
Dismissed.
Sir!
My mission is to escort you guys to your destination
and ensure that the ceremony goes smoothly.
Are you the only civilian Doll coming along?
That's right.
If you're wondering about Violet, she's not on this job.
That's music to my ears.
Though I am surprised she's still working as a Doll—
that defective, wannabe human.
Why, you...
Yeah, she may be defective,
but she's giving it her all.
And her letters have given hope and salvation to many.
Huh?
The letters Violet writes are magical.
They slide unnoticed into your heart
and let you express your true feelings.
So you made it.
1,041 of us Gardariki soldiers who
escaped from the internment camp
are reporting for duty.
Thanks for coming all this way.
Sir.
Please don't mention it, Brigadier General Merkulov.
You saved me not only in Intens,
but also from the internment camp,
so I'm very grateful to you.
Intens, huh?
That humiliation...
I can never forget it.
I'm also pleased to report that
our decoy strategy was a success.
The imbeciles in the south probably
think we were wiped out in Ctrigall.
Good.
We'll take this chance to destroy the
transport between the north and south
and reclaim Intens in the ensuing chaos.
That's the railroad.
You can follow it all the way to Leidenschaftlich.
This thing will bring our
country food and other resources.
The north and the south will be bound by peace!
Peace...
Yeah. Won't be any need for war no more.
And my work will get super busy.
I might even get to transport your letters.
Dad!
Welcome back!
Amy...
I'm home.
I hope she'll be back soon.
We've received reports of fires along
the train tracks in the past 24 hours.
Do we know where?
I'll have them check.
So they've made their move.
This is the Great Grandezza Bridge.
Without this,
the transcontinental railroad wouldn't exist.
Intens...
What the...
Fires?
No!
There are signs of explosions!
Let the brigadier general know
that we've infiltrated the train.
Roger.
Why won't it move out?
There was a fire nearby.
Vandal!
Let me down by that train!
Don't be absurd!
A colleague of mine is aboard! Please!
Fine. Hold on tight!
Seven fires since yesterday,
and that's only the ones we've confirmed.
They're all near the railroad,
and they're gradually headed this way.
The anti-peace faction?
Yeah. They'll target this train next.
Send a recon squad along the tracks
ahead to see what the enemy is up to.
Understood.
I'll have them ready immediately.
Violet!
Why are you here?
Where are you going?
Huh? To the peace treaty
signing ceremony in Gardariki...
I saw signs of explosions nearby.
I will accompany you.
No. You return to HQ.
But...
Why are you here?
I spotted her on my way
back from my mission in Ctrigall.
Ctrigall?
I ran into the remnants of the
Gardariki Army during that mission.
Did you really?
Yes.
Give me the details.
Violet!
I got visual on signs of explosions
and nine pillars of smoke from midair.
So they are planning to slow
down the train and attack it directly.
We'll depart as soon as the
recon team gives us the all-clear.
You get off this train at once!
Given the situation, I cannot leave.
Your orders, Captain!
I see you're still a tool who wants to be ordered around.
No.
I no longer...
Begone!
Message from Navy Captain Bougainvillea.
Someone, likely the anti-peace faction,
has been conducting acts of sabotage along the railroad.
They seem to be targeting the ambassador's train.
Tell him to protect the ambassador at all costs.
Have all our troops ready to sortie.
Contact our neighbors too.
We must avoid another war, no matter what!
Brigadier General Merkulov!
Message from the advance unit.
Right.
A peace ambassador is taking
a special train from Distery,
and Isidor has managed to sneak aboard.
We'll attack that train and send
the peace talks back to square one.
There was an explosion at
Distery Station after we departed.
No casualties.
As I thought.
We got away this time,
but we must keep close watch around the clock.
Don't let anyone near the train.
Where do you think they'll attack?
Somewhere the train needs to slow down,
and somewhere it'll be hard to make repairs.
The Great Grandezza Bridge?
It took ten years to build those tunnels.
If it's destroyed, the transcontinental
railroad will be out of commission for a long time.
The only passengers on this train are in the
first and second compartments of the third car.
There's a young man in the first,
and a middle-aged man in the second.
That one's probably the ambassador.
All the troops are in the fourth car and beyond.
Very well. Commence the operation.
Go!
Sir!
Who are you guys?
Enemy attack!
At the rear of car four! Hurry!
Separate them.
Hurry up.
They were planning to take
the troops out of the picture?
What was that shaking?
Violet?
I'll bring the ambassador.
You two stay here.
There are a few enemies to the rear.
I heard noises from the front too.
We have next to no troops left.
I'll stop this train.
You keep the passengers alive.
I understand, sir.
So you really do want to be ordered around.
No.
Yes.
You're a tool.
If I order you to massacre the enemy,
you'll do it without batting an eye, right?
I won't kill anyone.
I don't need a weapon.
What are you if not a tool?
You're Leidenschaftlich's...
We meet again.
What happened to the Ctrigallan brat from back then?
Did he die like a dog?
No need for you to get angry.
Nobody would be saddened by his death.
Lucky—
A woman?
Go.
I remember now.
I've met her on the battlefield before.
Leidenschaftlich's combat doll.
Why are you doing this?
To take back the things and
the people you've trampled upon.
Are you trying to start another war?
Has the War really ended in your mind?
It seems you're not entirely convinced yourself.
That violence still lingers
like burn marks within you and I.
For us, it will never end.
But it has ended in reality.
Like hell it has!
We all fought dreaming of the glory awaiting us,
living or dead, once the War was over.
But what happened in reality?
The brass are your puppets now,
and we soldiers, who risked our
lives and fought to protect our people,
are called useless and pelted by stones.
We were betrayed and abandoned
by everything we ever believed in.
Don't we have the right to destroy it all in return?
I don't want to kill anyone anymore.
Attack.
Is this important to you?
Hey, you all right?
What the hell is going on?
Major.
I...
Die!
Major?
What are you doing?
Brigadier General! Why, you!
Captain Dietfried...
Where do you get off not killing
when you can't even protect yourself?
Is that the kind of person
my brother Gil died to protect?!
I don't want to kill anyone anymore.
The major's orders were to live on, not kill!
A combat doll that doesn't fight
or kill is nothing but dead weight!
That's why you couldn't protect Gilbert!
You killed Gil!
So you should die too! Hurry up and die already!
Even so, the major told me to live on.
I wanted to protect him!
I wanted to protect him just as much!
Brigadier General!
Isidor!
anata no koe ga michishirube
Your voice is my guiding light
ichiwa no tori ga naiteiru
A sparrow cries out
namae no nai sora ni watashi wo sagashite
Looking for me within a nameless sky
yasashisa de amitsuzuketa yurikago de asu e yukou
I will head for tomorrow in this cradle woven from kindness
hare no hi mo ame no hi ni mo
Be it a day of rain or a day of sunshine
anata wo mamoru tame ni
I will be there to protect you
kakegae no nai takaramono
A treasure more valuable than all
namae no nai hana wa
A nameless flower
shizuka ni nemuru yo
Lies in peace