The tool I cast away became Gilbert's dog.
But even after losing her arms,
her master, and everything she'd ever had,
she still stood tall.
Thank you.
All too naïve.
Time's up.
If you'd killed me right at the
outset, you might have made it.
Bombs?
Stop the train!
Now!
It won't work!
Use the brakes in the carriage!
Emergency brakes!
What the...
Violet!
Get the other bomb!
Got it!
It's off!
Violet!
Holmgard,
Capital of Gardariki
Temporary
Leidenschaftlich Embassy
"The nations of Gardariki and Leidenschaftlich
will strive to maintain international peace and order
and hereby sign an all-encompassing
pact that respects each other's sovereignty.
To that end, both nations will immediately
recommence free and fair trade,
and Leidenschaftlich will, as a token of friendship,
provide one year's worth of emergency aid.
Both nations hereby swear to adhere
to and uphold this treaty to the utmost."
It's over.
Yeah.
What's wrong?
It's over, and yet...
It's over...
The War is over,
and yet our son still hasn't come home.
I keep telling my wife that we should give up on him.
But...
I understand.
I understand how you feel very well.
If you could please write the letter like so:
"Thank you for being born our son."
Of course.
Well then,
I will ensure that this is
delivered to the air show on time.
On that day, this letter will be
delivered from the sky.
Thank you for using the
Auto Memoir Doll service.
Thank you for all your hard work.
It must have been stressful
having clients stay so late.
It was no problem.
Air Show season, huh?
It had been suspended during the war,
so everyone's excited for its comeback after five years.
The deadline for letter submissions is
tomorrow, so let's keep at it for one more day.
Yes, I'll do my best.
I'm thinking of writing a letter myself.
I used to be a showgirl before I became a Doll.
Many of our patrons were soldiers,
and many of them are dead now.
I'm thinking of writing to them.
Why don't you write one too?
I've never written a letter of my own.
Then this can be a memorable first.
Just write how you feel right now—
as your heart wills you.
As my heart...
Major.
What is it?
Am I not needed anymore?
What are you talking about?
Will I be disposed of and transferred
into Colonel Hodgins's custody?
Will you not give me orders anymore?
Do you want my orders so badly?
Your orders are everything to me.
After this battle, you can stop taking orders from me.
Actually, you can stop taking orders from anyone.
Live free.
Is that an order?
Why?
Why would you take that as an order?
Do you really think I see you as a tool?
If I did, I would never have carried you
out of there and taken you back home.
I would never have kept you beside me all this while!
You should know that I'm only feeling this anger
and anguish because I want what's best for you!
Major?
You have emotions.
You have a heart, just like me!
If you don't...
If you don't, then how do you
explain that look on your face?!
You're perfectly capable of making such expressions!
You find me scary right now, don't you?
You don't like being yelled at out of nowhere, do you?
I don't understand.
These unreasonable words anger you, don't they?
You lie!
I'm not lying.
I really don't understand.
I...
I want to keep taking orders from you.
If you order me to, I shall go anywhere.
That's all.
I'm sorry.
But I can't watch you force yourself to remain a tool.
It hurts me.
I was the one who took you in when you
were so young and turned you into this.
And yet,
you still believe in me...
You haven't done anything wrong.
The final battle is only a few hours away.
Let's talk about this some other time.
You couldn't write one?
I do have emotions I want to express,
and I had them back then too.
But I don't know what I...
...want to tell the major?
Violet.
There is still some time left.
The deadline is tonight,
but if you can write a letter by the
morning, I'll take it to the admins for you.
So try to write something.
Even if it's short—
even if it's only one sentence.
Come in.
Excuse me.
Someone's here to see Violet.
A man named Bougainvillea.
Thank you very much.
Over here.
You must've been busy ghostwriting
letters for the Air Show until yesterday.
I'm sorry you had to meet me on your day off.
It's fine.
You've never been to our
Leiden mansion before, have you?
I should warn you in advance.
Their memory has gotten a bit hazy.
It's our mother.
You are?
This is Violet.
You said you wanted to meet her.
Oh, right. The one he wants us to adopt.
You're finally here.
Yes.
Oh.
I thought you were a much smaller girl.
How long ago was it?
Four years ago.
Ah, yes.
It has been a while.
Isn't Gilbert with you?
Mother, Gilbert is...
He is with us.
It's the same color as his eyes.
It's the same color as your eyes.
Beautiful, isn't it?
Yes.
I didn't know the word, so I haven't said it.
But I've thought your eyes are
beautiful from the first time we met.
Very beautiful.
So, what is your relationship with Gilbert?
The major took me in,
raised me,
and gave me a purpose.
But...
I know. In the battle of Intens, he...
That's right. You asked to see her to discuss that.
Isn't that right, Mother?
Right.
It wasn't your fault.
It isn't your cross to bear.
Dietfried keeps telling me to give up on Gilbert...
when I know he can't give up on him either.
The two of them were always such loving brothers.
He's alive...
within my heart.
So I won't ever forget him.
Even if it always hurts to remember,
I'll live the rest of my life thinking about him.
I mean, even now,
I still love him.
Right.
Right!
Violet.
Live his share of life too.
Live, live, live some more,
and die.
Those are my final orders for you.
I...
I don't need orders anymore.
Gilbert never treated the tool I cast away as one.
So, even though she lost her arms and her master,
she will never lose all the important things he gave her.
I'm really glad the weather cleared up in time.
Yeah. It actually snowed, and Leiden never gets snow.
Roland.
Oh, they're holding hands.
That's amazing.
So nice...
Violet!
Luculia.
I'm glad you could make it.
It must've been hectic with all
the ghostwriting for the Air Show.
Not really, but I did write a lot of letters.
I even wrote one of my own for the first time.
I see.
I wrote one to my parents too.
I'm sure it'll reach them.
Thanks.
I wrote one too.
To my future self,
who has become Leiden's—
no, the continent's most popular Doll!
That's one lofty goal.
What about you, Erica?
What did you write?
I've fallen for someone recently, so I wrote a love—
What?
Who? Who is it?!
Hey.
Want to know what I wrote?
Yes. I do.
Ah.
Believe it or not,
I wrote it to Hodgins.
"One day,
I'm going to be the boss."
Wait, you want to take my place?
What kind of letter is that?!
You're one to talk.
What kind of letter is this?
"From Papa, to my future daughter."
How'd you get that?
Stop!
I found a bunch of drafts crammed
into the trash can in your office,
Papa.
You of all people shouldn't be calling me that!
Papa...
Stop it!
"Papa's eagerly awaiting the day you are born.
And I'm praying that you grow up healthy and strong,
that you find happiness,
and that you love someone who loves you just as much.
And I pray that the future you and your children live in
is a world free of conflict and filled with happiness."
The feelings of countless people are raining from the sky.
Violet.
Major...
"Dear Major Gilbert,
Do you have any news? Are you doing well?
Where are you right now?
Are you having any difficulties?
Spring, summer, autumn, and winter...
Many seasons have come and gone,
but the one with you isn't coming around at all.
At first, I couldn't understand.
I couldn't understand anything about how you felt.
But within this new life you gave me,
I've begun to feel the same way as you, if only a little,
through ghostwriting, and through
the people I've met along the way.
I believe that you are still alive somewhere.
So I shall live, live, live,
and live some more, though there's
no telling what life might have in store.
And if I can ever see you again, I want to let you know...
that the phrase "I love you"...
I understand it a little now.
Ghostwriting request, Violet! They say it's urgent!
Benedict, you make some tea.
What? Why should I?
Violet, the customer's waiting.
I'll be right there.
Auto Memoir Doll and "I Love You"
anata no koe ga michishirube
Your voice is my guiding light
ichiwa no tori ga naiteiru
A sparrow cries out
namae no nai sora ni watashi wo sagashite
Looking for me within a nameless sky
yasashisa de amitsuzuketa yurikago de asu e yukou
I will head for tomorrow in this cradle woven from kindness
hare no hi mo ame no hi ni mo
Be it a day of rain or a day of sunshine
anata wo mamoru tame ni
I will be there to protect you
kakegae no nai takaramono
A treasure more valuable than all
namae no nai hana wa
A nameless flower
shizuka ni nemuru yo
Lies in peace
It is a pleasure to meet you.
If a client requests it, we shall go anywhere.
Representing the Auto Memoir Doll service,
I am Violet Evergarden.