My goodness.
Superintendent Tawashi,
we have the name of the victim.
Junichiro Tazaki, a legal scholar.
He's the one who proposed
the International Robot Laws.
Oh, the very man
who gave robots freedom and equality?
Yes.
Well then,
let's start by questioning everyone
in anti-robot law groups.
Yes, sir!
Horns, eh?
I remember hearing about cases
involving horns somewhere.
I'll have it looked into.
Hey, you there!
Still, what in the world happened here?
What caused this?
Did it collapse on its own,
or did someone use a power shovel on it?
We're analyzing it now.
I guess it wouldn't be impossible
for you lot.
Sir?
For a robot with some strength,
this would be a piece of cake.
Superintendent Tawashi!
The cases with the horns
happened in Switzerland and Germany.
That's right!
They were found in the head
of a destroyed robot called Mont Blanc.
There was another case
in Düsseldorf, Germany.
The victim, Bernard Lanke, was also
a leader in the Robot Liberation Movement.
We'd better contact Europol
and talk to the investigators
assigned to each case.
Actually, according to this data,
the same detective
is in charge of both cases.
The same detective?
Yes, and a robot detective at that.
A robot, eh?
What's his name?
Gesicht.
How curious.
What is?
When I look at you,
my identification system might malfunction
trying to tell if you're robot or human.
I get that a lot.
I've seen you many times in the news,
but seeing you
sitting right in front of me...
The news?
Yes.
When you arrived
with the peacekeeping forces
during the 39th Central Asian War,
the media raised a fuss, remember?
Right.
I only went there to help defend
the peace in that nation. Yet...
And yet, they treated you
like an idol or a pop star.
Yes.
Here you go.
Time to dig in!
Is something wrong?
No, it's just that you seem like
you're truly enjoying it.
I'm sure it's obvious
that I'm pretending to drink.
The more I pretend,
the more I feel like I understand it.
Understand what?
When something is delicious.
I don't know
if it's a truly human sensation,
but I feel it in my heart.
Incredible.
When you saw that kid
playing with a new toy earlier,
did you really want one too?
Yes. That toy is really popular
among kids right now.
Then, how about the snail?
Huh?
Earlier, you found a snail in the rain.
I did.
You didn't just collect a sample
of a pulmonate gastropod mollusk
from the helicidae family.
You felt something.
You were moved by life, weren't you?
Maybe? Beats me.
You really live up to your reputation.
You're amazing.
You may look like a child,
but I know your artificial intelligence
is far superior to mine.
That's why I was sold.
I look like a child,
and people found it amusing,
so they sold me to the circus.
Sold?
Gesicht?
It's nothing.
I'm sorry for bringing all that up.
It's all right.
Let me get down to business.
As I had mentioned in the email,
Mont Blanc of Switzerland
and North No.2 in Scotland
were killed in a series of murders.
And you think I'm in danger too?
Yes. I don't have any proof yet,
but the killer's goal may be...
to destroy the seven
most advanced robots in the world.
But why?
I think you know why.
Gesicht, could I please
read your memory chip?
What?
There may be clues to help solve the case
in everything you've seen and heard.
No, I can't do that.
It includes classified information
on other cases and my personal data.
Oh, right. Your artificial intelligence
is more advanced than mine.
I'll trust you.
It'll only take a minute.
Thank you.
For anything unrelated
to the investigation,
could you delete that?
I will.
I hope you can find information
that I've overlooked.
Something you've overlooked...
Pardon me, Gesicht.
- I'm going to the bathroom.
- The bathroom?
It's another habit I've developed
while mimicking human behavior.
I see.
Well, being as close to human as you are,
it makes sense.
Gesicht, you...
It sure rains a lot.
Yes.
Are you leaving Japan right away?
Yes, I have a lot of work waiting for me,
and I need to speak
to three more robots about this.
Gesicht, please come visit again. Promise?
Yeah, I promise.
Your wife is lovely.
This is why I didn't want
to let you read my chip.
Come on! No making fun of adults!
Delete that data now!
It'll be okay.
You and your wife will be okay.
Whatever happens, you two can handle it.
Thank you.
Goodbye, Atom.
Gesicht, I'll be waiting!
We'll meet again for sure!
FORENSICS DIVISION
Cause of death?
It was suffocation.
Suffocation?
What was the murder weapon? A rope?
We don't know yet.
We only know that his neck
was subjected to great pressure.
- No trace evidence?
- None.
Hey, bring up the 3D replica!
I've got a pretty good idea
who the perp might be.
What? You do?
Sure. For the suspect to not leave
any trace, that could only mean--
How strange...
You!
Atom!
Hello there, Superintendent Tawashi,
Inspector Nakamura!
Who gave you permission to be in here?
I have an admission pass here.
You requested cooperation
on the investigation from Europol, right?
I installed the memory
of Inspector Gesicht,
the one in charge of the cases.
So I have the data on the Mont Blanc case
in Switzerland and the Düsseldorf case.
Being a robot must be awfully convenient
to swap the contents of your brain.
But if you think you know everything
from that, you're very mistaken!
You robots don't even know
when something is beautiful or tasty.
Then again, when it comes to this case,
perhaps your kind might grasp it better.
You guys have finally done it.
A robot committed murder.
What makes you say that?
No human could have done this
without leaving a trace!
A living human would have left
fingerprints, hair, something,
but there is nothing here.
Then what do you make of this?
There's green tea under the rubble here.
Green tea?
Yes, two broken teacups
and some yokan red bean jelly.
- Hey, pick up this spot!
- Yes, sir.
It hadn't been that long
since this tea was brewed.
The autopsy did find some tea
and yokan in the victim's stomach.
Would you serve tea and yokan
if a robot came to visit?
You pretend to eat all the time!
The outside corridor...
Hydrangeas.
They sat outside
and admired the hydrangeas.
Hey, pick up that spot!
We can confirm that there were
hydrangeas in the garden there.
Robots don't understand beauty, right?
Do you still think a robot did this?
What are you saying?
That the human who committed the murders
also wrecked the house?
That after happily gazing at hydrangeas,
the suspect bulldozed the house?
- Pull up the witness statements!
- Yes, sir.
Yes, it was like a tornado.
I heard this crazy roar,
and suddenly the house next door was gone!
I can't believe our house still stands.
It was such a huge tornado.
See? They said it was a tornado!
And an unnaturally localized one
that only destroyed one house!
What do you make of that?
After that,
Mr. Tazaki went out to the garden.
Excuse me. Could you bring up
the image of the body?
No, it's not something
a child should see--
It's fine!
He only looks like a child.
He's just a robot.
Oh, right.
Hey, bring it up!
Yes, sir.
Horns.
The god of death had horns.
This is Gesicht's memory.
The lord of the underworld
in Roman mythology...
Pluto.
Excuse me.
Did Mr. Junichiro Tazaki use pens?
Huh?
There's a callus on his middle finger,
so it looks like he did.
The rain washed most of it away,
but there's a bit of ink on his hand.
Wet footprints.
He rushed into the house from the garden.
To the study!
Look, right here!
There's an ink bottle
with the same ink on his hand.
Hey, pick this up!
He must have knocked it over
to find something.
Find what?
Can you pick up what's beneath here?
Business cards?
INQUIRY COMMISSION
"Inquiry commission"?
There it is.
A business card with ink and fingerprints.
Whose card?
Not that matter again.
No matter what you say,
I will not change my mind.
Thracia may say what they want,
but we are not making robots
for them to use in wars!
Good grief.
Professor Ochanomizu?
Oh, Atom.
Do you have a moment to spare?
Sure. What brings you here at this hour?
Professor Ochanomizu.
Have you heard of a scholar
named Junichiro Tazaki?
Yes, I heard he died.
He was caught up in some incident.
It was he who proposed
the International Robot Laws.
He was a great man.
How about Bernard Lanke?
Lanke?
He was a key advocate for the robot laws.
Yes, I know him,
though I haven't seen him in years.
What about him?
He passed away.
Professor, where did you meet Mr. Lanke?
During the 39th Central Asian War,
as part of a certain inquiry commission.
Right before he passed,
Junichiro Tazaki
was looking for a business card.
It was yours, Professor.
He was trying to contact me?
Yes. I believe you're in danger.
Someone is after you.
You and the former members
of the Bora Inquiry Commission.
Please tell me.
What exactly is Bora?
It all started from the suspicion
that the Kingdom of Persia
was in possession
of robots of mass destruction.
As you know,
the Kingdom of Persia was ruled
by the dictatorship of Darius XIV then.
Its citizens and robots
were treated poorly,
not in compliance
with United Nations treaties.
Darius XIV used
overwhelming robot military might
to bring neighboring countries
under his control
and attempted to conquer
all of Central Asia.
That's when they proposed
the Prohibition of the Manufacture
of Robots of Mass Destruction treaty.
It was immediately passed
at the United Nations.
Soon after, the Kingdom of Persia
was suspected of possessing
robots of mass destruction.
President Alexander
of the United States of Thracia,
the one who had called for the treaty,
leveled the accusations against Persia.
Based on his accusations,
the Bora Inquiry Commission
was dispatched to the Kingdom of Persia.
No one knew what Bora was
or if it was just a code name
or to what it referred.
But I was a member
of the inquiry commission alongside Lanke
and Mr. Tazaki.
What happened with Bora?
Such robots of mass destruction,
as the United States of Thracia claimed,
were nowhere to be seen.
On what basis did the United States
of Thracia make such a claim?
There was this genius.
A genius?
It was believed that the Kingdom
of Persia's advanced robot army
came from the mind of a genius scientist.
What is the name of this scientist?
He was commonly known as "Dr. Goji."
No one knew his real name
or what he looked like.
We didn't even know
if such a person actually existed.
That's about all we found out.
But there was this one place
that we visited.
It was deep underground,
beneath an old mosque.
I still don't know what to make
of what we saw there,
those piles and piles of robot corpses.
The Kingdom explained to us
that it was a dump for unusable robots.
And then,
the war started.
You all right, Mont Blanc?
You two hurt anywhere?
Brando destroyed 2,895.
I destroyed 2,962.
How many did you destroy, Mont Blanc?
A lot.
A lot, huh?
How impressive.
It was 3,022.
What are we doing here?
We came here for a just cause, didn't we?
To liberate robots from oppression.
That's why we came, right?
We...
Access the network.
The palace of Darius XIV is about to fall.
The peacekeeping forces
have entered the center of town.
An "Emissary of Peace," huh?
Atom's got it easy.
Why did we come here, you ask?
Who is it that we should have destroyed?
Who is it that we were supposed to hate?
"Hate"?
Yeah.
What the heck is this thing
they call "hatred"?
Brando!
What a landslide!
Truly unbeatable!
The final round of the ESKKKR Tournament
ended with his instant victory!
Undefeated in 936 consecutive matches!
Will we ever see an end
to the legend of this invincible hero?
The strongest warrior in history!
Brando!
That was an impressive match, Brando.
Nah, I'm definitely
getting rickety these days.
Sometimes, I can't even move
after a match, like right now.
It's strange though.
You all wear
the same pankration suits in the ring,
but when you wear it,
you're the strongest.
Experience is all you need
to win most matches.
The rest is luck.
Luck?
Yeah. I know humans laugh
when a robot talks about luck.
But I'm a lucky man.
It's an old town, right?
Yes.
My place is upstairs.
Your face says,
"Why does a combat-sports superstar live
in a dump like this?"
Not at all.
Sure, with my fight money,
I could afford to live in a fancy mansion.
However,
I've chosen to use my money
on something else.
I'm home!
King of the fighting world has returned!
Daddy!
- You're home!
- Welcome back!
All right, kiddos.
Have you been good?
Daddy, you're so strong!
- You were amazing!
- You betcha!
Welcome home, dear.
Oh?
I almost forgot. This is my wife, Mine.
Pleased to meet you.
I'm Gesicht, of Europol.
Time for dinner, everyone!
- I'm starving!
- I'm so hungry!
Let's go!
Please come in.
Catch me if you can!
Hey! Don't go spilling things.
Hey, you!
No running during meals!
Hey, mister, are you really a detective?
I am.
Then do you have a cool weapon
or something?
No, I'm afraid I don't have anything cool.
Stop with the silly questions!
Keep that up, and you'll get a spanking!
Please excuse them.
No, I haven't had
such a fun meal in a while.
What do you think?
A human-style meal isn't so bad, is it?
Yes, so merry and lively.
This is how it is in our house.
Every day is a zoo event!
Honey! Eat your salad!
Oh...
My mom is the strongest in this house!
She's the world champion, right?
Champion!
Stop being silly and finish your dinner!
Yikes! So scary!
She really is the champion!
Is everyone asleep?
Yeah.
Don't drink too much.
This is the life I've made for myself
with the fight money I've earned.
Right.
Because I fight for a living,
Mine never knows when I'm going
to come home in pieces.
For a while, she had to stay home alone,
worrying about me every day.
That's when that policy came into effect.
The Robot Adoption System.
Right. We took in one first.
And then a second
because the more, the merrier.
Now we have five.
It's a funny thing.
Before kids, I never gave a shit
if I'd be torn into pieces in a match.
But now,
I want to live as long as possible.
Weird, huh?
I got kids, so I could die at any time.
But now that I have them,
I don't want to die.
I'm sure Mont Blanc wanted to live too.
I met him
during the 39th Central Asian War.
But more than the memory
of fighting together,
I remember the fun times we had
doing silly things and talking all night.
He told me about trees,
birds, all kinds of things.
For a great guy like him
to die the way he did...
Do you know a robot named North No.2?
Yeah, only by name.
He's dead.
Last week.
He was living peacefully as the butler
of a composer in Scotland, and then...
Was he killed?
Yes. And now you're in danger too.
You don't need to worry about me.
I'm the king of the fighting world.
That's why you're being targeted.
I say bring it on.
After what they did to Mont Blanc,
I'll rip them apart, just you watch.
Please don't be stupid!
If anything happens, call me right away!
Would you like another?
Oh, actually, this Turkish energy drink
is pretty potent.
I'm ready for another.
None for you.
Fine.
You sure you don't want me
to drive you back?
Yes, I can grab a cab there.
Okay. Come visit again soon.
Thank you. I had a great time today.
Yeah, kids are great, you know?
You might want to give it a thought.
Five of them like us
might be a bit much though.
You're right.
You can have the whole body for 500 ZEUS.
What's the matter?
Oh, it's nothing.
Maybe I had too much to drink.
Are you sure you can get home by yourself?
Yes, I'll be fine.
All right, if you say so.
Do take care of yourself.
If anything happens, contact me.
- Say...
- Hmm?
I told you that winning
was up to one's luck, right?
Humans leave things up to chance,
but I say luck is something you take.
It's because I have a family
that I've got luck on my side now.
If anything happens, you just call me.
I'm a lucky man.
Yes.
Thanks. I'm counting on you.
Please...
Don't you die on me.
Whoa! It's a double wrist lock!
Is this the end?
Rip his arm out!
Break it!
Twist it off!
There he is, the undefeated champion!
What a perfect match
to defend the title of world champion!
Everyone is intoxicated by the artistry
of Hercules, our god of battle!
Hercules!
Next month,
Hercules will finally have a showdown
with Brando from Turkey,
the European champion!
There it is, his signature pose!
The god of battle!
It's an amazing monument, Hercules.
I told them not to.
I said it would only ruin the view
of the world heritage site.
But they ended up building a statue
of my pankration suit.
Humans like that kind of stuff.
I saw the match last night.
You were strong, as usual.
As usual, huh?
Would you like to sit down
for a cup of tea and talk?
I don't imitate humans.
I'm a robot.
A killing machine
that destroys his opponents.
But in your recent matches...
You think I've gone soft, right?
That I held back last night
when it really mattered.
Are you worried
about my next match with Brando?
I heard you went to see him.
Yes.
He was in top shape.
I'll bet.
I've fought him many times,
and I know he's tough.
Just like he was back then.
During the 39th Central Asian War,
you mean?
Detective Gesicht,
do you know why humans
love building these monuments?
Because they forget.
Before their memory fades,
they build these things to remember.
But look at us.
Unless we erase them,
our memories will last forever.
We remember things vividly.
Our comrades in arms.
Mountains of robot corpses on both sides.
Ours and theirs.
That's how I learned
about murderous intent.
Ever since then, I haven't been able
to destroy my opponents.
What do humans call this feeling?
Compassion, perhaps?
Say...
Yes?
Don't you think
that we are evolving?
But why, Daddy?
You promised
that you'd come to the zoo with us!
Yeah.
Sorry, kiddos.
Some work came up
that I have to attend to.
What?
You're just going to cancel on us?
I'll come with you next time.
It's a promise!
You'll just break your promise again!
No, I promise this as a man.
And real men never break their promises.
All right. Stop complaining!
I'm coming with you.
You're a liar, Daddy!
I'm sorry.
A sudden work matter...
Did something happen?
Oh, it's an interview.
An interview?
It's a conversation with Miss Istanbul.
I owe this editor I know,
and I couldn't say no.
Well, have fun at this "interview."
Hey, your husband
is the European champ now.
I've got obligations...
What's the matter?
Don't "what's the matter" me.
You took your pankration suit out
without permission.
It won't be a problem.
I'll return it right away.
That's not the point.
You even took the cargo truck
without asking.
If anything happens,
they won't let you fight in the match.
The match with Hercules
is coming up next--
That's exactly why.
Huh?
I'm borrowing it
to get ready for the next match.
That may be, but--
Relax, pal.
Professor, do you think these incidents
were caused by a human, or...
A robot?
Or a combination of the two?
The only precedent of a robot killing
a human is the case of Brau1589.
Is that really true?
Why do you ask?
Never mind. So what kind of defects
did the AI of Brau1589 have?
There weren't any.
What?
His AI was perfect.
Perfect...
A perfect AI killed a human...
What does that mean?
Could it be
that it was human?
This should be a good spot.
What's the matter?
Detective Gesicht?
Patch yourself in, Hercules!
No way!
Atom, you patch in too!
Atom, what's wrong?
I'm getting a signal from Istanbul...
Gesicht, what's going on here?
It's communication from Brando.
Keep the channel... open!
Brando!
I'll show you the fight I have in me!
Stop! Stop it, Brando!
Brando, run!
I've identified his location.
He's on the coast of the Black Sea.
Let's go, Gesicht!
To avenge...
Mont Blanc!
Brando, do not take it head-on!
We're on our way!
The signal is disturbed.
What's happening, Atom?
Professor, I have to go!
But go where?
Someone is attacking Brando.
I have to hurry!
So strong...
What the heck is this thing?
What was that?
Brando, come in!
Brando!
The sea...
I did it.
Brando!
I beat it.
I won.
But it got me too.
We're coming! Hold on, Brando!
Hercules.
Our next match,
I was looking forward to it.
Me too.
I would have beat you.
Don't be silly!
You never know!
We're coming to get you!
Just stay there and wait for us!
I'm sending you the data I analyzed
on the guy I just fought.
Brando, don't push yourself.
Huh?
That's weird...
That's Brando's family.
Damn it...
My circuits are
all messed up.
Brando, that's enough.
Damn it.
I can't transmit
the correct data.
You've done enough.
That's odd.
Sorry, guys.
I can't control it.
Detective Gesicht.
Didn't I tell you?
I'm a lucky man.
Yeah.
I promised my kids
that I'd take them to the zoo.
I made the promise as a man.
Tell them
not to worry.
I'm a lucky man.
Brando!
This is where Brando
sent his last transmission from.
I've been sending him a signal,
but there's no response.
All I can see is
spilled oil on the water's surface
and a huge amount of wreckage
at the bottom of the ocean.
Gesicht.
Hercules.
For a brief moment,
did you notice something mixed in
with the signals Brando sent?
No, I didn't.
Was it a signal from someone
other than Brando?
Yes, a different AI
that had gone out of control.
Something like noise.
Noise?
What could it be?
- Atom, can you bring it up on the monitor?
- I can.
Atom, send it to us as well.
Understood.
Here, right after this.
What in the world is this?
What do humans call this?
Death incarnate.
Death incarnate?
Emotion.
Overwhelming... pain.
This is the Blue Mosque Coliseum
in Istanbul.
Scores of people are here
to mourn the death of their hero, Brando.
Daddy!
We'll go now to our reporter on the scene.
I'm here at the scene.
The ocean floor around here
is covered with wreckage,
and it is assumed
that most of it belongs to Brando.
The police and the military
are continuing their search,
but sources say it would be impossible
to recover all the wreckage
due to the muddy ocean floor.
How long are you going to let this go on?
The deadline for defending your title
is coming soon!
Are you listening to me, Hercules?
If you're not going to fight,
then I'll sue you for breach of contract!
I'm Al Haft, the biggest promoter
there is! You hear me?
They haven't found a damn thing.
They haven't found
a single piece of the killer.
All they've found so far
are pulverized pieces of Brando.
Brando fought the killer here and won.
So, why can't we
find pieces of the killer?
Hercules.
Even the military and the police have
given up on recovering everything.
So, why should you be the one to do it,
let alone out of your own pocket?
Is it your friendship with Brando?
Your fans are all waiting for you.
For Hercules, the god of battle,
to come back to the ring.
I am too.
So please, Hercules.
Come back--
Hercules! We found Brando's arms!
Good work!
Take great care with the recovery!
Actually, it's a little complicated!
They were found on a rock reef
about 100 km away from here,
not on the ocean floor!
We'll take you there!
Wait!
Hercules!
Come back!
Come back and fight one more time!
Hercules.
Right over there, on that rock!
What the...
Brando's memory chip.
Horns.
I don't believe this...
The killer
isn't dead yet!
Brando!
Subtitle translation by: Astrid Oliver