Stand back!
It's dangerous! Please step back!
What's the damage?
Oh, Inspector Nakamura.
You won't believe it.
A localized tornado is one thing,
but for it to only damage a single truck?
And, of all things,
an animal transportation truck, right?
Yes, sir.
Lions, tigers, and cheetahs. Five in all.
What?
We've got a problem, Inspector Nakamura!
A child!
Can't we do something?
A rescue team in the area is on standby,
but all five cats must be taken out
all at once or else...
Damn it! Call for more sharpshooters!
What is it?
A little girl has crossed the police line!
What is she doing?
Don't be scared.
It's all right. Come here, everyone.
That's right. Nothing to be afraid of.
Now!
We've secured the boy.
Hey now!
You're scaring them with those guns!
It's Uran!
Give me a break.
You sensed that they were afraid?
Yes.
So let me get this straight, Uran.
You're saying
the lion and the tigers were afraid?
I don't know. I guess.
And that's why you walked two miles
out of your way to school to go there?
Yeah, so?
You can sense that animals are afraid
from that far away?
Yeah, I guess.
Wow.
What an amazing ability.
So...
Can I go now?
Oh!
I'm sorry for all the trouble
my sister has caused, Inspector Nakamura.
Oh, not at all.
She's actually been a huge help.
Exactly. Thanks to me, the big cats
calmed down, and the boy was saved.
Worthy of
the Superintendent General Award.
I don't want something so boring.
Uran!
I'd rather be awarded that lion.
Please excuse her.
We'll be on our way now.
Inspector!
He's here, at the entrance.
What? Where's Superintendent Tawashi?
I've contacted him.
Good!
Uran, how many times must I tell you?
Don't take detours.
But I couldn't help it.
Hey, wait.
You two are this way.
No, we're supposed to go this way.
Huh? Really?
It's hard to tell these days...
Right this way, please.
Are you listening to me, Atom?
Huh? Yeah.
Like I said, I wasn't taking a detour,
and you wouldn't believe what I saw.
Thank you so much for coming.
I am Tawashi of
the Tokyo Metropolitan Police Department.
- Hey, get me a translation machine!
- Yes, right away!
No need. I can speak Japanese.
I see. Just what you'd expect from
Central Asia's greatest intellect, huh?
Yes, indeed!
Please have a seat.
I apologize for the drab surroundings,
Professor Abullah.
Not at all.
Everywhere in Japan is fantastic,
especially compared to the current state
of my home country, Persia.
Is this visit part
of the post-war reconstruction efforts?
That's right.
I'm here to attend
the World Science Conference in Tokyo.
By the way, Professor Abullah,
you also visited Japan
three months ago, correct?
I did.
And you met a legal scholar
named Junichiro Tazaki, didn't you?
I heard the shocking news.
Why did a great man like him
have to be killed?
You were the last person
to see Mr. Tazaki alive.
Please rest assured.
You're not under suspicion.
The incident happened as your plane
was about to depart from the airport.
It's just that we wondered if you noticed
anything out of the ordinary.
He had so many wonderful things
to tell me.
Mr. Tazaki was the first to propose
the International Robot Laws.
It was his true and sincere wish
for robots and humans to coexist.
Robots actually feel a lot more
than humans assume, don't you think?
Yeah.
But we're just not good
at expressing ourselves.
They say they can't tell
humans from robots without a sensor gate,
but I can tell right away.
Humans have
complicated facial expressions.
Like this.
That man...
Which man?
The man we passed by at the gate.
I couldn't tell
if he was human or robot.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Not at all. I'm sorry I wasn't much help.
Hey! I told you to turn it off!
- I'm sorry!
- The professor--
I lost most of my organic body
in the last war.
I beg your pardon!
Oh, please don't worry.
By the way, I heard today
there was another tornado in Tokyo.
Yes.
Where did it happen?
Fear...
But the big cats are okay now, right?
The feeling I had today
came flying at superspeed.
Like, whoosh!
You mean apart from the big cats?
I'm not sure.
And you're still getting that feeling?
It's really faint.
From which way?
It's too faint to tell.
You know, lions hide their fear
when they're really scared.
But right now,
the one who's most scared
is you, Atom!
You were looking at it again.
Don't blame yourself so much.
- Hey, Helena.
- Yes?
Let's take a trip.
A trip?
We discussed it the other day.
But can you take time off?
The higher-ups consider the robot attacks
to be concluded for now.
True. And a change of pace might be good.
It will be.
I'm sure of it.
How about Japan?
Japan?
I was just there for work,
and it was a lovely place.
I'll leave it to you.
This is Marco Polo Tourist.
Hello, I used your service before.
Mr. Gesicht, yes?
I'd like to make a reservation again.
Thank you very much.
My wife and I would like to go to Japan.
Very well.
I guess I'll have to register her
with you first.
Actually, your wife is already registered.
I don't believe she's left
the Euro Federation before.
Both of you have registered
with us before,
but you canceled your reservation.
- We did?
- When?
Two years ago. It was the same request
for a trip to Japan.
Two years ago to Japan?
Two years ago, we were in Spain
for my training assignment with Europol.
That's right.
We lived in Madrid for the entire year.
See? We have tons of photos.
Ah, this is the Sagrada Família.
This is Andalusia.
You tripped and disappeared
into the field of sunflowers.
I remember!
You even used your GPS to find me.
We sure took a lot of pictures.
Yes.
Maybe too many?
Right. We do try to copy human behavior,
but we never take this many photos.
It was fun, wasn't it?
Yes. Very.
Apparently, we planned
a trip to Japan during that time.
All done, Gesicht.
No abnormalities at all.
Thank you, Professor Hoffman.
Since you insisted on coming in,
I don't doubt you're experiencing
some sort of malfunction.
But according to the data,
everything looks just fine.
I still think it's due to fatigue.
And don't be too hard on yourself
about what happened to Brando.
Human memory is a convenient thing.
We have the function to forget.
Life can be tough if you hang on
to too many painful memories.
That's what forgetting is for.
But it doesn't work that way with robots.
Your memory will always remain fresh.
The only solution for robot memories
is to delete them.
Professor.
Yes?
Is there any record
of my memories being deleted?
No, I don't see any record of that.
How about traces
of nonfactual memories being inserted?
You mean like false memories?
Yes.
I heard things like that used to be done
at correctional facilities,
but now robots have rights too.
Why do you ask?
What if someone had deleted my memories
and replaced them with false memories?
What if that's the reason
for my nightmares?
That's an interesting theory.
I'm off to a meeting now.
Can we talk later?
I only need a minute, Director Schelling!
We'll talk later.
Did you do something
to Detective Gesicht's memory?
Director!
How many robots of Gesicht's caliber
are left in the world?
What?
How many robots have existed in the world
that could become
weapons of mass destruction?
There were seven altogether.
That's right.
And now, in this series of incidents,
three of them, Mont Blanc, North No.2,
and Brando, have been destroyed.
Now, there are only four left.
And one of them
is Gesicht.
But, Director,
that doesn’t answer my question!
Did you do something to him?
His artificial intelligence--
We made a huge investment
in Gesicht, you know!
All you need to do
is to maintain him properly.
That's all.
What did you do to Gesicht?
What exactly are you hiding?
These horns...
You think it's the same killer
from the other cases?
What do you make of this,
Detective Gesicht?
No, this is a copycat.
How do you know?
The perpetrator wore hybrid sneakers
to try and conceal their footprints,
but I see traces of movements everywhere.
Weight: 78 kilograms.
Height: 175 centimeters.
Most importantly, that drawer.
The culprit had difficulty with the knob,
so they removed their gloves for a moment.
You'll find fingerprints on it.
Forensics!
So this is a robbery
made to look like those incidents?
Yes, most likely.
Amazing as ever. You're perfect.
Perfect.
You're on vacation, right?
I'm sorry for summoning you.
You've been a great help.
- Detective Fersen.
- Yes?
This is the second time
we've met, correct?
Come on, I'm sure your robot memory
is more accurate than mine!
We met in Salzburg three years ago.
You did an excellent job on that case too.
Three years ago?
Yes, right after you came back
from The 39th Central Asian War.
I remember you telling me
all those stories from the war.
You had seven beers
at Karl's bar that night.
So you do remember!
And I'm still a beer drinker.
It was great to see you again, Detective.
Same here.
Let's go for drinks again another time.
I remember perfectly
what happened three years ago.
It's been four years since the end
of The 39th Central Asian War.
Democracy is starting
to take root in Persia...
The 39th Central Asian War...
We're military police!
There are terrorists hiding in this area!
All residents must evacuate immediately!
I repeat!
There are terrorists hiding...
They're not here.
There aren't any terrorists here!
The only ones here were children!
You dropped a bomb on my sleeping child!
To hell with "saving the oppressed"!
Is killing children your idea of justice?
Have you no humanity?
You must know how I feel!
I am a robot.
Stop it!
He's...
He's in despair.
It may be an emotion beyond understanding
for a robot like you.
Despair...
My memory from four years ago
is perfect too.
I got killed!
- Aw, man!
- Oh no, I'm sorry.
- I just got this yesterday, Mom!
- Hans.
Why can't we get a maid robot?
My whole class has one, but--
Hans!
Your mother is doing the best she can.
Watch your words.
Besides, no gaming during meals.
Yes, sir.
What's your plan for today, dear?
Today's the anniversary
of your brother's death.
You're going to go claim his body,
aren't you?
Yes, today makes three years.
I still can't believe they wouldn't
let you have it for three whole years.
It's the law.
The authorities keep
the bodies of criminals for three years.
It can't be helped.
He was a rotten apple, after all.
But you know,
he was a good brother to me.
I want to give him a proper burial,
regardless of who he was.
An explosion occurred
at a hotel in Berlin last night.
Judge Neuman from the German Ministry
of Justice has been confirmed dead.
Judge Neuman attracted attention
as the world's first robot judge
and was known for groundbreaking verdicts
on cases such as the Greifelt lawsuit.
The cause of the explosion is under
investigation, and according to forensi--
Good morning, Adolf.
I heard the news.
What news?
A robot judge was killed... No, destroyed.
Death to machines.
Death to machines!
Corpse number 902886.
Right this way.
In accordance with the König Law,
we acknowledge the passage of three years
and hereby return the body
to the family of the deceased.
Will you accept it?
Yes.
Then please sign here.
I don't need to look
at my brother's body, do I?
Given the degree of his injuries,
I would not recommend it.
I was told he was shot to death
by a police officer.
And it was lawful and appropriate.
Please state your destination.
Hofgarten Cemetery.
Confirmed.
Scratch that. New destination.
To Dr. Schiller's.
Confirmed.
I'm sorry to drop by unannounced, Doctor.
So, you want me
to view your brother's body?
Yes.
You have a problem
with the autopsy report?
No, not exactly.
Well, it's a chance to say goodbye.
Let's see.
This is...
Doctor?
What's the matter?
No, it's nothing.
We see more and more robots these days,
even in places like this.
They say robots can think like we do,
but who knows--
Don't say things like that too loud.
It'd be discrimination.
At least under
Universal Robot Rights Protection Laws.
I have one other thing
to take care of before I go home.
You go on ahead without me.
Okay. Be careful.
Armed robbery in progress!
There are multiple suspects!
They're fleeing
in a military-armed vehicle!
The suspects broke through Ward N-6!
This is Gesicht.
I'll try and head them off.
I have eyes on the suspects' vehicle.
Requesting permission to fire the SAAW!
Permitted!
Did you get them, Gesicht?
I only damaged the tires of the vehicle.
Hands in the air!
Freeze, or we'll shoot!
Splendid, Gesicht.
Is that a specialized anti-tank gun?
No, I had to use a special shell
to stop an armored vehicle like that.
What is it, then?
A special alloy.
Zeronium shells.
Brethren!
My wish is to eradicate every single robot
from the face of this planet.
Now is the time
to teach those abhorrent machines!
I will promise you all this.
Repeal the Universal Robot Rights
Protection Laws!
Abolish police-bots!
Robots are servants!
Robots are slaves!
Robots are inferior.
Robots are inferior!
Death to machines.
Death to machines!
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
So...
What is this urgent matter you spoke of?
I claimed my brother's body today.
I see...
That brother.
He was the kind of person
who deserved to be killed.
- But...
- But?
He was pulverized.
"Pulverized"?
They used a weapon
that should never be used against humans.
I was told the only ones capable
of firing a weapon of that caliber
are robots and no others.
What? If that's true,
it would be a huge scandal.
Yes, Article 13
of the International Robot Laws says,
"A robot shall not be able
to hurt or kill humans."
There are only a few robots in the world
that can fire such an armament.
And that armament is?
It's a special Zeronium alloy shell.
I see.
I know the robot you speak of.
Detective Gesicht.
A robot in whose development Europol
made their largest-ever investment.
He has solved many difficult cases.
During The 39th Central Asian War,
he served as a member
of the peacekeeping forces.
If he murdered your brother,
it's repulsive to even imagine it.
My brother,
he was a lowlife.
But still,
he didn't deserve
to be pulverized by a robot!
I couldn't agree more, Adolf.
Lend me your strength!
The strength to destroy this robot!
It's been a while.
I haven't worn this battle suit
since the war.
You kept it maintained?
I did what I could.
I had to be discreet, you see?
But taking a battle suit
without permission...
I owe you. I know I've asked a lot of you.
Well, we go back a long way.
But what are you going to do?
If they find out,
they'll revoke your license!
I don't mind.
What?
I'm retiring.
Hercules.
There's nothing
like a military battle suit!
The horsepower is way different
than in my pankration suit.
Yeah.
The left arm output feels a bit weak.
Okay, I'll work on it.
Two suns?
Hercules!
A police robot used a Zeronium shell
just the other day.
Care to comment, Spokesperson Wagner
of the Europol Information Office?
Yes, it was against an armored vehicle.
But if it happens to hit a human,
they'll be pulverized.
Any use of it requires permission
from headquarters,
and we make sure
that human lives are protected.
But there can always be mistakes!
Well, we make sure
human lives are absolutely--
Exactly how many robots
are capable of firing Zeronium shells?
It's like we humans walk the streets
under constant watch of an executioner.
The discussion is heating up,
but let's take a commercial break.
What do you think?
It's a TV program we've set up.
Our media strategy
is steadily making progress.
But it will take time.
There's no need to rush
as long as
we can stigmatize Gesicht in the end.
I've looked into his schedule.
He's going on a long vacation
in a few days' time.
We have to act now!
Please. No matter where he runs,
we will never stop denouncing him.
But...
If we rush, your brother's background
will come out as well.
To be honest, even I feel nauseous
hearing about the things he did.
If those facts are publicly revealed,
then society will turn against us, and you
can forget the anti-robot campaign.
You understand, don't you?
Hold on. Where are you going?
Hercules!
Are you okay?
This energy reaction...
Is it Photon Energy?
Epsilon!
That was a rough way to say hello
for our first meeting.
I apologize.
But I felt I needed to stop you.
Stop me?
It's still alive, isn't it?
The enemy that destroyed
Mont Blanc, North No.2, and Brando.
Don't forget you're a target too.
I know.
Then why stop me?
We must not fight.
A pacifist, are you?
Is that why you refused
to be deployed to that war?
That war did not have a righteous cause.
"A righteous cause"?
Even though so many robots were destroyed?
You're just scared.
And you're justifying it with excuses.
Yes, I am scared.
I heard you were forced
to do post-war cleanup
under terrible conditions because of that.
I was abused and heckled
by the entire world,
unlike you heroes.
But thanks to that,
I gained something valuable.
Something valuable?
I met many war orphans.
I took them in, and I'm raising them.
Yeah, I heard.
A robot raising human children.
Yet another reason to criticize you.
This valuable thing you mentioned.
Could it be love?
I'm sure you gained something
from the war, didn't you?
The ability to hate, perhaps?
Here is what I think.
Humans and robots are growing closer.
And if we get too close,
something bad will happen.
Here is what I think.
This is the first sign.
A sign?
We must break...
this cycle of hate.
This isn't an item
you can just find anywhere, pal.
It was used in the Central Asian War,
but you can't make or sell them anymore.
It's a compact cluster cannon.
A guided rocket launcher.
It locks onto its target and never misses.
It'll explode inside the body.
Even a robot will be blown to bits.
Whoa there. Be careful with that thing.
Possession is enough for civilians
to be charged with attempted murder.
I won't kill.
Not humans, at least.
When I was a child,
the use of robots
dramatically improved productivity.
At the same time,
because of the so-called
"robot restructure,"
many unemployed humans
ended up on the streets.
My father was one of the victims.
Dad, I'm hungry!
Let's grab something to eat.
Man, just another sandwich.
I want to eat some steak.
Get real, you idiot!
You think Dad found a decent job?
He's looking because he hasn't found one.
It'll be all right.
Don't you worry.
Dad, when is Mom coming back?
It's all right.
Don't you worry.
I wish we had a ball.
Here you go. It's a ball.
Huh? Wow, it's brand-new!
Where did you get it?
Don't worry about it. Go play.
Thank you, Dad!
There!
Hey!
He is the culprit.
He stole the ball from the store.
It wasn't me! I didn't do it!
He is the culprit.
I'm sorry, okay? Please let me go!
Damn it!
Forgive me!
Ah, damn it!
He came home a couple days later
and started to drink heavily.
Three months later,
he jumped from the roof of our building.
What's wrong?
Adolf, you wanted this, right?
Here you go.
Hey, this is a portable prep school!
What happened to your arm?
I had to off them.
"Off them"?
A robot.
They can't kill us humans,
but we're allowed to kill them.
Study hard, Adolf.
Study hard
and create a world without robots.
Toward the suburbs?
Did he notice me tailing him?
Maybe this is my chance.
What is he up to?
This is it!
Damn it!
You're Epsilon, I presume?
I'm sorry to have asked you
to come on such short notice.
It's fine. It's not something to discuss
over a simple data transfer.
You are the only one
with the authority to arrest our enemy.
The enemy died fighting Brando.
That's the official line
from Europol as well.
Do you really believe that?
We must stop Hercules.
We must prevent a duel,
a worst-case scenario.
That goes for you too.
No need to tell me that.
I am a police officer.
We must act, or another war will start.
War must never occur again.
No one should experience what the children
in my care went through.
Have you heard of what they're calling
Persian War Syndrome?
Yes.
Deep psychological damage
from the experiences of the war.
Many of the children in my care
suffer from severe symptoms.
Especially one in particular.
His entire village
disappeared in an instant.
He was the sole survivor.
Everything and everyone was simply gone.
An image is burned into his memory.
Something huge moving toward the desert.
Even today, he only speaks one word.
It's the word uttered
by the thing he saw that day.
Bora.
Atom!
What's wrong?
We gotta hurry, or we'll be late.
Hey, Atom, did you feel anything?
Feel what?
Like a small animal quivering in fear
because it can't find its way home?
Again?
I'm going to go find it!
What about school?
Think of an excuse for me!
She's nothing but trouble.
REDEVELOPMENT ZONE
NO TRESPASSING
Is it this way?
What on earth is this?
Such a terrible painting.
Hey.
Are you dead?
Were you the one crying?
You're a robot, aren't you?
I gotta report this!
Wait.
You'll be okay!
I'm gonna go get help.
Professor Ochanomizu can fix anything!
There's no need.
Yes, there is!
If we don't do something, you'll die!
Just leave me alone.
I can't!
You mustn't call any humans.
Then tell me what you need.
What kind of energy do you use?
SOL 208355.
I've never heard of that one.
ER 1059.
Not genuine though.
But it'll work as a substitute, eh?
Got it! I'll go get some!
Stay where you are, okay?
Are you okay?
It didn't agree with your body?
Thank you.
I feel better now.
That's good.
Mister, what's your name?
I don't know.
Where did you come from?
I don't remember anything.
All I remember is
running here as hard as I could, naked...
Running from something.
"Running from something"?
I don't know what, but it was very scary.
And there was a shack over there.
Must be a work shed
for the redevelopment project.
I stole these clothes from there.
That's why they don't fit you.
You're right.
You finally smiled! I'm Uran!
Uran.
Mister, did you paint that?
Yes, there was paint in the shed.
Are you an artist?
I don't know.
But I had the urge to make this.
I know!
This is called abstract painting.
Abstract painting.
Robots are capable of drawing
exactly what they see, right?
So it's rare to see a robot
paint a picture like this!
Or maybe you're just bad
at rough sketches.
Maybe.
I don't even know
what I was trying to depict.
Or why I was doing it.
I just don't know.
Mister!
Hello, Uran.
What are you doing?
Looking at these flowers.
Flowers?
Yesterday, there was only grass.
Oh, that reminds me. I got you more!
More energy catalyst!
And more paints!
Paints?
You need more colors, don't you?
Mister! I got you bigger clothes!
I've finished my painting.
Is this...
I finally figured out what it was.
A field of flowers?
Your rough sketch wasn't bad at all.
Actually,
it brings tears to my eyes.
Thank you.
Uran!
Good morning, Atom.
Don't you think it's too early
for a "good morning"?
- You think so?
- You're going again, aren't you?
I found a cat, and it's so cute.
An empty bottle of energy catalyst.
Is this what the cat is drinking?
I found it in your book bag.
You searched my book bag without asking?
Who went to bed right after asking me
for help with their homework?
It's a robot cat.
Then report it to the Ministry of Science.
No!
If it's broken, we should ask
Professor Ochanomizu to fix it.
What's the model number?
I don't know the model number.
It's not made in Japan?
Which country was it made in?
Anyhow, it's still scared!
It's finally starting to warm up to me.
I don't want it to run away again!
I'll introduce you to him
when I feel he's ready.
Please don't say anything
until then, okay?
Thank you! I'm off!
You'll never be popular with girls
if you keep peeking in ladies' bags!
Mister!
Where are you, Mister?
Oh no, did he really run away again?
Mister!
Mist-- Oh.
My goodness! The clothes I gave you
are so dirty already!
Hey, are you listening to me?
I've finally figured out
what I was born to do.
Huh?
Here, look.
Where did these flowers come from?
Watch this.
Wow, you made a dying flower bloom!
What is this power?
This is my... true power.
So that's why you painted this picture.
I'm not sure.
But there was a trace of this image
in my memory.
That's amazing!
You can breathe life into things!
Life. Do you think we will die eventually?
Die?
When you saved me, you said so.
That if we didn't do something,
I would die.
That would mean
your computerized brain being broken.
Professor Ochanomizu said
depending on how broken it is,
it may be impossible to restore.
Even if it's fixed,
you'd be a different robot.
Is that what dying is?
What does dying really mean?
This flower field represents life.
But there is another image.
A world of death.
"A world of death"?
Devoid of life.
What is this?
What is this giant monstrosity?
What is it?
I'm scared!
Mister! Mister, calm down!
You're okay.
I'm right here.
No need to be afraid.
It's okay.
Bora.
Huh?
Bora?
I've just arrived at Central Park,
Professor Abullah.
That was quicker than I thought.
You passed through customs
with no problem?
No problem.
I'm at the site
where the most recent tornado happened.
I know it's a lot to ask
since the park is so big.
It's no problem, sir,
because you gave me this body.
When you retrieve it,
be careful not to damage it.
He is another body I created, after all.
I'll repeat the model number
you are to retrieve.
SOL 2083553.
His name is Pluto.
I've located him, Professor Abullah.
Good.
I'm on my way.
Pluto.
I know you can do it, Mister!
Make the whole world like this painting!
"Like this painting."
Yes! You can fill the world with flowers!
That's why you were born.
"That's why I was born."
Exactly! You've got to remember.
You have the power
to turn the entire world into a garden!
That's not true.
Not true?
Not a garden.
Huh?
That's not it.
It's something much...
Yes?
Much bigger. Real nature...
A tornado.
It's raining.
Hey, look!
Flowers are blooming one after the other!
This is amazing!
Plants are growing so fast!
It's so beautiful!
Beautiful.
Uran!
Get away from him right now, Uran!
There's a strange
electromagnetic field around him!
Atom...
Uran, you have to come over here now!
You too, Professor Ochanomizu?
I've asked the staff
from the Ministry of Science to come!
I can't believe you, Atom!
You promised you wouldn't tell!
Now is not the time for that!
There's something dangerous
about that robot!
Squad A, in position!
- Squad B, in position!
- What?
The police too?
- Professor?
- Who told you to call the police?
I reported it per regulations.
Inspector Nakamura of the police!
Are you all right?
How could you?
How could you do this, Atom?
Atom.
You've got to get over here now, Uran!
Hatred.
System... overload...
Stop! Stop, or we'll shoot!
Mister...
I'm going to explode!
The surge
of rage...
Fire!
Wait!
So many robots...
Death...
They deserve to die.
How many did I...
kill?
Flowers in the desert...
A world of death.
Horns!
Mister!
I don't believe this!
What's the matter, Professor?
This can't be.
His computerized brain is missing!
What was that?
Oh, there it is!
That's my body!
What?
I'm a construction robot
working at this redevelopment site.
Huh?
I finished my 100-hour shift,
and when I was ready to go home,
I saw that my off-duty body was missing.
So, this is your body?
I've been looking for it.
I'm so glad I found it!
What on earth is going on?
A robot
without its artificial intelligence...
somehow activated on its own?
It's right over here.
Calling it "wandering anima"
makes it sound dignified,
but it is only a robot
without a computerized brain,
remotely controlled
through electromagnetic waves.
Are you satisfied now?
The time for your little stroll is over.
Come back.
This is your only body, Pluto.
And don't forget your orders
to kill Atom.
Subtitle translation by: Astrid Oliver