Hey there.
Yes, sir?
Why don't you quit standing there
and take a break?
No, not while I'm on duty, Professor.
Protecting you is of utmost importance.
Nothing is going to come after me.
Not on such a peaceful Sunday.
But if something
were to happen to you, Professor...
A few incidents involving
Bora Inquiry Commission members
do not warrant overreacting.
I don't see why anyone
would want to kill me.
More importantly,
I can't enjoy this rare day off
with you stuck to me like glue.
Please forgive me, sir.
Oh, no, never mind.
There's no need for you to apologize.
Do you have a name?
Yes! It is PPB49881327, sir!
I don't mean your registration number.
You have a name, don't you?
Yes. It's Yujiro, sir.
Yujiro. That's a name
that will bring you success.
Sir?
Perhaps you'll become
head of the criminal division.
It's not safe, Professor Ochanomizu!
This is...
A robot dog. Someone abandoned it.
Please step away.
It could be an explosive.
I'm sure it's fine.
It does not seem to be an explosive.
Looks like it's in pretty bad shape.
Let's take this little one
to my home, Yujiro.
Excuse me,
but what are you planning to do
with the robot dog?
Fix it, of course.
Fix it?
I'm the head
of the Ministry of Science, aren't I?
Hang in there. You'll be better soon.
The damage to your actuator
is pretty severe,
but your computerized brain circuits
are the issue.
This is Ochanomizu.
Oh, Professor.
I'm sorry to trouble you on your day off.
It's you again
from the Ministry of Defense.
I apologize for bothering you so often,
but the matter must be discussed
at next week's committee meeting.
To send more troops
to the Kingdom of Persia,
we desperately need your permission
to approve the increase.
No matter how many times you ask,
I will not change my mind!
But, sir--
There can be no more bloodshed,
whether it be human or robot!
But the United States of Thracia's request
is unchanged!
That doesn't matter!
A scientist does not create robots
to be used as weapons!
For crying out loud.
Don't you know when to give up?
What's the matter, Grandpa?
Oh, it's you, Takashi. It's been a while.
If you're busy, I can call back later.
No, it's fine. What did you need?
Well, there was a tornado
offshore earlier.
But now, I'm just playing with Bobby.
Are you two getting along?
You bet! You gave him to me two years ago.
I know there are newer models now,
but he's better than any of them!
He plays with me a lot!
Is that so?
What are you doing now, Grandpa?
I'm fixing a robot dog,
one that's much older than Bobby.
Older than him?
Are you sure you can fix it?
I sure can.
I know you can fix anything, Grandpa.
You can count on it.
Talk to you later, then.
Okay.
Now, then...
I'm looking for a KD-8083 booster
and an RSC-2969 router.
Those are quite outdated.
I've tried several other places, but...
Ah, looks like they're both discontinued.
Any stock at Nakamine Trading?
Unfortunately, no. They're too old.
I see.
The specs for these things
were overhauled four years ago.
What would you like to do?
No, it's okay. Thank you for your help.
I suppose it was us scientists
who changed the specs.
Let's see how much I can do on my own.
I'm sorry.
I was hoping to help you.
You really hung in there.
I know. Your owner
took really good care of you, didn't they?
That's why you lasted as long as you have.
You must have been loved.
Are you
still trying to play with me?
It's all right.
You've done enough.
Who could be here so early in the morning?
Um...
Oh, it's you, Yujiro.
Unfortunately, that robot dog...
A gentleman is here who says
he is the owner of the robot dog.
I'll check his ID
and do a full-body search.
No, there's no need. Show him in.
But, sir...
It's fine.
Thank you so much
for everything you've done.
I'm sorry that I wasn't able to help.
Not at all.
I was looking for him with his GPS,
but I never dreamed he would be seen
by the great Professor Ochanomizu.
Please have some tea.
Oh, no, that's not necessary.
You are a robot too?
Did it make you sad?
What?
When the dog, the robot dog died,
did it make you sad?
Were you sad during the war as well?
Who exactly are you?
Me?
My name is Goji.
Goji?
The one said to have created
the robot army for the Kingdom of Persia?
Your life is in my hands now.
Please summon Atom.
There's someone I want him to fight.
You think I'd summon Atom
because I fear for my life?
You will never force me
to make Atom fight like that!
- I'm not asking you to summon him here.
- What?
You must send Atom to the one location
in Japan where a tornado is occurring.
Hey, Mom!
Check this out.
It's the same location as your grandson.
There's no point in threatening me!
No matter what happens, I will never
let Atom do battle with another robot!
You claim to be Goji, yes?
Does that mean the genius scientist
of the Kingdom of Persia was a robot?
I don't know if I'm a genius or not.
At the very least, I can create
a robot that generates tornadoes.
Bobby?
And one that's extremely lethal.
Robots won't kill humans.
Why?
Because that's how we made them.
In accordance
with Article 13 of the Robot Laws,
we've developed a security system
with multiple layers.
To eliminate
even the most remote possibility.
Wonderful. Professor Ochanomizu,
you truly are a remarkable scientist.
You have developed
so many advanced robots.
And now robots are more human than ever.
What do you think happens
when robots are almost human?
Even then, robots will never kill humans!
What would be
the Japanese word for your attitude?
Seizensetsu, like innate goodness?
Or gizen, meaning hypocrisy?
Shall we test your hypothesis
right here and now?
Whether I will kill you.
Just who are you?
Dr. Goji...
The 39th Central Asian War
started because of rumors about you.
It was said that you built an advanced
robot army in the Kingdom of Persia,
along with robots that could be
weapons of mass destruction.
And who said that exactly?
The United States of Thracia.
Is everything that Thracia says correct?
That's why we formed
the inquiry commission.
And did you find anything?
No.
All we found
was a huge pile of discarded robots.
So despite not finding anything,
the Kingdom of Persia was burned to ashes.
Are you out for revenge?
You're seeking revenge against the former
members of the Bora Inquiry Commission?
Is that why you're trying to destroy Atom
and the other advanced robots
in the world?
See? You've admitted it yourself.
It's possible for robots
to seek revenge, right?
Oh, Grandpa.
Something's weird.
Is there a type of tornado
that doesn't move?
And Bobby's eyes haven't stopped glowing.
Now you have no choice but to call Atom.
You do as Bobby tells you, Takashi.
I'll call you later.
It seems they've come.
The police.
You destroyed Yujiro outside, didn't you?
Squad B, go around to the back!
The police are dispatched
when his transmission stops.
Squad C, get under the veranda!
Professor Ochanomizu,
were you stalling for time?
Squad A has secured the entrance.
Professor!
Oh, Atom!
Wait!
- Wai--
- Let him go, Atom!
Fire!
Go after him! Don't let him get away!
Professor, are you all right?
Never mind that. What are you doing here?
I caught the alarm signal
from Takashi's dog, Bobby.
So I contacted the police
and was told something was happening here.
I see.
Thank goodness.
That's why you came here.
What do you mean "thank goodness"?
It's nothing.
And what's going on with Bobby?
Damn it!
We've found him!
Cockroaches?
They carried something away.
Hey, look at this.
His computerized brain is missing.
Uran did what?
It was after she received
the warning from Bobby.
I tried to stop her,
but she flew off to Takashi's home.
Takashi! We have to go
to the basement now!
Grandpa told you too, didn't he?
Yes.
Okay, Bobby.
What's going on, Professor?
What's happening at Takashi's house?
Fatima!
Fatima! Open your eyes, Fatima!
Fatima.
Where are the kids?
Murat!
Lola!
Murat.
Murat!
Where's Pluto?
His transmission cut off.
So his system overloaded.
That's fine.
Everything's been taken over
by hatred.
Ouch.
Mom! Wake up! Mom?
You can't die, Mom!
What do I do, Bobby?
We gotta go to the basement!
Mom, are you okay? Mom!
Bobby?
Is anyone here?
I'm glad you're safe.
Where's Takashi and his mom?
It's all right now.
See, it's quiet now.
It's like we're in the eye of the storm.
Takashi is in the basement?
Bobby?
What is it?
Any word from the local police?
We can't get through to them.
The signal is too weak!
Please do not worry.
We'll do everything to protect your dau--
Contact Europol!
- Huh?
- I know who's responsible.
The one who's been targeting
the world's most advanced robots
and killing those people.
The real culprit is Goji!
Goji?
He's the man who built the robot army
for the Kingdom of Persia
in the 39th Central Asian War.
It's Dr. Goji.
The designated Europol agent
is Detective Gesicht.
Gesicht?
Patch me in
to Detective Gesicht right now!
I will speak with him directly.
Hurry. If we don't move quickly...
Atom is already on his way!
Uran!
Atom?
I'm headed your way.
Atom!
Your signal's too weak!
I'm almost there.
Atom.
Uran, what...
What was that?
You can have the whole body for 500 ZEUS.
Gesicht?
Atom!
What's wrong, Uran?
...n't come here...
No! You have to stay away!
Uran, I'm coming!
No.
Stay away!
Run, Uran!
Atom!
Take Bobby and get down to the basement!
- Okay, but what about--
- Go now!
What is that?
Atom, what is this?
Stand back, Uran!
Atom!
Atom.
Atom is
dead?
What's wrong, Gesicht?
You had another bad dream?
Yeah.
I'm okay, Helena.
Don't worry.
It's just...
it was different from the usual dream.
You should contact
Professor Hoffman in the morning.
Yeah, I'm sorry to make you worry.
Were you still awake?
Our trip starts tomorrow, you know?
There are a few drawings I need to finish
before we leave.
I see.
You're working hard.
Want me to stay with you for a bit?
Is something wrong?
No, it's nothing.
I'm okay now.
Damn it!
I can't stop shaking.
He's just a robot!
Damn it.
I've tailed him for a while.
There's no mistaking it.
Adolf is trying to kill Gesicht.
That's not good.
We can't let Gesicht die now.
It must be public opinion
that kills Gesicht.
You are correct, sir.
Dispose of Adolf.
I'm sorry, Professor Hoffman.
I know how busy you are.
No worries.
So tell me about the dream
from last night.
Right. It was different
from the usual one.
A new dream, huh?
What was it about?
Well, I'm kind of afraid to revisit it,
so I've placed it in my trash box
and haven't opened it.
I think it's best that you don't open it.
You think so?
There's a chance that it's a virus.
Plus...
Professor?
Oh, uh,
when unpleasant memories come up,
we humans also put them
in our emotional trash cans.
Don't pay too much attention to it.
May I ask you another question, Professor?
There is a human
who's constantly monitoring me.
Monitoring you?
When I'm traveling in my car
or when I'm at home.
Is it some kind of stalker?
I'm not sure.
I'm sure your line of work
will generate all sorts
of emotional reactions from others.
But I highly doubt that this stalker
would follow you to Japan.
You're leaving tonight, aren't you?
Yes.
Relax and enjoy your time.
If this person is still bothering you
after you return,
we'll talk some more.
Until next time.
I'm looking forward
to hearing all about your trip,
like about the science
and technology in Japan.
Director, that doesn’t answer my question!
Did you do something to him?
His artificial intelligence--
We made a huge investment
in Gesicht, you know!
All you need to do
is to maintain him properly.
That's all.
Today, for sure.
I've got to do it today.
Before he goes on his trip.
Change to Route 82.
To my brother's grave.
Brother,
give me strength.
Give this coward the push he needs.
What the...
...passengers, please proceed to gate 68.
How are you feeling?
What? Oh. I'm all better.
Really? That's a relief.
It's our first vacation in a long time.
Let's take it easy and relax.
Yes.
What's wrong?
I'm sorry. It's an emergency call.
Yes, this is Gesicht.
What, an explosion?
Breaking news.
WORLD-FAMOUS ROBOT ATOM IS DEAD
According to the UPB Network,
around 2:00 a.m.
Central European Time last night...
- And what kind of explosive was used?
- Dear...
Gesicht.
Um, excuse me for a moment.
- What's the matter?
- Look at the news.
...the world-famous robot, Atom,
was confirmed dead.
Atom is
dead?
...around 2:00 a.m.
Central European Time last night,
or 10:00 a.m. local time...
Dear?
Was it...
Was it him who did it?
Gesicht!
So he's still alive.
The dream last night!
Atom's time of death!
It wasn't a dream at all?
Unlock the trash box!
Dear...
Gesicht...
Atom!
You and Pluto are the same.
Are you the one who killed me?
You can have the whole body for 500 ZEUS.
Gesicht!
There's been an accident!
Someone call an ambulance!
Tobio.
Tobio!
You'll be fine.
Try and walk, Tobio.
Tobio walked!
He walked.
He walked, Gesicht.
The only ones here were children!
- It keeps crashing!
- Artificial neurons are firing!
- There's no virus!
- Scan his memory and prepare to reformat--
Are you all right, Gesicht?
Um, yes.
All functions are back to normal.
Just lie down and rest a little longer.
Gesicht, you collapsed at the airport--
No, I have to go.
Go where?
I'm getting an emergency call
from the station.
I'm so glad you're okay.
I'm sorry, Helena,
that our vacation turned out like this.
It's all right, dear.
I'll be back.
I know you must be worried.
Him going back to work
right after what happened.
No, I'm sure it's better for him
to go back to work
rather than going to Japan,
where Atom died.
I still can't believe that Atom is...
Let me ask you again, Mr. Haas.
You can't recall any reason why someone
might have a grudge against you?
Please stop asking
the same questions over and over!
But your car was blown up on purpose.
It was most definitely
an attempt on your life.
I'm telling you, I have no idea!
And the forensics report?
It was just as we had expected.
We found parts of an MZ-390
from the wreckage of his car.
A compact missile launcher that was
designated as an inhumane weapon.
What's his occupation?
He says he works in import and export.
Maybe an illegal arms dealer?
The bigger concern is who he's related to!
So tell us, Mr. Adolf Haas.
With all due respect, your brother was...
Don't you know
the Blomberg Civil Rights Law?
"Crimes committed by a suspect's relatives
cannot be used in questioning"!
That is illegal to ask me!
As ordered,
we will keep him under surveillance.
But, sir, Adolf Haas's brother was...
A weapon as severe
as the MZ-390 is mixed up in this case.
Do we have any other choice?
Yes, sir.
But at this rate...
Of all people, he's going to be...
The prosecutors are in the dark,
and so are the individuals involved.
There's no problem.
We are the only ones who know.
All right. That will be all for today.
He left for Japan already, damn it.
Received at 8:23 p.m.
You didn't come home
last night either, dear. Are you okay?
I know you're busy with work,
but at least give me a call.
Received at 12:13 p.m.
For reasons you will understand,
I won't be sharing my image.
Adolf, this is a warning.
You are in danger.
Your actions have become
a liability for the organization.
The leader wants you disposed of.
The leader?
He wants to dispose of me?
That bomb today...
Received at 3:45 p.m.
Adolf.
Leader!
I heard you were targeted.
This was right after the explosion.
How did he know?
It's not safe outside.
You should stay put there.
We are all in this together.
There could be another bomb right here!
I am Gesicht from Europol.
I've been assigned
as your personal protection.
Wow! And then what happened
to the bad guy?
Did you get him by shooting a rocket
out of your arm or something?
Dad!
Check this out, Dad! It's so cool.
He's a real super robot detective!
He's so nice too.
I've become a big fan!
Good morning.
Time to go.
Yes.
"A super robot detective"?
Give me a break.
Stop feeding my child stories, all right?
That was not my intention.
So how come
a world-class robot detective like you
was assigned to protect someone like me?
I'm only following orders.
Even if it meant giving up your trip?
How did you know that?
Your boss told me.
Mr. Haas,
do you hate robots?
I'm sorry that you ended up
being protected by a robot like me.
Let me check for any explosives here.
It's all clear. No abnormalities.
Right.
I've checked the entire office.
I'll be in the other room, so please
let me know if you need anything.
Brother.
If only I had the tools to destroy him!
He is so close!
Damn it!
I know that you cops think I'm suspicious.
Mr. Haas...
You think I did something sketchy
to deserve having my car blown up?
You keep saying you're here to protect,
but I know you're here to investigate!
Investigate me all you want.
You don't mind?
No.
But I want you out after you're done.
What do you handle
in your export-import business?
See for yourself.
You mainly handle
computer parts and systems.
You went to Persia
during the 39th Central Asian War.
So what?
Post-war reconstruction
provides opportunities.
Tens of thousands of businesses
took similar steps.
But not many companies can handle
Class A confidential projects like mine.
We are trusted
because of our steady track record.
TV, on.
The body of renowned robotics expert
Ronald Newton-Howard
was found at dawn on the fifth
in a Canberra, Australia suburb.
DR. NEWTON-HOWARD FOUND DEAD
Dr. Howard was known
for his discovery of Photon Energy...
Hey, listen, it's big news.
...murder weapons
were placed on his head like horns...
Hey, they said horns!
I received the report earlier.
Wasn't Dr. Howard the scholar
who made Epsilon?
Don't you have to go?
A scholar who made
one of your friends got murdered.
My mission is right here.
I wonder if Epsilon would even be sad.
I'm sure he would.
He would?
A robot?
Then why don't you go visit him?
Go and comfort him, robot to robot, huh?
My mission is right here.
No matter how you look at it,
it's the same killer as the other cases!
Weren't you the designated agent
on the case?
Ever since then,
there have been several copycat murders.
We don't have conclusive evidence
they were committed by the same person.
Let me show you something interesting.
They mentioned
the Bora Inquiry Commission on TV earlier.
You know of Kara-Tepa Prison, don't you?
Yes.
It's a prison in Persia
run by the United States of Thracia.
My company was contracted
to install all of its systems.
But there was a problem.
Someone tried to erase
surveillance footage
in solitary confinement,
so we were called in for maintenance.
Initially, we thought
it would be an easy fix,
but it turned out to be rather serious.
We ended up having to swap out
some of the hard disk drives.
This is one of them.
Are you not interested?
I am.
What is that? A human voice?
This should clean it up a bit.
Lanke. Tazaki.
Lanke. Tazaki. Howard.
This footage is...
What do you think?
He's repeating people's names, right?
Repeating the names
of the murder victims like a curse.
Perhaps I can enhance it
with my image stabilization function.
Didn't I tell you?
You shouldn't be hanging out here,
protecting me.
Mr. Haas,
you do know what type of place
Kara-Tepa Prison is, don't you?
It's where they keep war criminals, right?
Correct.
The most dangerous ones at that.
Good, it's clearer now.
Tazaki. Howard. Ochanomizu.
Isn't this...
Reinhardt. Lanke.
Mr. Haas! Why did you keep
such important information to yourself?
It's nothing but a video
of some crazy inmate!
How would I know?
- Don't you know who this is?
- Huh?
He's the supreme leader
of the former Kingdom of Persia,
Darius XIV!
He has aged
from the long incarceration, but...
Ochanomizu. Hoffman.
Hoffman?
Coming!
Professor Hoffman is in danger!
My lab!
You're Epsilon!
Professor Hoffman, you're being targeted.
We must get you far from here.
Aren't you supposed to be
a pacifist robot?
This sure is rough treatment.
My creator was murdered.
I'm on the verge of losing control.
So?
Did you get a hold of Professor Hoffman?
No. I'm not sure where he is yet.
I asked for an emergency deployment.
Then why don't you go yourself?
Didn't he help bring you into this world?
I'm more concerned
about the data you have.
There is a possibility
that Darius XIV is involved in this case.
I'll have you submit it
as a crucial piece of evidence.
But...
Could it not be connected
to the attempt on your life as well?
Am I wrong?
Get down!
A Photo-Thermal Smart Bomb.
I've seen that before.
During the Central Asian War,
they instantly vaporized people...
Where did it come from?
Help me! I'll tell you everything!
I'll talk! Just get me
into the witness protection program!
I'm a member
of an anti-robot organization!
That is who's been trying to kill me.
They think I'm a traitor.
An anti-robot organization.
Remember that robot judge
who was killed in an explosion in Berlin?
That was our organization.
What made you become their target?
I promise I'll testify.
So, please, get me
into the witness protection program!
If we don't hurry,
they'll kill my wife and my son!
Please calm down, Mr. Haas.
It seems you're telling the truth.
I'll make arrangements right away.
We'll take your family into protective
custody too. Please rest assured.
Anyhow, we must leave here right away.
Adolf Haas is being protected by Gesicht.
Ironic, isn't it?
But now, it's only a matter of time.
Surely, Adolf will reveal information
about our organization.
Use this.
What is it, sir?
It's the same model that Adolf had.
Death to machines and death to traitors.
The safe house is just ahead.
You'll be safe there.
What about my wife and Hans?
We've secured them.
They're on their way here.
And Professor Hoffman?
We have not been able to locate him yet.
This is no distance to fly
while carrying a living person.
Have some water, Professor.
Thank you.
I needed to bring him this far
for his protection.
You don't want to fight,
so you're leaving him with me, huh?
It's fine. Just what I needed, actually.
With this much bait in one spot,
the enemy will be lured into the open.
I'm not sure how much I can rely
on someone who keeps running away,
even after his creator has been murdered.
Professor Hoffman,
there's something I'd like to ask you.
It's about the secret conference you
and two other scientists had at Kimberley.
Kimberley.
Seven years ago,
you met Dr. Ronald Newton-Howard there.
Oh, yes.
I had always wanted to meet
the inventor of Photon Energy, Dr. Howard.
And there was another scientist
at the conference, correct?
Yes.
A Japanese scientist who invented
the ultimate computerized brain,
Dr. Tenma.
What was the purpose of this conference?
We wanted to share our research
with each other.
"Share"?
Our hope was to create a robot
that could help end wars
and save the planet.
Professor Hoffman,
the inventor of Zeronium,
Dr. Howard,
the discoverer of Photon Energy,
and Dr. Tenma, the leading authority
on computerized brains, gathered together.
What happened at the conference?
Dr. Newton-Howard and I
put all of our cards on the table.
Everything.
However...
However?
Dr. Tenma didn't disclose his research.
This is what he said.
A perfect computerized brain...
a perfect computerized brain will be
capable of suffering, hatred, and error.
Without revealing any of his research,
he understood all of ours in an instant.
He took it and ran?
It's not that simple!
Our research was not at the level
where he could just take it and run.
Yet, he understood it all in a glance.
We humans
call someone like him "a genius."
No, I suppose I should say
he was the one with the perfect brain.
As he was leaving,
he left us with these words.
Let this be a warning to you.
You should be careful.
Stop trying to make robots more human.
Something terrible will happen.
Though, it may already be too late.
Where is he now?
Where is Atom's creator, Dr. Tenma?
Patch me in, please.
Who should I connect you to?
To Dr. Tenma.
Dr. Tenma!
I've been put in charge as your successor
of the Ministry of Science.
My name is Ochanomizu.
It's regretful to see the creator
of the ultimate computerized brain
leave the Ministry of Science.
Computerized brains
are not something you create.
They grow.
Profound sorrow, frustration.
These are the things
that develop computerized brains.
To comply
with Article 13 of the Robot Laws,
robots are equipped with a control device
to suppress their emotions.
This hinders the growth
of their computerized brains.
But, Dr. Tenma, you created Atom,
an absolute masterpiece.
Atom?
A masterpiece?
Atom is...
a failure.
Tenma.
I was unable to find
the line you were looking for.
Dr. Tenma had withdrawn
from the main stage
and disappeared
into the underbelly of society.
When we set up
the conference at Kimberley,
all we could do was reach out to him
through the Internet,
knowing that he might not respond.
Looking back now,
I'm surprised that he even showed up.
Anyway, he's been missing ever since.
Do you think he came to warn you?
"Stop trying to make robots more human."
"Something terrible will happen."
Do you think he did it?
Do you think Dr. Tenma
actually built his ideal robot?
I think he did.
Detective Lieman, I've confirmed
that Professor Hoffman is safe.
Yes.
I just received word from Hercules.
I'm glad that he's safe.
Truly.
And how goes the analysis
of the video data from Mr. Haas?
Hey, let me hear it too!
There's no doubt about it.
It is footage of Darius XIV
at Kara-Tepa Prison.
And the words he keeps repeating
are the names of members
of the Bora Inquiry Commission.
Three of them have already been killed.
But we can't be sure if this is
an actual assassination order.
Did Darius XIV have a grudge against
the Bora Inquiry Commission members?
Yes.
After all, Persia was plunged into war
after the commission pulled out.
But they never found any robots
of mass destruction in Persia, did they?
They found nothing,
yet Persia was attacked?
That must be why Darius hates them.
I wouldn't say they found nothing.
This is classified information,
but included on a list of materials
that the commission found
is a special chip for creating
a highly advanced computerized brain.
Then again,
that does not prove they were
trying to develop a robot weapon.
What is the model of this chip?
Well, let's see.
It's called the Tenma chip.
The Tenma chip.
By the way, Mr. Haas.
Yes?
We're still investigating the anti-robot
organization that is targeting you,
but they may not be
the only ones who want you dead.
You were in possession
of such dangerous data, after all.
We'll ask about the details later.
For now, please head
to the safe house with Gesicht.
How are my wife and son?
They're in our protective custody,
so please rest assured.
I'm counting on you, Gesicht.
Understood.
What's wrong?
I feel nauseous.
Let's take a break.
Let me check if the bathroom's safe--
No sign of weapons.
Inside is just a general-purpose
cleaning robot with no computerized brain.
It's occupied.
I said it's occupied!
What the hell?
Just a cleaning robot.
Message for you.
Huh?
If you want to save your family,
kill Gesicht.
I repeat. If you want to save your family,
Mr. Haas!
You have to stop, Mr. Haas!
I said stop!
There it is.
You've finally shown your true colors.
Did you have the same look
in your eyes back then?
Back then?
Is that how you looked when you did it?
What do you mean?
You're the one
who killed my brother!
He is not a failure!
Atom is a masterpiece,
the pinnacle of human technology!
Professor Ochanomizu.
You don't understand a thing
about computerized brains.
Frustration, intense hatred.
Seething hatred
that could lead one to murder.
These help computerized brains grow.
You're wrong.
Dr. Tenma, you are mistaken!
A brain that is capable of error.
That's what it means to be perfect.
And that is what will give birth to...
the Greatest Robot on Earth.
Subtitle translation by: Astrid Oliver