Stop!
I...
Can't you see I'm badly wounded?
Still playing innocent?
You murdered my brother!
"Super robot detective," my ass!
You're nothing but a murderous machine!
You call this a safe house?
It's just a log cabin!
How can I protect myself
in a place like this?
The inside is equipped
with a state-of-the-art security system.
Hey! Where are you going?
I'll be back in an hour.
Get inside and don't leave,
no matter what.
Your wife and son should be here soon.
Hey, wait! You're abandoning your post?
Your mission is to protect--
If you want to save your family,
kill Gesicht.
Under the larch tree 200 steps north
of the safe house,
there will be a weapon.
Dad!
Hans.
Where's Gesicht?
Don't mention his name.
Dear.
What's going on?
I'm sorry to have worried you, Ilsa.
Why must we go through all this?
What in the world did you do?
You're back, huh?
He said you might be coming...
Ah, there you are.
So you finally remembered.
How does it feel?
Wow!
The basement is like a fallout shelter!
And there's a gym too!
Is that the whole truth?
Yes.
Unbelievable.
To think you would go after Gesicht...
I was hoping you'd understand.
Well, I don't!
Gesicht may have killed a human,
but we're talking about your brother!
A goal! Hans is the champion!
I'm sorry for what I'm about to say,
but your brother deserved to die.
He committed countless crimes,
and it's not just about the number.
It sends chills down my spine.
Just thinking about it makes me nauseous.
Yes, he was a sick man.
But even so, he didn't deserve
to be killed by a robot.
You don't know that it was intentional.
Robots can malfunction.
No. It was his duty.
Gesicht was faithfully following orders.
He didn't do it
out of any particular emotion.
Gesicht
didn't kill your brother out of hatred.
You killed him out of hatred.
I knew it from the first moment I saw you.
You and I are the same.
Try as they might,
that memory will never be scrubbed away.
The scar from that gaping wound
will always be there.
Stop!
I was wrong!
I...
Please spare me! Don't do it!
Try and scratch that itch.
Then you'll remember even more clearly
how true hatred feels.
I must return to my post.
In the red corner, the WPKKR champion,
the god of battle, Hercules!
Hercules!
His opponent this time will be formidable.
But that doesn't matter.
The strong prevail
until someone stronger defeats them.
That's all there is to it.
The sea is getting rough.
Listen, Gesicht
is investigating this case.
Don't do anything reckless.
Work together to find a solution.
Yes. We will.
It's coming.
You sense it too?
Yes. Abnormal electromagnetic waves.
Shall I help you?
You are not equipped to help me here.
True. I am not wired that way.
And I am wired precisely for the task.
I'm a machine made for battle.
Leave quickly.
A robot with no combat functions
will only slow me down.
You're looking down on me again,
just as you did
when I refused to fight in the war.
Maybe you were right.
Maybe you were right in refusing to fight.
I am built to fight.
But that war was no fight.
Back then,
there was a robot who fought alongside me.
As an airborne brigade elite,
he helped lead us to success
on many missions through his actions.
The last time I saw him,
he kept washing his hands.
Over and over again.
Despite being a robot,
he kept washing his hands.
Hey, what are you doing?
It won't come off.
What won't?
The enemy coming our way is a ghost.
A ghost?
What I'm about to fight
are the ghosts of those who fell.
Go.
You bear no guilt.
You have no reason to be killed.
But Atom was killed.
He bore no guilt either,
so why was he killed?
You know something.
No, you learned something in that war.
Just go.
I'll be standing by at 3,000 meters.
Suit yourself. You can collect the data
from my fight up there.
I fight better when there's an audience,
even an audience of one.
After all, I'm Hercules,
the god of battle.
Brando...
We fought many battles
that will go down in history.
They all ended in no contest.
I wish we could have settled it, Brando.
We may not have been able
to settle our score,
but I will settle it with this thing!
However, this isn't a game.
It's a fight to the death!
They say the world
is made up of winners and losers,
wise men and fools,
the living and the dead.
But everyone is a loser, a fool, and dead.
Everyone except for me.
You won't fool me
with childish tricks like that!
Die!
I hereby declare
the 99th military tribunal in session.
The defendant is to be sworn in.
I order you to take the oath immediately,
defendant Darius XIV.
Oath?
God has no faith in the oaths of men.
You have repeated the same response
99 times now.
Take the oath immediately.
Humans lie.
God does not believe them.
The defendant is out of order!
In the eyes of God,
humanity is a failed creation.
Humanity is in need of replacement.
A new species.
Robots are that species!
Enough nonsense!
Court is adjourned!
Remove the defendant from the courtroom!
He's responsible!
A new species?
You're the one who slaughtered them!
You're full of contradictions!
- Order in the court!
- That's right!
There are no contradictions.
That was no slaughter.
It was an evolutionary stage.
Hold Darius in contempt of court!
Darius must be sentenced!
Death to Darius!
I'm from a human rights organization.
If there's anything we can do to help you...
Bring me crayons.
Hercules...
These parts are his...
No, some belong to the enemy!
Did they destroy each other?
That's the body Hercules uses
for daily life.
What is going on?
The parts are scattered all over the sea--
The abnormal electromagnetic waves are--
That's...
If I can break off this horn,
then surely you will...
If I help him now,
we can defeat the enemy!
Hey, what are you doing?
It won't come off.
What won't?
What are these images?
I can't move my body!
So that's
who you are!
It's way past lights out.
What are you doing?
When the flood returns,
the ones who board the ark,
the ones chosen by God...
Hey!
Humans or robots, which will it be?
Open up.
The only one who will survive...
What the...
...is Pluto.
Hercules!
Where
am I?
I'm
running away.
From what?
Hercules is dead.
I must let him know.
I must!
Only he has the authority
to arrest the enemy.
Gesicht.
Gesicht?
The channel's been cut off!
Gesicht!
Gesicht, please respond!
Did you have the same look
in your eyes back then?
You're the one who killed my brother!
Right this way, please.
Could you confirm that this is your child?
Gesicht, I can take it from here.
Check the other room.
There's no mistake. This is our child.
Humans cry like that
in these situations, don't they?
I understand somewhat.
Yes.
We applied as soon as
the Robot Adoption System was launched.
It took four years
until this child came to us.
There were many couples
on the waiting list, you know?
I was so happy
when I met this child for the first time.
Yes.
We're finally living in an age
when robots can have families.
We thought we could live as a family.
I'm Gesicht. I'll be joining
the investigation from today on.
Nice to meet you.
Is it a good idea
to have a robot on this case?
I'm just following orders.
Robot children were kidnapped
and torn to pieces.
The crimes may have been committed
by someone with anti-robot beliefs.
Your involvement could be considered
a conflict of interest.
Yes, and that's why I will
only investigate other possibilities.
What about the surveillance?
Like the others, the kidnapping took place
after the B-Com Eye 3 was destroyed.
In all, there have been
23 kidnapping cases like this one.
Every time, the perpetrator kidnapped
the kid after destroying the system.
There are 304 places
where B-Com Eye 3 systems were installed.
All known robot haters, radicals,
and ex-convicts in the area
were recorded elsewhere
at the time of the crime.
Which means all of our suspects
have an alibi.
What is the meaning of this?
Why did you tell the media
that I joined the investigation?
It's a diversionary tactic.
We'll show the public
how committed we are to solving the case.
More importantly,
your involvement might prevent
the next crime from happening.
We've narrowed the list of robot haters
to those not seen on surveillance
in the Euro Federation
at the time of the crime.
There are seven of them.
They're all under surveillance right now.
What is the failure rate
of B-Com Eye 3 systems?
Huh?
Can you compare the failure rates
before and after the incidents?
Oh, the manufacturer has that data.
The system itself is top-notch,
but it is prone to failures.
The failure rate over the last three years
is 3.26%.
And after the incidents...
Huh?
It's 3.25%.
Though the crimes were committed
after the suspect destroyed the system,
the failure rate isn't affected.
We have a report
of a kidnapping in Ward W-25!
The victim is a robot child!
Gesicht, head to the scene.
Yes, sir.
Helena? Sorry.
I'm responding to an emergency.
What?
What's wrong?
Hey, where are you going?
- Henry!
- I'm coming!
Find the causes
of the B-Com Eye 3 failures.
What?
I can't access the data in this case.
I need your help.
But if we don't hurry to the scene--
Just do it now!
Gesicht?
You don't sound like yourself.
These are the causes of all failures
occurring in the last three months.
Three outages due to lightning strikes
and 38 problems with control chips.
Can you compare that
to data from the last three years?
Okay.
The ratio is pretty much the same.
The perpetrator
didn't destroy the systems.
What?
But it's possible to emit electromagnetic
waves that are identical to lightning...
There is one case where the system
was clearly destroyed by human means.
It happened yesterday?
But there were no kidnappings yesterday.
Show the list of maintenance contractors.
Bring up the maintenance contractors
in the kidnappings' vicinity!
It didn't start with the system's failure.
It started with its repair!
There's only one person responsible
for repairing the system
at the kidnapping site!
Hey, Gesicht?
Gesicht! Do you copy, Gesicht?
Gesicht isn't responding!
It's no use.
The comm channel has been shut off.
Respond, Gesicht!
This is insubordination! Gesicht!
Stop!
Please don't!
Don't shoot me!
No, I can't.
I can't run away from this.
Damn it!
There will be a weapon.
Where the hell is this so-called weapon?
Mr. Haas!
Oh, I'm Meyer from Europol.
What are you doing there?
You want me to go back
to the safe house, right? I know.
No, that's not it.
You stopped at a rest area by the forest
before you got here, didn't you?
What about it?
There was a suspicious man
on the security camera footage from there.
We looked into him,
and it seems he's a member
of the organization that's after you.
They know your movements.
We must transfer you
to another location now.
Oh, I see.
Inspector Meyer!
Gesicht is back.
Hey, Gesicht!
You're not to leave your post
without permission!
I'm sorry, sir.
It's unthinkable for a robot
to do something like this.
I'll have to file a report later.
But for now, Mr. Haas's protection--
I heard the situation.
I will move him right away.
Let's go, Mr. Haas.
Abandoning your mission, huh?
Just like back then.
What you did to my brother
was not your mission.
My mission right now is to protect you.
Say, which direction
are the bad guys coming from?
Stop talking nonsense and sit down!
But we'll be okay
no matter where they come from, right?
Because Gesicht is here!
The other inspector's car behind us
is guarding the rear.
You don't need to worry, Hans.
What will you do if the bad guys show up?
- Does your arm transform into a gun?
- Hans!
But I learned in school
that robots can't shoot people.
How are you going to do them in?
He'll shoot them if it comes to that.
Right?
That's enough, dear.
What is it?
The car behind us...
Wait, I don't see the inspector's car!
I've lost communication.
They're coming!
Someone's after us?
I'm going to speed up.
Fasten your seat belts!
They're speeding up--
The police car disappeared in an instant.
The weapon they're using could be...
A compact cluster cannon.
Most likely,
it's the same model I had acquired
since it's strong enough to kill you.
Help us, please!
At least my wife and my son.
Please.
The robot at the rest area told me
that if I wanted to save my family,
I'd have to
kill you.
But from the start,
they were planning
to dispose of all of us,
so I couldn't expose the truth
about the anti-robot cult.
I hate you.
You killed my brother.
That's why
I tried to kill you.
This hatred,
you know it too, even if you are a robot.
Without hatred,
you could never kill someone like that.
But that's between you,
me, and my brother!
My family has nothing to do with this!
Please...
Please save my wife and my son!
Mr. Haas, grab the lever to your right.
- What?
- Grab the lever to your right!
Hans! Mrs. Haas!
Hans! Ilsa!
Hans!
Ilsa!
A regular gun is enough for you.
But the leader told me
to make this all look like
it was your doing,
and that you died in the explosion
from the cluster cannon.
No hard feelings.
Drop your weapon!
Ah, the robot detective.
Aren't you forbidden
from firing your right arm?
I'm a human, you see?
You're not allowed to kill humans, right?
Come any closer,
and I'll fire this bad boy.
Mr. Haas, walk toward me slowly.
Step slowly behind me.
Suits me just fine.
This cluster cannon can easily blast
the two of you into pieces,
even if you're made of Zeronium.
Two birds with one stone.
Get behind me!
My left arm shoots sleeping gas.
You can surrender quietly,
and I'll read you your rights,
or you can be knocked out by the gas.
Which will it be?
Say it.
Gesicht.
My brother was the worst of the worst.
And yet,
you used your own body to shield me,
the man who tried to kill you.
It was my duty.
Gesicht...
Mr. Haas, there's something
I want to ask you.
Does the hatred you humans feel
ever disappear?
Or does it never go away,
no matter how many times
you try to erase it?
What I was most afraid of...
is myself,
now that I've learned how to hate.
She's been keeping to herself
on the schoolyard these days.
She used to be so cheerful,
but she doesn't talk much anymore,
not since the incident.
I guess it proves
how advanced she is as a robot.
Who knew a robot could go through
a personality change...
Of course she could!
Robots feel sorrow and shed tears,
just like humans do.
Principal...
There are no high or low specs
when it comes to the heart.
You're right, sir.
Even an old robot model like me
feels sorrow.
Mr. Sakamoto...
But the question is,
what can we do as educators
in a situation like this?
How can we save her from her sorrow?
Uran, you aren't the only one
who grieves Atom's loss.
I feel something.
Something out there
is feeling sadder than I am.
Was it you who was feeling so sad?
Where's your mommy?
No.
It's coming from over there.
Is it you?
Are you the one who is feeling sad?
Leave me alone.
There's an electromagnetic net below,
so there's no use jumping.
Then...
then what am I supposed to do?
I get bullied day in and day out.
They threaten me for money!
They call me dirty and stinky!
What am I supposed to do?
I'd be better off dead.
I don't understand.
Huh?
I don't understand what it feels like
to want to die
because I'm a robot.
How could a robot possibly understand?
I'm not programmed that way.
Just leave me alone already.
And that's why my brother
had no feeling of wanting to die.
Yet, he was killed.
Right now, I'm really sad.
If I were human,
would I want to die like you?
This kitten was sad too,
but it didn't want to die.
All it thinks about is how it wants milk
and how hungry it is.
Was that cat abandoned?
It's pretty cute.
But we've got to feed it soon.
It's shaking.
Can you get some milk for the cat?
What?
There's someone even sadder over there!
Hey!
Is this what you're looking for?
Oh!
Yes, this is my wallet.
I put my pension card in here
so I could buy a gift for my grandchild.
Thank you.
I'm truly grate...
It's here.
I can sense
such immense sadness from here.
This is the spot.
The person I sensed was just here.
Incredible sadness...
As if they experienced
the same person dying twice.
"Tobio... Tenma."
Oh, Minister Ochanomizu.
The Chief Cabinet Secretary
called many times...
Let them wait.
But, sir...
Tell them I have no interest
in discussing a state funeral for Atom.
I'm not giving up yet.
More importantly,
have you heard back from him yet?
"Him"?
I told you! The former minis--
You can't enter without permission!
Please make an appointment.
Otherwise, the security system
cannot verify you.
There will be no problem with security.
But, like I said...
I am the former head
of the Ministry of Science.
- What?
- Dr. Tenma!
You came! I've been waiting for you!
I knew you'd come.
You're the only one
who can save Atom in his current state.
Only you, the one who brought Atom
into the world.
It's impossible. He can't be saved.
I've come to say goodbye.
Atom is dead.
Tobio is
dead.
Tobio, what did you do today?
Today?
Today, I studied in the morning
and cleaned up my room in the afternoon.
I found an insect encyclopedia
at the back of my bookcase.
It was so interesting
that I forgot all about cleaning.
There's a pretty butterfly
called a zephyrus.
I'd love to see one in real life.
Tobio.
Do you think this dish is tasty?
Yes, it's really tasty!
I see.
Minister! Minister Ochanomizu!
It's Dr. Tenma!
He's repairing Atom!
He's trying to revive him!
It's incredible.
I've never seen anything like it!
He's connected RS-889 while simultaneously
controlling the motherboard!
And he's randomly replacing motion data.
Outputting data to H2K-4380.
Releasing shield on Troy 647K.
Updating TNT module.
BQ lines on auto control.
Are we witnessing
the technique of a true genius?
You said you came to say goodbye.
I knew you would do this.
Dr. Tenma...
After working nonstop for 18 hours,
you should get some rest.
I'll leave your tea here.
So, what do you think about
Atom's prognosis?
The head of the Ministry of Science,
Professor Ochanomizu,
poured everything he had into him.
Your operations were brilliant.
Spare me the jokes.
No abnormalities
in his artificial hippocampus
nor his artificial right and left brains.
The receptor adjustment,
synaptic cleft, everything checks out.
Your repair work was perfect.
Then why won't Atom wake up?
Why did Atom have to meet such a fate?
This case involves the destruction
of all the world's most advanced robots.
You know this, yes?
And the former members of the Bora Inquiry
Commission are being killed one by one.
Dr. Tenma,
do you know of a person named Goji?
I do not.
That can't be true!
I'm talking about Dr. Goji, who built
the robot army of the Kingdom of Persia!
The robot army that was only possible
because the AI you developed
was leaked to them. Am I wrong?
I have no idea.
My artificial intelligence
shouldn't be wasted
on the likes of a robot army.
A robot with my artificial intelligence
would be more noble and more complete.
Wanna know something?
I once created a perfect robot.
It was commissioned
by a certain individual.
I told them it would be extremely costly,
but they insisted.
The artificial intelligence of the world's
most advanced robots, including Atom.
Their programming is extremely complex,
but there are limitations.
So, what do you think I did?
I analyzed and programmed
9.9 billion personalities,
the same number as the world's population.
In other words,
I put every single option and possibility
into that artificial intelligence.
A brilliant idea, no?
Such a robot
could potentially become anything.
A grump, a coward,
a crybaby, a hard worker,
a scholar, a hero, or a genius?
Perhaps a murderer?
What do you think happened to that robot?
It never woke up.
No, I should probably say
that it refused to wake up.
It was too complicated.
It would take an eternity
to simulate 9.9 billion personalities.
But I knew how to wake it up.
All I had to do was to steer the chaos
of the 9.9 billion in one direction.
How?
By destroying the balance.
Anger, sorrow, hatred...
By infusing unbalanced emotions.
Unbalanced emotions?
Yes. Imbalance is the program
that simplifies chaos.
But if you did something like that...
Where is that robot now?
Who knows.
The owner must have it hidden away,
still asleep.
Don't tell me...
Are you saying that Atom is
in the same state right now, Dr. Tenma?
That he has sensed something inconceivable
and is simulating the response endlessly?
Atom won't wake up for the same reason
your perfect robot didn't wake up?
Are you suggesting
that we infuse Atom
with unbalanced emotions to wake him?
If we did that,
Atom could be reborn
as something horribly different!
Yes.
He might come back a monster.
I see.
You think it's tasty?
Yes!
Tobio.
Yes, Dad?
The real Tobio died in a traffic accident.
But I'm here now.
Tobio was terrible at cleaning,
and his room was always a mess.
Okay, from tomorrow,
I won't clean as much--
Tobio hated studying.
Then I won't study--
Tobio stuffed
the encyclopedia I bought him
in the back of the bookshelf
without looking at it.
Tobio
hated this dish.
Do you like me?
Yes, I love you, Dad.
I was so hard on Tobio,
scolding him all the time.
Because of that, I'm sure that Tobio...
hated me.
Gesicht?
Do you read me?
Gesicht!
Hoffman here. Please respond, Gesicht!
You're still in the middle of an overhaul.
It's too dangerous
for you to return to work!
There is still shrapnel
from the cluster cannon in your body!
Gesicht?
Please respond, Gesicht!
Gesicht, this is Epsilon.
It's urgent. I need to--
...right away--
I have an appointment.
I am Gesicht from Europol.
Verified. Please enter.
Please wait in B-325.
Welcome.
I'm Colonel Armstrong
of the United States of Thracia Army.
Gesicht of Europol.
Our nation did not join
the International Criminal Law Treaty.
Your request has been granted
by a special directive from the president.
Time is limited, so I ask that you
complete your business here quickly.
- Begin.
- Yes, sir.
Begin right here?
Yes. Is there a problem?
Well, no...
What are you doing? Hurry it up.
Yes, sir.
This is
a state-of-the-art prison facility,
but as you can see,
our robots are outdated.
Our country is
on the cutting edge of technology,
but as you may know,
we're far behind in the robot industry.
If we had excellent robots like you,
the restoration of Persia
could have gone faster.
But from a human rights perspective,
we do not produce
robots of mass destruction.
The link is up.
Make it short, please.
You really expect me
to interview him like this?
Yes. Is there a problem?
You're Darius XIV, correct?
Correct.
I'm Gesicht from Europol.
I'd like to ask you some questions.
How is life in this prison?
Not bad.
Let's stop with the farce.
- This isn't a real interview.
- Huh?
There are many layers of security,
so you can censor any comments
you find inconvenient.
What are you talking about?
Stop playing games!
He is an extremely important witness!
I will meet him in person.
Hey, you!
Wait!
The president granted you
a special interview,
but your actions
clearly violate international law--
- Halt!
I don't care about any relationship
between you and Europol.
None of that matters!
Right now, the whole world is in danger!
So you're a robot.
How extremely well-made.
You look just like a human.
I hope you're not as stupid
as humans though.
Are you the mastermind
behind the recent serial destruction
of advanced robots?
I spoke too soon. Stupid indeed.
Did you order the assassinations
of the Bora Inquiry Commission members?
They are all liars.
They reduced my country
to a barren desert.
They needed us to remain have-nots.
They took everything from us,
including our glorious robot civilization.
Because of their damn machines
and filthy artificial intelligence,
my country was turned to ashes.
Out of that resentment,
you created a robot of mass destruction.
You created a monster.
I created a monster?
We didn't create it. It was born.
He's the most capable and untarnished
of robots. One beloved by God.
"Untarnished"? "Beloved by God"?
A robot that repeatedly
kills and destroys?
You're wrong. He was reborn.
Reborn?
With a stronger, more powerful body.
A body that was more suited
to the robotic hatred
that had spawned inside his AI.
Robotic hatred.
This field of flowers.
This is Pluto.
Pluto.
Who is he?
Who is Pluto? Tell me what he is!
I'm sure you already know.
What?
He bit through his tongue!
I need help!
What the hell?
What have you done?
Call a medic!
Get him out of here!
"I'm sure you already know"?
What? Darius XIV attempted suicide?
Yes. But they managed to save his life.
You're going to get us in hot water again.
I'm sorry, sir.
I'm ready to take responsibility.
In any case, return immediately!
Epsilon.
I couldn't reach you, so I looked up
your location and flew here.
Hercules left this behind.
But that's not all he left.
I'd like to show you something.
Huh?
A great deal
of electromagnetic waves were emitted
while Hercules was fighting.
My analysis shows that most of them
fall into the genre of hatred.
But there was a flash
of something entirely different.
This is it.
I'll transfer it to you now.
What is this image?
This couldn't possibly be.
Pluto?
Subtitle translation by: Astrid Oliver