Hey, mister!
Have a look,
and I'll give you a good price!
Believe it or not, these rugs
were woven by humans, not robots!
Hey, mister!
These are electronic parts
found on the battlefield!
They're still usable!
Gesicht, that's enough. Come back!
We'll handle all matters
related to Darius XIV's attempted suicide.
The United States of Thracia
is too self-righteous.
We'll confront them head-on.
I'm fed up with that president's methods.
Either way, we're concerned about
your physical condition.
Professor Hoffman is worried
that your Zeronium's strength
might have been compromised
by the cannon blast.
Thank you for your concern,
but I'm about to make a break in the case.
What? Are you sure?
So you have an idea
of who's behind all this?
Yes, I think it is
what you humans would call "a hunch."
"A hunch"? How can a robot have a...
Huh? Hey, Gesicht. Gesicht!
Are you all right?
Can you stand? Here, grab onto me.
Thank you, mister.
Ever since I got damaged in the war,
my balance has been off.
I see. Take care of yourself.
Mister, please buy some flowers!
Oh, I'm sorry, but I'm in a hurry.
I take credit cards, you know.
Here's my reader.
I'm only passing through here.
I'll be leaving soon,
so I have no use for flowers. Bye now.
Mister!
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
No, you're actually right on time.
I am Gesicht of Europol.
I'm Abullah, head of the Republic
of Persia's Ministry of Science.
Something the matter?
No.
Oh, I'll have coffee.
You can relax around me. I'm a scientist.
They also have energy drinks here.
I'm fine, sir.
The look on your face tells me
you're wondering if I'd prefer
an energy drink myself.
Your identification system
didn't malfunction.
I lost most of my body in the last war.
Please excuse my rudeness.
Not at all.
Thank you for coming all the way here.
I wanted you to see it.
I wanted you to see how this country
is starting to rise from the ashes of war.
The nation had been reduced to rubble,
but now the bazaars are reopening.
A friend of yours?
No.
I met him earlier.
It is those children I feel pity for.
Our economy is starting to recover,
but the kids
in the margin of society still suffer.
What we must do now
is provide them with a better life.
I'm sure you understand.
I do.
So, what is it that you wanted to ask me?
Yes, I'll get right to the point
since we don't have much time.
What was your relationship
with Darius XIV?
We got along fine.
To his loyal subjects, he was a kind man.
He often talked about turning this desert
into a country of green fields.
Do you mean "fields of flowers"?
Yes.
Do you know a person named Goji?
Can't say that I do.
There's no way the head
of the Ministry of Science doesn't know.
I've heard that it was a genius scientist
named Goji who enabled you to build
such an advanced robot army
during Darius's reign.
Only a rumor, no?
That name does show up in the report
by the Bora Inquiry Commission,
but his existence was never confirmed,
as evidenced by the fact
that I don't know such a person.
And what about the Tenma model AI
that was imported here?
Tenma model.
Since we're discussing rumors,
let me tell you a story that I've heard.
Dr. Tenma and this genius scientist
you mentioned
managed to create
the ultimate artificial intelligence.
The ultimate artificial intelligence.
Yes.
However, said artificial intelligence
was so advanced, the robot didn't wake up.
Rumors say the robot is still sleeping
somewhere in Darius's former palace.
Why don't you look for
this marionette yourself?
Oh dear.
I'm afraid our time is up.
Please forgive me.
Thank you for your time
from your busy schedule.
One last question.
Please take a look at this image.
Have you ever seen this man before?
Can't say that I have.
Thank you.
I appreciate your cooperation.
I hope you solve the case soon.
I apologize for my confusion
about whether you were a human or a robot.
No, it's quite all right.
I've experienced it once before
when I met Atom.
I see.
So Atom was that advanced of a robot.
Yes.
But just now, my system
finally identified you as a human.
Because you lied.
You said you've never seen
the man in the field of flowers.
My system determined that to be a lie.
And robots can't lie.
Mister! Please buy some flowers!
You're still here?
Just one is fine. Please?
If you stick too long
to customers like me,
your boss will get mad.
Hey, mister.
How about a good luck charm?
Keep this on you, and it will help you
find the answers to life's problems.
This is a charm of Goji,
the sage of the sands.
Goji?
Yes. God gave life to the sand.
He's a legendary sage
who turned back to sand
after showing the truth of life
to the king of the ancient Uzbek.
The sage of the sands,
Goji...
Artificial intelligence was so advanced,
the robot didn't wake up.
Just one is fine. Please?
Okay, then. Just one.
Thank you!
What is your name?
Muhammad Ali.
That's a great name.
Do you think I can be great like my name?
Of course you can.
I want to be a scholar!
You can be if you study a lot.
Do you think I can be like Sahad?
Sahad?
Yes. You showed a photo of him earlier.
You mean this man?
Yes! He studied abroad in the Netherlands
so he could turn this land
into a field of flowers.
He's my hero.
You think I can be like Sahad?
What's wrong?
Oh, it's nothing.
Sure, you can.
Never lose hope.
Hope?
Yes, hope.
Mister!
Will I see you again?
Yes. I'm sure we'll meet again.
Yes, of course! I know Sahad very well.
He used to be one of my lodgers.
There, that room on the third floor.
See those beautiful flowers
on the windowsills?
Sahad planted all of them.
They're beautiful.
Oh, so even a robot like you can tell.
Sahad was studying botany, right?
Even after so many years,
the flowers he planted
are still going strong.
One time,
I asked him if there were any flowers that
bloomed year-round and never withered.
Those would be easy
to take care of, right?
And what did he say?
He said that after producing seeds,
flowers ought to wither away.
He's right, I suppose.
Flowers ought to wither away, huh?
Ma'am, do you happen to have
a photo of him?
I'm sure I have one somewhere,
but all my old data is on my old computer.
It must be in storage. I'll take a look.
Come by again later.
Thank you.
But if someone from Europol
is asking about him,
should I be concerned about Sahad?
No, ma'am.
Of course not. Someone like him
would never get into trouble.
I mean, Sahad was a truly nice person.
So much so, you'd never be able to tell
he was a robot.
He was an excellent student.
No, excellent isn't the right word.
Passionate.
Yes, almost as if his life depended on it.
Depended on it?
Yes, because Sahad
loved his country above all else.
He was devoted to filling
the Persian desert with flowers.
His research was truly innovative.
One day, he said to me,
"Professor, look how strong
Igor has become."
Igor?
Or another time,
he'd say how Janus is getting sick.
Or how Ishtar is getting better.
They are the names of his tulips.
He named all of his tulips.
He said that they grew better that way.
No offense, but he was a robot.
The most advanced robot in Persia is made
from the best technology available.
And yet, he would say
the most unscientific things.
Unscientific...
I see.
Yes, things for which
there was no substantive basis.
There's something I'd like to show you.
This is it.
A tulip?
Sahad was growing it.
And it continues to bloom
without ever withering.
It never withers?
How many years has it been?
Three years.
He asked me not to plant it in the ground
until he got back.
If he never returns,
we will end up studying this.
You know, it feels as if this tulip
is waiting for him too.
Oh dear.
Now I've said something unscientific.
Does this tulip have a name?
Yes, I'm sure there must be one.
Thank you for your business as always.
Anton.
Could you deliver this
to Mr. Van Dyke's shop?
Okay!
He's a hard worker.
He's been a huge help.
Before I came here,
I met a little flower peddler in Persia,
but he wasn't working as happily as that.
Persia. Sahad's country.
I understand he came to this shop often?
Yes, every day.
He'd help me with the shop
when he had time off from school.
He didn't seem to have friends.
But he would talk to me
about all kinds of things.
Like how he wanted to fill
his homeland with flowers.
Hearing a robot like Sahad
talk about dreams made me happy.
But one day,
something was different about him.
Out of nowhere,
he told me he was going back
to his country to enlist in the army.
I tried to stop him
because someone like him
should never have to become a soldier,
despite how long the war raged on.
And then,
he told me his father died in the war.
His father...
I couldn't say anything.
Then, with a sad look in his eye,
Sahad said,
"I might end up like him."
Him?
What was the name of that tulip again?
Yes, I heard
that he named all of his tulips.
That's right.
At the research site in Zaandam,
he repeated many experiments to develop
a flower that could survive the desert.
A stronger, more resilient flower.
He wanted more and more.
But then, one day,
Sahad went to the field
to check on his flowers as usual and saw...
just one tulip standing.
All the flowers around it had withered.
I believe the name
of that flower was...
Pluto.
I found the photo of Sahad.
I'm sorry for all the trouble.
No problem. Let's see.
How do I do this again?
Like so.
Oh, that's right.
I ask for photos
when I accept lodger applications.
Ah, here it is.
See? He had such a gentle smile.
This photo has been cropped.
Ah, yes.
I think he said it was a photo
taken with his father.
His father?
Well, since he's a robot, he likely meant
the person who created him...
This man is
Professor Abullah?
His father, who had supposedly died?
Gesicht is getting closer.
Very impressive.
Don't you think so?
His investigative skills are amazing,
but that's not all.
His ability to fulfill missions,
the weaponry he possesses,
and his Zeronium.
Gesicht is the most powerful weapon
of mass destruction to date, so to speak.
Pluto may lose.
It's true.
But you know,
there is one good way to kill him.
Shall I tell you?
Well...
From Persia to the Netherlands, huh?
As I am a prisoner here,
I can't help but be jealous.
But with this body,
I couldn't go anywhere even if I was free.
So, you know who's behind this?
Yes.
Professor Abullah.
He was truly a great scientist.
Dr. Ronald Newton-Howard.
The Photon Energy he developed
will brighten our future
like the rays of God.
His achievements will never be forgotten...
You must be Epsilon.
I never imagined we'd meet like this.
My name is Abullah.
You came all the way
from the Republic of Persia?
It is truly regrettable.
I wish I could have met Dr. Newton-Howard
while he was still alive.
His achievements developing
Photon Energy will go down in history.
As a Bora Inquiry Commission member,
he helped end dictatorial rule
in the Kingdom of Persia
and restored peace to the country.
To lose someone like that in such a way...
But then, he did leave you behind.
The level of your perfection
amazes me, Epsilon.
You as well, Professor Abullah.
I've heard about you.
How you lost most of your body
in the last war.
It is nothing compared to losing family.
I see. Abullah, huh?
It's also just like you
to have a lack of direct evidence.
But that's not all
you came here to discuss, is it?
Suppose that an ultimate
artificial intelligence exists.
If a robot were equipped with
an artificial intelligence too advanced,
what would happen?
It wouldn't wake up.
And why is that?
Because it would not know what to become.
In order to simulate all
9.9 billion personalities on the planet,
it would take an eternity.
As such, it wouldn't wake up.
Then how could it be woken up?
By introducing extreme emotions to it.
Extreme emotions?
Hatred.
That's right.
Anger.
Yes.
Sorrow.
Correct!
Then, it would wake up.
Now,
what kind of robot
would it turn out to be when it awakened?
It looks like it's about to rain.
Your powers weaken
on a day like this, don't they?
Yes.
Well, you have no need
for such mighty powers anyway.
You refused to participate in that war,
and you were right to do so.
There is no such thing as a just war.
You lost your family in the war.
My wife, my children...
The war took everything from me.
Tears.
The rain has started.
And it appears the funeral is over.
Yes.
Epsilon.
What is most important to you?
I'm sorry to have kept you waiting!
The funeral is over, so let's go home!
Okay, Epsilon!
Epsilon!
We saw a squirrel over there!
- Really?
- I found an acorn!
You can have it, Epsilon!
How wonderful.
I had heard that you adopted war orphans.
Please take good care of these children.
Love these children,
for me and the ones that I've lost.
I must attend
the European Robotics Conference.
The restoration of Persia requires that
we create more wonderful robots like you.
Hey, I don't see Wassily.
Yeah!
Wassily!
- Wassily, where are you?
- Wassily!
Oh!
There he is!
Wassily, we're going home.
What's wrong, Wassily?
Bora.
It's all right.
This is not a battlefield.
Don't be scared.
Bora.
It will lie.
Once this robot gained consciousness,
it would tell lies.
To others, of course, but also to itself.
You are close to solving this case.
Where is Pluto now?
He must be undergoing maintenance
to tend to the damage he received
in the fight with Hercules.
He's probably back home.
Home?
Sahad's homeland, Persia?
No, Pluto's home.
The tulip.
Abullah's whereabouts?
Yes, we must take him
into custody right away.
Don't be ridiculous, Gesicht!
He's a VIP!
It doesn't matter!
I need to know where he is!
And what do you intend to do?
I will go to where Pluto is.
Pluto? Where he is?
The Kingdom of Persia has an agricultural
research facility in the Netherlands.
It's in Zaandam,
on the outskirts of Amsterdam!
Just one tulip standing...
All the flowers around it had withered...
The name of that flower was
Pluto.
It's close.
Pluto...
What a fantastic speech!
You absolutely deserved
that standing ovation, Professor Hoffman.
Thank you very much.
Despite the hardships
you've faced recently,
we truly appreciate you attending
the European Robotics Conference.
Did you find
the security we provided satisfactory?
Yes. Thanks to them,
I was able to carry out an important duty.
Professor Hoffman,
your helicopter is here.
As you can see, these brawny bodyguards
are giving me door-to-door service.
I'll go check the heliport.
No, I'm sure they have
their own security there.
Still, you can never be too careful.
Professor Hoffman, the entire world
of robotic engineering depends on you.
Thank you. Goodbye.
Please, take care.
Uh, I need to use the bathroom.
I've checked it.
Then I will be fine on my own.
Well, that was a wonderful speech.
I was especially moved by your remarks
about the potential for Zeronium
to contribute to peace.
And you are...
It's a pleasure to meet you,
Professor Hoffman.
I'm Abullah from the Republic of Persia.
Just a regular power generator
in the basement.
They're faint,
but these electromagnetic waves
are the same as those recorded by Epsilon
during the fight with Hercules.
It's close.
You!
I've always wanted to speak with you.
After all, you're the one
who brought Gesicht into this world.
The pleasure is mine.
If there's anything I can do
to help with the restoration of Persia...
Zeronium is the perfect metal.
Perhaps you could consider
deregulation of Zeronium imports.
Right...
Even the culprit who's going around
destroying the most advanced robots
wouldn't win against Gesicht.
I suppose not.
I heard a rumor
that Gesicht was recently damaged
by a cluster cannon.
Oh, yes, you're very well-informed.
But please do not worry.
It wasn't serious.
Wonderful.
Even damage to that degree
will not affect him?
Yes.
I see.
Then, Gesicht has no weaknesses.
No, he does have flaws.
It's just that layers and layers
of advanced control systems
are built into him.
I see. So you're saying
that prevents error?
Error?
Well, he doubts and struggles,
just like we do.
Is that what you meant by "flaws"?
Those systems are the source
of his strengths and flaws.
Given his superiority, what would you do
if he were to make an irreparable mistake?
For example...
if he killed someone.
You lot!
What are you protecting?
A robot that kills humans.
There was such a robot once,
was there not?
Brau1589.
Apparently, he described what he did
as an "execution."
The same logic humans use
when they commit murder.
What are you trying to say?
Well, is that not
what the world did to Persia
after you and other Bora Inquiry
Commission members entered the nation?
Please forgive me. I've gone too far.
After all, democracy has taken root
in Persia, thanks to you.
But if a robot did happen to kill a human,
I think that robot should be executed.
If Gesicht ever did such a thing,
what would you do?
That would never happen!
A robot as advanced as Gesicht
could even take his own life.
- Nonsense!
- No.
Perhaps the authorities would erase such
memories from Gesicht before he did so.
Did you do something to him?
His artificial intelligence--
All you need to do
is to maintain him properly.
Director!
What did you do to Gesicht?
Robots' memories can be deleted.
I can't help but envy them.
I wish I could do the same.
Gesicht, this is Europol Headquarters.
Can you hear me?
Yes, I can.
We've located Abullah. He's in Düsseldorf.
He's attending
the European Robotics Conference.
Understood. Take him into custody
as soon as possible.
The thing is, Professor Hoffman
is also attending that conference.
What?
Professor Hoffman?
Thank you for waiting.
Let us get going, sir.
Is everything okay, sir?
Oh, no, I'm fine.
It is the same thing.
The same thing.
What the world did to Persia.
They must be executed.
Please confirm Professor Hoffman's safety.
I'll be there soon--
This is Europol!
This building is now on lockdown!
What? What's going on?
Nobody goes in or out!
Stay where you are
until instructed otherwise!
Excuse me! Please take a look
at the elevator monitor!
Professor Hoffman!
The elevator is heading toward
the heliport on the top floor.
Damn it! Get up there now!
None of the other elevators are working!
What?
What the hell is that thing?
Aren't you supposed to be
my robot bodyguard?
Did something else
hijack your artificial intelligence?
Professor Hoffman, can you hear me?
Please stay calm, and don't--
Are you the one who killed
all those scientists?
You must be executed.
Gesicht. Can you hear me, Gesicht?
Professor Hoffman
has been abducted. Gesicht!
I can hear you.
I'm headed there as soon as I can.
However, right now,
right in front of me is...
Is this because of
what the commission did in Persia?
I do feel responsible.
But what would killing me achieve?
Open up! Open the door!
That's your partner.
He's on your side too, isn't he?
I'm opening the door now!
Professor, run!
Horns.
That's how you're going to kill me too?
Just what are you?
Bora...
What?
Squad A here.
We're almost at the heliport!
What the hell is with these cockroaches?
Target sighted. He has captured
Professor Hoffman and is on the move.
We do not have a clear shot as it stands.
- Do it anyway.
- What?
It's fine. Take the shot!
But what about Professor Hoffman's safety?
What about the professor?
Is Professor Hoffman safe?
My body is made of Zeronium.
Thermal and magnetic rays
won't work on me!
If you move, I'll shoot!
Freeze!
Its combat capabilities plummeted
from 1,200,000 to 5,800.
It buried itself alive, huh?
This is Gesicht!
I have captured the target.
Is Professor Hoffman safe?
What do you want us to do, Captain Becker?
Yes, he's fine.
Destroy the target.
Illusions like this won't work
on my artificial intelligence!
A field of flowers...
- Pluto...
- Huh?
Pluto...
- Pluto!
- No!
You are not Pluto!
Pluto!
Your name is Sahad!
Yes. You are Sahad.
Sahad.
Father.
You're alive, Father.
I'm so glad.
I received news that you were
also killed in the airstrike.
Thank God.
Yes.
But I've lost everything.
As a robot, I'm sure
that you understand this.
I've lost most of my body.
But more importantly,
my wife, Fatima, my daughter, Lola,
and your robot brother, Murat.
Those barbarians.
They took the family I held precious!
My most beloved treasure!
Father...
Now, all I have is you.
You are all I have left, Sahad!
You understand, don't you?
How I feel.
Hatred.
I have a favor to ask of you.
Please save this country.
Do not let them kill
any more of our people.
Do not let our people
experience sorrow like I have.
We must take revenge.
This war will soon be over.
Revenge only begets more revenge.
The hatred would never fade away!
That's right.
Hatred never fades.
Let me install your brain
into the strongest of bodies.
The strongest of bodies?
What is this, Father?
I love you, Sahad.
Father...
I love you.
Gesicht!
What are you doing? Shoot it now!
I give my authorization!
Destroy the target!
No.
What did you say?
I am not programmed to destroy a robot
that has no intention of attacking.
What the...
Gesicht, listen to me.
You destroy that thing,
and the case is solved.
This is an order.
Take the shot!
I refuse.
Gesicht! How could you say that?
In the past, you've...
Listen, Gesicht.
I'm ordering you once again.
Destroy the target at once, and--
I said no. That's final.
Gesicht!
Captain Becker,
do I have the right to resign?
Huh?
Stop with the nonsense.
You were developed as a robot detective.
You do not have a choice!
Then I'd like to request
a leave of absence for one year.
You what?
I've had enough.
Right?
Is Professor Hoffman safe?
He is safe.
That's a lie.
I just accessed the camera
of the Science Forum's heliport.
What is that robot?
The robot that has Professor Hoffman.
It's...
Captain Becker.
You ordered me to fire even though
Professor Hoffman was in such danger.
Gesicht.
Let's make a deal.
Who are you?
Let's exchange hostages.
Release my beloved Pluto.
Who are you?
Step away from there,
and I will release Professor Hoffman.
Gesicht!
Do not act without permission!
Your actions are in violation of
Article 1, Clause 3 and Article 15,
Clause 2 of the Robot Laws,
and you will be penalized severely!
Gesicht!
This is from the heliport.
The robot that had Professor Hoffman
suddenly collapsed!
I've secured the professor!
Sahad.
Your father does not love you.
Are you crying?
Oh, Gesicht.
Hey, Helena. You're still working?
Yes.
But I'm ready for a break soon.
- How about you?
- Right.
It's finished.
Really?
Yes. Really.
You say that now, but I know you'll be
on your next assignment in no time.
This time is different.
Let's take that trip to Japan
for real this time.
From now on, I will have plenty of time.
You sound as if you're going to quit
being a detective.
Shall we apply
for permission to adopt a child?
We've tried before.
Yes, but we couldn't find
a good match for us back then.
Things are different now.
Robotics has advanced,
and the regulations have been relaxed.
I wonder if I'll make a good mother.
Of course you will.
I know it.
- What?
- Um, well...
Besides, if we had children,
you wouldn't feel lonely.
I'm not lonely.
I have you.
We'll talk more when I get home.
Okay. Come home soon.
I will.
Professor Hoffman, are you all right?
Yes, I'm all right, Gesicht.
I'm more worried about you.
I'm not injured.
And the monster?
I was told you cornered it.
Yes, it's only a matter of time
until it gets captured.
Good. There's no need for you
to confront it face-to-face again.
Your body is not in optimum condition.
Yes.
Anyhow, now we know who's behind it.
- Just as you said...
- Abullah.
Yes, the robot bodyguard
that attacked me was hijacked by him.
It was all Abullah's doing.
What bothers me is
Professor Ochanomizu's statement.
He said the true culprit is Dr. Goji.
Goji and Abullah, huh?
For now, leave things to the others.
You must rest.
I hate to repeat myself,
but because of that cluster cannon blast,
your Zeronium body has metal fatigue.
If you experience
another shock like that, then--
Professor Hoffman.
About the dreams
I've been telling you about...
Yes?
I may not have them anymore.
What do you mean?
I'm not sure. I just have a feeling
that I've figured out
the true nature of my dreams.
What? Wait, does that mean
your memory has...
Until next time, Professor.
Wait, Gesicht!
Zaandam Agricultural
Research Facility to base.
Squad D has arrived.
We're heading underground.
Squad F here,
currently doing a search underground.
We're almost at the spot where
Detective Gesicht cornered the target.
The target's combat capabilities
have declined significantly,
but keep your guard up.
Destroy it on sight!
I repeat! Destroy it on sight!
- Director.
- Where's Gesicht?
He's on his way to Amsterdam.
I heard the report.
Contact Gesicht immediately!
Yes, sir. As soon as
things are ready at Zaandam--
Do it right now!
Gesicht, why are you acting on your own
without permission?
Not only are you disobeying orders,
you say you want to resign?
And if you can't resign,
you want an extended leave of absence?
I will not allow either!
Your artificial intelligence
is malfunctioning.
You must undergo maintenance right away
and then report to the advisory committee.
Are you listening, Gesicht?
There's something that must be done
before any of that, isn't there?
Why didn't you punish me?
I committed a crime
deserving of execution.
Why did you erase my memory?
My precious...
Don't you dare cut out, Gesicht!
Gesicht!
You're such a hard worker, Anton,
working so late.
Yes! I'll be done after this delivery.
Hello, Gesicht.
Hello. I'd like
a bouquet of flowers, please.
Of course. Who is it for?
For my wife.
How nice. I'm jealous.
What kind of flowers would she like?
He's alive, you know.
Sahad is alive.
Is it true?
Did he do something wrong?
He didn't do anything bad.
It's not his fault.
Hello, Anton.
We meet again.
You are
Ali from the bazaar in Persia.
Why are you in Amsterdam?
You can have the whole body for 500 ZEUS.
He walked.
He walked, Gesicht.
You're...
Ali, come here.
No need to be scared.
You heard the gunshot, right?
It's dangerous here.
Come this way.
You know, I have a little one like you.
Ali!
What's wrong, Ali?
Last night, in Amsterdam's Old Town,
a robot agent was murdered.
The victim was one of the most
advanced robots in the world, Gesicht.
A deactivated small D-class robot
with a cluster cannon on its arm
collapsed nearby.
Detective Gesicht suffered damage
from the same weapon a few weeks ago,
and he was involved in an intense battle
hours before his death.
His strongest...
Welcome. It's been a long time,
Professor Hoffman.
Since the inquiry commission,
Professor Ochanomizu.
Allow me to introduce you.
I'm Helena, Gesicht's wife.
I don't know what to say.
I'm truly sorry for your loss.
If there's anything I can do to help...
Oh, I'm truly grateful
that you invited me here.
Gesicht was looking forward
to visiting Japan again together.
In fact, he made reservations
for the trip on the day he died--
Minister Ochanomizu, we should get going
before the media finds us.
Ah, yes.
She's put on a brave face.
You think Gesicht is another victim
of the series of robot destruction?
Yes, though Europol refuses
to reach a conclusion just yet.
Our lives may still be in danger as well...
Professor Ochanomizu?
It's just as Gesicht said.
What is?
He told me that the air in Japan
has a faint trace of soy sauce.
KAMINARIMON
She's trying to act like
she's enjoying herself in order to forget.
That is
some extremely sophisticated behavior.
Indeed.
Even though robot memories are permanent
unless you erase them from their AI...
It seems that Europol tampered
with Gesicht's memory.
"Tampered"?
Was it within the standards
of the Robot Laws?
No, as an extrajudicial measure.
That's not good.
I looked into it,
but I couldn't get to the truth.
It's wrong for humans to tamper
with robot memories as they please.
But now, I want...
to erase them for her.
I actually asked her
if she wanted to erase
any parts of her memory.
Then she said to me,
"Please don't erase my memories of him."
Mr. Hoffman, your room is the Maple Room.
Miss Helena, your room is the Pine Room.
This is the room Gesicht booked for us.
Will you be okay alone?
- Yes.
- Right this way, ma'am.
I can find my own way from here.
Very well, ma'am.
You must be Dr. Tenma.
I am.
Do you have it?
Will this help find the culprit?
Of course.
Dr. Tenma.
What's the matter?
I can't process it all.
Process what?
The overwhelming amount of grief.
Memories of Gesicht
just get clearer and clearer.
I don't know what to do.
Helena, go ahead and cry.
When things like this happen, humans cry.
Yes.
You can start by imitating.
That's right.
Very good.
You're doing great.
It may be an imitation,
but eventually, it becomes the real thing
like it did for me.
You'll be able to truly cry.
These are
real tears.
Atom is dead,
and I am heartbroken too.
Subtitle translation by: Astrid Oliver