Me?
No, me.
It's me, for sure.
Maybe it's me.
Ought to be me.
Hey! It's me.
Me.
Me, me, me.
It's me.
Me, of course.
- It's me.
- Me, obviously.
- Me!
- It's me.
- Of course it's me.
- Me!
So, how goes it?
If he were human, I'd say he's dreaming.
But there's absolutely
no sign of him waking up.
I see.
You're better off not seeing his face.
The 9.9 billion personalities
programmed in him
are being simulated on his artificial skin
at an incredible speed.
It's beyond imagination
how hideous his face would be.
Perhaps it is impossible
to create a perfect robot after all.
What should we do?
How can we wake him up?
There is a way.
What?
Are you prepared?
He may turn out to be a devil.
A devil, huh?
Dr. Tenma.
She went back to her country.
"She"?
Gesicht's wife. Helena.
I see.
I wish you could have met her.
She was concerned about Atom.
Though it pains me to admit,
we scientists tend to focus
only on technological results,
but her sense of kindness
is worth studying too.
It's almost as if
she were Atom's equal.
Dr. Tenma.
The National Diet has set the date
for Atom's state funeral.
With that, Gesicht's death
won't be in vain, right?
We humans call things like this
"a soul" as well.
I will take good care of
your husband's soul.
You are entering
a Class-A restricted zone.
Retinal scan in progress.
Please proceed.
Devil or not, it doesn't matter!
Nothing matters unless he wakes up.
What do we do?
Introduce unbalanced emotions.
"Unbalanced emotions"?
Yes. Anger, sorrow, hatred...
Tipping the scale is the simplest way
to solve the chaos of 9.9 billion.
To bring you back from the dead,
I'd gladly become a devil.
Gesicht's hatred...
As Gesicht... died...
toward whom was he directing his hatred?
It's been raining for three days.
At this rate, just like Gesicht, I might...
Epsilon, you have a visitor.
He looks really strong.
It sure rains a lot here.
I'm Hogan of the Ministry of Science
Defense Agency.
Nice to meet you.
I've been assigned as your bodyguard.
They say you're the next target
since Detective Gesicht has been killed.
My power isn't even
in the same league as yours.
But with all this rain
and with you being powered
by Photon Energy...
I'll take you to the safe house.
But what about the children?
We cannot drag them into this.
Today is my birthday, you see.
Huh?
The children are throwing me a party.
It's a surprise party.
Well, it's meant to be a surprise,
but I already know about it.
Can you make it short?
Thank you.
Oh, you all...
- Happy birthday!
Thank you.
Thank you very much, everyone!
We have presents for you, Epsilon!
Wow, really? I'm so happy!
This is from us!
What a lovely necklace!
- You made this yourselves?
- Yes!
This hat is lovely too.
Look at that, Epsilon.
It's something you love!
It's the sun, huh?
With this, you can feel happy
even on a rainy day like today, right?
You're right. Amazing!
It does cheer me up.
See? I told you he would love it!
These children
lost their parents in the war.
To those kids,
Epsilon is like their sun.
Hey, Wassily, you drew something
for Epsilon, right?
Don't be shy. Show him!
Is that true?
Let me see.
Bora...
This is Bora?
Bora
ate it...
Earth...
Wassily is saying something
other than "Bora"!
...ate it...
The giant made a south pole
In the desert
A song?
The giant released a river of fire
And summoned the floating glaciers
The giant made the rains come down
Until there was a great flood
The giant swallowed the fire
The glaciers, and all the rain
And then he ate
The earth itself
He ate
Amazing, Wassily!
But what a weird song!
We need to get going.
Five more minutes.
It's been a while, Arnold.
Oh, why if it isn't Epsilon?
I'd like to ask you something.
Okay!
Let the United States of Thracia's
best weather-forecasting robot, Arnold,
predict it for you.
The rain you've been having
should stop tomorrow before dawn.
Just be patient--
Not that.
Three years ago.
What? Three years ago?
Do you have any records
of abnormal meteorological events
in Persia three years ago?
For example, something like this picture.
What is that?
I'm not exactly sure.
Three years ago in Persia, huh?
Nothing in particular.
The smoke you see in this data
is the kind caused
by battlefield artillery shells.
Some of the children you took in
are from this area, aren't they?
- Yes.
- Huh?
There's something gigantic
inside the smoke...
What is it?
It's impossible to analyze.
It's time, sir.
I'll be back soon.
Epsilon, where are you going?
What about the rest
of your birthday party?
Some last-minute work came up.
Be good while I'm gone, okay?
Wassily...
Wassily?
Hey, over here.
It's dark, so watch your step.
I guess you do come in handy.
Sir, I have brought him.
Whoa, you're bright. Dim your light.
I'm Brigadier General Scott
of the UN Forces.
So you're the Epsilon
who refused to join the army.
You've got a dainty frame for a robot.
No wonder you're a coward.
At least you can help
with the post-war cleanup.
Have a look. This is your job.
What is this?
You are going to melt all of this down.
With your Photon Energy,
you'll finish in no time, right?
You want me to do that
to these?
They're advanced robots, but their
artificial intelligence has been removed.
It's just a pile of marionettes.
It can't be.
I'd heard that the robot rights
had been recognized in Persia.
What happened to the AI that was removed?
No idea.
Anyway, just get it done quickly.
I'll let you know
when we're at a safe distance.
You ready, Epsilon?
- I'll start the countdown.
- Wait!
We're past the scheduled time.
Start the process immediately.
No, listen to me!
- There's still someone nearby!
-What?
Someone's out there.
That's impossible. We've checked.
There's no one left alive.
I'm getting a life-form reading.
Must be a dog or a cat. Just do your job.
Come here.
It's okay.
Don't be scared.
Come on out.
Here.
Bora...
Do you realize that you...
No.
I almost turned this boy to ashes!
We'll take care of the kid.
We don't have much time.
Just get on with it.
Eight, seven, six,
five, four,
three,
two,
one.
It's been a while, eh, Epsilon?
It's me, Scott, from the UN Forces,
though now I'm a full general.
Excellent work you did back then.
Quite a flashy explosion, as I recall.
Quite frankly, he's got so much power,
it's silly for us to think
we can act as his protection.
Plus, this is more like a fortress
than a safe house.
But of course, you are the last
of the most advanced robots.
If anything happened to you,
it would be a loss for the whole planet.
I'm sure you know this already,
but according to the data retrieved
from Detective Gesicht,
the enemy's name is--
Pluto.
Right.
And as his brain,
the AI of another robot named Sahad
had been installed.
You're prepared as expected.
What is Bora?
Those robot corpses I destroyed...
How are they connected to Bora?
"Connected"?
What was the Bora Inquiry Commission
in the first place?
The members of that mission
who found that robot graveyard
are being killed off one by one.
Now is not the time for secrets!
Your life is in danger too!
Pluto's power is terrifying.
But an even greater power
is waiting beyond its evolution.
One that could
"eat the earth itself."
What are you talking about?
It's from the song
that boy was singing, isn't it?
Listen, they're singing it even now.
Yes, I can hear it.
The giant made a south pole in the desert
The giant released a river of fire
And summoned the floating glaciers
The giant made the rains come down
Until there was a great flood
The giant swallowed the fire
The glaciers, and all the rain
And then he ate up the whole earth!
And he ate up the whole earth!
Bora
Hey, Wassily. Everyone loves your song.
The giant made the rains come down
Until there was a great flood
The giant ate up the fire
The glacier, and all the rain
And then he ate the earth itself!
Bora
Bora...
What's the matter, Deacon?
- What's going on?
- What is it?
No! They have to flee!
Flee?
What's wrong?
I must return to Australia right away!
Oh, wow.
What is that?
Everyone, run!
There's something above us too?
General, take your men and run!
Run? The defense system here
can instantly respond to any attack.
We aren't like you,
who only thinks about running away.
You have to flee n--
Epsilon!
Do you read me, Epsilon?
I have to save them!
It's too late. Everyone's been vaporized.
Because of me, they all...
That's not true!
There were plenty of chances to target you
over the last three months.
It's highly possible
that the general was the target.
The Bora Inquiry Commission assassinations...
Take a look.
They look like two horns.
Whatever the case,
I must return to the children!
Such destructive power.
What weapon could do this?
No.
It was probably
Bora.
What is Bora?
I'm not sure.
It's like he has emotions
but doesn't at the same time.
Is he just a puppet?
Who is it?
Who? Just take a look.
It's me. Higeoyaji.
Oh, Principal Ban.
I wasn't asking about you.
Then what did you mean?
I just saw two great rushes of sadness
emerge somewhere in the world.
Pinocchio, eh?
Pinocchio struggled to learn
about the human heart.
But Uran,
you have more heart than most humans.
They're crying.
What's the matter?
You can tell me.
Why are you crying so much?
Wow!
It's coming this way.
Should we run?
I'm sure we'll be fine
if we stay inside the house.
Everyone! Gather around me!
Now!
Huddle closer!
Get down and protect your heads!
Epsilon!
Get down!
It's okay.
Don't be scared.
Come on out.
Here.
What power...
The sun came out.
Hey, look!
There are two suns!
Epsilon!
Thank goodness.
You defeated it, then?
Wassily...
Epsilon...
You called my name for the first time.
Thank you.
Thank you,
Epsilon.
Uran.
Uran!
What's wrong?
He's Pinocchio.
What?
The child is like Pinocchio.
The one who was sad and crying?
He can't find it.
His heart.
No matter where he goes,
it's darker than inside the whale's belly.
He doesn't want to be a puppet.
He doesn't want to be controlled.
He thinks he's acting on his own,
but he's controlled by his hatred.
But you see,
he's not the only one being controlled.
Geppetto is too.
Geppetto is
just another puppet.
I wanted to talk to him some more.
But he's gone.
Can you tell them to hold off
on Atom's state funeral?
If that's what you'd like, sure...
Thank you.
Come on, Wassily!
Run faster, or you're gonna get tagged!
You're it!
Are you all right, Wassily?
Oh, someone is coming.
It's Mr. Simon.
Hello there. Nice weather today, eh?
It sure is.
Is Epsilon around?
Unfortunately, no.
Oh, he's not here?
He's not. He's at a hearing.
A hearing?
So, Epsilon,
did you defeat your adversary?
Yes, I did.
Are you sure?
I thought robots couldn't tell lies.
I defeated my enemy.
Completely?
Then can we discuss the other issue?
Why did you fail to protect the general?
Everyone stationed at the safe house
was gone in an instant.
That was different.
It was an attack with a different weapon.
A different weapon?
In any case, please take a look at these.
These are the parts scattered
around Epsilon's orphanage.
They seem to be from the left arm
of a robot made in Persia.
A robot that was created
for environmental development
but converted for the military.
Just the left arm?
Anything else?
Not that we have found.
Epsilon, we're all aware
of your pacifist views,
so we're concerned that you may have
gone easy on the enemy again.
No matter how many times we fight,
he will never be my adversary.
Something like this should be discussed
once Epsilon gets back.
That's why I came today.
What?
I'm sure you are aware, Ms. Griffith,
of what people say about this foster home,
about whether a robot
can be a parent to a human child.
We at the Child Services Agency
have no problem with outstanding humans
like you serving as childcare workers.
The problem is Epsilon.
Epsilon cares more for the children
than any human could!
Even so,
it would be better for these children
to be taken in by humans.
Don't you agree?
Especially since we have Mr. Johansen here
willing to get involved.
Yes.
Once he becomes my child,
I will make sure he has a happy life.
Mr. Johansen is one
of the most prominent people in Oslo.
My wife and I have visited several times,
and our hearts are set
on helping this child.
I hope for a favorable answer.
But
out of all the children, why that boy?
Yes?
I've brought him.
Oh!
Wassily, come here.
Wassily.
It's okay. Don't be scared.
Wassily, have you ever seen snow before?
Mr. Johansen, Wassily is--
Mr. Johansen is prepared to make
a substantial donation to the foster home.
Are you going to deny the boy the chance
to be adopted by ideal parents
just because he doesn't like it?
Why don't we go see snow?
Look! It's Epsilon!
- Welcome back, Epsilon!
- It's Epsilon!
Welcome, Epsilon!
You're back!
Hey now, I've only got one body, you know.
Stop that, children.
Epsilon must be tired.
The hearing must have been tough.
It was fine.
Well then, what shall we play today?
Where's Wassily?
He went with that man.
The man who's really rich.
What's going on?
Where's Wassily?
He went to Oslo.
Oslo? No one told me about this!
We had no choice.
Enough already.
How many times do you have to stop?
Mr. Johansen is prepared to make
a substantial donation to the foster home.
There's no point holding hands anymore!
There's the door.
Once you go through, my work is done.
Don't give me any more trouble.
Quickly now.
I told you to hurry up!
I have the tracking results!
Wassily was taken
to Vigeland Castle in Oslo.
However,
Johansen, the man who took Wassily,
doesn't exist.
- What--
- That can't be.
I've brought the boy.
I hope you've been gentle with him.
Why, I handled him
as if he were made of glass.
Well then, if you'd excuse me...
Bora...
Don't be scared.
Bora!
Don't worry. Everything's fine.
- There's nothing to be scared of.
- Bora!
You'd better not shout that so loud.
You're a bad boy.
That's why this is happening to you.
You're a very bad boy for seeing Bora.
But Epsilon will come to the rescue,
even for a bad boy like you.
Epsilon is quite kind, isn't he?
Isn't that right?
I've come this far for you.
Failure is not an option. Not this time.
Epsilon is the last one remaining.
Kill him, and all will be over.
You will be victorious.
Even with only one arm, you will win.
When it's all over,
the world will regret
the sins it has committed!
You hear me, Pluto?
Epsilon, isn't that...
The body armor that was issued to me
during the Central Asian War.
I had no need for it
since I refused to enlist.
Wait!
Wassily's life is in danger.
The military will be ready to deploy
any moment now.
It's me they're after.
Why didn't you finish him off?
You must have had the chance
to strike the final blow.
Why didn't you do it?
You don't need to come.
I don't want to create any more victims.
No, I'm coming with you.
You don't need to protect me.
I'll be protecting Wassily.
He'll be here any moment, Pluto.
You must settle it by sunrise.
Bora!
Be quiet!
What are you doing?
Defying your father, are you?
Since when do you take
that sort of attitude with your creator?
Once this battle is over,
you can go back to your original body.
You know that, right, Pluto?
I'm picking up Wassily's bio-readings.
I'm going in.
I want you to stay here.
But you are a Photon Energy-powered robot.
You should wait until sunrise!
I have to rescue Wassily
as soon as possible!
Wait! I will use my stealth ability!
Behind this door.
I'll break it down.
Breach!
Epsilon!
Rescue Wassily, quickly!
- But--
- Hurry!
Wassily!
He still had that much power left?
Wassily! Are you all right? Wassily!
I'm running out of energy.
Is it
dawn yet?
Finish him! Finish him off, Pluto!
The child...
The child?
You mean Wassily?
I've secured Wassily! He is safe, Epsilon!
He's safe!
Is it Sahad inside you?
What happened to you?
Who is Abullah?
What is Bora?
The sun is rising.
Finish him off now!
Help...
Help me...
TOBIO TENMA
So it was you.
You're the one who's been leaving flowers
at Tobio's grave.
You're...
This is my son's grave.
Are you, by any chance...
I'm Uran.
Atom's little sister.
Yes.
A robot visiting a grave...
Truly incredible.
You're Ochanomizu's masterpiece.
Can you tell me
how Tobio is doing up in heaven?
I don't know about heaven
or that sort of thing,
but I do know that you are grieving.
You do?
You understand grief?
Understand the heart?
I don't know if it can be called a heart,
but emotions...
Like right now.
Somewhere, far away,
I sense two emotions.
Terrible, terrible sadness...
from two sources.
It's sunrise!
You've won, Epsilon!
What are you doing? Finish him off, Pluto!
Why didn't you finish me off last time?
Why didn't you kill me?
Because the wavelengths you emit told me...
you were sad.
Then kill me now!
That's it.
Use your Photon Energy to melt me away!
Do it! Kill me, please!
Come on! Do it!
You are
Sahad.
Let's find your original body.
We'll put your artificial intelligence
back into your original body.
Let's stop this.
You can stop by your own will.
I can't.
He's coming.
Who's coming?
The sun. It should have risen already,
yet it's disappeared.
Bora!
What's happening?
Wassily!
It's no use! I can't hold on!
Use my energy!
Epsilon...
That's your brother.
Dr. Tenma? Doctor?
Wassily! Are you all right?
Your hands are protecting us!
Hi, everyone.
Everyone, I'm back.
What's going on?
Everyone?
I see.
This is just an image in my memory.
I thought you all were here in real life,
so I tried to hug you.
Hug you...
Huh?
Where are my arms?
Where is my body?
Am I...
Atom?
Do you recognize me, Atom? It's me, Uran!
So he's finally awakened.
Dr. Tenma.
I've installed certain data
in his artificial intelligence.
Unbalanced emotions.
A program to simplify the chaos.
It finished processing
all the information,
and the only thing left to do
was to wait for him to wake up.
And now, it has finally--
What are these brain waves?
And these numbers?
What is going on here?
Something came down just now.
Right before Atom opened his eyes,
something flew down!
What is this "something"?
A humongous
sadness.
I understand now.
I understand everything.
I know who Pluto is,
who Abullah is,
and what Bora is.
Bora!
That huge shadow...
Is that Bora?
Epsilon is...
Don't look!
Epsilon...
Epsilon has...
become light.
The morning sun is back.
The giant shadow is gone, and so is Pluto.
Those hands...
Epsilon's hands!
Yes.
They protected us.
Thank you, Epsilon.
Someone.
Anyone.
Please, in my stead...
For the earth, in my stead...
For the earth...
Epsilon.
You probably would be reluctant
to hear this,
but you are no coward
who dodged enlistment.
You were a truly brave warrior.
Sadness flew down, huh?
Uran, you must love reading books.
What?
You are simply good at
expressing things poetically.
You don't understand
other people's feelings.
But I do understand!
I know how sad you were
in front of Tobio's grave!
I sensed it!
I can sense how sad and empty
you feel right now!
Dr. Tenma, wait!
Dr. Tenma!
Atom.
Atom, it's me, Uran! Do you understand me?
I understand.
Thank goodness.
Atom,
you came back to life.
I understand, Epsilon.
What?
Atom?
I understand,
Gesicht.
Hmm?
A crack?
The earth is going to break.
Subtitle translation by: Astrid Oliver