Once upon a time,
in the land of Manu Katche,
there lived a tribe called the Nanabu.
The Nanabu were a peaceful people
who hated fighting.
One day, a tribe bearing gold
came in ships.
The tribe told the Nanabu
that whoever possessed this thing
called "gold" would become happy.
The Nanabu exchanged
some of their horses for the gold.
Rumors about the gold spread quickly,
and the Nanabu
soon gave up all of their horses.
Not only that, they even handed over
their houses and precious land
as advised by the gold-bearing tribe.
The Nanabu people lost everything.
In the end, they were driven
to Mt. Manabonzo
and threw themselves
into its volcanic throat one by one.
The spirits of the Nanabu people
transformed into a giant.
That giant slumbers
deep inside the volcano,
and legend has it
that it will one day rise again
here in Eden National Park.
I see.
Now, let's move on
to the local native reservation.
Stay close to the flag, please.
It's done. All of it.
They're all dead.
Yes, everything went according to plan.
We have now eliminated everything
that could pose a threat to our country.
Our country, Thracia,
will forever be prosperous!
This is Tse Tse Mar, the tribal elder.
His role is to ward off evil
and other things.
What is he mumbling?
Can you translate it for us?
Let's see...
"An evil spirit...
lurks underneath the earth..."
"Its anger
shall end the world."
We've completed the transfer.
We've got maximum security here.
No matter what happens, we'll be ready.
"No matter what happens," huh?
What do you think will happen next?
Excuse me?
Atom is awake.
What do you think will happen next?
Has Dr. Tenma been located?
Not yet.
What did you do,
Dr. Tenma?
What did you do to Atom?
He said he installed a certain program.
A program?
What program?
I don't know.
But I felt it when Atom woke up.
Somewhere in the world,
a great sadness spread with a "boom."
Minister Ochanomizu!
We've got a problem! It's Atom!
He said he wanted a pen,
so we gave it to him. And then...
My goodness!
Let me go!
Atom!
Take her outside quickly.
Yes, sir.
No, let me go!
No! Atom, what are you writing? Atom!
Minister Ochanomizu, what is this formula?
It's a plan for an Antiproton Bomb.
An Antiproton Bomb?
It's a formula to destroy the earth.
Atom has
completed a recipe for a bomb
that will destroy the earth.
Well, well.
What an honor it is to be visited
by such a renowned roboticist.
Then again, I knew you would come.
Atom woke up, didn't he?
Did he say, "Good morning, Dad"?
So you knew. That's impressive.
When artificial intelligence
like Atom wakes up,
the rest of us
across the world take notice.
You're the only artificial intelligence
that's comparable to Atom's.
You didn't come here
to fix me up, did you?
I want to ask you something.
If you repair me,
I might be willing to talk.
Dr. Tenma, I will not rely
on your help anymore!
I will bring Atom back!
Minister Ochanomizu,
we've got an emergency!
Now what?
Atom has escaped.
I can't believe it.
The walls should have stopped any attack,
yet Atom smashed right through.
Where did he go?
We can track him through his GPS.
Request military help!
No, I will handle this.
He's currently in Kudanshita.
Not so far from here.
Dr. Tenma, what did you do to Atom?
But I knew how to wake it up.
By destroying the balance.
Anger, sorrow, hatred...
By infusing unbalanced emotions.
He said he installed a certain program.
He couldn't have...
You installed Gesicht's memory chip
in Atom, didn't you?
Yes.
The data containing the memory
of his last moments.
What if the last memory
etched in the chip was
of hatred?
You'd better...
not make me angry.
Huh? What's the matter?
Atom is alive...
What? But weren't they all destroyed?
He's alive and filled with
an incredible amount of hatred.
Hatred?
Don't be silly.
Robots can't hate anything.
You didn't know?
You thought robots can't feel anger?
You thought robots can't cry?
You thought robots can't feel hatred?
Atom...
Is that a snail?
Squads B and C, move to the south!
Kurt! If something happens to Kurt, I...
Please! Please save my son!
Sir, ma'am, please calm down.
Where are the reinforcements?
I'm Gesicht of Europol.
What is the situation?
The perpetrator doesn't seem
open to negotiations.
He's barricaded himself up ahead.
What weapons does he have?
A recoilless MMG. Military grade.
He's up ahead, behind that structure.
Be quiet, brat!
Drop your gun!
Don't come any closer!
If you do, I'll shoot him! I mean it!
You must be Kurt.
I'm a robot policeman.
This electromagnetic gun
will only hit the bad guy.
I promise it won't hit you.
Hey, didn't you hear me?
But I need you to stay perfectly still.
Kurt!
Think of the people you love the most.
The people I love the most?
That will give you courage.
Shut up! I'll blow his head off!
Mommy...
Daddy...
Good job.
Mommy, Daddy...
Very good, Kurt. You're being very strong.
Suspect secured!
You did great, Kurt.
Kurt!
Mommy! Daddy!
Thank goodness you're safe, Kurt!
Kurt!
I won't ever let you go again!
I won't ever let you go,
even if the world ends!
"I won't ever let you go,
even if the world ends," huh?
Hey, you there! Out of the way!
Oh, sorry.
Jeez, the guy had to make a scene here,
of all places.
I've lost a whole day of business.
I'd better check for recyclable parts
before I start crushing it.
I might make a fair amount
if I sell the parts to a robot hospital.
Excuse me!
Hold on a second!
Huh?
It's moving.
This robot is still alive.
Nah, it's far too gone to call it alive.
It's quite an old model too.
There's nothing usable left.
It'll just have to be crushed.
I'll take it.
Excuse me.
This child...
"Child"?
May I have it?
Sure. Fine with me.
It's just junk.
You can have the whole body for 500 ZEUS.
Helena.
I'm on my way home.
I've got a surprise for you.
What is it?
You'll just have to wait and see.
I know you'll love it.
I'll be home soon.
Yes.
He walked...
He walked, Gesicht.
Yes!
That's right. You're doing great!
Just a little more!
Is this really our child?
Yes, this is our child.
He's alive.
This child is alive!
I finally understand
what it means to be alive.
This is what it means to live.
Pa... pa...
Ma... ma...
We must give our child a name.
You're right.
Robita.
How about it?
What a beautiful name.
I won't ever let you go,
even if the world ends.
Stop!
I was wrong!
I...
Please spare me!
Please don't!
Don't shoot me!
Gesicht.
Mr. Haas, there's something
I want to ask you.
Does the hatred you humans feel
ever disappear?
Or does it never go away,
no matter how many times
you try to erase it?
What I am most afraid of
is myself, now that I've learned
how to hate.
What?
Wait!
I don't know
whether the hatred can go away.
But...
my hatred is...
What's wrong, Ali?
You heard the gunshot, right?
It's dangerous here.
Come this way.
You know, I have a little one like you.
Ali!
What's wrong, Ali?
Nothing will be born from this...
Nothing comes from hatred...
Atom.
You...
I'm all right now.
Professor Ochanomizu.
Atom, my boy.
The hatred is gone.
Hatred and sorrow never fade.
You may think they have passed,
but they continue to burn silently.
That's for sure.
But I want to ask you something.
That's why I came here.
Where's Abullah?
I have a responsibility to stop all this.
You don't need to look for him.
He will find you.
- Sorry to have kept you waiting.
- Not at all.
To the airport, please.
Yes, sir.
Go ahead and tell us, Atom.
Okay. Gesicht's memory chip
was installed in me.
What I'm about to tell you
are the full details
of what his investigation uncovered.
When Darius XIV was dictator
of the Kingdom of Persia,
he developed a plan to quickly turn
his desert kingdom into fertile land.
And he asked Professor Abullah
to create an earth-altering robot.
This plan was called the Bora Project.
So it wasn't a weapon of mass destruction?
Right. At least not in the beginning.
But the Bora Project
was faced with many setbacks.
Each prototype Professor Abullah created
failed and was discarded.
That's what Professor Ochanomizu
and the others found.
Oh, the graveyard of robots.
Then, Professor Abullah
came up with an idea.
In order to complete the Bora Project,
he realized he needed a capable assistant
whose abilities surpassed those of humans.
"Abilities surpassing those of humans..."
"A capable assistant..."
A robot with the most advanced
artificial intelligence.
To achieve that goal,
a certain scientist was invited to Persia.
A certain scientist?
Dr. Tenma.
Tenma?
Where am I?
I heard Atom has been revived.
So it was you, after all, Abullah.
It is good to see you, Dr. Tenma.
So you kidnapped me as bait
to lure Atom here?
No.
There's no more need for that.
Then why?
This is why.
Is this...
Is this Pluto?
No, this is Bora.
A masterpiece created
by a genius scientist named Goji.
My plan is to transplant my brain
into Bora here
and create
the world's most sophisticated cyborg.
You are the only one
who can make it happen.
The only human as capable as me.
Professor Abullah
lost his entire family in the war.
He grieved for them
from the bottom of his heart,
and he began to hate the world.
A capable human, huh?
Abullah, you are not human.
And
the professor himself
was killed in the war.
Wait a minute. That can't be right!
We just saw him a little while ago!
You are not a human.
What are you talking about?
Since I lost most of my body in the war,
I guess one could say
I'm close to a cyborg.
Not a cyborg.
You're a robot.
Don't be ridiculous.
I've known you for a long time.
Because you are
a robot that I created.
What nonsense.
Abullah asked me to create a robot.
A perfect robot.
But the artificial intelligence
of that robot was too advanced,
so it didn't wake up.
However...
Dr. Tenma, you must go to the airport now!
It's not safe here!
I know!
Dr. Tenma! I have terrible news.
Professor Abullah died
in the bombing of the Timur region.
You've verified this?
We rescued the professor from the debris,
but he died soon after.
Dr. Tenma listen to me.
This contains a copy
of a certain part of my brain.
Dr. Tenma, I know you can...
He left this for you.
This contains Abullah's hatred.
He wanted me to install it in you.
The bombs are getting closer!
That face...
You mean to say...
The man we met who called himself Abullah...
That's you.
You lie.
A lie?
Right.
I'll tell you one more thing.
The most advanced
artificial intelligence can lie.
It can lie to others,
as well as to itself.
The genius scientist Goji...
He does not exist.
You are Goji.
Goji is Abullah.
A robot with a dual personality was born.
I am Goji?
That's a lie...
Then where is Goji?
You don't need me to do a transplant.
Your artificial intelligence
has already been transferred
to several other robots.
You lie! You're a liar!
It's time to stop this.
The world fully understands
your suffering now.
After showing the truth of life
to the king of ancient Uzbek,
the legendary sage of the sand
turned back into clay.
The name of that sage
was Goji.
I am the only person who can save you.
Abullah created Pluto,
and Goji created Bora,
just as they had planned.
Pluto inherited Abullah's hatred.
And he hated us,
the world's seven most advanced robots.
So what happened to Bora?
Oh no.
Bora is no longer a robot
designed to produce plant life.
Now, he's a weapon of mass destruction.
We must inform the whole world!
Even if you do, there's nowhere to run.
What?
The whole earth will be destroyed.
I hereby declare the 108th
Military Tribunal to be in session.
Swear in the defendant.
Do not be unnerved
by a little earthquake like this.
What in the world is this data?
This is terrible!
The whole earth could be...
The end of everything shall begin soon.
Darius XIV!
The defendant is not authorized to speak!
However, this is not my doing.
I did not cause this.
Silence!
Hatred caused this.
Please don't, Your Majesty.
Now is not the time to take your life.
Don't try to stop me, Abullah.
Your Majesty, may I show you something?
Pluto... So it's finally complete!
Use this to kill them all.
Kill all seven of the cursed robots!
Leave it to me.
I will take care of
the Bora Inquiry Commission as well.
But the worst of the wrongdoers
is Thracia.
However, there's nothing
we can do about them.
Yes, there is, sir.
It can be done. I can make it happen.
Silence!
Hatred caused all of this.
No one can escape.
Huh?
A huge eruption?
Yes, Mr. President.
An eruption is almost certain.
Where? How big?
Our weather robot can give you details.
Arnold, at your service.
A robot predicting volcano eruptions?
Now that's something.
Thanks to you, many lives will be saved.
Mr. President, I'm afraid
many lives may not be saved.
Hmm?
The eruption will take place
in Eden National Park.
It's close.
The time of awakening is near.
There are no volcanoes
in Eden National Park.
However, there is a huge pool of magma
eight kilometers below the surface.
This pool contains
3,000 cubic kilometers of magma
that rises and falls
due to the movement of ore-forming fluid.
What is it doing now?
It's rising.
And its eruption cycle?
Approximately once every 5,000 years.
When was the last eruption?
It was 5,200 years ago.
What happens if it does erupt?
It will eject 100 million tons
of cinder and ash per hour,
and pyroclastic flow will decimate areas
within a several-hundred-kilometer radius.
The temperature of pyroclastic flow
is about 700 degrees Celsius,
and its speed can reach
300 kilometers per hour.
The ejected volcanic ash will immediately
fly 50 kilometers into the stratosphere,
covering the entire planet.
Several hundred million tons of ash
will block out the sun.
Plants will wither away,
and after a long period of acid rain,
an extreme cryogenic phase will begin.
In a few months,
most biological life will be dead.
And you think
this worst-case scenario will happen now?
Under normal circumstances, no.
- What?
The magma pool is definitely rising,
but the caldera is not at the state
where it should open,
so a cataclysmic eruption
shouldn't be triggered.
Jeez, why the commotion, then?
Giving us all that doomsday talk...
However...
if something artificial
was heading toward the magma pool...
What is this?
It's my simulation.
For example,
if this were an Antiproton Bomb...
An Antiproton Bomb.
We have a problem, Mr. President!
Just now, at the military tribunal.
No one will escape.
A huge bomb will erupt
right below Thracia.
Hello there. What's the matter?
Don't tell me you...
Yes, I knew.
Why did you keep something
so important from me?
That weather-forecasting robot...
He didn't have to pretend
like he was so alarmed.
"Pretend"?
Didn't he tell you?
Most "biological life" will die.
We robots will survive.
Don't worry.
About 10% of the earth's population
will survive too.
Those remaining humans
are my gift to you, Mr. President.
That's the story, Professor Ochanomizu.
The whole earth would explode...
This is what you meant, Atom?
Yes.
Hold on! When is this explosion
going to happen?
If it continues to move
at its current rate,
Bora will arrive at Eden National Park
in about 72 hours.
Impressive, Professor Ochanomizu.
But how do we know it won't speed up?
I think the professor's prediction
is accurate.
How do you know?
Seventy-two hours from now,
it will have been exactly four years
since Professor Abullah lost his family.
I see. The anniversary
of the birth of hatred...
Is there no way to stop it?
Bora is moving quite deep
beneath the ground.
There is nothing else on earth
that could reach that deep.
If a chance exists,
it would be when Bora approaches
the surface to induce the eruption.
If it comes to that,
then the only robot who can stop Bora is...
Leave it to me.
Atom...
But before that,
there is something I must do.
Well, well. It's been a long time.
So happy to see you, my friend.
I came here today to ask a favor of you.
Is that so? I have something
I wanted to ask you as well.
What do you plan to do with that formula?
So you know about it?
I caught them right away,
those strange brain waves
you were emitting as you worked.
I regret doing it.
After I woke up in the lab,
I succumbed to the waves of hatred
that were swirling all over the world.
The enemy must have noticed it as well.
Yes.
That's why I've come to ask you this.
You mean the other threat.
I will carry out your request.
Thank you very much.
Atom.
May I touch you?
You're warm.
Atom, you are so...
So this is a heart.
How gorgeous.
It looks like a completely new home!
We're so glad we chose you, Helena.
I'm pleased that you like it.
We've dreamed of living
in a house like this, right?
Yes.
I'll check back with you later
about the landscaping.
Thank you.
Gesicht.
Atom.
You must be Helena.
You have Gesicht inside you, don't you?
Yes. Thanks to him,
I was able to come back.
Thank you.
Thank you, Atom.
- I came to tell you something.
- Huh?
Gesicht was always thinking about you.
Until the very last moment,
he wanted to see you.
So despite what happened to him,
you'll never be alone.
Thank you, Atom.
You're trying to cheer me up, aren't you?
It's the truth.
Robots can't lie, remember?
You're right.
I almost forgot.
It's strange of me to cry so much
when I'm a robot.
Not at all.
May I ask you a question?
Of course.
Gesicht and I realized
we were both missing memories
from the same period of time.
I still can't remember
what those missing memories are.
But Gesicht...
I keep wondering
if he might have found out what they were.
Do you know
what our missing memories are about?
No, Gesicht didn't know
anything about that.
Are you hiding something?
I am not.
I'm prepared to take on any sorrow,
no matter how big it may be.
Please tell me everything.
No, I've told you everything I know.
I see.
You're leaving?
Yes.
Atom.
Can I see you again?
Of course.
Robots can't lie.
Atom,
you just lied to me now.
Thank you.
Atom.
Gesicht, the time has come.
I've paid my respects to everyone.
I've let them know
this will be the end of everything.
It's about to begin.
I have to go now.
Goodbye, Gesicht.
Pluto!
I'm going to destroy you!
You may be filled with hatred...
but my hatred is greater than yours.
Atom.
Don't do it. Atom!
Mont Blanc loved the forests.
He tried to protect
the forests of Switzerland.
He didn't want to die.
North No.2 never wanted to fight again.
He loved music.
He didn't want to die either.
But you...
Yes, that's right.
I killed them!
Brando.
He loved his family
and believed in the future.
Brando and Hercules were rivals,
but they were united by a friendship
stronger than any!
I'm certain that both of them
didn't want to die!
Epsilon was against the war so much
that he refused conscription.
He tried to give his love to the children
who lost everything in the war!
He didn't want to die!
And inside me is Gesicht's...
hatred!
Stop it, Atom!
Pluto isn't using his tornado!
There is still a kind heart inside of him!
I'm going too!
Wait, Uran! You can't be of any help!
But if we don't do something, Atom will--
It's all right.
Atom is strong. He won't lose so easily!
- What if it's too strong?
- What?
Too strong,
and there's no telling what he'll do!
If his hatred or sorrow are too strong,
then Atom could...
He could kill!
We have to believe.
That's all we can do.
Atom is not that kind of boy.
We're 75 kilometers
from Atom's GPS signal!
Atom...
You will pay for this!
Atom.
Nothing comes from hatred.
Everyone,
it's just as you all say...
Pluto.
What is this?
No, you're Sahad.
I don't know why either.
Why do these fall?
I don't understand.
A shooting star.
Humans say that if they wish
upon a shooting star,
their dreams will come true.
Did you make a wish?
I did.
What did you wish for?
Probably the same as you.
It's time.
Sahad,
I have to go.
Go where, Atom?
Eden National Park is
in an extremely dangerous state right now.
I don't care. We're landing!
But, Professor Ochanomizu...
Where does Atom's GPS show?
He was around here until a minute ago.
You don't suppose that Pluto could have...
Atom is no longer as weak as you think
because I infused him
with unbalanced emotions.
Dr. Tenma!
Pluto may have been killed by Atom.
But the problem is Bora.
Bora will end the earth soon.
Even Atom can't stop him.
We've landed.
Open the hatch.
Here, Professor Ochanomizu.
The air outside is filled with hatred!
Abullah's hatred ate away
all the other emotions
until nothing else was left.
Bora is that hatred itself.
The earth is doomed,
no matter what anyone may try.
That's only in theory.
You've spent too much time in your lab.
You should breathe fresh air
once in a while.
In theory, the earth is doomed.
No matter where we hide,
we're all going to die.
But even in the face of death,
even though we're fully aware of our fate,
we humans never give up hope
until the very end.
Just like Atom.
You are a brilliant scientist, Dr. Tenma.
You created Goji,
but you also created Atom.
What in the--
No one's here?
No response from Orchid City!
Another huge earthquake in Capital Town!
Is this all caused by the crustal movement
in Eden National Park?
Yes, and if an additional
large-scale shock is introduced...
A large-scale shock?
For example,
if an Antiproton Bomb explodes,
then the earth will...
Mr. President, we must declare
a state of emergency!
Mr. President?
We're safe in here, right?
I'm protected here, aren't I?
Yes, I will protect you.
In exchange,
you will be my slave
for the rest of your life.
Atom.
Atom is down there?
He is trying to disable Bora
and the Antiproton Bomb.
Atom can do it, right?
Yes. However,
before he can, his body will melt!
Bora.
Can you hear me, Bora?
Gesicht taught me
that nothing comes from hatred.
Hatred must end.
I tried, but you leave me no choice.
I'll begin.
It'll take five minutes
to disable the bomb.
I have five minutes
until my body starts melting.
In theory, it's impossible.
But I have to give it a try!
I will protect your body.
Sahad.
Let's charge right in.
Okay.
You are mistaken!
Nothing comes from hatred!
Atom, send me the blueprint
of the Antiproton Bomb.
- What?
- Hurry!
Creating fields of flowers,
that was my calling.
I can never be Sahad again.
Atom, please tell Uran for me.
What?
I was glad
we could paint pictures together.
I am grateful!
Sahad!
We must evacuate now!
It could explode at any moment.
Evacuation is pointless.
If it explodes, then the earth will end.
Atom?
Atom!
Atom, take care of the earth for me.
Sahad!
What in the world?
It's the Peltier effect.
When metals
of different properties are joined,
and a high voltage is applied,
sudden heat absorption is induced,
resulting in
an extremely low-temperature state.
Look at the sky!
How brilliant!
It looks like a field of flowers!
Pluto.
No, Sahad saved the earth.
Atom.
I only wanted to protect our citizens.
To protect their future.
That's all I wanted.
Oh?
Something's not right.
The magma is beginning to subside.
The explosion has halted.
Was it Atom? How boring...
Thank God.
I'm so glad.
Well, I can come up with another plan.
My options are endless.
Please!
Let us find a way to prosper together
without destroying the human race!
Who's there?
Welcome, Brau1589.
Now, let us begin together.
The creation of our new world.
So warm. And so weak.
I see now, Atom.
Oh dear. What a disappointment.
I thought you had ascended
to the realm of gods like me.
This is not the end.
Unless hatred disappears from the world,
there will be another...
Professor, will we ever see a day
when there is no hatred?
I don't know.
We can only hope that day will come.
Mont Blanc,
North No.2,
Brando,
Hercules,
Epsilon,
Gesicht,
and Sahad...
I'm sure they're praying
for that day to come.
All of them.
Subtitle translation by: Astrid Oliver