CCG Base to 203,
we have reports of intruders in the
Aqua Building located in the 20th Ward.
Intruders are believed to be ghouls—I repeat, ghouls.
All units are to proceed on-site immediately.
More! Give me more!
Delicious.
I guess they weren't exaggerating
when they called you a binge eater.
You know, I hate it when
people interrupt me during a meal.
I suppose you haven't heard of me then?
Of course I have.
You're a hopelessly dull person with abhorrent tastes.
I have my orders.
I've been told to take you back alive.
But you know...
Before I do that, I think I'll help myself to
a couple of fingers, an arm, or maybe even a leg or two...
You don't mind, do you?
Such a small toy for such a big boy. I bet you like playing house.
How adorable.
Allow me...
to remove them for you.
Give them back...
Those are mine!
Give them back!
I'm not going to play with you.
Several unidentified male bodies were discovered
early this morning in the Aqua Building,
a commercial facility located in Tokyo's 20th Ward.
What is assumed to be ghoul saliva was retrieved from the bodies.
The incident is being investigated as a criminal ghoul offense—
Is it actually that funny to you?
Come on. You can't be serious about
going to a bookstore for your first date.
Why not? She might be thrilled, you know!
For your information,
that's never going to happen. Period.
What? Fine then, how about I take her
out to Big Grill instead, just the two of us,
and grab some burgers?
I'm being completely serious here!
No, no, it's great! That's so like you!
But when it actually happens, it'll be a total flop.
What, you don't think I can handle it?
What would you do then, Hide?
Listen up. When it comes to dates,
you have to pick a place that excites the girl.
Right. Such as?
Huh? S-Such as...
You don't even know!
If I knew, I wouldn't be wasting my
afternoon here having a date with you.
Predatory ghoul attacks in the 20th Ward
have been on the rise these last few days,
I suppose that's true.
with CCG's 20th Ward Branch announcing an investigation
into the possibility of a single
culprit for every incident so far.
That's pretty close, huh?
In other news...
So, what else have you got?
Who's the lucky girl?
The cutie you were talking about?
Oh?
It's gotta be her, right?
No, it's not!
I mean, she's pretty cute too...
Excuse me!
One cappuccino, please!
And you, Kaneki?
I still haven't finished this.
One cappuccino.
While we're at it, what's your name?
Hide!
It's Kirishima Touka.
Touka-san! Are you seeing anyone?
Stop that, you idiot!
She's so cute.
What'll I do if I end up getting kicked out!?
This shop is the only place where she and I both—
She's... the one.
Don't even go there.
It'd be just like Beauty and whatever with you guys.
The Beast!
Well then...
Now that I've seen you lovelorn,
I think it's time for me to head off.
Wait— Hide...
See you later, Touka-chan.
Keep your head in the clouds, Kaneki!
I guess you struck the jackpot this time.
Yeah. Who would've thought that
she'd like the same novelist as I do?
Uh, what's-his-face, right? Takasaki Sen?
It's Takatsuki Sen!
We're going to hit the bookstore together this coming Sunday.
Oh, yeah? I'm still not convinced
on the whole bookstore thing,
but you go and have a good time.
Yeah.
I have to say though. This sure is getting ugly.
That's for sure.
Rumors say that they'll be fine
with eating just one person a month,
but these binge eaters are something else.
They're like a bunch of wild animals, eating everything in sight.
Ghouls as animals, huh?
On second thought, they're worse than livestock.
That's true.
Kaneki-san, what's your favorite work by Takatsuki?
It would have to be his debut book.
It was an instant bestseller after all.
A refreshing delicacy amidst all the clutter, you might say.
Y-Yes, exactly. To be blessed with that much writing talent, releasing a bestseller whilst still in his teens—
Are you all right?
I-I'm fine...
Er, I mean... That's...
Rize-san, you don't eat very much, do you?
Actually, um, I'm currently on a strict diet...
Excuse me, I need to use the restroom.
She's so refined...
Thank you very much for accompanying me today.
No, thank you. I-I had a great time.
Actually, I kind of live near the recent
incidents that have been occurring lately...
Oh, you mean the ghouls?
I'm quite squeamish when
it comes to these sorts of things.
I can't stop myself from trembling
whenever I think about it.
You'll be okay.
Please, rest assured.
I'll make sure to see you home safely.
Right, so then Hide asked me,
"Which do you like better, me or the novels?"
He sounds like quite the joker.
He sure is.
What was it that sparked your passion for books?
My dad left a lot of his books behind.
I lost him before I could barely even walk.
I enjoyed the books he left behind,
so I spent a lot of my days reading
while waiting for my mom to come home.
Then, ever since she passed away...
You know, Hide is the only one I've ever told this to.
Is that right?
It's this way.
Oh, okay.
Touka-chan, what's up?
No, it's nothing.
Well, we're pretty close now, so...
Rize-san...
Um, if you wouldn't mind, can we go out again?
Well, we do have similar tastes in books, and we share the same age...
There's a lot we have in common, huh?
Kaneki-san...
Y-Yes?
The truth is, you caught my eye.
I noticed you, the way you were looking at me...
Huh? Then, you're saying...
Yes.
I, too...
happen to have fallen head over heels...
for you.
Ah, how delightfully exquisite!
Kaneki-san,
there's something I like even more
than reading. Would you like to know?
Tearing apart the luscious organs of someone
who isn't trying to escape from me is most enjoyable.
Yes, that marvelous expression!
Would you kindly allow me to...
thrill myself even more!?
No way! This can't be happening!
This can't be happening!
Tag, you're it!
Kaneki-san!
I'm going to gently scramble up
your intestines for you now, okay?
Oh, dead already?
What a shame. I really did like you.
You have just the right amount of fat on you...
All nice and soft. A pleasure to eat!
How... could...
this...
His abdominal organs are ruptured.
What's going on?
Commence operating immediately!
Where... am I?
I thought I was on a date with Rize-san...
Prepare for an organ transplant!
Without consent from his family!?
Organ? Family?
What exactly are they talking about?
Doctor Kano!
I will accept full responsibility!
Transfer her organs into him at once!
It's warm...
Is this...?
Something's not right...
What the hell is going on?
Kaneki-san!
Is that all you're going to eat?
Oh, right. Your friend visited you again today.
Ah, Doctor Kano...
How are we feeling, Kaneki-kun?
I hear you haven't been eating
much ever since your admission,
but there doesn't seem to be
anything particularly wrong.
Um...
My tastebuds... don't seem quite right.
Tastebuds?
Everything just tastes like ash...
That might be a psychological problem in itself.
It was a serious accident after all.
There's no rush.
Take all the time you need to recover.
I'll stop by again later.
Nothing particularly wrong, huh?
It almost feels like the time I spent together with Rize-san
was only the product of some whimsical dream of mine.
But if nothing else, there's one thing I'm certain of...
Ever since then, something has been...
Something has been eating away at me.
Kaneki!
Congratulations on your discharge!
I present you with the finest leftovers my house
has to offer, along with your favorite hamburger.
You better be grateful!
P.S. When you're up to it, come on back to school.
It's rough here on my own.
Hide...
Thanks,
but I'm sorry.
Well, in the first place, a ghoul has no need for
an appetite this large within such a short period of time.
Just a single dead body would ensure their survival for a month or two.
But Ogura-san, wouldn't the normal food that we eat suffice for ghouls as well?
Absolutely not, as ghouls are only able
to derive their nutrition from human organs.
Not to mention, their tongues
function in a way different from ours, too.
Should they attempt to consume human food,
they'd just be left with an incredibly awful aftertaste.
Their tongues function in a way different from ours...
They'd just be left with an incredibly awful aftertaste...
No way...
I present you with your favorite hamburger!
Hide...
Did you go out and buy this just for me?
This can't be happening...
A friend of yours?
Yeah.
He was supposed to be discharged today,
but he isn't picking up his phone.
I even went to his place several times,
but he wouldn't answer the door.
I wouldn't even bother anymore
with a rude brat like that.
Kaneki and I have been best friends since we were kids.
Best friends, huh?
Hey, Kaneki? How are you doing?
I was in front of the station
and saw Takatsuki what's-his-face
signing autographs at the bookstore, so I thought I'd hit you up.
Anyway, give me a call when you're feeling better.
People... So many people...
People... These are people...
Children...
People, more people...
Woman...
Flesh...
Girl...
Man...
Flesh... Flesh... Flesh...
Family...
Children...
Boy...
Flesh, more flesh...
Woman...
Child...
Flesh, I want flesh...
Boy...
Flesh, I need flesh...
Flesh, so much flesh...
Flesh!
Hey, that man...
Don't get involved, idiot!
What the hell is this!?
I know what's happening!
Transfer her organs into him at once...
Blades such as knives or kitchenware cannot hurt them...
If that's true...
If this is really true...
Then surely, this will...
What am I supposed to do now?
Flesh...
Murder a human... and devour their flesh!
What am I—
It's almost as if...
That scent...
It's something I've never smelled before, but it seems so welcoming...
A sweet aroma, like Mom's home cooking...
There's something over there that awaits me,
something that even I can eat!
Where is it?
Where is it!?
It's close...
A ghoul...
And a human!
How could I have been enticed here by the scent of a mangled corpse!?
You're a ghoul... right?
What's the matter? Are you all right?
My name's Kazuo.
I haven't eaten for a while,
so I can't share too much with you,
but here, help yourse—
Seriously,
how about you leeches back
away from my hunting grounds?
Well, you're a face I haven't seen around here.
More importantly, where's your
other red eye? That's kinda gross.
You know what happens when you get
caught on someone else's territory, right?
N-No, I wasn't— I didn't know...
I just happened to be passing by...
Okay, imagine this.
Your girlfriend is naked and lying on the ground.
There's a guy there with his pants down, he turns around and says to you,
"I wasn't doing anything. I just happened to be here."
That's exactly what I'm getting from you right now.
If it were up to me, I'd blow his damned brains out.
That's why I'm going to kill you,
because you trespassed on my hunting grounds—
Whose hunting grounds did you say?
Since when were these your hunting grounds,
Nishiki?
Touka...
She's dead, right? That binge eating woman?
And that gives you an automatic claim to this area?
Now that Rize's gone,
the responsibility of allocating hunting grounds
to the weaker ghouls and those at the 20th Ward
falls on Anteiku's shoulders.
Are you serious?
A bunch of fence-sitters like those of you at Anteiku have no right to make decisions for others!
This was my hunting ground before Rize came—
Because you were too weak.
Getting told off by some younger,
overconfident little punk really pisses me off.
Does it now?
Enough is enough!
You'll have to cut deeper than that!
Are you sure?
Should I cut a little deeper next time?
Take your corpse with you, coward.
You want this?
You're not gonna eat?
Then again, only one of your eyes is like that...
You're the one who was with Rize.
Why weren't you eaten? Wait...
That eye...
Please, help me!
I know you're not going to believe this,
but I swear I'm human!
And yet...
I desperately want to eat that...
I want to devour it so badly that it aches...
But if I do...
I won't be human anymore!
If you're in that much pain, then eat.
No way in hell!
I'll never do it! No way!
There's no way I can eat something like that, right?
What is this? What is it to be a ghoul?
Killing people, killing each other...
I'm not like that!
I'm... human!
This is ridiculous.
Why don't you just give in?
If you don't have the nerve to eat...
then I'll give you a hand!
Yoshida Kazuo, 41-year-old ghoul.
Occupation: Fitness Club Staff.
On one of my days off, I received a hunting ground from Anteiku's Yoshimura-san.
So while I was at home, I sat my eyes on a target,
killed it,
and was about to eat it.
When suddenly a young ghoul appeared before me...
Screaming and shrieking—
signaling me to my demise.
Off you go!
And then, my head was knocked off by Nishiki-kun.
Yoshida Kazuo, age of death: 41
Former Fitness Club Staff.