I said eat!
Why would you do something like that!?
How could I eat a fellow human's flesh!?
I'm human!
I'm not like you damn monsters!
Really, now? So if I'm a monster, then what does that make you?
Please, I'm begging you.
Tell me, what am I supposed to do from now on?
Ever since that day, my life has been complete hell!
Hell, huh?
I want you to tell me something instead.
Tell me. What does cake really taste like?
I can't tell since I gag every time I look at it,
but it's something that humans enjoy eating, right?
Why don't you tell me what it's like to live a peaceful life?
One where you didn't need to live in fear of the CCG and other ghouls?
Your life has been hell?
Get over yourself.
Does that mean my entire life has been hell!?
Hey, answer me!
I'm...
I'm human!
You're not a ghoul, that's for sure.
But then again, you're not a human either.
A half-breed like you has no place in this world.
I'm... I'm...
If you're so hung up on being a human,
why don't you test how long you can go without eating?
I'm warning you.
Being a hungry ghoul feels worse than hell.
Touka-chan, I think that's quite enough.
Manager...
It's been rough for you, right?
Come with me.
But Manager, why?
Touka-chan...
It's our policy to lend a helping hand to ghouls in need.
Thank you for waiting.
Enjoy.
Do you not like coffee?
It's not that, but...
Kaneki-kun, take a good look at that coffee.
Any thoughts?
It looks quite inviting.
It's just a regular cup of coffee.
It's really good...
This is great!
But when it comes to food,
I'm always left with a terrible taste in my mouth...
Through history, coffee has proven to be the only
thing that we ghouls can enjoy alongside humans.
However, drinking coffee isn't
enough to keep our hunger in check.
Which is why...
What is that?
If you run out, don't be afraid to ask for more.
You're always welcome here.
Manager...
Why did you help him?
Touka-chan,
do you remember the story about an organ
transplant that's been on the news recently?
The one where two students were
crushed underneath some steel beams.
The doctor riskily decided to transplant the deceased girl's organs into the young man's body, who was barely alive.
But the girl that died in that accident was...
It was Rize-chan.
Wait. You couldn't possibly mean...
Yes. He is that very young man.
The doctor transplanted the organs of a ghoul into him.
But that's just absurd!
I've never seen anything like it before,
but he may be turning into one of us.
Flesh...
You're neither ghoul, nor human.
A half-breed like you has no place in this world.
Who cares if you're sitting on both sides of the fence?
Neither human, nor ghoul...
You're still you.
Cherish this life as a half-breed.
An appetizing meal of flesh awaits you, after all.
That lusciously alluring taste...
Just one taste, and you'll be instantly hooked.
It'll give any steak...
a run for its money.
Now, go on. Feast yourself on this flesh.
It's been prepared extra rare, just for you.
Hide...
Have you ever been to the sweets shop in front of the station?
That place has some good stuff, right?
Hey, Kaneki!
How long are you gonna skip classes for, you jerk!?
Pay more attention to me!
I'm hanging out on a limb here!
Hide, I'm sorry.
Anyway, what's with the eyepatch? You making a fashion statement?
I was so bored while you were gone that I ended up joining the school's festival committee...
Wait, "I'm sorry"? When did I...
This all seems so familiar...
Hey, Kaneki!
How long are you gonna stay cooped up in your house?
Do you know how rough it is
for me when you shut yourself in!?
Hello, earth to Kaneki?
Oh, sorry. What'd you say?
Anyway, I've gotta go see that arrogant
upperclassman of mine to borrow some class material.
Wanna tag along?
Sure.
Kaneki, are you eating all your meals properly?
Huh?
You're looking pretty pale.
You better be eating, or else you'll fall sick.
Hide's always been that type of person.
He has a strange way of noticing the small things.
He knows all too well how people feel on the inside,
but acts like he doesn't know instead.
If I were to throw away my humanity,
would I ever be able to walk next to him again?
I've been meaning to introduce him to you, Kaneki.
You mean Nishio-san?
Yeah, him.
I wouldn't say that he's super rude or anything like that.
He's just a little difficult to be around.
Don't...
Here we are.
We're coming in!
Hide, at least knock.
Nagachika, ever heard of knocking?
Sorry, Nishio-san.
You know, nothing ticks me off
more than a violation of territory.
Right...
Oh, this is Kaneki, the good friend I mentioned before.
I see.
I'm Nishio Nishiki, a second year in the School of Pharmacy.
Nice to meet you, Kaneki.
You wanted last year's material, right?
Yeah, I need to see the retail data.
Man, where'd it go?
Yeah, I think it's at home.
Are you for real?
Nagachika, why don't you come with me to grab it?
What, to your house?
Yeah.
Well, I guess.
Sorry, Kaneki, but you'll have to go home without me since I'll be with Nishio-san.
Hide...
Um, can I come with you guys as well?
What's up with you all of a sudden?
Sure, why not?
It's not like I plan on letting you guys in anyway.
Oh, that's fine then.
Let me just deal with this before we go.
So what's your deal today?
It's nothing.
Nagachika...
Yeah, what's up?
How much did you see earlier?
Why do I keep running into ghouls wherever I go?
Oh, er, just her shoulders.
Just your shoulders, he says.
They were very pretty.
No, it's not that. They were always there to begin with.
I'm the one who wound up in this mess.
Want one?
How nice of you.
Yes, step right up! These are freshly baked daily!
Here.
Ugh, it's making me feel nauseous.
Here's yours.
Thanks a lot.
Kaneki, are you in any clubs?
No. I'm not too good around
large groups of people like that.
The exact opposite of Nagachika, huh?
How can a ghoul eat something like this?
This is really good.
All nice and crispy, too.
Kaneki, you're not gonna eat?
I'll save it for later.
He blends in perfectly with human society,
carrying out his part as a normal college student.
That's pretty impressive.
I think it's safe to say that nobody suspects him of being a ghoul.
It'd be pretty messy if anyone were to see this.
Hide!
What are the chances of having a fellow ghoul on campus?
You sure do reek.
You smell just like a female ghoul!
You were going to have Nagachika for dinner, weren't you?
There's nothing quite like the look of pure anguish
that dances across their face as you betray the genuine trust they placed in you,
right, Kaneki!?
I'm not like you...
Is that so?
Bratty little kids who talk back to their
superiors happen to be a pet peeve of mine.
Actually, did you know?
You have an awfully squishy body.
I almost mistook you for a piece of tofu.
Man, this is gross.
Seriously, how do humans tolerate that crap?
I might as well be eating horse shit.
My bad, Kaneki.
I made a mess all over your mouthwatering meal.
You've known this guy for a long time, right?
You guys are best buds, right?
When were you planning to eat him?
Humor me, Kaneki.
Which part were you going to dine on first?
Hide... isn't something to eat.
Your foot... Remove it.
What foot?
Leave him alone!
Seriously?
What's that bag gonna do for you,
you little girl? Bop me over the head?
You just don't get it, do you?
Humans are nothing but livestock,
the same things as cows and pigs, no?
Do you enjoy befriending these
bags of meat before you do them in?
I won't kill them...
I see. Then again, I think
Nagachika is a pretty risky choice.
The guy is no idiot.
Even someone like you should realize
his smarts are a threat to your secret intentions.
And this...
You can't even control your own eyes.
Come on, get up. Or should I kill Nagachika first?
Whoa, what's this now?
Here, try and dodge this!
All right, I guess the fun's over.
My kagune would've made short work of him too.
There's no way... I can win.
Hide...
Hide!
Oh? Great, you're up. Now that's more like it.
Better get a move on now, or I'll crush his skull.
Isn't he unconscious?
Even now you're trying to save me, huh?
See ya, Nagachika.
No...
No!
Hey. You're the one who's always
alone with a book at school, right?
I-Is that a bad thing?
That's not what I meant.
I don't have any friends since I just moved here.
So, wanna be friends?
Sure, I don't mind.
All right! I'm Nagachika Hideyoshi.
You can call me Hide. Nice to meet you!
Y-Yeah. It's nice to meet you too, Hide.
Even back then,
Hide reached out to me when no one else in class would.
No...
I don't want Hide...
to die!
That's... something I won't allow!
Damn you!
Stop! Stop that, you bastard!
I'm gonna die! I'm gonna fucking die!
That was... Rize's...
Damn it all to hell...
Hide...
Mm, he sure looks tasty.
Such a fragrant aroma. I'm getting hungry myself.
Here, do you see him?
Take a good look. Isn't he just scrumptious?
Stop it! Hide isn't food!
Are you sure about that? Take a closer look.
See? You understand, right?
Yeah. I understand.
He looks really appetizing!
No, stop it!
What are you talking about?
You want it so much that you can't stand it, right?
There's no need to hold back.
You're not doing anything wrong.
Quickly, now. You should let loose with your desires.
My desires?
He's all yours.
All of him?
Go on now.
You're right. This is my special treat, isn't it?
I... I have to eat him...
Hide is my...
friend!
That's right! He is my friend, so I have to eat him!
Guess you didn't hold out long, huh, half-breed?
Your head's completely given way to your stomach, right?
Out of the way!
Not even your friend's life has value to you anymore.
Wanna know something?
Gobble this guy right up and you'll regret it later,
while drowning in a sea of blood and entrails.
Such is a ghoul's hunger, and our destiny.
You really are a hassle to deal with.
I'll play nice with you just this one time,
so make sure you go down nice and easy!
Touka-chan brought you back here.
Where's Hide!?
Come with me.
Hide!
I've been... consumed by my hunger this entire time.
At that moment especially,
I was so hungry I thought I might die.
I wasn't even aware of what I was doing.
And then, I went after Hide...
But right now, that's completely gone.
That blood that was in my mouth...
Please, give me an honest answer.
What did you do while I was asleep?
There is only one way to satisfy a ghoul's hunger.
You know what that is, right?
If you had starved for any longer,
you would've pounced on your friend there.
You have to accept what you are.
I don't want to hurt my friend.
That's why I can't be around Hide anymore.
But I can't enter the world of ghouls, either.
As someone who's neither
human nor ghoul, I... am all alone.
There's nowhere I can call home now!
You're wrong.
You are both ghoul and human.
You are the one and only person who holds a place in both of these worlds.
Come over to Anteiku.
I'm certain that it'll lead you to
a path where you can hold your own.
I also want you to understand us better.
To see whether or not we're just ravenous monsters.
How about it?
Why don't we start off by learning
how to brew a delicious cup of coffee?
Well, um...
Do you have faith in someone like me?
Great weather, huh?
The rain dulls their senses.
These working conditions are just right.
According to the 20th Ward's report,
there was an incident three months ago
concerning a binge eater in this very building,
as well as eyewitness accounts of Jason.
A binge eater and Jason, huh?
Interaction between two S-rated subjects?
Who knows?
I doubt they were cordially sharing a meal though.
Mado-san?
Mado-san!
Amon-kun!
You see? I knew it!
If I had to come up with a drawback to this weather,
it'd be that I can't hear those shitbags' dying screams over the howling rain.
This tastes like horse shit.
Nishio-senpai, you know what horse manure tastes like?
What are you, Kaneki, a fool!? Of course not!
It's a simile! A figure of speech!
Oh, yeah?
What!? Nishio-senpai has eaten horse crap!?
Cow manure too!?
And every other kind of feces, it seems.
For real?
K-Kaneki?
Hey, Nishiki! How's that poo taste?
Nishiki-kun, you smell like poo!
You're a disgrace as a ghoul.