Yes.
Thank you very much.
Take care.
Next patient, please!
Help...
Knock, knock...
I've finally found you.
Yamori...
I seem to have misplaced that
nifty little toy you made for me.
I want you to prepare a replacement.
Of course...
Splendid. I'll be back.
Dear...
Slowly, now.
There's no need to rush. Just keep up those spirals.
R-Right.
How is it?
If I were to compare it to yours,
this cup doesn't quite hit the mark.
Each cup of coffee is unique in that
it reflects the amount of effort poured into it.
Like when dealing with people,
coffee doesn't like to be rushed.
I see.
There's something you need to consider.
Anteiku isn't just your average coffee house.
It's also a place where the ghouls of
the 20th Ward can interact and feel at home.
Of course, we also gladly serve human customers here.
Just as we once did for you, right?
But if ghouls are trying their
hardest to blend in with society,
why would you go out of your way to serve human customers as well?
It's critical to understand human behavior in order to inhabit the world they live in.
Humans are living, breathing textbooks for ghouls like us.
Besides, I like them.
Humans, that is.
All right, I think it's about time I send you down to give Touka-chan a hand.
R-Right.
He likes humans? What part of them, exactly?
Okay, some other time—
Hey, Kaneki!
H-Hide! What are you doing here?
Silly, I came here to thank Touka-chan, of course!
Thank her?
She helped us out when we got
caught up in that mess, remember?
Huh?
Poor guy, looks like he hasn't fully recovered yet.
You okay?
Yeah.
That's good.
I hear Nishio-senpai is still recovering at the hospital since he had it pretty rough.
We were lucky to get away with just
a few scratches thanks to you, Touka-chan.
All right Kaneki, I'll catch you later.
Yeah, sure.
Thank you very much.
Make sure he doesn't find out about your ghoul situation.
I know.
If he catches even the slightest wind about us...
I'll slaughter him on the spot.
What!? But that's...
If you don't want that to happen, keep your damn mouth shut.
Welcome!
Touka-chan...
Ryouko-san!
Kaneki, towels!
Yes!
I'm sorry to bother you like this.
Don't worry, it's nothing.
Hinami, it's been a while.
Hinami...
Where is Yoshimura-san?
Inside.
Kaneki!
Hand her a new one.
Oh, here you go.
Thank you very much.
They're ghouls, right?
That's Fueguchi-san.
We'll be taking care of her from now on.
Taking care of?
Yeah, it's a bit of a long story.
Story? What happened?
Seriously, I've almost had it with you!
You're not even good for anything!
I'm well aware of that...
Oh, right. Did the manager tell you anything?
Huh?
About the Suits?
Suits?
The guys who walk around with those big suitcases.
This is the current status of the 11th Ward.
These patterns clearly indicate
the start of organized movements.
At this rate, it'll only be a
matter of time until a war is waged.
That concludes my report.
Does anyone else have anything further?
Amon Koutarou, First Class Investigator.
I'll start with this.
I believe everyone is aware
of the incident that happened three months ago,
where Jason from the 13th Ward initiated contact
with an S-rated ghoul from the 20th Ward, a binge eater.
The following piece of evidence
was left behind at the crime scene.
And that is?
A pair of medical pliers,
tailored for ghouls, supposedly.
Upon further analysis,
we have identified it as a Quinque weapon.
Jason's objective is currently unknown.
However, I'd like to direct your attention
towards the abrupt decline in binge predation lately.
In short, those ghouls might
be planning something in the 20th Ward.
I expected nothing less from the Academy's top student.
Good for you, Mado.
Having such a reliable partner gives you
more time to play with your toys, no?
Fortunately so.
Now, if you could just get this meeting over and done with,
I'd be spending my time on
something far more productive.
Blunt as ever, I see.
All right, I want you guys to stay on top of things in the 20th Ward. Got it?
Yes, sir.
With the quietest ward's sudden flare in ghoul activity,
something tells me that this
is a glimpse of things to come.
But our purpose here at the CCG
is to eradicate every last ghoul from Tokyo!
This is the one and only responsibility that we've been entrusted with!
Even now, that fact remains the same!
All right, let's stay focused and get right to it!
Yes, sir!
This meeting is now adjourned. Dismissed!
In any case, we're free to investigate the
20th Ward without any restrictions now.
Yes.
Or so we say, but we only have this one lead.
It's enough. We've grasped the end of the thread.
Now we just have to reel it in,
until we reach the catch at the other end.
Right.
The 20th Ward...
Mado-san?
The Gourmet, the binge eater, and Jason...
Give it a try.
M-Manager, I'm sorry but this is just...
Are you all right?
This bread tastes like a dried-up sponge
and the cheese smells like
my socks after an intense workout.
Well, that's quite the vivid imagination.
The trick to this is swallowing it whole without chewing.
Pretend to chew it about ten times for good measure.
You should also make chewing
noises for a more convincing act.
Then, be sure to throw it back up
before your body starts to digest it.
It'll be bad for your health otherwise.
Kaneki-kun,
with a little practice, I'm sure you can eat with your friend again when the time comes.
I'll do my best.
I have a present for you.
Sugar cubes?
They're a bit different on the inside.
If you dissolve them in coffee and drink it,
they'll keep your hunger at bay for a little while.
What exactly do they contain?
Some things are probably best left unsaid.
Still, if I have these...
Listen, Kaneki-kun.
Can I trouble you to stay late today?
Oh, of course. I don't mind.
I'd usually ask Touka-chan,
but she's busy studying for a test.
I'd like you to go procure some food in her stead.
P-Procure some food?
I-I can't kill anyone!
Worry not, you won't be harming anyone.
Anteiku provides food for our friends who don't wish to hurt people.
You understand the necessity for that, yes?
Yes.
But if we're not hurting anyone...
Then, would you mind taking it up with Yomo-kun for me?
U-Um, Yomo-san?
What exactly does "food procurement" mean?
For ghouls who don't wish to hurt people...
I wonder if that lady and her daughter from this morning are the same.
Get out.
Whoa, this is pretty high up.
What are we—
Don't do that.
Huh?
You'll fall.
I'm alive...
A lot of people die here.
Many of them come to throw their lives away.
So the people of Anteiku
choose to eat suicide victims...
Pack him in.
E-Excuse me?
I'm sorry, Mado-san. I was a second too slow.
Amon-kun, it's all about your senses.
Use your five senses.
Now then...
You there, any idea what this is?
Wh-What?
I'll ask you one more time.
Have you ever seen anything like this?
H-Hell if I know. What is it?
What do you wa—
A mask, you say?
That's right. I think it's time you had your own.
I see...
Touka-chan.
Yes?
Would you mind helping Kaneki-kun out with his mask tomorrow?
What!?
Just when I finally landed a day off, too.
Why should I have to spend it with this guy!?
Kaneki-kun would probably get lost if he went alone.
Not to mention, it's pretty dangerous around those parts.
That may be true, but he doesn't need one yet, does he?
Touka-chan...
There are Investigators
sniffing around the 20th Ward.
Doves!?
Doves?
They've already inflicted damage.
I'd like to prepare one for him right away, just in case.
All right.
Hey, Eyepatch.
Meet me in front of the train station tomorrow, 2:30.
Miss it by a minute and you're dead to me.
R-Right!
J-Jeez, what?
We've got some nice girls here!
Screw you, jerk!
Uta-san!
Hello?
Jeez, maybe he's asleep?
Boo.
What are you doing, Uta-san?
I went out of my way to pleasantly surprise you.
This is Uta-san. He'll make a mask for you.
That's me.
I'm K-Kaneki. It's nice to meet you—
You smell... different.
Touka-san, I understand the Doves are on the prowl.
Yes.
The 20th Ward is nice and quiet,
no one ever bothers to check us out.
I assume this is Rize-san's impact.
Tsukiyama seems to be pushing his luck lately too.
Ah yes, that guy...
Um, is the 20th Ward known for
being reasonably quiet? I wouldn't know.
Live somewhere else for a bit,
and the difference will be clear as day.
If you're up to it, you can stay over for the night.
If you're lucky, you'll get to experience
some cannibalism. That's always fun.
I-I'm fine, thanks.
Having a place like Anteiku must be pretty great for you.
Sit over there. I'll take your measurements.
Do you have any allergies?
No...
What about rubber or metal?
They're fine—
You want a full mask?
Uh...
Well, it is your first time.
Maybe a half-mask instead.
S-Sure...
Cute eyepatch. Are you a fan of it?
When I get hungry, this eye turns red
regardless of whether or not I want it to.
You could always just fill up, you know.
Care for a snack?
I-I'm good.
Kaneki-kun, do you have anyone special?
Huh? I guess not.
You're like one of those, how do I say it...
Those guys who get pampered more
by older ladies than girls their own age.
U-Um, are these questions relevant to anything at all?
Yes. I feel more motivated if I get to know you better.
What about Touka-san?
Her? She's kind of scary.
Scary? You think so?
She looks like a dedicated hard worker to me.
A hard worker?
In order for us to blend into human society,
we need a mask that should never be taken off.
If someone catches onto us
for even a moment, we're all done for.
That's why we have to carry ourselves in
day-to-day life without getting too involved.
She lives her life accepting that risk.
Her job at Anteiku, and even going to school...
Is the risk really worth it?
That's a good question.
But you know, whenever the occasional human customer walks in, I get a different feeling.
My pulse races. It's hard to explain,
but it's a good feeling.
A hard worker, huh?
While I'm... nothing...
Touka-chan!
What?
What exactly is Hinami-chan's situation like?
Is there any use in you knowing something like that?
I want to know!
I want to know...
If there's anything that I can do...
She has to live away from her father now,
so she must be anxious.
She isn't usually like this.
So that's how it is...
A-Anyway, Touka-chan, what are those masks used for?
Huh? You came without even knowing what they're for?
Uh, yeah.
Jeez, that manager...
If you ever bump into a couple of Doves, and by that I mean Investigators,
you don't want them catching even a glimpse of your face.
That's why we have Uta-san making a mask for you.
Screw those damned shitheads.
You filth...
Hey, shitbags, ever seen this before?
Huh? No, you piece of—
What about you?
I-I dunno jack shi—
I mean, no, no I haven't!
For sure?
Yes, I'm sure—
Thank you for your cooperation.
Let's go, Amon-kun.
Maybe we'll have better luck somewhere else.
Yes, you're right.
All right...
Um, I... T-Take your time!
You saw her eating, then?
That's no good, Kaneki-kun.
Girls are sensitive when it comes to that stuff.
I see...
Here.
You can bring this up and apologize as well.
Hinami-chan, may I come in?
Yes.
Sorry about earlier.
Here, as an apology.
Go ahead, at your leisure.
U-Um...
Yes?
Um, Onii-san, I...
Well, which one are you?
I'm sorry. You're completely different from everyone else.
If you were one of us,
I'd be able to tell from miles away.
I've been through some pretty hard times, you see.
My body has the tendencies of a ghoul,
so if I had to say, I think I'm closer to what you are.
I suppose you could say I have the
mind of a human and the body of a ghoul.
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have asked.
I-It's no big deal.
Hey, that's a pretty cute drawing.
What kind of animal is it?
Um, it's my father.
Y-You did a really good job on him!
Your father, huh?
I hope you'll be able to see him again soon.
That's Monochrome of Rainbows, isn't it?
Huh? Oh, yeah.
Hinami-chan, you read Takatsuki's books?
That's impressive, given how tough they are to read.
Oh, but those are short stories so I guess they're relatively easier.
Hinami-chan, which story is your favorite?
U-Um, Small Rain... Night Time...
Small Rain Night Time?
Oh, you mean Showers at Sunset.
That was the prototype for Egg of the Black Goat.
Pro-type? Showers at Sunset? U-Um...
How do you read this?
That's "hydrangea."
Hydrangea? Like the flower?
Yes.
Th-Then, what about this one?
That's written like "thin ice,"
but pronounced "black ice."
"Black ice..."
But at other times, it can also be read as
"lackluster" in more sophisticated terms.
There's a pretty ring to it, don't you think?
Yes!
Hydrangea...
That's admirable of you.
Showers at Sunset...
You're even diligently taking notes.
I-I don't go to school,
so I write down the things I learn in here.
I see. I have an idea, Hinami-chan.
How about I teach you new words like this every now and then?
You mean it?
Yeah.
Onii-chan, thank you!
Okay, then how about this one?
That one is...
Seriously? Suits in the 20th Ward?
Definitely not your lucky day, huh?
Yeah. The 20th Ward is nowhere near safe anymore.
Damn, this stings!
That Gourmet guy has been on a rampage lately.
He must've grabbed their attention.
Did a Dove do that to you?
Nah, this is from something else.
Man, this is seriously killing me!
Man up, will you?
Get Doctor Fueguchi to have a look at you or some—
I guess what they say about shit
sticking together is true, after all.
Yes.
N-No way...
Now then, I'm curious...
What kind of scum is this piece of shit going to cling to next time?
Good morning, everyone!
Morning!
N-No, there's no need to...
Morning, Onii-chan!
Morning, Hinami-chan.
What are you smiling about, dummy?
Get back to work.
Welcome!
A most delightful aroma.
I really do feel more...
composed here.
Onee-chan, there's a bird on the veranda!
It must be lost.
It looks wounded.
We have to treat it!
Onee-chan!
Why are you running away!?
Wait up!
Onee-chan! Wait up!
I'm afraid of birds!
Maybe I should give it a name.
Its owner will probably show up soon.
But...
Fine then, we'll deep fry it.
Onee-chan...