Tsukiyama!
It's been a while, Kirishima-san.
What do you want?
Friendly as always, I see.
Though I suppose that's just part of your charm.
You're sickening, you pig.
The man with the eyepatch over there...
You're new, right?
U-Um...
What's your name?
K-Kaneki.
What a marvelous aroma.
Hey, you.
You're being a nuisance, not to mention gross.
Take a hike already.
A bit harsh, aren't we?
I'll be back some other time for a cup of coffee.
Yoshimura should be around then.
O-Okay...
Charmed to meet you.
Farewell, Kaneki-kun.
Until we meet again...
Who was that guy?
You'd better keep an eye out for him.
He's the scourge of the 20th Ward.
And here we have a national specialty, the eyes of virgins.
Thank you.
Kaneki-kun, was it?
How utterly captivating...
that scent of his.
What?
Another jam bun today?
It's fine. This is as good as cafeteria food gets.
That's not good enough!
You're still a growing girl, you know.
Which one shall we choose?
Fried chicken!
Say "ahh!"
Huh? It's fine.
There's no way I'm gonna let you off with just bread.
Now open up!
Fine...
I fiddled around a bit with the seasoning.
What do you think?
What is it?
Ow!
Well, it's pretty good.
You're just saying that.
No, I mean it.
Don't vomit! Don't vomit! Don't vomit! Don't vomit! Don't vomit, damn it!
Don't vomit...
Thanks for the food.
I ate it, Yoriko.
Kaneki-kun.
Hi there.
Oh, hi, uh...
Tsukiyama Shuu.
May I?
Oh, of course.
Many thanks.
Tsukiyama-san, what brings you to Kamii University?
What if I were to say...
that I came here to see you?
Huh? Uh, well, I don't know.
This man is the Gourmet, the scourge of the 20th Ward...
You seem to be quite the intellectual savant.
Or so I've heard from a regular of Anteiku.
I wouldn't say that. You flatter me, really.
Books are wonderful, aren't they?
A single sentence can whisk you
away into the wildest of fantasies.
I believe that by immersing yourself in a literary work,
you gain a clearer view of the author's vision.
By that point, you are truly free to roam
through the author's radiant macrocosm.
As soon as your soul enamors
itself with those wonders within,
you can let go of your real self along with the rest of reality.
You're an avid reader, aren't you?
It was during the worst moments of my life
that I found refuge in literature.
He and I... We're awfully alike.
What a pleasant surprise.
You read Takatsuki too?
Oh, yes.
Though ingenuous at first,
there's a profoundness to be discovered in his words.
I can't help but gravitate towards the subtlety of his writing style.
I, too, adore his style of writing.
I see. Takatsuki, huh?
Listen, Kaneki-kun.
I know of a great café that's run by a passionate reader.
If you'd like, how about accompanying me sometime?
Rumor has it that Takatsuki Sen stops by from time to time.
He does?
Actually, on second thought...
Kirishima-san must have said something about me.
No, it's just...
Oh no, it's fine.
I've always been easily misunderstood.
I've been lonely ever since
Kamishiro-san passed away, too.
Kamishiro? You mean Kamishiro Rize-san?
You remind me of the person she once was.
It's rare to see fellow ghouls
with a burning passion for books.
I merely wish to find someone
who'll share a like-minded conversation with me.
H-Hey...
If you're fine with me, then...
Well then, I'll see you this Sunday at three o'clock.
He didn't seem like such a bad person...
Kaneki-kun, you're done for the day.
Oh, right.
Have a nice evening.
Oh, and Kaneki-kun...
Yomo-kun told me he was waiting for you downstairs.
Yomo-san? Downstairs?
Um, where are we going?
Silent as always.
Doves have entered the 20th Ward.
Huh? And by that you mean...
If it comes down to it, you'll have
to take matters into your own hands.
Let's go!
H-Hold on!
Dodging seems to be your strongest suit,
but that's all you can do right now.
R-Right.
Meet me here every day after work. I'll train you.
All right.
Would you like to come with me?
There's someone who wants to meet you.
So you're the infamous Kaneki-kun, are you?
I'm so glad you came to see me.
Ren-chan and Uta told me all sorts of things about you.
I'm Itori, the bar owner.
Nice to meet you.
Th-The pleasure is all mine.
Oh relax, no need to be so formal! Loosen up, Kanekicchi!
U-Um... How long have you all known each other for?
Well, we've always been a rotten bunch.
Back in the days, Ren and Uta
rarely played nice with each other.
In fact, they turned the entire 4th Ward upside down with their crazy antics.
But we're the best of friends now, am I right?
Whatever.
Ren-chan was pretty much an untamed beast, back then.
Th-That bad?
Yep. Kinda like the male version of an angry Touka-san.
Spot on, right?
That is pretty terrifying.
Enough talk about me.
Itori, didn't you have something to say to him?
Ah, that's right!
Here, drink up.
Oh no, I'm still underage.
It's not wine, silly!
This is amazing!
I've never seen a one-eyed ghoul before!
Sorry, sorry.
Don't worry. We're all ghouls, right?
Here, a token of my apology.
I wonder if the other one-eye is like him too.
Who knows?
U-Um, is there someone else
besides me with only one, uh...
Oh, did that pique your interest?
Yes.
All right.
You see Kanekicchi, when a human
and ghoul love each other very much,
what do you think happens when they get busy?
A human and a ghoul's baby?
It dies.
Biological impotence.
The chances of getting pregnant itself are pretty low to begin with.
But in extremely rare cases, one is born.
A half-ghoul, half-human baby.
A half-ghoul, half-human...
The abilities of a hybrid ghoul far exceed those of a pure one.
And this baby...
only had the red eye on one side.
But then again, these stories are just urban myths.
A one-eyed ghoul...
U-Um...
Oh? What is it? Ask me anything.
About Rize-san...
Do you know anything about Kamishiro Rize-san?
And why exactly do you ask?
This whole mess with my body
began when I got involved with her.
And yet, I know next to nothing about her...
So that's how it is. Rize, huh?
She was a troublemaker, her death shrouded in mystery.
Indeed, her so-called death has spawned
nothing but rumors over these last few months.
"So-called death"? But the accident...
Think about it. Was that really just your regular, old accident, Kaneki Ken-kun?
Itori...
You see, I heard someone was standing on top of the building when the accident took place on that fateful day.
Huh? S-So you're saying it wasn't a coincidence?
Somebody killed Rize...
Or something.
Itori!
I'm just saying!
It's nothing but a rumor, all right? A rumor!
Who...
Who would do something like that?
Kaneki-kun.
Kaneki-kun?
Oh, yes?
Is something the matter?
Oh, not at all.
Um, Tsukiyama-san.
Hm? What is it?
What kind of things did you talk about with Rize-san?
Oh, Kamishiro-san?
We conversed about things such as literature...
and of course, we also discussed fine dining.
Tsukiyama-kun, I appreciate the thought,
but I have absolutely no interest
in joining your exclusive gourmet club.
W-Why not?
Are you not in pursuit of the
finest tastes—of even greater heights!?
Well, don't you see?
Anything you manage to serve me just won't be enough.
Of course, the exquisite flavor sampled whilst eating is an immense pleasure.
But for a ghoul to think so highly of himself by simply claiming he has "taste?"
I find your cute little human pretense
quite absurd, don't you, Tsukiyama-kun?
That contemptuous harlot...
A crude sow like her dares to make a mockery of my culinary refinement!
U-Um, Tsukiyama-san?
Ow!
Goodness, how could I have allowed that to happen?
I'm sorry.
I'm fine. It's just a little cut.
L-Let me make it up to you, Kaneki-kun.
It's not much, but there's a place that Kamishiro-san used to visit regularly.
Would you like to go there together?
A place that Rize-san visited regularly?
Yes, I'd like that very much.
Well, then.
Now that it's settled, let's head there right now.
How is your cut doing?
Oh, it's fine.
The bleeding seems to have stopped.
I'll wash this later and—
O-Oh, er, no it's fine. Don't worry about it.
I'll wash it myself.
That was too close for my liking.
I can't believe I lost it for a second there and startled him.
Be cool. Keep it smooth, all right?
Tsukiyama Shuu, it won't be long now...
This sweet essence...
Such tranquil harmony...
Finding this novel delicacy...
Delights me more so than the discovery of a new star!
Oh, Monsieur Savarin...
You were absolutely right...
Why am I taking a shower, anyway?
Kaneki-sama.
Oh, yes?
I have prepared some clothes here for you.
Feel free to take your time.
Okay, thanks.
So this is Rize-san's favorite place.
I brought you a cup of coffee.
Enjoy.
Excuse me, where is Tsukiyama-san?
What's going on!?
Ladies and gentlemen,
the moment you've all been waiting for!
Without further ado, today's main dish!
Our entrée for today is an unusual cut of meat.
A ghoul, of all things!
Ghoul?
Cannibalism doesn't quite appeal to me.
Brought to you by Mr. MM!
Oh, Mr. MM!
It's Mr. MM!
My fellow esteemed diners.
The flesh of a ghoul has a crass flavor not worthy of devouring.
Of course, those of you with refined palates will regard this as nothing new.
Tsu-Tsukiyama-san!
W-Why?
My attention was instantly
riveted on this man's alluring scent.
Though he is a ghoul, the rich aroma
of human blood still runs through his veins.
Oh, he's right!
How delightfully grand!
Magnificent!
Ah, I can't take it!
Are you not enthralled?
A ghoul with a human scent.
How does that sound!?
I've been set up.
This whole thing was just an elaborate ploy.
We shall venture into the unknown in the pursuit of new smells and tastes...
Now!
Let us bask in the ultimate epicurean delight!
And now, the scrapper
who will be serving today's main dish!
Say, Madame A...
Yes, PG-sama?
Which scrapper have you brought with you today?
Today it's my all-time favorite, Taro-chan.
'Tis a pleasure to meet ya.
Don't let him get away!
Whuh? W-Wait up now!
I said wait up!
Run Taro-chan, run!
Mama!
His owner, Madame A,
offers a few words of encouragement!
I've gotta get out of here! How do I get out!?
I-I gotta do something!
Where d'ya think ya going?
Crush him to a pulp!
Shit, I have no way out!
It's no use. He didn't even flinch.
Is something the matter, Kaneki-kun?
Why don't you release your kagune?
The clock is ticking.
There's gotta be some way out of here!
Think Kaneki, think!
Shoot!
What happened there?
Did his legs cramp up?
Ladies and gentlemen, it appears the drug is starting to take effect.
Don't tell me that coffee was...
A-All right! I g-gotchu now!
Hell yeah! Wring his damn neck!
Rip his guts out!
Fun! This is so much fun!
Bye-bye, Kaneki-kun.
Huh? What's that?
Could he be...
A... A one-eyed ghoul!
One-eyed!?
One-eyed? For real?
Walk it off, Taro-chan! Get up!
Hurting! It hurts! Hurts!
One-eyed... How incredibly rare!
MM-sama?
Are you all right?
What an absolute luxury!
Get up! Taro-chan!
Mama!
It's no good...
That's it! Who's a good boy? You are!
Who's Mama's little boy? You are!
Mama is so excited!
That hurts!
Ladies and gentlemen,
I'm terribly sorry for all the commotion.
Never would I have imagined
him to be a fabled one-eyed ghoul.
However, I don't intend
to spoil the banquet we all came for.
How does this sound?
It hurts!
Why don't we dine on Madame A's
pet boy instead, the scrapper?
Taro-chan! Taro-chan!
It hurts...
Taro-chan, you...
Useless sack of meat!
Embarrass me, will you!?
I hope you get eaten quickly, damn you!
Mama...
Did you have fun, Kaneki-kun?
This was only supposed to be a joke between the two of us.
I may have been a bit hard on you. Can we move on?
This unique treasure...
He's going to be all mine.
Yes, that's it!
Yes, Tsukiyama-kun! That's the face I want! Nice feeling!
More! Express yourself even more! There it is!
Absolutely fantastic.
This is great, Tsukiyama-kun! I can't praise you enough!
Um... What's going on here?
Oh, well, you know.
Apparently, I'll be making a guest appearance on the upcoming cover for a comic book.
Kaneki-kun, care to join me?
Well?
Huh? Uh, I think I'll pass.