Help! Somebody!
Tsukiyama-san!
Thank God you're here!
Tsukiyama-san, help—
Kaneki-kun.
Nice to eat you!
I heard there's another Dove prowling around these parts.
How many have they sent out now?
I'm too scared to go out on my own.
The 20th Ward isn't going to be safe for much longer.
Kaneki-kun, I'm letting you off for today.
I've asked Kaya-chan to take over.
Oh, sure.
Where's Touka-chan?
She's feeling a bit under the weather today.
Kaneki-kun, why don't you pay her a visit?
Oh, but...
Touka-chan just lives a floor above us, after all.
Kirishima... Ayato?
Touka-chan, keep an eye on Hinami for me, all right?
Hinami! Play nice with your Onee-chan, okay?
Hello.
Well?
To what do I owe the pleasure?
Um, I heard you weren't feeling
well so I came to check up on you.
No "get well soon" gifts?
Uh, well...
Onii-chan, how do you read this?
Which one?
Let's see...
That's "sweet olive."
Is that a flower, too?
Yep.
I'll put on some coffee.
Oh, Touka-chan, I can do th—
It's fine.
You're helping Hinami out with her vocabulary, right?
But if you're not feeling too good...
I just ate too much.
You... ate too much?
She wouldn't...
No!
Yoriko!?
What's she doing here?
Yoriko, what's up?
Sorry for suddenly showing up like this.
I was worried since you missed school today, Touka-chan.
Oh, so you came to see me?
That, and...
No way!
Touka-chan, you couldn't possibly be...
Um, this is Kaneki, and he's...
Touka-chan, I made this for you.
Share it with him!
Hold on, you've got this all wrong.
Hey, Yoriko!
Er, have I done something I shouldn't have?
What are you going to do with all that?
Eat it, obviously!
Yoriko made it for me, after all.
But that's just going to worsen your condition...
Thanks for the food.
She must be someone precious to her.
Oh, what to do?
What to do?
How best to prepare delectable Kaneki-kun?
I've got it!
This transcendent feast...
requires third-party intervention...
in a maestoso venue,
with Kaneki-kun reaching a crescendo...
until at last, I arrive...
with a fortissimo!
Oh, Kaneki-kun...
He got me good.
Yomo-san can really pack a punch.
Nishio-senpai!
Why don't we kick things off by snapping his arms in two?
After what he did to Hide and me...
U-Um, excuse me...
Don't you think he's had enough?
K-Kaneki Ken...
Is this piece of shit called Nishiki a friend of yours or something?
Uh, I wouldn't exactly say that...
Oh, cool. So can you do us a favor and get lost?
We're about to cannibalize him, you see.
C-Cannibalize?
You wanna take me on, boy?
He's a snail compared to Yomo-san.
Maybe all that training is starting to pay off.
You little shi—
I hit him...
Screw you...
Playing the knight in shining armor...
Is this the place?
Nishiki-kun!
Where have you been!?
You're all beaten up again!
I'm so hungry it's driving me insane.
Let it go, Kimi.
But this guy is...
I know...
The shitty little brat who turned my insides out...
Kimi-san.
You're a human, right?
What are you doing with a ghoul?
I want him by my side.
Even though he takes the lives of other people?
As long as he doesn't harm my parents or siblings, I'm sure...
I'm sure that my feelings won't change.
He needs to eat, after all.
I... see.
Kaneki-kun, is there anything
I can do to help Nishiki-kun!?
If he doesn't eat any flesh, then he'll most likely...
But what am I supposed to do about that?
Kimi-san, let me...
see what I can do.
Thank you.
I must do everything in my power to help him.
I'll have to trust Kaneki-kun with the rest.
Good evening, mademoiselle.
Now, if you would kindly lend me
your assistance with a little something.
It's locked tight.
I guess there really are humans who
choose to stay with ghouls, despite the risks.
A rose and a note?
There's only one person who'd do such a thing...
Dear Kaneki-kun, let us share a
most enjoyable dinner at midnight.
The woman you were speaking with
earlier will certainly delight in your company.
How does a pleasant evening
with just the three of us sound?
Kimi-san!
Nishio-san!
Kimi still hasn't come home...
Damn it!
Why would Tsukiyama...
This is the worst.
Why did this have to happen?
Why!?
I'm the one Tsukiyama-san is after.
I'll accept his invitation and bring Kimi-san back with me.
I'm coming with you.
In this state!?
What are you even saying!?
Don't be ridiculous!
You expect me to laze about at home
when Kimi is caught up in this mess!?
I have to go.
Kaneki-kun,
are you perhaps a fan of Beethoven?
Tsukiyama!
Nishio-kun, I don't recall ever inviting you.
Give Kimi back to me!
Unfortunately, that's not going to be possible.
She shall add a dynamic spice, here at tonight's banquet.
I want Kaneki-kun to devour her
tender flesh at its absolute prime!
What!?
To be more precise,
I'd like to delight in Kaneki-kun's
flesh as he ravages her intestines!
Yes, that's what I want!
You queer piece of shit...
You're sick.
Sick? I must say, this is quite a shock.
Well, if that's how you really feel...
Kaneki-kun, everything I do is entirely your fault.
Take responsibility for your actions.
Do you realize just how deliciously tempting you are?
Nishio-san!
You can take it nice and easy over there.
Still horribly clumsy, I see.
You remind me of a newborn chick, waddling about.
Let me show you.
This...
is what you call a punch.
And this...
is what you call a kick.
Let's see, now.
What kind of attack would you like to stomach next?
How about this one?
Your plain, old, sneak attack.
Touka-chan!
My, my.
Things are certainly taking a turn for the worst.
Oh, how it's been so long...
since I've gotten a scratch.
I'm gonna put my foot so far up your ass
that you won't be eating for a week, Tsukiyama.
What a dirty mouth you have there, Kirishima-san.
He's not hurt!
You used to be as sharp as a knife.
But you're just a dull blade now, it seems.
Otherwise, this injury would've
taken longer than ten seconds to heal.
That was just a friendly greeting.
Instantly crushing you to a pulp
would be extremely boring, right?
My goodness, you sure are a handful.
Though...
I suppose that's what makes you so cute.
Your reactions are as speedy as ever.
You were only fourteen back then,
and I was eighteen.
Those cold, piercing eyes of yours,
like a pair of crystal shards...
are something I can never forget.
You sicken me.
I'm about ready to throw up here!
Yes, back in those days where
I fell head over heels for you.
I refuse to be eaten as someone's fancy meal.
I'll be taking Kimi-san with me.
A splendid kick, Kaneki-kun.
Oh, deary me...
If memory serves me correctly...
Like this, no?
Well, then. I'll help myself to a sample...
Absolutely outstanding!
What a divine flavor this is!
Coalescing so passionately over
my tongue, this profound harmony!
Oh, God! It exceeds even my wildest dreams!
But alas, now I seek even greater pleasures!
I refuse to let the curtains close
on the luxury that is Kaneki-kun!
Finally, the time has come for me
to play the part of a most gracious host!
The raw intensity you possessed
back then was truly breathtaking.
But now, you're just a flickering flame.
Something has ignited the heat in your eyes.
What a shame, Kirishima-san.
That affection...
was something you really didn't need.
Touka-chan!
It's rude to interrupt one's dinner!
Stop it!
I'm the one you want to eat!
Have you forgotten?
I only want to devour you as you eat someone else.
How can you take the lives of other people so easily?
People's lives?
I'm an equal-opportunity carnivore.
Rather, when looking at life as a whole,
humans take far more than we do.
But unlike them, humans are the only things we kill.
What is this unflattering scar?
Kimi...
Nishiki...
No...
I really don't want to eat a person.
There's nothing we can do about it.
It's the same thing when humans eat cows or pigs.
But I feel bad for them.
Everything's going to be okay. I'll take care of you.
Work?
That's right.
We can't keep living like stray cats forever, right?
But still...
Don't worry! No one's going to find out.
Okay, I'm heading out!
Have a safe trip.
I'll be going, now.
See you later.
Well, I got fired again.
Not again.
What is it?
You've grown quite a bit, Nishiki.
You look just like Dad.
Who was that?
The manager at my workplace.
Which way did they go!?
Search the area over there!
Sis! Sis!
Stay with me, Sis!
Nishiki...
Keep on living, by yourself...
No! Don't you die, Sis!
Don't you dare die on me!
Live...
So you're the one who turned her in, after all.
I-I beg you, spare me...
You reap what you sow.
For both you and Sis.
There's no way I'll ever place my trust in someone.
Hey, you.
Did you forget your change?
Huh? Oh...
Here you go.
Thank you very much.
She was a pale-looking girl.
But who knows? Maybe she'll be useful in the long run.
It's a pretty nice name.
Huh?
"Kimi," meaning "noble future."
Was it your mom or dad who gave you that name?
Hm? Hey...
What? I just don't get it.
Kaneki, you shitty little punk!
This wound isn't healing!
Flesh...
I need to eat some flesh!
Nishiki-kun?
Nishiki-kun! What happened!?
Is this blood!?
Boy, am I glad I reached out to you!
Flesh, let me feed on your flesh!
Forget it... I don't have the strength.
Nishiki-kun... You're a ghoul?
It's all over now...
I'll get reported, and then it's lights out for me...
A death just like my sister's...
God, what a shitty life it's been.
Nishiki-kun.
Did you know?
When I heard your voice calling out for me that day,
I had lost my mom, dad, and little brother to a fiery wreck.
I was so devastated, I thought I would rather be dead.
But you were there for me, Nishiki-kun. You saved me.
That's why...
it's okay. Live on.
I don't need any more.
What are you, stupid?
I find it hard to place faith in the humanity of others.
But if it's someone like you...
then maybe being betrayed wouldn't be so bad.
What is your deal, for God's sake?
You don't stand a chance
against me without your kagune!
The strength of a ghoul largely depends on their kagune.
If your kagune is the engine,
then a human's flesh is the gasoline!
A poor diet can only lead
to an unsatisfactory performance.
It's... exactly as he says.
Touka-chan...
I didn't expect Yoriko's food to let me down here...
Now then, enough of the idle talk.
A persistent pest, aren't you?
Shut the hell up!
Stop bothering me! Stop bothering me! Stop bothering me!
Let's get along, all right, Nishio-kun?
Nothing...
There's nothing else...
Kimi is all I have.
Nothing else...
If you ever lay a hand on her, I'll kill you...
Even if it costs me my life,
I'll fucking kill you!
At this rate...
A human's flesh is the gasoline...
Fuel...
Touka-chan.
Who's stronger at full strength, you or Tsukiyama?
We were about even, a long time ago.
I have an idea, Touka-chan.
You're gone, now.
I'm just about this close to pulverizing you.
Tsukiyama!
Here I go.
Don't look.
He belongs to me!
He belongs to you?
Don't make me laugh.
There's not a single thing here...
that belongs to you.