Here I go.
He belongs to me!
He belongs to you?
Don't make me laugh.
There's not a single thing here...
that belongs to you.
Calmato.
Amazing...
So that's Touka-chan's kagune.
I'm delighted, Kirishima-san!
To think that I'd sustain this much damage
from a kagune so equally-matched to mine!
I didn't think I'd get to see this side of you again.
It's as if the smoldering passion from way back then...
is being rekindled anew!
Allow me to garnish Kaneki-kun...
with your organs as trimmings!
This unexpected hors d'oeuvre!
I'm truly grateful.
Not bad, Kirishima-san.
It seems I have no other choice.
It's absolutely not what I'd hoped for...
but tactically speaking,
I need a bite!
Nishiki-kun...
What are you,
a zombie!?
Let me go! Let me go! Let me go! Let me go!
Let go of me!
Kimi...
I've had enough out of y—
The show mustn't end here, no?
This is going to take...
an awfully long time to heal.
Kaneki-kun, for God's sake...
Just one bite...
Just one—
bite.
Why don't you just keel over and eat your own damn flesh?
You shitty Gourmet.
Kimi...
Nishiki-kun?
Just you wait...
I'm coming to help you now.
Nishiki...
Stand aside.
Touka-chan?
She knows about both you and Kaneki, right?
I can't let such a dangerous woman
escape with her life.
Touka-chan!
You can't!
She's the equivalent of what Hide is to me,
or what Yoriko-chan is to you.
What if it was Yoriko-chan up there instead of Kimi-san?
Would you be able to kill Yoriko-chan?
Shut up!
I have to get rid of her...
To make sure that never happens!
Nishiki-kun?
How beautiful...
Oh, um...
What's with that?
Nishiki-kun?
Nishiki-kun!
Thank God...
How am I...
beautiful?
After that incident we had at the church,
All right, it's perfect!
there were a number of changes made around Anteiku.
Good work.
We're still just gettting ready to open, you know.
Don't sweat the small details.
What are you doing!?
N-Nishio-senpai!?
Hey, Nagachika.
I see that rotten look on your face is the same as ever.
For one, Nishio-san joined us at Anteiku.
For Kimi-san's sake as well,
I think you should stop taking the lives of others for food.
With the food that we provide,
you'd be able to live a rather guilt-free life as a ghoul.
However, we make sure each person earns his keep.
We'll have you work here from now on, Nishio-kun.
Well, Nishio-san, I gotta say...
The longer I stare at you, the less you fit in with Anteiku's classy atmosphere.
I'll kick you out.
We're only getting ready to open right now.
Why did you decide to work at Anteiku anyway?
Stop poking around. I have my reasons.
Don't tell me you're after Touka-chan!
Like I'd have any interest in that witless girl!
Speaking of Touka-chan, is she still not feeling well?
Yeah.
Ever since that day, Touka-chan has refused to come in for work.
I... I...
I want to be with Dad!
What was that about?
Who knows?
There's all sorts of mysteries to life.
Oh, crap! I've got class!
Thanks for everything!
Hinami-chan?
It's all my fault.
Without her dad here, I have to handle things for the both of us.
If I may ask, why is Hinami-chan so upset?
We haven't heard anything from him for some time now.
So she insists on going to see him.
Where is her father right now?
Yamori...
It's nice and quiet here today, huh?
Take this and get going already.
Very nice.
You do some fine craftsmanship.
I'll catch that woman with this...
W-Would you mind not coming around here anymore?
It seems like I've made a bad name for myself.
I just want to live in peace.
Please.
I understand.
Hinami...
Ryouko...
I'll see you soon.
But before that, I wish you'd tell me something first.
Since when were you a human's puppet on a string?
He...
He was apparently caught up in some dangerous business back in the 13th Ward.
But once Hinami was born, he cut all those ties for us.
He really is a good man.
To Hinami and me, he really is...
All right, then.
U-Um...
It'll be fine. I'm her mother, after all.
If I don't spoil Hinami, then who will?
A Suit...
What are Doves doing here?
It looks like our gamble paid off, didn't it, Amon-kun?
Using small fry to lure the monsters out.
Then again, this one seems to be a monster right to its very core.
Mado-san, that's...
Jason.
What's the big fish of the 13th Ward doing swimming around here?
Well, why don't we hear it from the horse's mouth itself?
S-rated... Jason of the 13th Ward.
Hinami?
It's Mom. Can you open up for me?
No! I don't want to talk to you!
Hinami, this is your—
I want to see Dad!
Why!? Why won't you let me?
I hate you, Mom!
Enough, Hinami!
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have raised my voice.
You miss him, don't you?
I'm sure Dad misses you too, Hinami.
But you know, we'll only make things difficult for him if we go see him now.
I'm sorry I've put you through all this.
Jason!
Jason! Jason!
Those are some good moves.
I'll play with you for two minutes.
My apologies.
I didn't step in close enough.
Don't worry. You can nail him with the next one.
Yes.
You seem...
awfully fragile.
Are you okay, Amon-kun?
Yes!
Catch your breath.
What a shame.
A shame indeed.
Nice, nice.
Feeling sleepy?
Not on my watch!
Time's up.
Let's play again sometime.
Damn him.
Mado-san?
Hm. My Quinque broke.
Let's see now...
what use might this scum have in store for us?
Hinami...
Mom misses your dad too.
Oh?
Mom...
Hinami!
Good grief...
Hinami, I'm so sorry.
It's okay. Don't cry, Mom.
I won't cry anymore. Thank you, Hinami.
Let's wait together...
for Dad to come home.
So Jason managed to escape?
My Quinque broke.
We couldn't have stopped him either way.
Even so...
As long as we keep picking them off one by one,
I'm sure another opportunity will present itself.
You're right.
We can definitely use this.
All right. Since you've held up all this time,
I want to buy you a present to show you I'm sorry.
Is there anything you want?
Okay, you think long and hard about it.
Thanks, Mom!
No, thank you.
What do you want?
U-Um... About tomorrow's shift...
Pass.
Y-You know—
That woman... I couldn't kill her.
Earlier,
Hinami-chan and Ryouko-san were fighting...
but they were able to patch things up in the end.
I saw the two of them and thought, "Families sure are nice."
I realized that the affection between mother and child doesn't depend on whether they're ghoul or human.
That shouldn't be a surprise.
But before this all happened to me,
I didn't have a clue.
If we could all come to terms with that...
Then Nishio-senpai and Kimi-san's relationship
could serve as a beacon that guides the way
for how things between a human and ghoul could be.
And what did you want, again?
Oh, uh, nothing...
I shouldn't have senselessly opened my mouth back there,
without knowing the relationship between you and Yoriko-chan.
I'm sorry.
Okay then, I'll let the manager know.
When she was first accepted into society,
I'm sure Touka-chan must have had the same thoughts.
But if she had been rejected even once for her efforts...
there would have been no going back.
The same goes for Hide and I.
How is Onee-chan doing?
Huh, good question.
I hope she starts feeling better soon.
Yeah.
Onii-chan, let's do the next one. How do you read this?
Let's see... That's "cloudburst."
"Cloudburst"?
It refers to a moment when it suddenly starts raining.
Hinami?
Oh, Mom!
Are you learning new words?
Yup!
Thanks for always taking the time to help Hinami out.
Oh, it's no problem at all.
I'll be on my way, then.
Thanks, Onii-chan.
See you tomorrow.
Okay.
Mom, look! I learned all of the vocabulary in this book!
Really? Good job!
So now, Mom...
What is it?
I want a new book.
Huh?
I want to learn even more words, so I can surprise Dad!
Dad's birthday is also coming up soon, right?
So...
You want to give him a book as a present?
Then, why don't we go to the bookstore together?
Thank you very much.
Looks like it's going to rain soon.
You're right! It's starting to rain!
See? Mom knows best, after all.
Yup! Oh, Mom.
Yes?
This is called a cloudburst!
Cloudburst?
When it suddenly starts raining, it's called a cloudburst.
Onii-chan said so!
Kaneki-san knows all sorts of things, huh?
I wonder if Dad knows that.
Let's ask him sometime.
If I know something that even Dad doesn't, that means I'm pretty amazing, right?
Yes, it does.
What's up with you today, Hinami?
It's been so long since I've gone out with you, Mom!
Come on Hinami, you're getting wet!
Hinami, let's head home.
Mom?
Weren't we going to one other place?
I just remembered something else I have to do.
Hinami?
It's Dad!
Mom, Dad is somewhere nearby!
I-It couldn't be...
He came for us!
Ah, Hinami!
This way, Mom!
Hinami, wait!
Dad!
Wait for me!
Wait for—
Hinami!
It's Dad's scent!
Dad!
Dad?
Hinami!
What is it... That smell?
Nice weather today, isn't it?
Though I wouldn't want the rain to come down any harder than this.
Your dying screams wouldn't be able to reach my ears, after all.
May I please have just a moment of your time,
Fueguchi-san?
Mom...
Hinami.
Run away.
Mom?
It's okay. Head on back to Anteiku, I'll catch up soon.
I promise I'll come back.
No...
No!
I want to stay here with you, Mom!
Kusaba! Use your Q-Bullets!
Y-Yes!
Go!
H-Hold it!
Was that supposed to be an act of motherly love?
How sweetly sickening.
I won't let you pass!
Somebody...
Somebody!
Onii-chan... Onee-chan!
Mom!
Hey, Nishiki-kun...
Yeah?
Wanna wear this with me?
Huh?
Bangles! They came in a set.
How embarrassing. Is she actually going for a "pair" look?
Well, since it's a present...
Jeez, these bangles look like horse crap.
What was that? Horse crap?
Er, no, Kimi...
I meant, you know, the good kind of horse crap—