Whoa! Hey, watch it!
Jeez...
Hinami-chan!
Onii-chan!
Sorry!
Hinami-chan, what's wrong?
Mom...
Mom is...
Where is she?
Let's hurry!
Quite the inexperienced fighter, aren't you?
You're rather sloppy with the use of your kagune.
A mother sacrificing herself to protect her precious child...
You make my skin crawl.
It's amusing,
watching this little human charade that you ghouls keep up.
What good will it do if I get involved?
Amon-kun, you've done enough.
I'll handle the rest.
What should I do?
Why?
No, it can't be!
It certainly can!
Dear...
Good...
Good! This is great!
Despair, terror, hatred!
Yes, expressions like those!
More! Show me more!
Mom—
You have to be quiet!
What should I do?
What am I supposed to do!?
I suppose I should listen to your last words out of pity.
What's wrong? There's no need to hold back.
Whoops.
What a shame. Time's up.
The only thing I could do...
was cover her eyes from that horrendous sight.
Huh?
Um...
Touka-chan, how are you feeling?
I'm sorry for skipping out on so much work.
It's fine.
Um, did something happen?
Ghoul investigators have taken Ryouko-san's life.
Ryouko-san...
What about Hinami? Is she safe!?
I've put her to sleep in the other room.
Her face. Did they see her face?
What is this?
Could things get any worse?
When the time comes,
I'm thinking of relocating her to the 24th Ward.
That's a joke, right? That dump of a place?
There's no way Hinami can survive on her own in a place like that!
Touka-chan...
We could always just kill the Doves, right?
Every last one of them. I mean, we have Yomo-san,
and if we all work together...
No. If the 20th Ward Doves are killed in action,
then they'll just be replaced. It'll be one after the other.
Until they've hunted all of us down.
But—
Touka!
Yomo-kun is right.
We must not take any action against them.
For the sake of everyone's safety, this is the path we must take.
Even though we've lost one of our own?
We've just lost one of our own, and all you think we should do is sit around!?
Hinami's mother was killed.
Wouldn't it be sad if we couldn't avenge her!?
It's not because we can't avenge her that we should feel sad.
The only thing that's sad here...
is a person who's so blinded by revenge that
they can no longer live properly on their own.
What are you trying to imply?
Back there, if only...
If only it was Touka-chan who happened to be there...
You mustn't blame yourself,
Kaneki-kun.
I... I...
couldn't do anything at all...
So Jason's base isn't located in the 20th Ward after all.
Going by this report, the 11th Ward seems like a better fit.
Do you suspect Jason's involvement in those organized movements?
That's what my instincts are telling me.
I hate to say it,
but there's nothing within our jurisdiction to do here, Amon-kun.
We'll hand Jason over to Special Investigator Marude.
The remaining S-rated subjects in the 20th Ward are...
that one binge eater and the Gourmet?
They're both keeping a low profile,
almost as if they're adjusting to match our actions.
In this situation,
I can confidently say that pursuing them would just be a wasted effort.
Which means...
We go back to the small pickings and catch them up one by one.
We'll definitely reel in a big fish that way.
Without a doubt.
All right. From tomorrow onward,
it's back to straight-up detective work for us.
That's all for today. Enjoy your evening.
Very well.
Yes, sir.
And you, Mado-san?
I don't really have much of a life outside my work.
Oh, I almost forgot.
Number 745, who is still at large,
has seen our faces. As such, be sure to watch yourselves.
He's just scaring us. She's only a child after all.
An orphan?
So that's them.
Welcome!
One shrimp tempura set with chicken rice balls.
Again, Nakajima-san?
Shut it.
He always orders that.
I see.
What about you, Amon-san?
Large kakiage bowl, order up.
Amon-san, you're from the Academy, right?
Well, yes.
What sort of things did they teach you over there?
Everything you needed to know about ghouls.
They also build on your physical fitness, I suppose.
It's against regulations, so I can't go into the details.
There are women there too, right?
Hey, Kusaba!
There were two of them in my class.
They were both women of intelligence and strong will.
And?
Were you interested in either of them?
That's none of your business!
They were both killed in the line of duty.
Killed?
Yes.
S-Sorry, I...
It's not uncommon.
The passionate ones are always the first to lose their lives.
With that, I'll be taking my leave.
You two take care.
Good work today.
Moron.
M-My bad.
The passionate ones are always the first to lose their lives, huh?
Then I guess we should kick
back from time to time, right?
Don't even think about it.
There's a mountain of work waiting for us.
Not as much as the other wards though.
The guys back at headquarters could easily take care of that stuff for us anyway.
You say that,
but we're always going to be at the bottom of the employee ladder,
both you and me.
Amon-san didn't seem to be very interested in moving up, did he?
It's as if he motivates himself
purely through a sense of justice.
Yeah. That's just the type of person he is.
Honestly, he's pretty admirable.
There's no point in comparing yourself to someone from headquarters, Kusaba.
Right.
Actually, I was hoping for some desk work.
It's easier and safer.
But then, looking at him,
I find myself getting excited as well...
Maybe I'll try harder at work.
Kusaba...
Kusaba!
Why, you...
Nakajima-san, stand back!
Who is that?
Ukaku!
So you're a high-speed type of ghoul!
This is it...
No!
If the foe is before you, even if it costs you your arms and legs...
That's right, Amon-kun.
That's what it is to be a ghoul investigator.
But forgetting to bring your
Quinque is no good, you know?
Mado-san...
You can't afford to lose your composure, Amon-kun.
Yes.
Take a short breather.
Dodged that, did you? Well done indeed.
Are you perhaps friends with that female ghoul I killed yesterday?
Would you like me to tell you how that pig was slaughtered?
Oh, my apologies.
I've completely forgotten. It was just yesterday too.
She was so weak and miserable...
I had quite the laugh.
You bastard...
This is some great timing, Amon-kun!
Let's go over what you learned at the Academy.
A ghoul with an ukaku is characterized by a
flurry of attacks that entirely depend on speed.
However, they all share a lack of stamina.
If you drag out a close confrontation,
the strength of their hits will drop considerably.
Listen, that female ghoul had a piglet with her, right?
Would you mind telling me where she is?
I mean, I kinda feel bad because she's separated from her mother, you know?
I have to hurry and slaughter her, too.
You scum!
Fool.
Do you have any idea how many of your fellow scum I've wiped out?
You're nothing more than a number!
Well, no matter.
Rabbit, the ukaku ghoul...
Hinami-chan...
Touka-chan!
Stay back!
But you're bleeding!
Don't concern yourself with me.
Did you move against the Doves?
Touka-chan's injured. She needs medical attention.
No.
Huh?
I said no.
What do you mean?
If she's taken her own measures against the Doves,
it means that she's prepared to accept full responsibility for her actions.
Whether she lives or dies is of no concern to anyone else.
You can't be serious!
Touka-chan!
Stop this!
Manager, I'm sure you've been through a lot,
and you have those experiences to back your actions.
But when the decision to strike back against the investigators comes,
or when the rules of a ghoul's society are concerned,
I don't understand anything at all.
That's why I need to experience these moments myself
before I can decide what's right.
What?
You need to get bandaged up.
I don't need it.
But you're bleeding.
It has nothing to do with you, does it?
But still...
You're annoying the hell out of me!
You're just a human!
I'm half ghoul you know!
Why did you go alone?
I don't care if a murderer like me dies.
But when a ghoul like Ryouko-san or Hinami
gets killed for no good reason...
I can't stand it.
She knows that what she's doing is wrong.
She knows, and yet she still fights.
Touka-chan,
I can't bring myself to kill anyone.
Even if I think the investigators' goals are unjustified,
I don't believe your actions are the right choice either.
But after witnessing Ryouko-san's last moments,
I realized that it doesn't matter
whether they're human or ghoul.
If someone close to me died, I'd be heartbroken as well.
I'd be devastated if you died, Touka-chan.
That so?
I want you to let me help you.
I won't kill any investigators,
but I refuse to just sit around any longer.
To show our respect for Investigator Kusaba Ippei's bravery,
a man who lost his life in the line of duty to ghoul aggression,
a moment of silence.
Is Mado nowhere to be seen?
One of his own men has died,
and he can't even muster the effort to pay his respects.
That's pretty reflective on him as a superior.
You know, Amon. It'll be the same when you die, too.
If only that one thing hadn't happened,
that fool would be an assistant special investigator by now.
It's all messed up.
There's going to be some action over in the 11th Ward soon.
When that hits, I expect you to help out,
so get a move on and clean up the trash in the 20th Ward already.
Nakajima-san...
Amon-san...
He was single, fortunately.
Imagine if he had a wife.
He respected you a great deal.
What, me?
Here you go.
Where's that fellow with the glasses today?
A glass of cold water, please.
All right, water for three— two, I mean.
I...
I always order this same set.
That moron Kusaba would chime in every time I ordered,
"Again, Nakajima-san?" without fail.
That freeloader... He'd let me pay for his meal every time,
and I'd only say "Shut up and eat," for God's sake.
Who am I going to eat my meals with now, you moron!?
There's no good reason for why Kusaba-san was killed!
Nakajima-san, this time, please pay for my meal!
I can eat a lot more than Kusaba-san ever did!
Well, I guess I can kiss my paycheck goodbye.
Touka-chan!
What exactly are we doing?
You said you wanted to help me, right?
Yeah, but...
This should do.
All right, onto the next.
This time, it's your turn.
What do you mean? Wait, Touka-chan!
This is Mado.
Senior Investigator Mado,
we've received some eyewitness accounts regarding number 745.
They sounded pretty nervous,
so it may have been another prank call,
but I thought you should know.
And?
I see. Thank you.
Men who adhere to a sense of justice...
Children with their loved ones taken away from them...
Those who fought to protect someone...
Why should they have to lay down their lives?
It'd be difficult to use a Quinque there, huh?
A ghoul's acute sense of smell...
The Rabbit was clearly of some relation to number 745.
And now, this...
How do they all connect?
Come on in. It's ready.
I'll join you for a little splashing around, Rabbit.
Hinami...
I'll change it.
I am going to change...
this backwards...
world of ours!
Kaneki-kun! Kaneki-kun!
Oh, Uta-san?
Your mask is done, so I wanted to personally deliver it.
I'm already here anyway, so I'd like to see you put it on.
Yes, just like that. Yes, that's it.
L-Like this?
Good! Very good!
I was thinking of making a one-eyed
mask at first to match your appearance,
but this was definitely the right call!
Thank goodness! It was worth all the effort!
Uta-san...