We're going to split up?
Yes. The waterway is rather extensive.
Rabbit and Number 745.
Nothing would be better than
disposing of the both of them.
Are you certain they'll show up?
My instincts say so.
Very well.
Let's head off then.
Mado-san, what are those?
Some things are better left unsaid.
Mom?
Touka-chan.
Where have you been?
None of your business.
If there's anything that I can do...
There's probably nothing you can do at this point.
Hinami?
Hinami!
Why?
Hinami...
Touka-chan!
No good. She's not here either.
Anything on your end?
Where could she be?
You don't suppose...
Where are we?
This is where Ryouko-san...
Hinami-chan.
Please, no more...
She's close!
Where is she?
Touka-chan?
That's...
The man from before!
This is bad!
Hinami!
That speed.
It's Rabbit, all right!
Who are you?
Hinami.
Hinami, what's that?
Mom...
Let's get out of here, Hinami!
It's too dangerous to stay.
No!
Is it wrong for ghouls to live?
I want to be with Mom.
Take me there. Take me to where Mom is.
I'm begging you...
Hinami.
I miss...
I miss Mom.
A friend of the Rabbit's?
I don't have time to entertain you.
Why don't you step aside?
I won't let you pass!
How is that wound of yours doing, Rabbit?
Attempting to lead us out here with false stories is a pitifully cheap ploy.
Childish indeed.
Oh, that's right! Did you like the present I left you?
You must miss your dear mother.
You bastard!
Don't make light of me!
I can't let him go.
I can't let this man get to them.
That is my...
Going to take me seriously, are you?
In that case...
You're on a different level compared to the other small fry, aren't you?
Bounce around! Keep bouncing around,
you little gnat!
You can't use your weapon efficiently around here.
I've always had a question for you freaks.
You casually prey on innocent people and compulsively devour them.
Why does your kind exist?
The children whose parents have been killed...
The grief of those left behind...
The loneliness...
Have their feelings crossed your mind even once?
Answer me!
The terror of realizing that your life is being mindlessly preyed on...
Do you understand how that feels?
Having the people dear to you
crushed like insects beneath your feet...
Do you have any idea what that feels like?
You piece of shit...
Rabbit murdered one of my friends.
Why was he killed?
Because he was an investigator?
Because he was a human?
Don't kid yourselves!
What reason did she have to take his life away?
Why don't you tell me the reason for Ryouko-san's senseless death!?
There's a lot of wrong in this world.
And scum like you are the reason for it all!
If it weren't for people like you...
Die!
Well? You know what this is, don't you?
It's your...
dearly beloved...
mother!
Quinques are made from a ghoul's kagune, after all!
You fucking bastard!
Ghouls are stirring up trouble in this world...
Is that really true?
Was there a deeper meaning as
to why Ryouko-san was killed?
What about Hinami-chan?
Hinami-chan also had the lives of
those dear to her taken away, didn't she?
Ghouls have feelings too.
Just like humans.
Why can't humans see that part of us?
Why don't they try to understand?
I'm not done yet!
It's something so obvious.
It's something so simple.
Tough nut to crack, aren't you?
I'm the only one...
who realizes it.
The only one who can reach out to it...
Only me, the ghoul...
Only me, the human...
I'm the only one.
No.
It's not the world that's wrong.
Sure, there are misguided ghouls
who have chosen the wrong path.
But that doesn't mean it's the same for all of us.
We should learn more from each other.
Both humans,
and ghouls.
Ghouls aren't the only things wrong with this world...
It's you too.
What are you talking about?
You won't even try to understand?
In that case...
I'll make you understand.
You should make a fine tool indeed.
But really, the combination of these
two parents make for a wonderful pair.
It was a pleasure to put both your mother and father down!
Stop it...
Now then, which one should I finish you off with?
I'm gonna fucking kill you, you filthy geezer!
What a dirty little mouth you have.
I said stop!
What can I do to get through to him?
What can I do to make us see eye-to-eye?
We can't compete with each other.
We can't keep taking from each other.
Both humans,
and ghouls.
We have to break it.
This cycle of grief.
What should I do?
That's enough!
I don't have time to waste on you.
Why, you...
I mustn't let him pass.
If I can just do something about that...
But I don't have nearly enough strength.
That's right...
There's no way around it, is there?
If that's how it's going to be, then just this once...
I'll embrace you, the person within me...
Rize-san!
I feel like my appetite is going to consume me.
I'm slipping into an indulgent rampage...
But I won't lose sight...
of the person I am!
He's aiming for the Quinque!?
If I have this much strength...
Don't take me for a fool!
Now...
Now he can no longer fight.
There's nothing I can do without my Quinque...
No!
If the foe is before you, even if it costs you your arms and legs...
Please, run away.
If this keeps up for any longer, I'm going to kill you.
Please...
Run away!
Don't you mock me! I would never run from a ghoul!
Hurry!
Go!
Please...
Don't make me a murderer.
Would you say the same thing if you were a ghoul?
What's so wrong about having the will to live?
If people are all we can eat,
then what other choice do we have?
How are we supposed to lead
a proper life with bodies like these!?
Tell me, how!?
Just die!
Die, die, die, die!
You can all fucking die!
All I want...
All I want is to live, just like you.
I can't bear to hear any more.
It's the end of the line for you!
No!
My Quinque...
is gone?
Or rather...
what's gone is my right hand.
Hinami?
Stop hurting Onee-chan.
Don't use Mom and Dad for something like that!
Incredible!
Simply superb!
You've inherited only the best
traits from your mother and father!
I want it!
Give it to me!
Hinami.
Finish him off.
I can't.
He killed your parents.
I don't care about that.
I don't care about revenge.
I'm just sad, that's all.
I miss Mom and Dad.
I'm just really sad.
Mom... Dad...
It's lonely all by myself!
Outstanding.
Yes...
She belongs with the rest of her family.
She can belong to me as my Quinque!
Well, you've done it now...
Scum of the earth like you aren't even worthy of living...
Don't make me laugh.
I still have a score to settle.
Not until I catch him,
that one-eyed... And bury him myself...
I can't die yet...
That ghoul...
Why did he let me go?
He was crying.
It's hopeless. I can't control it!
God, no! Somebody help me!
Flesh! I need flesh!
If I don't do something...
Is there someone there?
I'm awfully hungry right now.
You know?
I understand why Yoshimura-san has taken such an interest in you.
Now I, too, wish to see what
you'll go on to do from here on out.
Come home, Ken.
Yomo-san...
What have I done?
Eat this.
You'll feel better.
You even wore gloves.
Does the idea of touching us...
disgust you that much!?
Hinami-chan!
Touka-chan?
Is it okay to live?
Is it really okay for me to stay alive?
Hinami-chan.
Back then, I believe Ryouko-san
told you to live.
Good grief, I can't believe
I actually kicked the bucket back there.
Amon-kun must be in a worrisome situation.
I wonder what kind of eternal rewards I'll get in the afterlife.
Man, this bathwater is great.
It sure hits the spot.
It feels so good, I might lose my head.
My head!
Sounds like someone's making a racket.
It's just your imagination.