I'll be joining you all in
Control Division One starting today.
My name is Amon Koutarou.
I look forward to working with all of you!
The new guys this year are quite serious, huh?
S-Special Investigator Arima!
Your teachers have told me
all about you. It's a pleasure, Amon.
L-Likewise!
I'll be placing you under the care of Mado-san.
Yes, sir.
Mado-san? You're only a newbie. Man, you have it tough.
He gets a little excited sometimes,
so make sure you don't get caught up in his flow.
Mado-san, this man will be
your partner from today onward.
All right.
Mado Kureo. Nice to meet you, Amon-kun.
I look forward to working with you.
Applehead, was it?
Yes. That ghoul has claimed fifty
predatory kills in the last year alone.
Have you narrowed it down to any suspects?
There is one.
Specifically, a woman who's in the area
every evening. Muramatsu Kie, age sixty-eight.
Is it really that surprising? You think ghouls
old enough to be your grandparents don't exist?
Er, no...
I'm quite convinced that this woman is Applehead.
What makes you so sure?
My instincts.
I-Instincts?
Instincts are nothing to sneeze at, Amon-kun.
In fact, I'm rather confident in my instincts.
Is this guy right in the head?
Good afternoon, Muramatsu-san.
My, good afternoon. Nice weather, isn't it?
I see you've brought a handsome
young man with you today.
This is Amon, my new partner.
Pleased to meet you.
This harmless, old woman is a ghoul?
Thank you very much for sending me that doctor's certificate.
If we take a look at your RC levels,
it'll be obvious whether you're a ghoul or not.
You have an RC count of 231.
Such a number would be impossible for a ghoul.
I'm terribly sorry for casting my suspicion upon you.
Why didn't you tell me that
you had a doctor's certificate from her!?
It's easy to forge a document like this.
It doesn't prove anything.
But even so...
It's all part of my plan.
She's going to end up giving herself away.
You should watch what I'm doing and take notes.
You're still a fledgling after all.
Very well.
Oh, right! Amon-kun,
do you mind showing me your Quinque?
I'm rather curious about the type of
Quinques they hand out to newbies these days.
With all due respect, Senior Investigator Mado,
I take my job seriously.
I'd like to refrain from any action that is not conducive to the investigation!
Now if you'll excuse me.
For God's sake...
What does that man think he's doing?
Why is someone like him stationed at Headquarters?
Muramatsu-san?
Thanks for going out of your way to help me.
Not at all.
If only my own son were as kind as you.
You flatter me.
I really am grateful.
Suspecting a woman like her... He must be out of his mind.
I must say, this is rather heavy.
I'm surprised you were able to haul it this far yourself.
Don't treat me like some helpless old lady, you little brat!
Is this it?
That's no good, Amon-kun.
You can't drop your guard in front of scum like her.
Mado-san.
I'm sorry. I...
No harm done.
I took your inexperience into account for my plan.
I highly admire that passion of yours.
But keep this in mind:
if the foe is before you, even if it costs you your arms and legs, you fight.
That's what it means to be an Investigator.
Yes, sir!
Hey, crybaby Amon!
Shinohara-san!
Hey there. Back from the grind?
What are you doing in the 20th Ward?
I needed to see you for something.
What's that?
I was going to visit Mado-san.
Ah, that's right. It's been fourty-nine days, huh?
Yes.
To think that he's no longer with us...
I still can't believe it.
Anyway, what did you need?
Oh, it can wait. I'll be back tomorrow.
But...
It's fine. Go on.
Say, Amon.
He...
was really proud of you.
Right. It's the same for me.
Mado Kureo was my pride.
Multiple bodies were found on the streets of the 11th Ward last night.
The CCG are curently investigating this as a criminal ghoul offense—
Onii-chan!
Uh, H-Hinami-chan?
That's my name!
What's up with the outfit?
I borrowed some of Touka-oneechan's stuff.
I'm about to go out with Yomo-san.
Go out?
We're going to buy a home for Loser.
Loser! Loser!
All right, Yomo-kun. Take care of Hinami-chan, okay?
I'm a cat. Loser!
Off we go!
After things settled down,
Hinami-chan moved in with Touka-chan.
She's slowly reverting back to her usual self, one step at a time.
T-Touka-chan.
Where's Loser?
The manager took him inside.
There's no way I'm keeping that bird at home.
Touka-chan likes to space out sometimes.
What are you looking at? I'll kill you!
Er, sorry.
It really feels like everything's gone back to normal.
However, something like that just isn't possible.
Everyone's gotten over the tragedy.
It may be painful,
but we must live on.
And so we desperately tried to salvage what we could of our previous lives.
What are you doing, you damn woman!?
Is that any way to speak to your senior, damn Nishiki!?
You, my senior, at this damn useless job!?
Ah, the future looks damn bleak indeed!
Having a damn sickening college boy with a damn smart mouth as my damn junior
makes me pretty damn discouraged as well!
Why don't you just hurry up and quit?
It's not your place to ask things like that, you damn woman!
Um, we're in the service trade,
What's your problem, damn Nishiki!?
so would the two of you keep the "damns" to a minimum?
Damn you Touka!
Damn you Nishiki!
What is it with you? Can't you come up with a better comeback instead of parroting me, damn Touka!?
I'm about ready to get angry myself.
Comparing me to a bird—
Of all things! Damn you Nishiki!
You guys do know the legend of the Devil Ape, right?
Damn you Touka!
Damn you Nishiki!
There it is again! That's all an idiot like you knows!
You're not going to pass any exams with that brain!
That's none of your business, damn Nishiki!
I'm sorry, Mado-san. If only I had arrived sooner...
I will kill Rabbit with my own two hands. I swear it.
So you're telling me that Rize was somehow controlling you?
Well, no. I'm not sure how to describe it.
My memories aren't too clear on what happened during those moments.
When I came around, I had attacked Yomo-san.
Impressive. You actually pierced
through Ren-chan's sturdy body.
You're pretty strong aren't you, Kanekicchi?
Itori-san!
I'm just joking!
Kanekicchi, the only person who's worse than you at recognizing my jokes is Ren-chan!
Sorry.
Something like this had happened before.
Back then, it felt like Rize-san had overwhelmed me too.
So you decided to call me for any information I had about Rize?
Yes.
Good choice, Kanekicchi. You can always rely on me.
Rize, huh?
Well, Kanekicchi, the truth is...
Yes?
I can honestly say that there's not much I know about Rize.
You see, she just showed up out of the blue one day.
Just showed up?
Nobody knows why she came here,
or what she was doing before that.
But even then, it's not like Rize
just appeared out of thin air.
If you search hard enough,
you should be able to find some leads.
I guess.
Why don't you start by visiting the 11th Ward?
The 11th Ward?
Rize was in the 11th Ward before she moved here.
That, I'm certain of.
The 11th Ward...
Maybe I'll take a look on my next day off.
Oh, excuse me!
No, excuse me.
I spaced out for a second there.
Well then, off I go!
There's something about him.
Must be going!
It smells really good.
Insurance card, library card,
and here we have...
His student ID! Kaneki Ken,
age nineteen. Oh, we're the same age!
And the real jackpot...
What a shame.
Pickpocketed?
Do you remember their face?
I never got a good look.
Did you file a report?
I didn't have that much in it.
Jeez, you're pathetic.
If you paid more attention to your surroundings, creeps like that wouldn't be coming after you.
We've just received some breaking news.
Well, I guess so.
Following Chairman Washu Tsuneyoshi's decision,
the CCG has increased the number of investigators
allocated to both the 11th and 20th Wards.
This decision was made in order to reduce ghoul activity,
Is the 20th Ward really that much of a riot?
Beats me.
which has been increasing as of late. The 11th Ward—
I wonder if the balance has been tipped.
Oh, I thought that maybe there was some
ghoul organization here in the 20th Ward.
Wh-What makes you say that?
If you look at other Wards, there's a noticeable
difference in the amount of predatory cases here.
I figured the ghouls in the
20th Ward were working together.
Both the binge eater and Gourmet suddenly disappeared as soon as they started actively preying on people.
Which means it's possible that this ghoul organization cleaned up their mess before the CCG could step in.
You look kinda pale, Kaneki.
N-Nah, I'm fine.
Hide, you're pretty interested in ghouls, huh?
Yeah.
The thing is...
This book is super fascinating!
It's about a gang of ghouls in the
3rd Ward who wear clown masks,
and about how Matsubara, the ghoul from Wakayama, came to Tokyo.
It also has stuff about how ghouls grow hair!
See ya later, Kaneki.
Amon-san, the reassignments from
Headquarters are waiting for you.
Understood. I'll be right there.
I wonder who they're assigning.
There wouldn't be any openings among the veteran force.
Yo!
Shinohara-san! Don't tell me you're coming down to the 20th Ward.
Nah, I've been assigned on something else.
These two will be overseeing the 20th Ward.
Houji-san!
It's been a while, Koutarou.
A very long while indeed.
A-Amon-san!
P-Pleased to meet you!
Second Grade Investigator Takizawa Seido, Headquarters Control Division One!
Quite the fan of yours, apparently. He's been very anxious.
A-Assistant Special Investigator Houji! Well, I mean...
Nice to meet you, Investigator Takizawa.
It's a pleasure meeting you!
Amon, the 20th Ward is going to have these two on hand for the time being.
You're being assigned to a special task force.
Special task force?
Yup. Maru told me.
You'll be at the 11th Ward with me.
The 11th Ward...
Oh, really? So things are that
bad in the 11th Ward now, huh?
From what Yomo-kun said, the ghouls are
working together to hunt Investigators down.
It sounds like a real mess.
Is that so?
If this keeps up, we could be in for some big trouble.
What sort of big trouble?
A war, perhaps.
The day where I get called the
Devil Ape again may be fast approaching.
Anyway, where's Touka?
I think she's looking after Loser.
I thought she wasn't very good with birds.
That's true. I'll go have a quick look, then.
He had a family too.
Touka-chan?
I wonder where this guy's family is.
Everyone has a family, right?
Ayato!
What is it, onee-chan?
Poor guy. He looks pretty hurt.
Dad...
How about we take him home?
Yeah!
I found a worm!
Don't be a baby! Man up!
But...
This is for Chunta.
You caught this many?
Touka, you're as boyish as your mother.
What about me? What about me?
I can't stand worms either.
You're just like your dad, Ayato.
You two need to take a bath.
Give me a hug first!
Me too!
All right.
You two just keep getting bigger.
Touka, you're the older sister,
so you have teach Ayato all sorts of things.
Ayato, you're the boy, so you have to protect your sister.
Promise me.
What kind of people did you have in your family?
Oh, well...
My dad passed away before I even had any memories of him.
Same with my mom, too.
I was still in elementary school.
I see.
Loser, it's dinner time!
Onii-chan!
Hinami-chan! You got a haircut, huh?
Yup! Does it look good?
Very good. Did you go to a salon?
Nope. Actually, I had Onee-chan do it for me!
What?
Oh, nothing.
You think it's out of my character, don't you?
I'm just surprised at how good you are.
I-Is that so?
Loser! Stupid scum!
Son of a bitch! Son of a bitch!
Hey, you! You've got a filthy mouth, you stupid cockatiel!
I'll deep-fry you in oil, you—
Loser!
It's bitter.
Haven't you met her before?
Rize?
Well, my memories of her aren't the fondest.
She won't get away this time.
The 20th Ward.
It's my first time here.
It feels like time passes by slowly around here.
Idiots. Don't let your guard down.
Let's hurry and get to work.
Are you sure she's here, Banjou-san?
There's a coffee shop called Anteiku.
It's run by a rather odd old ghoul.
Let's get going. Rize-san must've gone there.
Not even the least bit of a fight in them.
Any news from that airhead Banjo?
None.
Damn that clown. At this rate,
Yamori and that fairy are going to get the jump on him.
All right, we're heading for the 20th Ward as well.
Our objective is to secure Rize.
Yes!
Come to think of it, you're from
the 20th Ward, right, Ayato-san?
I don't remember much.
It's basically just a cesspool of peace-addled wimps.
Now that I think about it,
a relative of mine still lives there.
One of the peace-addled wimps.
What's happening here, a showdown?
That new ghoul and Uta-san are gonna go at it.
Are you the one who's been
making a fuss around here lately?
What's with those stupid glasses?
Hey guys, wanna see me beat him to tears?
Uta-san means business!
They're going to make a mess of the 4th Ward like this!
He's pretty strong, huh?