Yes, this is Control.
Marude here! Give me a situation report!
The branch is being attacked by a band of ghouls we believe to be Aogiri Tree—
What happened!?
He was the last one.
Who the hell are you?
All done?
Yeah.
Ready, Eto?
Yes, Tatara-san.
This is terrible.
What do we know about them?
They're a band of ghouls who go by the name Aogiri Tree.
We have no way of knowing their exact numbers,
but their leader is...
the One-Eyed King.
One-Eyed, you say?
Let's make our way back, Yomo-kun.
The shop feels a bit empty nowadays, doesn't it?
There have been more Doves around recently.
Everyone's wary of going outside during a time like this.
Welcome.
Is your manager here?
U-Um...
I asked you if your manager was here!
Th-The manager has stepped out for a bit.
Then where did he go!?
Hey, you.
What do you think you're doing?
If you've got business here,
the least you could do is order a cup of coffee.
What was that!?
If you have something to tell the manager, I can relay it for you.
I have something I want to ask you guys as well.
Do you know Kamishiro Rize?
My name is Banjou Kazuichi.
I'm here from the 11th Ward.
I was acquainted with Rize-san
back when she was still there.
And what makes you think she's here?
When Rize-san left the 11th Ward,
she said something about a coffee shop—
That's...
Why do you have Rize-san's scent on you!?
Hey!
No roughhousing in here!
Banjou-san!
Are you him?
Are you Rize-san's man?
N-No, we're nothing like th—
"We're"!?
Y-You've got it all wrong!
It's a misunderstanding!
Banjou-san! Get a grip on yourself!
I'm so sorry!
He's out like a light.
I knew it.
Sorry about our leader here.
What a wimp.
Shinohara and Amon, coming in.
Assistant Special Investigator Chino
and Senior Investigator Tainaka.
Not to mention Special Investigator Arima's old partner,
Senior Investigator Hirako.
Special Investigator Kuroiwa is involved too?
Have a seat, everyone.
As some of you may already know,
the 11th Ward Branch has been hit.
Despite the enemy's relatively short occupation,
on-site police reports indicate
that the number of survivors...
is zero.
Ah, he's finally awake.
Are you all right?
I'm sorry about earlier.
What's your name?
Kaneki.
Kaneki, huh? You're tougher than you look.
Oh, not at all...
It's the reason why Rize-san chose you, right?
You've got it wrong, Banjou-san.
Rize-san and I didn't have that type of relationship.
So I was mistaken!?
Yes.
Sorry! It was my fault! I sincerely apologize!
It's fine, lift up your head—
No! If I don't do this, I won't be able to live with myself.
So where is Rize-san now?
Rize-san is...
She's no longer...
She isn't here anymore.
I-I see.
She never was one to stay in a place for too long.
I'm sorry I couldn't be of any help.
Listen, Kaneki. I have a favor to ask you.
A favor?
Yeah. If you ever see her again, I want you to tell her this:
Run.
A few months ago, a band of ghouls named Aogiri Tree
carved their way through the 11th Ward.
They set their sights on the Doves in order
to overthrow the rest of us in the same ward.
They're strong.
By now, it's likely that every single Dove
in the 11th Ward has been hunted down.
Even though I'm just an underling of theirs,
I can tell you that they're all after Rize-san.
I don't know why.
But it can't be anything good, that's for sure.
Rize-san?
They'll eventually start wreaking
havoc in the 20th Ward as well.
You should get out of here too.
Nobody's gonna blame you.
Otherwise...
Banjou-san!
What are you screwing around here for, Banjou?
Want me to mess you up until
you can't spit out any more blood?
A-Ayato...
H-Hey!
Touka-chan!
Ayato.
So that's Touka-chan's...
Yo. It's been a while, Sis.
Where have you been, moron?
Out and about, observing society.
Unlike you, a dweller of complacent peace.
You arrogant little brat!
You're the brat.
It's time to face reality, fool.
Are you finished yet, Ayato-kun? May we come in?
What are they doing here?
Pardon the intrusion.
Oh, whatever shall I do? Where on earth could I be?
Well, look at that! I've located a police box!
It's my lucky day!
They call themselves Aogiri Tree.
We currently have information
on over two hundred members.
There has never been an
incident of this magnitude before.
What could their objective be?
Does it look like I'd have an idea?
However, we have lost control over the 11th Ward.
That much is certain.
As soon as that gets around,
it's expected that the ghouls
who've been acting on their own
will join Aogiri Tree.
This will be a war between humans and ghouls.
That's why you must surrender your lives to me!
That's an order! You have no right to refuse me!
From here on out, the 11th Ward special task force—
Excuse me!
I'm Shinohara-san's protégé, Suzuya Juuzou!
I'm terribly sorry for being late. I got lost along the way.
Oh, jeez...
Please accept my sincerest apologies.
Hey, Ayato-kun.
Oh, my.
I did hear about your older sister being here.
Aren't you both just gorgeous!
I'm so jealous.
I'm impressed you found me, Yamori.
I only had to follow Banjou-kun.
Your men sure are first-rate, huh?
R-Rize-san isn't here!
It stinks in here.
It reeks of an odor I absolutely despise.
Hey, Nico. Will this one do?
Fine by me. Let's hurry up and kidnap him.
Right?
Kidnap? Don't think you can do as you please!
As I please?
Those with power are always free to do as they please.
Kaneki!
Fight or surrender? Which will it be?
Behave yourself and you'll get
through this without a scratch.
But right now, it seems...
Oh, dear.
One-eyed, huh?
You asshole!
You're weak, Touka.
Just like your dad.
Dad... fought for our sake.
What would someone like you know!?
You're the one who doesn't understand, Touka.
Mom and Dad are both dead.
Their lives were in vain and were lost in an instant.
But I'm different!
I'm gonna teach everyone the difference
between insects like them and ghouls like us.
You can't fly anywhere with that wing of yours.
Go ahead. Crawl like the insect you are.
You're so cool, Ayato-chan.
Touka-chan!
Still some fight left in you, it seems.
You really do remind me of her.
I'm getting a little jealous.
Tough little nut, aren't you?
In that case, how do you like this?
And this? What about...
this?
All right then, how's this?
This?
What about this?
You like this?
K-Kaneki...
How's this? And this!?
What about this? How do you like this!?
Amazing! I can't break him at all!
Y-Yamori-san! W-We should be on our way—
Macho-beard is right.
Nico...
Ooh, splat! Very nice!
Let's continue this at home, Yamori.
Thank you, Nico.
No problem.
Banjou, stuff that one-eyed guy
in the bag. We're heading back.
How are you feeling?
They took him away, didn't they?
Yomo-kun, round everyone up for me.
Anteiku will be closing up shop for a little while.
It's clear that signs of an organized
movement are starting to appear.
That's all we know about Aogiri Tree.
I'd like to pursue them immediately,
but we have to be patient for the time being.
We will engage them in one week.
Until then, the 11th Ward is under mandatory evacuation.
The police are at your disposal.
I will deal with the media. That is all.
Dismissed!
Yes, sir!
So you're Suzuya, huh? Awfully skinny, aren't you?
Oh, boy.
You're eating properly, right?
Is your coin purse empty?
Now, now, Maru-chan.
Suzuya just got here and I'm sure he's tired.
Cut him some slack, okay?
What gives? I was just making small talk.
Yeah, yeah. Save it for tomorrow, all right?
Suzuya is the only Third Class Investigator?
Maru will use anything that's at his disposal.
He must have decided that
using Juuzou would be a good idea.
In any case, Chairman Washuu personally admitted this kid.
Right after Arima.
I see.
However, the enemy has a trump card of their own.
You mean Jason?
Yeah. The 13th Ward's S-rated troublemaker.
He's a sadistic bastard, one who
murders for fun rather than food.
Not someone I'd want to go up against, that's for sure.
Oh, right. You fought him before, didn't you?
Yes. Together with Mado-san.
Right.
What's with that kid with the eyepatch from before?
Don't make me a murderer.
His words, his expression...
They're dredging up memories I don't want to remember.
Koutarou, who said you could come in?
Amon.
Amon!
Sorry. Could you repeat that, please?
I said your Quinque got broken, right?
Oh, yes.
In that case, choose one from Mado's effects.
It's in his will.
Well, see you later.
Mado-san.
Rei-chan, apparently there are
heaps of ghouls in the 11th Ward.
I might be able to get a new Quinque.
I can't wait!
I have to be a good boy or else
Mama will be cross with me again.
We're acting accordingly to increase
Investigator presence in the 11th Ward,
as well as pinpointing the base of this ghoul organization.
I can state that it's only a matter
of time before this case is closed.
But isn't this full-scale evacuation
of citizens in the area a little overboard?
That is ultimately for everyone's safety.
The CCG is on everyone's side.
Please avoid entering any areas that are marked as off-limits.
You could at least text me, Kaneki.
Hinami.
Onee-chan.
He's not as soft as he looks.
Nishiki...
Looks like everyone is here.
There will be a few more coming later,
but we'll start without them.
This concerns the issues surrounding the 11th Ward,
and the actions Anteiku is to take.
But before we get to that, I have something to say
about the kidnapped Kaneki-kun.
It's probable that we'll never see Kaneki-kun again.
Hey, gramps! What the hell are you talking about?
Stop!
Stop.
We're going, right? We're going to save him, aren't we?
Aogiri Tree is made up of ghouls who
bank their entire existence on fighting.
Sneaking into the base to rescue
Kaneki-kun won't be an easy task.
No way...
Not to mention that we can't
afford to ignore the CCG's movements.
They'll probably deploy
a detachment into the 11th Ward
to take out Aogiri Tree soon.
If we do attempt a rescue,
there's a good chance that we'll
be the ones exterminated instead.
What? You're not thinking of abandoning him, are you?
I'm going.
What was our policy, again?
Manager, if you're not going...
then I'll go alone.
I'm going too.
I owe him after all.
I want to help too.
Onii-chan is always helping me out, so...
If there's anything I can do, I'll do it!
Hinami.
Let me say this, so there's no misunderstanding:
I planned to rescue Kaneki-kun from the start.
However, I wanted to let you all know that
I can't guarantee the safety of anyone here.
I understand how you all feel.
Know that if you wish to save Kaneki-kun,
you must place your lives on the line for him.
And in return, Yomo-kun and I
will protect you with all our might.
It is Anteiku's policy to help each other out, after all.
There is one more thing.
You may enter.
You! Why!?
Amore!
Heartbreak!
Just imagine, my best friend Kaneki-kun facing danger
at the hands of an uncouth bunch!
No kidding!
Jiro, how do you think Rize-san feels about me?
Where's this coming from all of a sudden?
If you want to get in her good books, why not give her a present?
A present? Oh, but I could never ask her directly.
It would ruin the surprise.
He's going to get me to ask her instead.
What a wimp.
Rize-san, Rize-san! I have a question for you.
She says she likes any and all internal organs.
I see. Thanks.