I can't afford to lose here!
What am I doing here?
I don't want him here.
He has no intention of helping Kaneki!
Our chances of successfully rescuing
Kaneki-kun will increase if we bring him along.
We would have less to worry about with him around.
How the hell are you even alive?
"Eat yourself."
I simply followed the advice you gave me.
As you can see, that turned out rather well.
And, unexpectedly enough,
I happen to taste pretty good.
Whatever the case, I'm still against this.
This guy just wants to eat Kaneki!
You need not worry about that.
I'll look after him.
He won't try anything under my watch.
Yomo-kun, any movement from the CCG?
It seems like they're ready to mount
an attack once all civilians have been evacuated.
We will rescue Kaneki-kun
by using the CCG's attack as cover.
Are there any objections?
Kaneki...
Finally awake?
Isn't my room nice?
Tatara-san said he had no use for you,
so I went ahead and claimed you for myself.
I couldn't be happier.
I've been dying to have you as company...
Right from the moment we met.
No.
Since before we even met.
So please, try not to disappoint me.
RC inhibition fluid.
When it enters a ghoul's body,
all kagune activity is suppressed.
As soon as that happens, their body becomes vulnerable and my scalpel can slice through them with ease.
Almost as if...
they were a mere human.
While ghouls are immune to
hypodermic needles for the most part,
there is one place a needle will pass through.
And that...
is the mucosa!
Here's our current situation:
It's been two months since
the shopping mall was first occupied.
From what we've gathered,
there are about five hundred ghouls within the premises.
Their forces have substantially
increased within the past week.
Once the first mission starts...
Mado-san.
Here.
What's inside?
A present from Mado.
He wanted you to use it.
Team A will rendezvous at the main entrance.
Take it.
Next, Teams B and C will proceed to the annex.
I'll treasure it.
Units are to move in at their own discretion as soon as ground conditions have been verified.
Civilian evacuation has been completed.
All units, move out!
Yes, sir!
The CCG and the police are
preparing to raid the 11th Ward
with a total of over a thousand men.
The leader on-scene is Special Investigator Marude ltsuki,
the same man who located the ghoul organization's base.
Ninety-nine percent of our force will be devoted to ensuring the safety of everyone's lives.
The remaining one percent shall be made up from everyone's support and cooperation.
Let us unite!
We shall take back the peace in the 11th Ward!
That was Special Investigator Marude.
Now, back to the studio.
Kaneki...
Where are you in the count now?
Five hundred and fifty-nine...
I'll be back after they regrow.
Five hundred and fifty-two...
Five hundred and forty-five...
Clean that mess up.
Yes, sir.
Kaneki.
Banjou... san?
I promise I'll find a way to get you out of here.
Just hang in there.
Why... me?
I heard that Rize-san is dead.
You didn't tell me in order to spare my feelings, right?
You're a good guy.
Shu and Haru will be taking over for me.
You can trust them.
If anything happens, you tell them.
Kaneki, hang in there.
Is everything ready?
Uta-san! You're coming with us?
Of course.
Kaneki-kun is a valued customer of mine, after all.
I assume we're all here?
Let's go.
Is there something wrong?
What were your thoughts after
going up against this guy, Amon?
He's not like any ghoul I've met before.
He had a distinct sort of vibe.
This was before they started calling him Jason.
He was arrested by the CCG and detained at the Cochlea Ghoul Internment Center.
While there, a certain—
Well, how should I say this?
A rather conflicted Investigator was assigned to him, you see.
Five hundred and fifty-nine...
Five hundred and fifty-two...
Let me take more!
Five hundred and forty-five...
Allow me to remove them all for you!
He was the subject of intense torture,
which led him to create another personality within himself.
For the sake of his survival.
And soon after that,
he broke out.
Ever since then, acts of savagery have been something he takes delight in.
It reflects the torture that he personally withstood.
The name "Jason" came around soon after that as well.
That was sooner than we thought, huh?
Yeah.
Bin Brothers, you're in the main building.
Understood.
Kirishima, the annex.
Right.
We're going, Eto.
Take it from here, Noro.
Where's Yamori?
Beats me.
Who knows where he's wandered off to?
That bastard. At a time like this, too.
The weak are trampled upon,
overrun,
violated,
and afflicted.
Stop... D-Don't...
It's unusually quiet.
Two hundred and twenty-three...
Two hundred...
How are we being outgunned!?
The enemy is using kagune shields and scopes!
Former soldiers, huh?
Damn it!
You've gotta be kidding me!
Give me that!
Take out that insidious sniper nest immediately!
Here.
Amazing...
What's that?
Your motorcyle, Marude-san.
Hold up!
What are you doing with my bike!?
I'll be borrowing this!
Hold it!
Hey... Hey, now. You can't be serious.
W-Wait a second. W-W-Wait!
Yahoo!
Good evening!
Move in!
Hey, which team are you with!?
Anteiku.
Incoming at three o'clock.
Ten of them!
Hitting them with the Emerio!
Ten at nine o'clock!
Hirako.
South entrance block secured!
Keep an eye on our perimeter.
This is Shinohara.
We've secured the main building and second-floor entrance.
Awaiting instructions.
Divide into three units.
Take the interior and the parking lot from below.
You should be able to rendezvous on the top floor.
Copy. Also, I don't see Suzuya around.
I can't let him die until he reimburses me for my bike.
Send somebody to find him.
Copy.
Hang in there!
Hang in there, hang in there, hang in there!
You can do it!
Don't die on me now...
It's too cruel.
Thank... you.
Kaneki-san. Banjou-san told us to bring you a message.
"I promise we'll save you, so don't give up."
All right, Kaneki-san. We'll be back later.
We'll definitely get you out of here.
Kaneki, where are you?
Is that...?
Hold it!
What are you doing here,
Rabbit!?
Is he the guy from back then?
Mado-san...
Fire! Fire!
What!?
Up there!
It's no use!
It's not working!
They're closing in faster than I thought.
Their footsteps are...
It's all right.
It sounds like they all made it in successfully.
That's amazing, Irimi-san.
I'm sure you'll be able to do it one day, Hinami-chan.
Kaya-chan, how are the CCG's movements?
They've split into three forces. CCG has the upper hand.
It looks like there's no other choice.
We'll need to buy them a little time.
Kaya-chan. I'm leaving Hinami-chan in your hands.
Right.
You! At last!
Was he really this strong?
Why is he going to such lengths?
Is it because of me?
I don't have time for him right now!
You won't get away!
Who was that other one just now?
Hey.
That was combo number three.
He's pretty tough.
The S-rated... Bin Brothers.
Who are you?
Following my nose, the strongest aroma
seems to have brought me to you, Mr. High C.
Keep your guard up.
This is no ordinary ghoul.
What a charming mouth.
Allow me to give you a passionate kiss.
Let's go!
Fighting solo against two S-rated?
Can I take on something like this, Mado-san?
Amon-kun, how do you think a human of inferior physique
can win in a fight against a ghoul?
I'd say that a solid buildup of strength and stamina would be vital.
That's true.
But in a face-to-face encounter,
you won't be able to overpower them.
What can you do in order to bridge that gap and win?
Any ideas?
No.
Combo number one!
Right!
Be sly, Amon-kun.
As long as it's for the right cause,
there's nothing wrong with playing dirty.
I have a Quinque named Kura among my collection.
It complements you nicely.
Should I die...
I want you to use it, Amon-kun.
Mado-san!
I can't afford to lose here.
Not until I have avenged you!
Kaneki...
Pay more attention to your surroundings, moron.
Nishiki!
Yo, Sis.
What are you doing here?
Ayato...
Team one has taken control of the annex's third-floor north exit.
Team two has taken control of the
main building's second-floor west exit.
Shinohara, how are things on your end?
We've secured the fifth floor and parking lot.
We're heading for the roof.
Copy that.
Just like the good old days, huh?
Yeah.
They were all good men.
This is Shinohara. We've arrived on the roof.
There are no Aogiri here.
Something's not right.
Shinohara-san!
Amon! Are you all right?
Actually, Shinohara-san—
What's going on?
Maru, it's him.
The One-Eyed Owl.
Shinohara. Take only distinguished men
who don't mind dying with you.
If you guys can't handle him, then nobody can.
Dropping dead for no reason won't buy us any time.
Challenge him with as few men as possible.
That is all.
Even when I'm depressed,
riding you clears my mind in no time.
On days when my good-for-nothing subordinates
or pressure from above brings me down,
riding you like this invigorates me completely!
You're the best partner ever!
Hm? My keys...
Yahoo!
Impossible!