Mom...
Rize-san.
It's been a while, Kaneki-kun.
What's wrong?
You're all beaten up.
How amusing.
The master has arrived.
How far have you counted?
Five hundred... and fifty-nine...
Five hundred... and fifty-two...
I'm going to fill this bucket up to the brim.
Yamori had ordered me to count down in seven second intervals, starting from one thousand.
Five hundred... and thirty...
I didn't understand this order at first,
Eight...
but I now realize that it was
an attempt to retain my sanity.
I held onto those numbers for dear life.
Five hundred...
and twenty-four...
And while Yamori took my fingers and toes,
over and over, and over, and over,
and over, and over, and over,
and over...
Five hundred...
and ten...
Each time my fingers and toes grew back,
Five hundred...
I knew that I had become a monster.
Good morning.
Rize-san? You're alive?
Things like that don't really matter now, do they?
Tell me, Kaneki-kun.
What kind of person was your mother?
You called me "Mom" a moment ago.
Is that her?
I'm home!
Welcome back.
Is that you, Kaneki-kun?
Come look at this, Mom.
Well, aren't you adorable?
What does this say?
What's that you're doing over there?
She would always help me out with kanji I couldn't read,
and carefully write down the pronunciation for me.
Where is she going?
To work.
Whose room is this?
It was my dad's reading room.
What was he like?
I don't know.
He passed away before I could even remember.
All I know is that my love for literature came about
because of the books he left behind.
Wasn't it lonely for you, being all by yourself?
Well, I had my dad's books and my mom's kindness.
She was an amazing person.
She did all the housework and
always managed to put food on the table.
She always wore a smile and
never caused trouble for others.
She treated everyone with kindness.
My mom was my pride.
Ken. It's okay to feel pain.
Nice boys like you can find happiness despite all that.
It's better to be hurt than to hurt others.
Kind people are able to find happiness with just that.
That's what she taught me.
She was a kind and wonderful person, huh?
That's why you're caught up in this mess.
You're a fine one, Kaneki-kun.
Would you like to know why
I'm so... personal toward you?
I don't know if you've realized this or not,
but you have remarkable regenerative abilities.
And it's all thanks to Kanou's experiment.
He turned you into a ghoul using Rize.
One-eyed.
Rize's scent.
That's who you are, Kaneki-kun.
Have you heard of the red-headed Chinese centipede?
I feel like letting it wriggle around in your ear.
You don't mind, do you?
N-No... Don't... Please, I beg you.
No... I don't want it! Don't!
Stop... Stop!
Oh, no! How fascinating!
I want to kill you! I want to eat you!
Kill you... I'm gonna fucking kill you!
It's okay if I kill you now, right? Am I allowed to eat you now?
You want me to kill you!?
You want me to eat you!?
Kill me... Please, kill me...
It's better to be hurt than to hurt others.
Have you been living your entire life believing that lie?
That's what my mom taught me. That's why...
So you thoughtlessly hung onto her every word?
You can't be serious.
How dull.
Don't you want him to burn in Hell?
Are you sure your mother was the kind
and wonderful person you thought she was?
What's that over there?
An allowance.
For who?
My mom's sister.
She would always whine about financial difficulties,
and ask my mom for money.
Laboring part-time during the day, collecting garbage by night,
and working at home during her free time.
Mom never stopped working.
Mom?
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
And then?
And then...
She overworked herself.
And I was left all alone.
There wasn't a place I could call home anymore.
Hey, Kaneki! How long are you
gonna stay in that house of yours?
Do you know how rough it is for me when you shut yourself in!?
Oh, right... There was just one.
There was just one place I could go.
Kaneki, if you were a ghoul,
would you eat Yoshikawa from Class 2?
The one you like so much?
N-No, I wouldn't!
And I don't like her that  much.
Hide was the only moral support I had.
He's a dear friend, isn't he?
But you're going to lose him too, aren't you?
And it'll all be your fault.
"All suffering in this world is born
from an individual's incompetence."
The person who told me that was a real piece of shit.
But right now, I'm grateful to him.
I've come to understand something
rather well these last few days, Kaneki-kun.
Never mind your physical capabilities,
your mental fortitude is unexpectedly tough as well.
So I came up with a little plan to test that resolve.
A man and woman,
who love each other very much!
You'll decide which one of them dies!
Up until now, I've let these two look after you.
You were hanging onto that sliver of hope that help was coming, right?
You saw these two as your saviors, right?
Which one will it be?
If you don't choose, I'll kill them both.
Wait, let me rephrase that.
Which one do you want to save?
Why... me?
Why do I have to be the one that decides?
Come on now. Hurry up and choose.
I can't be the one that decides something like that!
Wouldn't that just be the same as me murdering them!?
Pick one! Pick one! Pick one! Pick one!
The man? Or the woman?
Right? Or is it left?
Pick one!
There's no way I can pick one!
If you have to kill someone, kill me!
I see. Very well.
Watch closely, now.
This one? How about this one!? No?
Come on! Pick one! I said pick one!
She's gonna die! Well, Kaneki?
Come on! Come on! Pick one! Pick one!
Well!? How about it!?
Well!?
Pick me, Kaneki-san!
Haru... Haru's going to die!
Pick me! Me! Pick me, Kaneki!
She broke, didn't she?
It's all your  fault.
I-It's not my...
No... It's all my fault.
It took you that long to realize it?
You'll just sit there and blame yourself over and over,
but that won't change anything.
You don't try to change. It's all  your fault.
That's only to be expected, right?
Whose fault is it that things ended up like this?
Coincidence? An accident? Fate?
There's no such thing as fate.
It's simply a combination
of one circumstance and the next.
And who is it that creates those circumstances?
Who is it?
It's you.
"All suffering in this world is born
from an individual's incompetence."
He's right, isn't he?
This mayhem began because you were
foolishly naive to the ways of the world.
You were a fool, and I easily tricked you.
The doctor played around for a bit,
and now we're one and the same.
It's all  because of you.
It's better to be hurt than to hurt others.
That's why you're caught up in this mess.
If only you were strong enough to kill Yamori,
those two would have been spared.
If only you had chosen the man,
the woman would have been spared.
If only you had been strong at that moment.
Ryouko-san.
S-Stop it!
But there's more to come...
Touka-chan...
Hinami-chan...
The one you hold most dear...
Hide!
You're a monster.
N-No... I'm...
Why didn't you tell me?
You failed to choose, like you always do. That's why...
this... happens.
You see? This is the path that you chose.
It's the future that you chose.
Why are you crying?
Why are you sobbing?
You chose to be hurt rather than to hurt others, right?
You're kind and wonderful.
It may seem like you're choosing both, but, really, you're forsaking both.
Your mother was the same.
If only she had turned her insufferable sister away,
she wouldn't have died from wearing herself out.
Stop.
What a foolish mother.
If she truly loved you,
then she should've abandoned her worthless sister.
Stop it.
Deep inside, that's what you truly wished for, right?
Mom...
Why?
Why did you leave me all alone?
I miss you... I don't want to be on my own.
I wish... I wish you would have chosen me!
I wish you had lived for my sake!
Even if it meant forsaking your aunt?
Even if it meant that!
Even if it meant hurting someone?
Even if it meant taking her life?
Even if it meant that!
Good boy.
That's right, Kaneki-kun.
There comes a time when you have to forsake something in order to preserve the other.
Your mother couldn't do that.
That's not kindness.
That's just being weak.
She didn't have the strength—the resolve to turn her back.
Will you allow yourself to be hurt any longer?
Are you going to let Yamori get his way?
No... I won't!
As soon as Aogiri strengthens their ranks,
they'll wreak havoc in the 20th Ward sooner or later.
I won't allow that to happen.
Your dear friend Hide, and your companions at Anteiku
might be exposed to the
same tragedy that happened here.
I'll spare no mercy for anyone who tries to take my home from me.
Do you have that kind of strength?
Yes.
Are you saying you accept me?
No. I'm not saying that.
I can surpass you at any time.
Are you sure you're not making the wrong choice?
I'm not the one who's wrong.
What's wrong...
is this world!
That will do...
Kaneki-kun.
To live is to devour others.
Eat.
I am... a ghoul.
Kaneki-kun.
Our special time together has nearly come to an end.
The Doves are closing in.
It's my job to take care of them, you see.
It's Aogiri's goal to eliminate
anyone standing in their way.
Not only does that include humans, but ghouls, as well.
The ghouls who stand against Aogiri's cause...
are the very ones you work with—Anteiku, was it?
They are also one of Aogiri's...
targets for elimination.
Kaneki! Let me take more from you!
Now that we're at the end of the line, let me devour you!
How amusing.
You really are a trivial man.
Exceptional until the very end!
Let me remove them for you!
Fuck you.
That's foul.
Wh—
Y-You...
bit me?
Almost like the intestines of
a fish on the verge of spoiling.
I'm not letting go!
You think something like that would hurt,
after all I've been through?
Kill you... I'll kill you!
I'll kill you! I'll kill you! I'll fucking kill you!
I'll devour you! I'll make a sloppy mess out of you!
I'll kill you!
I'll tear you apart, limb from limb!
Kaneki!
Now...
it's my turn.
Count backwards from one thousand by sevens.
I'll ask again.
N-Nine hundred... and ninety-three...
N-Nine hundred... and eighty-six...
Nine hundred... and seventy-nine...
Nine hundred and seventy-two...
Nine hundred and sixty-five...
You tried to devour me.
So you won't mind
if I eat you, will you?