Production
The phantom Pokémon, Mew, eh?
Holding mysterious powers, it's said
that he can do things like create heavy floods
and produce crops on a barren land
to share with the people.
He's surrounded in various legends.
Is he an angel or a devil?
He might even just be a whim.
He's also said to be immortal.
But isn't he extinct?
Actually, there have been recent
reports of Mew sightings.
None of them have been confirmed.
Right, sir.
There haven't been any photos
with clear evidence either.
Right, sir.
This is Mew.
And this is what I found this time...
A fossil.
A part of Mew?
So we believe.
Let's bring it to the research lab immediately.
If this is truly a fossil of Mew...
Yes...
We should be able to create the strongest Pokémon.
Where am I?
Who am I?
Why am I here?
This one's the same as the other copies.
Why won't it wake up?
Theoretically, there shouldn't be any problems, yet...
Perhaps it needs something else to be born?
Someone's talking about me.
That shouldn't be.
But what are they saying?
Those are human words.
Who are you?
A human.
But I'm a lot like you.
A human?
Am I a human too?
You can talk, so you might be a human too.
Or maybe I'm actually a Pokémon!
Human?
Pokémon?
What're those?
Which one am I?
It doesn't matter.
You and I are about the same, after all!
There are a lot of others like us here!
This is...
Mewtwo and Aitwo are communicating with each other.
There are responses from the others too.
Through telepathy?
I can't confirm it, but there is plenty
of basis for that possibility.
Ai...
Everyone here, including me, are all copies!
That's why we're not one, we're two!
Then I'm also a two?
I'm Aitwo.
But, I'm actually Ai!
Ai...
What are you talking about with the others?
My precious daughter, Ai...
Dear...
What do you think of this holograph?
Isn't it beautiful?
I've reproduced Ai's conscious patterns electronically.
What will come out of doing this?
Ai won't come back.
That's wrong.
Just watch.
I'll show you that I can bring her back to life.
Ai is within this light!
I...
I don't want to live a life controlled by memories.
This is goodbye.
I'll name this holograph Aitwo.
Mew's fossil?
The phantom Pokémon, Mew.
It's said to have immortal life force.
We've obtained a fossil of his eyelashes.
We'll create copies of Pokémon.
We'll create the strongest Pokémon.
Once we grasp the secret of this gigantic life force,
we might be able to give Aitwo true life as well.
Ai, come back to us.
Ai...
This is a place in my memories:
the place where Ai was born.
What's that?
That's the sun.
The sun?
It gives us light and warmth!
This is wind.
Wind?
Sometimes it's gentle, and sometimes it's harsh.
It comforts us!
The sunset.
It means we'll meet again tomorrow.
What are those?
The stars and the moon.
So that you won't be lonely
in the pitch darkness of night,
they tell you that you're not alone!
Hitokagetwo's life signs are fading away.
Has it begun?
Zenigametwo and Fushigidanetwo
are also fading away.
So this time was a failure too.
Where did everyone go?
Aitwo's life signs are...
fading away.
Ai.
What's wrong, Ai?
What's happening?
Looks like it's about time to part ways.
Ai...
Something is coming out of my eyes...
What are these?
Tears.
Tears?
They say living beings only cry
when their bodies are in pain.
Humans are the only ones
who let out tears when they're sad.
Thank you.
Thank you for your tears.
But please don't cry.
You're living!
Stay alive, okay?
I'm sure it'll be fun.
Ai, the tears aren't stopping!
What should I do?
Answer me, Ai!
Mewtwo's brain waves are vacillating.
He seems pretty restless.
It's too dangerous to apply
a stimulant to him now.
Use a tranquilizer!
Put him to sleep!
Injecting tranquilizer.
10...
20...
30...
40...
50...
60...
70...
80...
Brain waves are showing signs
of returning to normal.
90...
100.
Tranquilizer injection complete.
Brain waves are normal.
Mewtwo has entered a deep-sleep state.
A long time...
I've slept for a long time.
Things about Ai...
Things about the Pokémon created here...
Everything disappeared from
my memory during my sleep.
And then...
Where am I?
Who am I?
I've always been seeing a dream
of this world without memories.
Who are you?
Wait!
I...
I'll never forget that world
where I saw that creature flying.
Where am I?
Who am I?
Who brought me here?
Why am I here?
No...
I am simply here.
I haven't...
been born in the world.
Who am I?!
He awoke!
Did he do that?
How wonderful!
Mewtwo has been completed!
Mewtwo?
That's you.
From the Pokémon considered
to be the rarest in the world,
we gave you life!
Yes,
that is the Pokémon considered
to be the rarest in the world,
Mew!
Mew?
Is that my parent?
My father?
My mother?
You could say both, but you can't really say either.
You were created with Mew
as a base and made even stronger.
Who did?
If I have no mother or father,
then was it God?
Are you saying God created me?
Only God and humans can create
other beings like this.
You people?
Humans created me?
This is truly a victory for science!
With this, we can prove our work!
We can continue our research!
This place has become a new sacred ground!
We'll rise to the top for sure!
We'll upgrade for the next step!
I'll contact the others.
Congratulations!
Who am I?
Where am I?
Why was I born?!
We've created the strongest Pokémon in the world...
Our dreams...
Is this my power?
I'm the strongest Pokémon in the world?
Mew...
Am I stronger than you?
You just might be the strongest Pokémon here.
But there's something even stronger in this world.
Humans?
If you combine your powers with
my human powers, the world will be ours.
The world will be ours?
But if you let that power of yours run wild,
you'll only end up destroying the world.
You must learn to control your powers.
Control?
Are you okay with leaving everything to your powers
and burning everything in the world like this island?
What should I do?
So this armor protects my body
and holds back my powers.
What do you intend to have me do with this?
It's simple.
Just get rid of anyone who gets in our way.
Anyone?
Fight, destroy and plunder.
The strong ones win.
But who am I?
Where am I?
For what am I fighting for?
Why am I living?
You're a Pokémon.
Pokémon live to be used by humans;
they live for humans.
Are you saying that I'm fighting for you?
I'm fighting for humans on this planet?
You're a Pokémon that humans created.
What other value do you have?
My value?
Who am I?
Why am I alive?
What are you doing?!
I was created by humans.
But I'm not human...
Yet as a created Pokémon,
I'm not just a Pokémon either!
Who am I?
Where am I?
Who wanted me here?
Who wished for me to be created?
I curse everything I was born upon.
That's why...
not as an attack or a proclamation of war...
against all of you responsible for my birth...
I'll strike back!
Theatrical Edition
In order to become a Pokémon Master,
Satoshi continues his journey of training with the others.
The weather is nice, so they're taking a break in a field.
Takeshi, is it ready yet?
Satoshi!
Why don't you help out too?!
Can't.
I'm so hungry I can't move a millimeter.
Geez.
Boil it slowly, patiently raise it...
You can't rush with neither soup nor Pokémon.
Hey!
You boy over there!
Have you got all 8 badges?
Are you Satoshi from Masara Town?
Yeah, so?
Can you battle Pokémon with me?
Okay!
If it's a battle you're offering, I'll buy it!
I thought you weren't able to move a millimeter!
I can do one or two Pokémon battles before breakfast!
This is lunch, by the way.
So it'd be before your afternoon meal...
tatoe hi no naka mizu no naka kusa no naka mori no naka
Even if I have to go through fire, water, grass, forests
tsuchi no naka kumo no naka anoko no sukaato no naka (kya!)
earth, clouds, or under that girl's skirt (eek!)
nakanaka nakanaka
It's really
nakanaka nakanaka taihen da kedo
really really tough, but
kanarazu GET da ze!
I'll make sure I catch you!
pokemon GET da ze!
I'll catch you, Pokémon!
masara taun ni sayonara bai bai
Farewell, bye-bye, Masara Town
ore wa koitsu to tabi ni deru
I'm going on a journey with this guy
kitaeta waza de kachimakuri
I'll win with my polished techniques
nakama o fuyashite tsugi no machi e
I'll make more friends and go to the next town
itsumo itsudemo umaku yuku nante
Things always going well
hoshou wa dokonimo naikedo (sorya souja!)
There's no guarantee of that happening (That's a given!)
itsudemo itsumo honki de ikiteru
I'll always live with all I've got
koitsu tachigairu
These guys are with me
tatoe hi no naka mizu no naka kusa no naka mori no naka
Even if I have to go through fire, water, grass, forests
tsuchi no naka kumo no naka anoko no sukaato no naka (shitsukoi!)
earth, clouds, or under that girl's skirt (You're persistent!)
nakanaka nakanaka
It's really
nakanaka nakanaka taihen dakedo
really really tough, but
kanarazu GET da ze!
I'll make sure I catch you!
pokemon GET da ze!
I'll catch you, Pokémon!
tatakai tsukarete oyasumi gunnai
Tired from fighting, good night, good night
mabuta o tojireba yomigaeru
Once I close my eyes, I'll revive
honoo ga moete kaze ga mai
The flames burn, the wind whirls
nakigoe todoroku ano batoru ga
And that battle roars
kinou no teki wa kyou no tomo tte
Yesterday's enemy is today's ally
furui kotoba ga arukedo
There's an old saying like that
kyou no tomo wa ashita no tomodachi
Today's allies are tomorrow's friends
sou sa eien ni
That's right, forever
aa akogare no pokemon masutaa ni
Ah, the aspired Pokémon Master
naritai na naranakucha
that's what I want to be, I just have to
zettai natte yaru!
I'll definitely become one!
Oh my God!
We did it!
Your opponent was just weak.
He hadn't raised them well enough.
Pikachu is improving by the moment.
Beautiful.
We've never been able to win against them,
but there aren't any words like
"give up" in my dictionary!
We'll definite get that Pikachu!
But look at that...
I'm hungry.
I have a frying pan.
Without meat or vegetables,
that's just a plate of iron.
Master, would you like to send
these people an invitation as well?
As you wish.
What was that for?
Is this for me?
Please forgive the urgency in this letter.
What a pretty woman!
You have been acknowledged
as promising Pokémon trainers,
and the strongest Pokémon trainer,
my master, has invited you to a party.
The location is the Pokémon Castle on New Island.
Please check on the reply card
whether you may attend or not.
The strongest Pokémon trainer
greatly desires you to attend.
The pretty woman...
What should we do?
If they want us, we must go!
It feels nice to be called promising.
Then check yes on the postcard!
Yes, yes!
You can't just make such
a flashy exit without greeting us!
My, my, a postcard.
Calm down, calm down!
Kingler, get a hold of yourself!
It was such nice weather a while ago...
The weather changes easily near the sea.
The ferryboats have been suspended?
We can't go to New Island?
No way!
Just when I was invited...
Everyone, calm down!
This is the one who oversees this wharf.
My name is Voyager.
If you want to know the sea,
ask the seagulls at the wharf.
You don't even have to ask.
Look at the clouds.
I've never seen a hurricane like this.
Is it that horrible?
I've been raised in this town,
yet I've never seen a storm like this.
On top of that, the storm stretches all the way
from this coast to New Island's upper skies.
I cannot put any of you through that danger.
That is my wish in order to protect this harbor!
That's why the ferryboats have been suspended!
It'll be fine with my Pokémon!
My Pokémon are strong in water.
I'll show you I can cross!
Wait.
As someone who knows the sea,
I've already said no.
That's right!
Besides, if your Pokémon get hurt on the way,
we won't be able to treat them at the Pokémon Center!
What do you mean?
The Nurse Joy at this Pokémon Center has gone missing.
Without Nurse Joy, we can't treat Pokémon.
The search poster is posted over there.
She's pretty.
Huh?
Where have I seen her?
Stop right there!
If you don't, I'll arrest you!
There's no point in trying to stop them.
They're Pokémon trainers.
They're adventurers.
If they were people we could stop,
they wouldn't have gathered here in the first place.
I pray for their safety.
The strongest trainer is across this sea!
I can't step down like this!
But our Pokémon can't cross a stormy sea!
That's true...
Looks like you need a lift.
How about it?
We won't do it for free,
but we'll still head out in these conditions.
They had these kinds of boats too, eh?
We must be pretty lucky!
But is this boat really all right?
This is nothing to us!
We just whistle it off when we see
these kinds of stormy waves in these waters!
What are you talking about...
Togepi, stay still for a while, okay?
You!
It's you guys!
You guys really do show up when you're expected!
What do you want?
When we're asked something or other...
We'll answer...
There's no time for that!
Satoshi!
Kasumi!
Where are Satoshi and Pikachu?
I don't know!
Everyone, hang on tight!
That's...
You did well in coming here.
Please show me your invitation.
You mean this?
These people are indeed the ones who have been invited.
It really is you!
Yes, sir?
The nurse on the search poster.
Now that you mention it, they look similar.
What are you speaking of?
I have been in service on this island since my birth.
Now, please come this way.
The others who have been invited have already gathered.
Sitting there are all of trainers who have been accepted.
Only three people?
There were so many others before.
These trainers who have overcome the storm
have proved their worthiness.
You mean that storm was to test us?
Please let your Pokémon out
of their monster balls and take a seat.
You are the chosen trainers.
Now, in order to sneak into this castle...
We'll have to come in from an outlet.
Where would that be?
Over there.
Th-Th-The sewers!
We're not rats!
Stop complaining!
What's wrong, Musashi?
Nothing.
C-Come on, let's go.
So you guys came too?
You're...
I came through the sky.
Hurricanes are nothing to my Pidgeot.
Everyone, say hello.
That's...
That's my Gyarados.
I rode him and crossed the sea.
Waves like that are no big deal.
Gyarados, you mean the atrocious Pokémon, Gyarados?
Yeah.
There aren't many people
who are tough enough to handle these guys.
My Pokémon are... these guys!
Everyone, thank you for waiting.
The strongest Pokémon trainer is now arriving.
That's...
Yes.
This is the strongest Pokémon trainer,
and also the strongest Pokémon,
The great Mewtwo.
Mewtwo?
A Pokémon is a Pokémon trainer?
Get real!
Is it wrong?
I'll decide my own rules.
This voice...
Is it telepathy?
What the...
Go, Gyarados!
Gyarados, Hyper Beam!
Gyarados!
How trifling.
I don't have any more use for you.
Nurse Joy.
Where am I?
What am I doing in a place like this?
In order to aid me,
I brought you from the Pokémon Center.
A doctor knowledgeable
in treating Pokémon is convenient.
You were quite useful.
You don't remember anything of it, right?
What?!
If humans had my power,
they would control anything
without a second thought.
That's so cruel!
Heave ho...
What's this place?
How cute!
That's cute?
This place doesn't seem to have any treasure.
These are the results of our research.
This is a machine to create copy Pokémon...
These are... copies... advanced...
In order to do this, samples are required.
Nyasu!
My fur...
My fur!
Three hairs!
This is sufficient.
After investigating the Pokémon's organization,
a copy of the original Pokémon can be created.
Who's that Pokémon?
Nyasu!
Nyasu?!
I'm Nyasu!
Th-Then, this is...
A copy of Nyasu?
My gosh...
However,
our copies were more than we imagined.
This is a legendary Pokémon
that was discovered in an ancient civilization.
His name is Mew.
Researchers were successful in finding
a fossil of Mew's eyelashes.
After bringing it back and analyzing it,
we seized the opportunity and created Mewtwo.
We created the strongest Pokémon in the world.
That was our dream.
However...
Mewtwo unleashed a ferocious amount of destruction.
It's all over.
This research lab is about to be destroyed.
The only path that remains is...
Those who are responsible for...
The research lab means this place, right?
Yeah.
But it doesn't seem like anything happened to it.
Maybe someone rebuilt it?
Huh? Who did?
I once shared an ambition with another human.
But I was greatly disappointed.
Humans are the worst existence for Pokémon.
Just like humans do, I once tried to mercilessly control
those who were weaker than me,
but this planet... is no good.
Then those like you...
Are you saying Pokémon should rule this world?
Pokémon are no good either.
That is because...
humans control this world.
There are Pokémon who live for humans.
What?
You say you're not under their command?
You're with your trainer because you like him?
Just being with them is your main mistake.
Pikachu.
Weak Pokémon find attachment in people.
Satoshi, are you all right?
Yeah.
How dare you do that to Pikachu...
No matter what Pokémon it is,
as long as it's a Pokémon, it can be caught!
Go, Saihorn!
Saihorn!
It's useless.
I was born stronger
than any other Pokémon on this planet.
We don't know that for sure!
Do you want to test me?
That's just what we want!
What a spooky feeling!
It spoke.
It flew.
Mewtwo?
These are the Pokémon given to anyone
who wishes to become a Pokémon trainer.
Hitokage.
Zenigame.
Fushigidane.
These are the evolutions of these Pokémon...
Copies of them.
Copies?
Those are?
A stadium?
Are you saying we should do Pokémon battles?
I have my Fushigibane, Benard!
And I have my Kamex, Kusukusu!
And I have Lizardon.
Lizardon, I choose you!
Lizardon! That's not the one...
That's a rather ill-tempered Lizardon.
Who will be my first opponent?
I let my guard down earlier,
but it won't be so easy this time!
Go, Benard!
Razor Leaf!
Vine Whip.
Benard!
I'm next!
Go, Kusukusu!
Kusukusu, Hydro Pump!
Kusukusu!
Satoshi, be careful!
His attacks are really strong!
I know that!
Lizardon!
Make this a speed battle, not a power battle!
All right, go!
How is this a speed battle?!
The opponent's too fast!
Lizardon!
Seismic Toss.
Hang in there!
Are you okay?
They lack both speed and power.
Stop it!
Are you stealing other people's Pokémon?!
Stealing?
No.
I'll make copies stronger
than the Pokémon you're so proud of.
Ones worthy of me.
Copies?
Stop it!
That's against the rules!
Don't give me orders!
I'll decide my own rules.
They're coming!
Everyone, run!
Gyarados!
Stop it!
I know!
Everyone, go back into your own monster balls!
Come back, Zenigame, Fushigidane!
It's useless.
Nothing is impossible with the monster balls I made.
We can't stay here!
Let's get out!
Yeah!
My Koduck!
Rokon!
Run, Pikachu!
Pikachu!
Pikachu, don't give up!
Pikachu!!
Who's that Pokémon?
Strike.
Dewgong.
Rafureshia.
Sandpan.
Nidoqueen.
Showers.
But... this is definitely Nyasu after all.
Ow!
Ow...
Brat boy!
Team Rocket!
Sorry, but I don't have time to deal with you today!
Who's that Pokémon?
Pikachu!
Damn it!
Why you, let go!
Let go of my Pikachu!
Let go!
What's going on?
Pikachu!
A whole bunch of copies!
My, my, they're coming out.
My copy too!
Those are all copies!
Huh? The copies...
Where are they going?
Yikes, the real ones came out too!
Zenigame!
Fushigidane!
Humans.
I won't go as far as to take your lives.
You should return at once.
If you can go back through that storm, that is.
Who are you?
Unforgivable...
I won't forgive you!
Satoshi!
Koduck!
Rokon!
Did you release them?
My Pokémon...
and my friends...
I'll protect them!
Satoshi!
Stop it!
What?
You're...
Over there!
Who's that?
A Pokémon?
Mew.
The Pokémon said to be the rarest in the world.
Mew?
It's true that I was created from you.
But I'm the stronger one.
I'm the real one!
Mew and Mewtwo?
Mewtwo was created from Mew?
I should be only one to remain alive!
Why won't you fight?
Are you avoiding me because you're afraid?
So at least you have some obstinacy.
We'll decide which one of us is the real one.
Which one is stronger, Mew or Mewtwo?
Who is stronger between you originals and us?
We were created stronger than you originals.
I see!
What's he saying?
The real ones are real.
No matter how much you attack and clash against us,
the real ones won't lose to copies!
That's what he's saying!
The real ones are real, you say?!
Fine.
We'll find out which ones are stronger
through our attacks.
We're the stronger ones!
Go!
What's with this fight?
Whether they're the real ones or copies,
they're all alive!
They're all living beings.
Even if they were created,
they're still alive as living beings.
Originals and copies...
But they're both equal living beings.
How can either one win?
If people tell us something or other...
What is this?
This all seems so pitiful.
It's like bullying yourself.
It's like seeing your old self.
And seeing yourself now...
What a bad feeling!
You're...!
These must hurt.
With all the other Pokémon fighting each other,
you're pretty unfair.
What?
"You're the one who's unfair?"
"Why do I have to fight you?"
"Don't those claws hurt?"
Your claws hurt even more!
"The moon is really round tonight," you say?
That's true.
I'm sure it's a full moon!
Talking about the moon at a time like this...
How poetic.
How did it end up like this?
Pikachu!
That's enough!
Stop!
Satoshi!
I have to stop them.
It's impossible.
As long as Mew and Mewtwo don't stop,
they'll keep fighting.
Living beings won't give in
to living beings of the same kind.
That can't be...
They'll fight until the other is driven out!
That's how living beings are.
That's how living beings are...
But Mewtwo was created from humans.
But he's already a living being.
He's a living being now...
Both Mew and Mewtwo.
Pikachu too.
And that Pikachu too.
Stop...
Satoshi!
Just stop already!
STOP!!
Satoshi!
Fool!
A human tried to stop our fight?
Pikachu!
It's true...
that you're a Pokémon who exists just like I do.
It might be best if no one knew of this incident.
It might be best to forget this.
Where are all of you going?
We have been born.
We're alive.
We'll go on living.
In this world...
Somewhere...
No ships are going out because of the storm!
A hurricane is approaching.
Please take shelter.
Everyone, put yourselves at ease.
The Pokémon Center is open as a refuge.
Anyone in need may follow me.
Nurse Joy, Constable Junsa, Miss Voyager...
They all look even more beautiful
from getting wet in the rain.
But why are we here?
Who knows?
We're here because we're here, right?
Well, whatever.
Yep!
Huh?
Is this...
The hurricane...
It's like it never happened.
I'm sure we can send ships out tomorrow.
Look at that!
What?
I don't see anything.
I see clouds floating by.
I saw a phantom Pokémon on the day
I set out to become a Pokémon Master.
I did just now too.
Then maybe you'll see it again someday.
The phantom Pokémon.
Yeah.
Some day, for sure!
Pocket Monsters.
This is a story of the mysterious beings, Pokémon,
for all who aspire to become Pokémon Masters.
And so their journey still continues.
There's absolutely nothing here.
But it's clean and refreshing!
It's different from usual...
A GOOD FEELING!
arukitsuzukete doko made yuku no?
How far will you keep walking?
kaze ni tazunerarete tachidomaru
The wind asks as you stop
tanjoubi iwau roosoku fueta kedo
Celebrating your birthday, the number of candles increased
tatta hitotsu no furusato tabidatta
You set off from your one and only hometown
ima mo nani ka wo motomete
Even now, you seek something
ooki na hitomi kagayaite
Your large eyes shine
kimi no poketta no naka ni wa
Inside your pocket
kimi ja nai dare ka to no...
Not just yours, but another's...
ikutsumo no deai
Numerous meetings
ikutsumo no wakare
Numerous partings
maboroshi no you na omoide mo sukoshi
And a few illusionary memories
arukitsuzukete doko made yuku no?
How far will you keep walking?
kaze ni tazunerarete sora wo miru
The wind asks as you gaze up at the sky
arukitsuzukete doko made yukou ka
How far shall we keep walking?
kaze to issho ni mata arukidasou
With the wind, let's walk on once more
daichi fumishime doko made mo yukou
As we journey through this land, we'll go anywhere
mezashita ano yume wo tsukamu made
Until we grasp that dream we aimed for
daichi fumishime doko made mo yukou
As we journey through this land, we'll go anywhere
mezashita ano yume wo tsukamu made
Until we grasp that dream we aimed for
LaLaLaLa La LaLa LaLaLaLa La LaLaLa
LaLaLa LaLaLa LaLaLa La LaLa LaLaLa