It's spring.
I've graduated high school,
and I start my job today.
I'm going to be working...
...at a game company!
I'm Suzukaze Aoba.
Nice to meet you.
Today's the day I become an adult.
All right!
Wait, can I really go in?
Hey!
Just kidding.
This is a company, so no kids allowed.
I-I'm sorry.
Wait, I'm not a kid!
I'll be working at Eagle Jump starting today.
I am Suzukaze Aoba.
It's nice to meet you.
Oh, you were a new employee?
I'm sorry about that.
I'm sorry as well.
My name is Suzukaze Aoba.
Have you heard about me?
Suzukaze...
Oh, I have.
We're on the same team.
I'm Toyama Rin. I'm an AD.
It's nice to meet you.
I'm speaking with a real professional!
So... You must be busy being an AD.
I see it quite often on the TV,
but there are so many intricate tasks,
and they look so busy.
Oh, my AD doesn't stand
for "assistant director."
I'm an art director.
So my job is to manage all the artwork.
I'm terribly sorry!
What?
Don't worry about it.
This is your desk.
Oh, would you like something to drink?
Oh, may I have orange—
No, I'm an adult now.
Coffee. Black please.
I'm so glad she seems nice.
I'm going to be a professional
starting today.
I'm tired.
No more...
Is it a ghost?
Panties?
P-P-P-P-P-P-Panties...
A middle schooler?
Why is a kid here?
I'm not a child.
Oh, you're up.
Rin, who is this?
She's our new employee.
Suzukaze Aoba-san.
Oh, this is mine, but do you want it?
Thanks.
Cool.
So where is she...
This isn't sweet at all.
Oops, then that's hers. Sorry.
Switch.
You have a mature taste.
You drink coffee black?
I'm an adult.
This is no big deal.
You can't drink it?
So how old are you?
I'm eighteen!
Wow, you're a high school grad?
That's rare.
But you don't even look like a high schooler.
What about you?
How old are you?
How old do you think?
What do I do?
I can't just say whatever.
Th-That's...
A poster of Fairies Story!
Oh, you know it?
That's the first game I was involved in.
What?
I was totally into it in elementary school.
That's how I found out about this company...
D-D-Don't tell me... you're thir—
I'm not that old!
I'm twenty-five.
I joined after high school, too.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it.
By the way.
How old do I look?
Twenty-three?
We're the same age!
Good girl.
I-It's such an honor.
I'm meeting with the people who
made the game I loved as a child.
I especially loved the character design.
My.
She's Yagami Ko who did the
character designs for Fairies Story.
You're the Yagami-sensei?
Well that earned me respect easy.
She will be your manager starting today,
so I hope you two get along.
I-I'll do my betht!
Hey, you bit your tongue.
P-Please forget that happened!
I quickly finished my introduction
to my team members
and then got to work.
It looks like I'm the only
new recruit this year.
That's kinda lonely.
No, no.
Don't be negative, Aoba!
Get friendly with the girl next to you.
Hello.
It didn't work.
I think this is a good pose.
What kind of company is this?!
Please Hold Your Card
Up To The Circle
Open
I wonder if the girl at
that desk is absent today.
Good morning.
Good morning!
H-Hello!
I'm Suzukaze Aoba. I'm starting today.
Takimoto Hifumi.
Nice to meet you.
Are you also on the character team?
I-I'm sorry.
What do I do?
I don't think I can make any friends.
What?
Why is there a cat here?
You're so cute.
Hey, there you are.
You came all the way here?
Are you the new employee, Suzukaze Aoba-kun?
Pardon me for my cat.
Oh, no problem at all.
You're cute.
I'm Hazuki Shizuku, the director
of the game this team is making.
Okay.
It's nice to meet you.
So who's the cat?
He's Mozuku.
I bring him in sometime.
If I leave him at home all the time,
he gets bored and messes up the house.
Hazuki-san, I've been looking for you.
Oh, Umiko-kun.
What do you need?
You're very late for the meeting.
Oh, oopsy.
Let's not look so upset.
That's how you get wrinkles.
I'm sorry!
Let's go now.
Everyone's waiting.
Suzukaze-kun, good luck with work.
Th-Thanks.
Maybe the director's not very important...
A private message?
I'm sorry about earlier!
I'm not very good at speaking.
I'm also on the character team, so ask
me anything if you have any questions!
Also, just call me Hifumi.
Hifumi-senpai!
Hey, newbie!
C-Coming!
Have you done any 3D?
I don't know anything besides drawing.
Okay, that's not a problem.
Then do chapter one of this book.
Okay!
Okay, then.
Wait.
Is that it?
Oh, no.
I don't understand this.
But who do I ask?
From Hifumi
I'm sorry about earlier!
I'm not very good at speaking.
I'm also on the character team,
so ask me anything
if you have any questions!
Excuse me, Hifumi-senpai.
Could I ask you a question?
Um...
Hifumi-senpai?
Huh?
From Ko@IWannaLeaveOnTime
Behind you! Behind you!
Excuse me.
Um!
Um...
What are they doing?
Do you have a question?
What?
Y-Yes...
But I think I've already figured it out.
I got another private message.
If you have questions for
Hifumin, send her a message.
Yagami-san.
Okay.
Sent.
My apologies for distracting you earlier.
I had a question.
It says you can hide all but the
selected object, in the book,
but I can't find the toolbox for it.
Where could I find it?
You don't need to use that.
Just use the Ctrl+H keyboard shortcut.
That solved the problem.
Thank you.
I'm very grateful for your help.
No problem.
But no need to be so formal.
Smile! Smile!
What? But I'm new here.
Don't worry!
Everyone here's pretty friendly,
so don't be so tense.
Then...
Thank you!
I guess?
Good!
I think...
I think I can do it!
I got a message from Aoba.
I'm doing the assignments in the book!
Easy peasy!
She got influenced so fast!
That's good.
Could you come see me at my desk?
I need to teach you a few things,
like how to use private messaging.
Uh                                      oh...
I-I'm terribly sorry!
Just know your place.
Yun, don't you think you should take
Suzukaze-san to lunch as her senpai?
I'm all for lunch,
but why don't you invite her?
You invite her!
You're such a coward. Aren't you her senpai?
Suzukaze-san, you want to go out for lunch?
I'll come, too!
U-Um, what about Hifumi-senpai?
Hifumi-senpai doesn't
usually go out to lunch.
You wanna come out today?
Sorry.
I'm sorry for disturbing you.
I hope you'll join us next time.
Aoba-chan.
I-I think I'll go!
Aoba, wanna go out for lunch?
Where is she?
Wh-What's up with you?
I haven't introduced myself yet.
I'm Ijima Yun on the character team.
She and I joined the same year.
I'm Shinoda Hajime on the motion team.
Nice to...
meet you...
I can't!
It's my first time having a kouhai.
And we've only just met.
Please don't worry. You're my senpai.
Shinoda-senpai.
"Senpai"?
That gives me goosebumps,
so just call me Hajime.
Hajime-san, then.
You can just call me Aoba.
Nice to meet you, Aoba... san.
Wait, is that weird?
She was asking me to invite you
in private messaging earlier.
Hey!
Don't tell her that!
Why not?
You're nervous because she's
your first kouhai, right?
Isn't she your first kouhai, too?
You were worried about her when she was
trying to talk to Hifumi-senpai earlier, too.
Don't tell her that, too!
Thank goodness.
Everyone seems so nice.
All right!
Let's get this done!
But first, I need to use the restroom.
Bathroom, bathroom...
When you gotta go, you gotta—
Y-Yagami-san!
Wh-What are you doing?
I went to use the restroom,
but I didn't have my ID card,
so I couldn't open the office door.
Oh, right.
The bathroom is outside the office.
Without your ID card,
you can't get into the office,
but we also can't track your time.
What is the management thinking,
forgetting to give it to you.
Ko-chan, did you already take
Aoba-chan's ID card picture?
What?
Hey.
I asked you to do it this morning.
I'll do it now!
Stand in front of the wall.
O-Okay!
You know, you can wear
whatever you want here,
but why are you in your school uniform?
Oh, please.
This isn't a school uniform.
This is a suit.
I'm an adult, after all.
It looks like a uniform.
Then at least learn how
to wear a suit properly.
She doesn't look good in a suit
because she looks like a kid.
Well, whatever.
I heard what you were thinking just now!
Well, take two.
I don't have enough light.
Hajime, can I borrow your light?
I don't have any light.
You have that light sword.
Hey, perfect.
Perfect!
Look forward to the finished product.
I see.
You couldn't come back in.
Yeah.
I didn't know what to do,
and I was about to cry.
You really had it rough.
Want to relax with some snacks?
Wow!
Hifumi-senpai, would you like some snacks?
Yeah!
I brought some cookies today.
Here.
Wow!
Aoba-chan, you're learning 3D, right?
Yeah.
I'm trying to learn as fast as
possible, so I can help out.
What's the release date of the
game we're making right now?
When was it?
It's in six months.
The rumor is, we're going
to get super busy soon.
What?
Yeah.
You won't be able to go home for a while.
It doesn't sound like a joke
when you speak like that.
But Yagami-san was already sleeping here.
Is it because she's the leader?
I think it's accurate to say she lives here.
She's incredible.
She does several times more
work than everyone else.
Though she has some personality problems.
Aoba, thanks for waiting.
Here's your ID card.
Now I really feel like an official employee.
You already were official.
It's fine to take breaks,
but you guys are still clocked in,
so make sure you get back to work soon.
Okay.
So how far have you gotten, Aoba?
Oh, right.
I'm right here.
That's fast.
I'll send you some work
soon, then, so be ready.
You'll learn the small
things through experience.
Okay.
How's Aoba-chan doing?
I'm glad she seems to be a fast learner.
She might turn out to be reliable.
Artist
Let's work hard!
But first, I need to use the restroom.
B-B-B-Bathroom!
Yagami-san!
Good night.
Yagami-san, you're not staying here tonight?
I wouldn't last if I stayed
overnight every night.
Rin would get mad at me, too.
Rin-san gets mad, too?
She gets mad a lot sometimes.
Artist
Which one is it?
How was your first day?
Do you have any questions?
Y-Yes.
I...
I forgot to ask you something important.
Sure.
Ask me anything.
What's the title of the
new video game we're making?
Oh, no one told you?
Oh, right.
We forgot to tell her, too.
We're making the third installment
of Fairies Story.
That's the video game that made me
want to be a character designer!
I'll do my best!
Thank you for having me!
I'm so tired.
Fairies Story 3.
Nenecchi
It's Nenecchi.
Aocchi!
Did you hear?
Moon Ranger's getting a movie!
What's that?
I've never heard of it.
It's a popular anime!
I'm so glad I've supported it for so long.
Let's go together when it premiers.
Sure.
I'm tired today, so I'm hanging up.
Good night.
Wait!
What?
Well, I figured you had a
rough first day at work.
So I didn't want to make you
talk about work at home.
It wasn't like that.
Get this!
It was incredible at work.
You know Yagami Ko-san?
She did the character
design for Fairies Story.
I'm going to be working with her!
What?
That's incredible!
I'm gonna work really hard.
I'm gonna work really hard
and learn how to do my job.
In order to make a new game.
Aocchi, is a video game company really busy?
I don't know, Nenecchi.
But there was someone who slept at work.
Did you run into someone
sleeping in her underwear?
Just kidding. No adult does that.
Next time: "So This is an Adult Drinking Party..."
Next Time
"So This Is an Adult Drinking Party..."