The first time I played Fairies Story
was when I was in grade school.
I was moved by the story and
overwhelmed by the game world,
but I especially grew fond
of the beautiful characters.
That's when I found out about
the character designer job.
Character Designer:
Yagami Ko
The character designer of this
game was called Yagami Ko.
Yagami Ko.
To me, that name...
means something special!
My name is Suzukaze Aoba.
I joined a game company one week ago.
The name of the company is Eagle Jump.
To my surprise, I was welcomed onto the
team that's making Fairies Story 3!
Morning.
Oh, good morning.
This lady who was sleeping under
the desk is Yagami Ko-san.
She's a hard worker, and it looks
like she stayed the night at work.
Character Designer:
Yagami Ko
I want to become a character
designer like her one day.
That's my current goal.
However...
I don't plan to sleep in
my underwear like she does.
Stop staring.
Ko-chan.
Don't be a bad example to other workers.
Whatever.
Good morning, Aoba-chan.
Good morning to you, too!
She's Toyama Rin-san, an art director.
Where're my pants?
An art director's job is to
manage all the art related jobs.
Goodness, clean this up.
Rin-san and Yagami-san joined at the
same time and are close friends.
Can I toss these out?
Oh, thanks.
I'm the only new employee this
year, so I'm a little bit jealous.
Good morning!
Aoba-chan, look.
I got the new wand from Moon Ranger!
Th-That's incredible.
There are twenty different
quotes in this thing.
It's so well designed and manufactured.
She's Shinoda Hajime-san with the motion team.
She sits right next to me.
It was super expensive, but totally worth!
She's a super bright and energetic person.
Good morning.
See this? When you swing it...
Ow.
Oh, no!
I'm sorry, Yun!
Yun-san!
Iijima Yun-san.
She's on the character team with me.
She joined with Hajime-san, and she's a
responsible, older sister-like person.
Why're you getting so carried away
at this time of morning?
I'm sorry.
I got carried away.
Oh!
I'm getting the urge to swing it around, too.
Whoa, there.
Good morning.
Oh, good morning!
She's Takimoto Hifumi-san,
also on the character team.
She joined before Hajime-san and Yun-san.
She doesn't talk or smile much,
but she's very nice and answers my
questions through private messaging.
Producer
Director
Planning             Programmers            Debuggers
By the way, our team
structure looks like this.
The director is in charge of everything.
Art Team
The art team consists of background,
character, effects, and motion teams.
Art Director         Background Team
Leader
Background Team
Character Designer
Character Team
Leader
Character
Team
I'll do my
best!
Yagami-san is also the leader
of the character team.
Effect Team
Motion Team
A little lonely
on the diagram
Hey, Mozuku-chan...
Stop, I can't work.
Say, "I'm sorry."
You look experienced.
I'm so sorry!
I'm playing with your cat.
I don't care.
Mozuku's at fault for interrupting your work.
In fact, you could discipline
me as his owner, too.
I'm kidding.
Come on, don't get in her way, Mozuku.
Hazuki Shizuku-san.
She's the director of Fairies Story 3, but...
Strangely, she doesn't act like one.
Shizuku-san decided on Mozuku-chan's
name because it sounded nice.
Tomorrow (4/10)
is Aoba's welcome party!
Don't Overeat or
Drink Too Much!!
Aoba-chan.
What are you doing for lunch?
We're gonna go buy boxed lunches.
I'm almost done with this part,
so I'm going to finish up.
I see.
But it's important to eat.
You should at least snack on this.
I shall repay you one day!
You can buy me lunch sometime.
Are you serious?
I'm finally done!
Yun-senpai, thank you so much.
I wonder what Hifumi-senpai does for lunch.
D-Did you need something?
N-No.
I was just wondering what you did for lunch.
I ate at home before coming here.
What? That's amazing.
I don't have time for that.
Though I come a little before lunch...
I wanted to eat with Sojiro.
S-S-S-Sojiro-san?
Is he your b-b-b-boyfriend?!
Wanna see his picture?
Can I really?
She's so fast with her phone.
Here.
A brush?
A hedgehog.
Oh.
You mentioned a boy's name,
so I thought he was your
boyfriend or something.
My boyfriend?
I can't feel relaxed around men.
Oh! I totally get it!
I get a bit nervous, too.
I don't really speak from experience.
I'm sorry.
I was talking about my fantasy world, too.
I have more.
Wow! He's so cute!
Isn't he?
Are hedgehogs friendly?
Not really.
He's always hiding in his hole.
He's a big coward.
I can see the resemblance.
But...
We've gotten close to where I can touch him.
You're smiling, Hifumi-senpai.
Forget what you saw.
Money?!
No.
Well...
I look so weird.
Not at all!
Your smile is so cute!
You look so kind.
You'd be much more approachable like that.
Do I not look weird?
Not at all!
Then...
No, you were almost there!
I can't.
Then don't look at me.
Look at Sojiro-kun.
Smile. Smile.
Lunch, lun—
What are you doing?
Aoba, did you eat lunch?
Oh, I wanted to work on my training.
Taking breaks is part of the job.
Here, have a rice ball!
I feel kind of bad.
Yun-san gave me her snack, too.
I'll take you out to eat sometime, too!
I can't let the newbie take me out!
When you're busy, you should
buy something before coming in.
Thank you so much.
Thank you for food.
Wow, it's already so late!
I have to eat fast.
Sojiro's...
friend?
Sorry.
N-No worries.
That caught me by surprise.
I'm home.
Sojiro, do you like it when I smile?
Hey.
You brought lunch today?
Yeah.
I got in a fight with Sojiro.
A fight?
I don't think Sojiro likes my smile.
What?
How far are you in the textbook?
Oh, here.
I'm at this part right now.
Cool.
Let's give you a project.
A project?
Real work.
You're gonna work on your first project.
Okay!
This is Knight-kun, the
protagonist of Fairies Story 3.
He looks great no matter how much I see it.
Just incredible.
But this town's kind of
lonely with no one around.
That's right.
Your first job is to make this city lively.
H-How would I do that?
Populate it with people.
I already did the designs,
so you just model them in 3D.
By the way, you call characters
you don't control "NPCs."
Or non-player characters.
The characters you can control are "PCs."
All the NPCs in this town are done,
so you can look at them as reference.
So many cat ears!
So cute!
It's a cat town.
Hifumin did a great job here.
Hifumi-senpai!
I'll do my best, too!
What?
You got your first project, Aoba-chan?
Yeah.
I'll do my best.
Watching you reminds me of
when I was just starting out.
Though she hasn't messed up as much.
I didn't mess up too much, either.
I just sometimes spilled tea
or went to the wrong company.
See what I mean?
Be quiet!
Thank you.
It's my second year now, though!
So don't expect me messing up anymore.
Hot!
No!
I'll go grab a towel!
You totally jinxed it.
I'm sorry.
Aoba's welcome party is
TODAY!! @ Taiheiyo
Don't Be Late
It's pretty hard.
How did Hifumi-senpai do it?
I see!
So that's how that goes.
Aoba!
It's almost time for the party.
How do I do this part?
Aoba!
Huh?
Oh, yes?
It's time.
Don't make everyone wait.
I-I-I'm sorry!
Well, then.
Let's get started with the welcome
party for Suzukaze Aoba-chan.
Cheers!
The company's paying for it today!
Let's all eat and drink like crazy!
Okay!
Time to eat!
Hey, don't grab all the meat!
Aoba, eat this to celebrate.
Huh? What is it?
Just eat it.
What was that? It's so spicy.
Spicy takoyaki, Russian roulette style.
You lose!
Aoba-chan, is this your first
time at a drinking party?
Y-Yes.
After all, you're not of drinking age yet.
What? Is she already drunk?
Yun-san, don't fall asleep.
It looks like Hifumi-senpai
has a high tolerance.
That's right!
And...
Hazuki-san!
I figured I'd drop by.
Suzukaze-kun, how is it?
Do you feel welcomed?
Yes, they're treating me well.
I heard.
You were already assigned a project?
Yes, but I haven't made
much progress with it.
It's still your first day on the project.
Working on a 3D project after just
one week might be too soon, Yagami.
Well, she was working through the
textbook pretty fast, so I figured...
Why can't you be more straightforward?
Not
Straightforward
Just say you were genuinely impressed.
Just Praise Her
Suzukaze-kun.
Yagami isn't very straightforward and is
actually a bit sensitive, so be gentle with her.
I see.
Please just go home already!
This is a party for the character team!
I'm on the motion team...
Don't try to make things complicated!
Our staff can be a little weird,
but I hope you don't get too weirded out.
Not at all.
I was a little apprehensive
about joining the company,
but I'm relieved that everyone's so nice.
That's good.
Now, then.
I'm going to get going.
You're really going home?
Mozuku will get lonely without me.
I'll walk you out.
By the way!
Thanks for the meat.
She ate mine!
Say, Aoba...
Do you have a boyfriend?
What?
Wh-Why would I have one?
But you look like you have one.
What?
Wh-Why would I have one?
Why are you blushing like a little girl?
I work all the time and
have no time for love!
Ko-chan, you're drinking too much.
I'll drink this.
That's a stiff drink!
I jon't have a boyfwiend, eijer.
No one asked you!
Aoba-shan!
Newbiesh should be pouwing
alcohol fer their senpai!
O-Of course.
I-I'm sorry!
Thash not how ya pour beer for shumone!
Watch and learn!
Ko-chan!
See?
This ish the besht in terms
of both looks and tashte!
Wow!
No, don't look so inspired.
Are you okay?
She drank too much despite
being a lightweight.
S-So this is an adult drinking party.
Can you order for me?
S-Sure.
Excuse me!
Coming!
Can I have this... Mori Musashi? Please.
Mori Musashi
(Mori Takezo)
That would be Mori Takezo.
Oh, yes! Mori Takezo.
How would you like it served?
We can serve on the rocks,
water mix, or soda mix.
Hifumi-senpai, how do you want it?
Just as is.
As is?
As is, please.
Straight, then?
Strai—
It would be straight if I serve it as is.
Yes, straight, please!
Mori Takezo, straight.
I'll bring it right out.
Whew.
Wow, alcohol is expensive.
Some go for 800 yen a glass.
I could buy a manga volume with that.
I-I wonder how it tastes.
Um...
May I have a sip?
What?
J-J-Just a sip...
Yay!
The legal drinking age of
alcohol in Japan is twenty.
Excuse me!
I-I-I'm sorry!
B-B-But I haven't done anything yet!
We're closing the kitchen soon.
Do you have anything else
you'd like to order?
What? Already?
It's too soon.
You can drink when you're twenty.
Please stop me sooner.
All right, then.
Who's coming to the after party?
I need to take Yun home.
Huh?
Hifumi-senpai already went home.
I can go.
All right!
Let's go with the three of us!
Bartender, get me whiskey.
You, Aoba?
I'm not trying alcohol anymore, so...
Do they have juice here?
Hey!
I'll have the Orange Blossom!
That's alcohol.
What?
I didn't have any drinks, but I feel drunk.
Hello?
Aocchi!
What's wrong, Nenecchi?
Get this!
Everyone at college treats
me like a middle schooler!
They're so mean!
But you look and act like a kid,
so you can't blame them.
You're one to talk, Aocchi!
B-But I'm a working member of
society and learning adult things.
I'm growing!
What'd you learn?
Like...
How to order alcohol.
Oh, no! Call the police!
I didn't have any.
How's work coming along?
I still have a lot to learn, but it's fun.
I'm modeling Yagami-san's
designs in 3D right now.
Cool.
Is that for Fairies Story 3?
What?!
What?! Are you serious?!
N-No! No!
That silence was just my wishful thinking.
Besides, I can't tell you
what we're working on.
It's confidential information!
I'm sorry, I'll forget it.
I'll forget what I heard.
I won't let you get arrested!
Arrested?!
You drink alcohol so well, Hifumi-senpai.
D-Do I?
I want to drink hot sake with some broiled
stingray fin dipped with spicy mayonnaise.
That's what I aspire to become.
Aren't you a minor?
Next time: "What Happens If I'm Late to Work?"
Next Time
"What Happens If I'm Late to Work?"