I'm Suzukaze Aoba.
No rain can get me down.
No wind can blow me away.
And obviously, no bed can keep me asleep.
It's just another day for me, as a
responsible working member of society.
I went back to sleep!
I'm late!
I'd forgotten that my mom was out today.
Wait, I'm not a student anymore.
What happens if I'm late?
Will I get in trouble?
It's great that you're feeling
more comfortable here, but...
You lack discipline.
As punishment, you're going to stay here in your underwear tonight.
M-My underwear?!
What's up?
Yun-san?
Oh, could it be that you're late, too?
What a coincidence.
Y-Yeah, why aren't you worried?
Well, sometimes, stuff happens
and you end up late.
W-Well, we're technically not late yet.
If we run from the station,
we might make it on time.
Sorry to disappoint you,
but with my endurance,
I can only run for a minute.
So you can go on your own if you want.
So you've already tried.
Get Your Dream Body
in Just 2 Months!
Aoba-chan, are you good at sports?
No, I'm really bad.
When I was in school, I was always
one of the last ones to finish.
People who run slow also usually run funny.
Do you run funny?
Oh, yes.
Something like that.
We're the same!
I'm super slow and always finished last, too.
People always tell me I run weird, too!
I see.
Okay!
I'll run with you!
I wonder if she just didn't
want me to see her run.
We're here.
Let's go!
Huh?
Y-Yun-san!
I'm sorry!
I... can't run anymore!
She's slower than me?
You can't give up!
Let's do our best and run until the end!
At this pace, we can make it on time!
Yun-san.
What?
It's rather empty in here today.
No one's called in sick yet,
so they might be running a bit late.
Three people late?
They all need a reality check.
I'll have to be a little strict with them.
Can you really do that?
Of course I can. How rude!
Good morning.
Wow, how nice of you to be
walking in so leisurely.
Do you realize you're late?
I-I'm sorry.
Especially you, Aoba!
It hasn't even been a month since you joined!
You're not in school anymore!
Right.
Ko-chan, they got to the
front of the building.
Aoba-chan tripped and fell,
and we were helping her pick up her stuff,
so that's why we're late.
You fell? Are you okay?
So that's why your nose is red.
Wh-Why didn't you explain yourselves sooner?
I made a terrible assumption.
You're always working so hard,
so it's not that I actually
think you mess around too much.
But I'm still your manager.
Anyway, I'm sorry for what I said earlier.
I'll let it slide for today,
but make sure all three of
you submit a tardy form.
I tried something new and messed up.
Ko-chan, you should've
asked what happened first.
Yeah, I'll be more careful.
— Several Minutes Later —
So what are these?
They're our tardy forms.
That's not what I meant!
Why did you both put down "overslept"
as the reason for being late?
I can't let you off the hook with that.
Redo it!
And... Hifumi-chan...
I spent too much time
eating breakfast.
What exactly is this?
Breakfast was just so good today, so I...
That's not what I'm saying!
Don't write emoticons on official documents!
Jeez!
Why did I feel bad earlier?
Yagami-san said she'll let us off the hook,
but it was my fault for staying
up late in the first place.
I have to keep myself in check.
Let's do it.
Aoba-chan always gives 100%.
Write your
tardy forms
properly!!
No emoticons!!
(Looking at you, Takimoto Hifumi)
I'm done!
It's pretty good for your first time.
However, it's lacking shadow and depth.
If you compare your character with
Hifumin's, she doesn't stand out as much.
Also, her facial expression looks stiff.
She's also a bit inconsistent.
Think about the balance more.
B-But isn't this just a villager?
People don't look at them that carefully.
Really?
I always look at NPCs carefully.
Like this.
Work on it some more.
Yes, ma'am.
Why is my character moving so disgustingly?
Isn't it disgustingly awesome?
I think Kii-chan should move more swiftly.
What?
That's not how she should be.
She lives in a cave, you know?
You just don't understand.
Let's just agree to disagree.
Yun.
Hifumin.
Get these done this week.
Here.
Wait, all of them?
This week?
Get me some more disgustingly awesome stuff.
O-Okay...
Make sure they're disgustingly awesome.
Don't forget that you're
getting this after me.
No. 164:
Undead Nation Monster
"Golm"
Its body is
composed of minerals
like rocks and clay.
Thanks!!
Comment:
It's a giant made up of three residents
of the Undead Nation
Mozuku.
Even if you beg me, I won't feed you.
Mozuku-chan, it's clear that
your begging has spoiled you.
Your selfish body speaks for itself.
That's right.
So can you play with my body
to your heart's content?
If you'd like...
You can play with my body.
I see.
You prefer Mozuku's body over mine.
What a shame.
You can use him anytime,
so whenever you feel down,
feel free to play with him.
Good night. I'm taking off.
Good night.
It's late, so be careful going home.
Thank you.
Okay!
Yagami-san.
Can you take a look?
Okay.
Use actual objects as reference.
Like this!
- Make shadows clearer
- Look at the actual objects
Check (reference pictures)!
- Look up images online
for relative size. Realistic/Deformation?
leather shoes women's
You need to think about which part of
the character you want to highlight.
Hot!
Aoba-chan.
It's late, so you should go home now.
Okay.
It's much better, but it
still looks a little stiff.
I'll give you the whole day
today, so do another retake.
Okay.
Another retake...
It's true that compared to Hifumi-senpai's,
I may still have a long way to go.
Looks like Yagami-san's being pretty strict.
Here.
A candy.
Thank you.
I was confident it would pass this time.
Don't overwork yourself too much.
I like your character, at least.
Th-Thank you!
Okay.
Sorry to bother you while you're working.
Yagami-san keeps telling me that my
character's expression looks stiff.
How do I make her look cute?
Just feel it out.
I think your character's pretty cute.
What are some things you pay attention
to when you're making models?
I make them while telling
them, "Be cute. Be cute."
Thank you.
I'll do my best!
Good.
Good night.
See ya, Aoba-chan.
What?
Good night!
Oh, no. I'm not done.
Aoba-chan.
How are you doing?
Toyama-san.
I'm still not...
Can I take a quick look?
It's really well done.
I think it's great for a first model.
Oh, but I'm still not satisfied
with a lot of parts.
I can't fool Yagami-san, either.
True.
She's a perfectionist.
Don't worry about delays.
It's already late today, so let's go home.
Okay.
Do you live on your own?
No, I live with my parents.
Then they must be worried with
you coming home late every night.
Yeah.
I called my mom earlier, and she told me
that staying up late is bad for my skin.
So she's not that worried
about your safety...
Is it fun creating an NPC?
It is...
But I never knew it was so difficult.
Before, I just drew on my own,
and it was done when I was happy,
so it's my first time
receiving so many critiques.
I see.
That's what it means to make
something professionally.
To be honest, what you
turned in this morning...
was actually good enough.
What?
What does that mean?
It was good enough, but it got a retake?
We are now arriving at Nakano. Nakano.
I guess she didn't want you to
be happy with just "good enough."
She has high hopes for you, you know.
I have to switch trains here, so good night.
Good luck.
Good night.
She has high hopes for me?
Hello.
Hey, Aocchi.
Wait, are you outside?
Yeah.
I'm near my house.
I'm just getting home.
Wow, a long day at work?
A super long day.
Oh, my mom told me this,
but staying up late is bad for your skin.
I've already heard that today.
What?
It's the first time I told you today.
Sounds like you're doing well at work.
Is it already done?
When's it coming out?
It's not even close to completion.
So it's still not your busiest time?
Are you getting enough rest?
I'm having a hard time modeling
a villager right now.
What? You're modeling a villager?
Yeah.
What's cool about Fairies is how much
detail they put into their mobs.
Yeah.
Yagami-san's really strict about it.
They go into a lot of details
on the character profiles, too.
Aocchi, do you remember?
The three idiots, Dumb,
Dumber, and Dumbest.
Are there mobs like that in the next game?
You sure love that stuff.
I'm just modeling an adorable villager girl.
Like a florist?
Yeah!
She'd be perfect for a florist.
Then she's a gentle girl with dreams.
Wrong.
She takes care of her parents,
is responsible, energetic, and...
Oh, please!
That's basically the same thing.
What?
The dreamer type is more up in the clouds,
but the responsible type
is more tough and sincere.
They're totally different.
Also, her facial expression looks stiff.
Hey, something wrong?
Are you listening?
Hello?
This is Nenecchi.
Can you hear me?
A-Aocchi?
Are you okay?
Hello?
Oh! I'm fine. Sorry.
I have to be up early
tomorrow, so I need to go.
Thanks, Nenecchi.
Snooze
Stop
Wake up. Wake up.
I'm tired.
Morning.
You're early today.
Good morning.
Hey!
Put on a skirt, please.
Oops.
Yagami-san, you should act more
like a lady when you sleep.
Like a lady?
I wasn't praising you.
Um, I'm sorry it's been so delayed.
I just finished up the villager model.
Could you take a look?
H-How is it?
Yeah.
It's good.
It's much better.
Yes!
Well?
Are you satisfied with it?
I'm satisfied with this character,
but if I make another one from scratch,
I think I can do much better.
Also, I spent too long on it.
True.
This one took more than a week,
but let's try making one in three days next.
What?
Was I unclear?
Three days.
C-Could I get four days?
Are you serious?
Ultimately, I need you making one a day.
What?
Is this what Hifumi-senpai was talking about
when she said we'll have to live here?
Well, you can leave when you're done.
No!
I don't want to sleep in my underwear.
Wh-What are you saying?
I'm wearing a skirt now!
I'm talking about when you sleep!
Hello.
Nenecchi?
Sorry for hanging up so abruptly last night.
It's fine.
What's up?
I just wanted to hear your voice.
Wh-What's wrong, Aocchi?
Did you eat something funny?
Don't tell me you're drunk.
We're still minors, you know?
It's really hard with still so much to learn,
but making a game is so much fun.
Good work getting one villager done.
Thank you.
I didn't know you spend
time making every villager.
You'll be making way more, too.
You have another a hundred or so to go.
What?
Can I really get that done?
Next time: "The First... Paycheck..."
Next Time
"The First... Paycheck..."
You have to, even if you can't!