Well, let's see.
She's a bit too tall compared to other
characters, so can you make her shorter?
Oh, you're right!
It's already late today, though,
so you can finish up tomorrow.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
But, Aoba-chan, compared to
before, you were much faster.
Not at all.
I'm still really slow.
Isn't it a lot of work bringing
Mozuku-chan to work every day?
Yeah, he is a bit heavy.
Though that helps me gain some muscles.
You may need to go on a bit of diet.
It's been almost a month since you joined.
What do you think?
Are you getting used to the job?
Not at all.
I still get asked to do a lot of retakes.
But it's really fun!
Wh-What was that picture for?
Your smile was just really good, so I had to.
You had to?
That's not a good reason.
What are you working on right now?
Oh.
I'm almost done with the third villager.
Soon, I think.
So you've been fixing that one up?
Yeah...
And the retakes weigh on me a lot,
but I can tell it gets better
every time I make the changes.
And when Yagami-san gives me the okay,
it's the best feeling in the world.
Oh.
I don't know if I should be saying this.
What is it?
You can tell me everything.
I'll keep it off the record.
I don't think it's good for her
to sleep in her underwear.
It's unprofessional.
I agree.
But when I see her working,
and the more I work with her,
I realize she's simply incredible.
So she's my role model and an inspiration.
I see.
I'm finally alone.
Now, then...
I'm free! I'm free!
What are you free from?
R-R-Rin?!
Why are you here?
I missed the last train.
Here, I bought drinks.
Thanks...
You should be more careful.
You're lucky it was me who found you.
But it actually feels liberating.
I'm the only one here anyway,
so why don't you take off your pants?
Even if it's just you, I couldn't
possibly take my pants off at work!
That's the spot!
I think you have a lot of
knots from sleeping here.
I go home every other day.
I think you should be going home every day!
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
Sleeping here together feels like
we have a deadline coming up.
So true.
It's going to get more lively here soon.
It's our job to prevent that, you know?
I know.
I wonder if the game will sell.
Who knows?
I only care about releasing
a product I'm proud of.
You're so strong.
Do you have butterflies in your stomach
since it's your first project as the AD?
A bit.
Oftentimes I think you
would've made a better AD.
You make the personality
of the game after all.
Let me tell you.
It's thanks to your management that
I get to focus on all my work.
And backgrounds are just as
important in a video game.
Besides, with my personality,
no one would follow me.
Why am I being so negative?
You can't show this side of you to anyone.
Anyway, I don't know if it'll sell well,
but I think it's becoming a good game.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Well, to be honest,
if our newbie, Aoba, is enjoying
herself working on it, we'll be fine.
She wouldn't enjoy working on a boring game.
Yeah, I'm glad Aoba-chan's such a good girl.
But if she wants to be a designer,
I need her to be much more assertive.
She's still new.
I know.
But if it were me, I'd find
a character I like and
ask to design it, even if I got turned down.
You're so staunch.
Am I?
But to be honest, I think she has her
hands full with her villager project.
Maybe you can let her design something
easy once she finishes that.
Yeah.
Once she finishes all her villagers,
I might give her a design project...
Wh-What's wrong?
My computer froze.
I wanted to get back to work, and I can't.
That's it?
It's a big deal!
This is why I hate 3D!
Then want to sleep?
No.
I already had coffee, so I'm gonna design.
Jeez.
Don't overwork yourself.
I'm going to sleep.
Okay, good night.
Alarm
Enter password
It's already morning?
She's showing her underwear again.
Ko-chan, you'll catch a cold.
I wonder if it really feels liberating.
Yeah.
It actually feels pretty good.
I saw it.
It's not what you're thinking!
What am I thinking?
L-Let me explain!
You should be more careful.
You're lucky it was me who found you.
Please hold your card
up to the circle
Open
Good morning.
Hide.
It's Aoba-chan.
Jeez. Why do I have to hide?
Let's get some work donezo.
She said "donezo."
I wonder if Yagami-san
stayed the night again.
Good morning.
Did you sleep here again—
I-I'm sorry!
It's not what you're thinking!
It's not what you're thinking, Aoba-chan!
I didn't see anything!
I won't tell anyone.
I won't tell anyone!
No! No! No!
Hifumi-chan.
Salary Statement
Here you go.
Yun-chan, good work this month.
Thank you.
Hajime-chan.
Yes?!
Keep up the good work.
I'll do my best!
Aoba-chan.
Yes?
Here you go.
Um... What is this?
It's your salary statement.
How much? How much? How much?
Take a look at it later.
M-My salary?
This is your first paycheck, isn't it?
Yeah!
I've never worked part-time either,
so it's literally my first.
So when you do direct deposit,
you just get a statement?
Because when I hear salary,
I had the idea of saying,
"Ooh! I'm gonna be loaded this month!"
Or "I'm poor," depending on
the weight of the envelope.
Aoba-chan, are you really eighteen?
B-But... is it really okay for me to take this?
This is all I've done,
and I've even received overtime.
You're staying late every night,
so don't feel so reserved.
That's right.
So you have to work really hard, so you
can fully contribute to the company soon.
O-Okay!
And once the company realizes your skills,
you'll get a raise!
Hajime-san, did you get a raise?
What gave that away?
Though it wasn't a lot.
You're just gonna spend it all
on the toys for your desk.
Who cares?
I use them as reference.
Yagami-san uses them a lot, too.
Especially this!
You really like that, don't you?
Even though it's useless.
What are you talking about?
Its awesomeness alone makes it valuable.
It's important to work with
a lot of energy, I suppose.
I even have a Western-style sword.
You have everything.
Aoba-chan, hold it. I dare you.
Wow, it's thin, but it's really heavy.
Isn't it?
It's a slab of metal.
I'm surprised that you can...
swing this around.
I-I'm so sorry!
N-No problem.
Wow, it was finally useful.
You get a raise once a year,
so maybe you'll get paid more next year.
Do I get evaluated well
if I produce quality work?
Since you're just starting out, you just
need to complete the work you're given.
But you also get evaluated
on how much you've contributed to the
team in addition to your own work.
By the way, the character team gets
evaluated by your leader, Ko-chan,
Yun
Aoba
Hifumi
Character Team
and myself, the AD.
Leader
Rin
Ko
Contribute?
Sounds complicated.
I suppose.
But for now, just do what
you think is helpful.
But you know,
you guys have it hard with Yagami-san
since she's strict about work.
You say it like it doesn't apply to you.
Oh, right.
Yagami-san isn't the leader
of the motion team.
Wait.
Then why are you in this booth despite
being part of the motion team?
I'm sorry.
I want to be with my own team, too.
We ran out of space at
the motion team booth.
But it's just one booth over.
By the way, do you already know how
you're using your first paycheck?
Oh? I don't know.
I hadn't thought that far ahead.
How did everyone here spend theirs?
If you buy a figure that you like,
it'll be even more memorable!
She's back to full energy.
I bought clothes.
I splurged a bit to buy from a good brand.
Clothes are a good choice.
H-Hazuki-san.
I wonder what you all would look good in.
Oh, this tea is good.
Thank you.
Hazuki-san, what did you buy
with your first paycheck?
Oh, I don't know.
It was so long ago, so I
don't remember too well.
Oh. Then how old are you?
Crack
Hey, Hajime!
That's a sensitive subject.
What?
I'm curious.
Let's see...
I stopped keeping track of
my age after twenty, so...
Let's say I'm forever twenty.
You're not at your desk.
I should've known I'd find
you loitering around.
Why hello, Umiko-kun.
It's fine to take breaks,
but what happened to the documents
I asked you to look over?
I'd forgotten.
Let me finish taking my break.
If anyone's curious to
find out Hazuki-san's age,
I can be of assistance.
Shall we go, Umiko-kun?
Time is of the essence, after all.
Goodness gracious.
Let's go.
See you later.
A mysterious twenty-year-old.
So what were we talking about?
Your first paycheck.
That's right.
What are you gonna do with it, Aoba-chan?
Hm...
I think I'll save up.
She's so realistic.
How did you use yours, Toyama-san?
Me?
I...
What are you guys all talking about?
I was asking Toyama-san how
she spent her first paycheck.
Hey, I wanna know, too.
How'd you use it?
You don't remember?
I can't believe you!
Uh, did we do something?
Why are you so mad?
Ow!
We had a day trip to a hot spring together.
That's right! That's right!
Jeez, you don't have to get
so mad over just a trip.
Just a trip?
We picked the place and everything together.
Oh, now I sorta remember!
Then do you remember where we went?
Ko-chan!
They're so close.
They joined together, too.
It must be a bit lonely that you're
the only new hire this year.
Yeah.
But it doesn't bother me too much since
I feel like we're all the same age.
What are you saying?
We act more immature around you
so we're more approachable.
That's right.
What? Really?
I didn't know that, either.
Hifumi-senpai, do you have
someone you joined with?
Yeah, in another team.
That's disappointing that
you guys got separated.
Not really.
I don't talk much.
Oh, that's right.
By the way, how'd you
spend your first paycheck?
...play...
A cosplay costume.
Seriously?
Do you have pictures?
Not telling.
W-Well, saving up is nice,
but I think doing something
memorable is good, too.
Though some people will forget it anyway.
But you're right.
I'll think of something.
How I should spend my first paycheck, huh?
All right!
I'm done!
Time to go buy figures!
You're buying more?
You jelly?
I didn't ask out of jealousy.
But maybe I'll buy something
on my way home, too.
Aoba-chan, you can take off now, too.
You should take the opportunity
and leave early today.
Thank you, I'll do that.
Shut Down
I wonder what I should do.
Clothes...
Oh, yeah. My parents bought me this suit.
It was expensive, too.
All right.
I'm home!
Oh, welcome home.
The bath is ready, so you should get in.
Okay.
I hope they'll like it.
Ta-da!
I got my first paycheck today,
so I bought a cake!
Rin.
Hey, are you still mad?
No.
I'm not mad at all.
I'm sorry.
I just completely forgot
about the hot spring.
I don't care.
Our very first trip together probably
meant nothing to you anyway.
I'm just kidding.
I'm sorry, Ko-chan.
I'm really not mad.
I know.
Let's go somewhere nice together right now.
I've always wanted to come to this spa.
What's gotten into you today?
Well, you were saying your stomach
hurt from the responsibility as an AD.
Oh, it's better to heat
up your stomach first.
Thanks, Ko-chan.
Wh-What? What is it?
Well, it's just... Rin...
Did you get fat?
Yeah, this upper arm feels kinda...
Rin?
Ko-chan!
Aoba-chan, you bought a
cake for your parents?
Yeah.
My dad was in tears.
Every father's happy when their
daughter does something nice.
But my mom ate it all while he was crying.
Your parents are interesting.
Next time: "That's How Many
Nights We Have to Stay Over?"
Next Time
"That's How Many Nights We Have To Stay Over?"