Is that Aoba-chan's model?
Yeah.
I'm adding motions to her.
This is the idle motion.
What do you think?
Let's see.
She's a cute model, so I think
you should make it more cutesy.
Cutesy?
Hm...
But I don't want to overdo it.
It's kind of embarrassing hearing
them talk about a model I made.
What about this pose?
It looks calculated.
What's up?
I think she's curious about her.
Right.
I know...
So this is the conversation motion?
This is the walking motion?
Wow, and this one?
Please don't tease me!
Sorry.
I couldn't stop because you react so well.
Excuse me.
Could I take a quick look?
Sure, but it's nothing special.
It is!
Even from my desk, it looked
like she was actually alive.
It's been on my mind all week.
Hajime-san, you're incredible.
I-I guess I am.
But I'm sure you could pick it
up if you worked hard for it.
You really think so?
They're so transparent.
You gotta work hard though.
Of course.
Ko-chan, do you have an extra tablet pen?
No, I don't have any.
That's not good.
Mine's not responding well.
We should make Hajime and Aoba go buy one!
Yeah, I'm a genius.
I could just ask the other teams.
Hajime! Aoba!
Yagami-san.
What do you need?
She's so easy to read.
Do they give errands often?
No.
Only sometimes.
But I'm sure I won't be
tagging along next time,
so make sure you don't
throw away any receipts.
O-Okay.
I'll be careful.
I-It feels so good to be a senpai.
I didn't know tablet pens
came in so many sizes.
Which one should I get?
Hm, I don't really know.
Just get the normal one.
Then I'll take this one to the register.
I-I'm sorry.
I forgot my wallet at work.
What?
You're so lax.
Make sure you don't forget it next time.
Did you forget it, too?
No.
I dropped mine.
It's always in my pocket.
What?
It looks like it's not in the store.
I'm gonna go ask the service desk,
so can you go back to work
and bring your wallet?
Okay.
But I'll be sure to keep
an eye out on my way back.
I'm such an unreliable senpai!
But Aoba-chan's responsible.
She's also diligent and cute.
She's also still a teen.
Damn it!
Life isn't fair!
Only 21
Are you okay?
I was enjoying the sunlight and I spaced out.
I know how that feels.
I spaced out and lost my wallet...
Hajime-san, there you are.
Aoba-chan, the service desk
didn't have my wallet, either.
What's this?
Hajime's Wallet
Aoba-chan!
Hajime-san, you're overreacting.
When I went back to work,
I found it on your desk.
Oh, that's right!
I'm sorry I'm such an airhead.
Not at all.
I'm absent-minded, too.
So it kinda makes me feel better.
Oh, no.
I shouldn't agree with you.
Damn it, she's so cute.
But you're cute, so it's okay.
What?
You're cute, too, Hajime-san.
Am I?
Am I meow?
W-Wow, you're so cute...
Oh, stop it.
Yagami-san!
We got the pen.
Hey.
Thanks.
Here you go!
Okay.
Thanks...
Wh-What's wrong?
Oh, me?
What do you mean?
"Oh, me?"
Hajime, I think you got
your persona mixed up.
No need to tell me!
Damn it!
Hajime-san!
We Have
Cold Ramen!
Open
It's gotten really hot lately.
Cold
Boo.
Cold!
Good morning.
Good morning, Aoba-chan.
Is that frozen?
Yeah.
It's the best on hot days.
I didn't know you biked to work.
Do you live nearby?
Yeah, like five stations.
What?
I would take the train living that far.
But we sit all day at work,
so we gotta get some exercise.
You might outgrow your school uniform, too.
It's a suit!
It's true that I do feel like
I've gained some weight.
Why don't you get off one station early?
Oh, good idea.
What bike do you recommend?
What?
I'd need a bike from the station.
Just walk.
Of course...
It's nice and cool at work.
A little too cold, if you ask me.
In that outfit, I'm not surprised.
I should've brought a sweater.
Good morning.
It's really hot outside.
They said it's going to hit 30 degrees.
Oh, you're still in long sleeves, Yun-san?
Y-Yeah.
I don't feel too hot yet.
Good save.
I can't tell her that I don't
want to expose my chubby arms.
Do you think I could lose weight
just by walking one more station?
Wh-What's up?
You're going on a diet?
Yeah.
I think my arms are getting a bit chubby.
Chubby
Could it be...
Wh-What is it?
Do I look fat?
What do I say?
Are you the type who goes
on a diet in secret?
I-I don't do anything.
T-Too close for comfort.
More importantly, I think it's way too cold.
There's nothing more important!
Stupid!
I have to lose weight before they notice.
Are we not allowed to raise the temperature?
Yagami-san was changing it a lot last year.
Let's do it.
Would raising it by two degrees be enough?
I doubt people would notice four.
Hot
It's hot.
Is the AC broken?
Now it's colder than before.
It went down by six degrees?
I don't know who it was, but bring it on.
I'll raise it by eight!
My goodness.
It's really hot.
What did Hajime set it to?
I feel disgusting from the sweat,
but I can't roll up my sleeves.
If I sweat here, I can lose weight!
I can kill two birds with one stone!
Don't give in here, Yun!
Yun-san looks busy.
Do it -in-4-days!!-
in 3 days please ♥
I can't slack off.
Do it -in-4-days!!-
in 3 days please ♥
What?!
Who raised it by eight degrees?
I'll get her the next time she comes.
Bring it on!
Oh, no.
It feels perfect.
I haven't even sweat a full cup.
At this rate...
I'll never be able to wear short sleeves.
Don't be easy on yourself, Yun!
I can't be easy on myself, either.
Unbelievable.
Yun!
Were you raising the
temperature all this time?
Yagami-san!
I-It wasn't me!
It looked like you set
it pretty high just now.
It's because I... I...
I can't tell her I'm trying to
lose weight by sweating at work.
Wait right there!
Hajime?!
I was the one raising the temperature before.
I think it's very clear now.
Yun wants the high temperature, too.
Basically, we have the majority on
setting the temperature to high!
How is it reasonable to decide the
temperature among the three of us?
Then don't you think it's unreasonable
that you get to choose?
Don't try to start a fight with her.
What if the computers overheat?
Look, you two.
I was just—
Hey!
So you three were behind the
drastic temperature changes?
Toyama-san's mad!
Can't you all just come to a compromise?
B-But my tablet will overheat...
I-I'm cold.
If you can't compromise, I forbid you
from changing the AC in the future.
O-Okay.
Thank goodness we got that resolved.
We're done here then.
Go back to work.
It's so cool how she deals
with problems so well.
I admire her.
Really?
We Have
Cold Ramen!
Competitor Aoba looks full of energy!
She used the early riser skill!
Good morning.
Oh, no one's here yet.
Yagami-san...
isn't here.
How rare.
This is her desk.
I am Aoba, a character designer.
Wait! No!
I was just feeling playful, and I...
A-Aoba-chan.
Um...
Good luck.
Th-Thanks...
Yagami-san's desk is always so messy.
I've always been curious.
What are these papers?
I'm not watching.
I won't do it if it's bad!
I think it's okay to just look.
I think so, too!
Wow, these are all character designs.
Bad
They're just minor changes,
but Yagami-san has a lot of redo.
I see Ko-chan scratching her head a lot.
Really? That's so surprising.
Toyama-san's desk is so neat.
It's an old picture!
If the package of Fairies is on here, then...
It must be the first one.
But Yagami-san looks
different in this picture.
She used to be really quiet.
What? That's hard to believe!
Winter, 2 Years Ago
We used to sit next to each other,
and she never tried talking to me,
so I liked her, but...
Spring, 3 Months Later
One day, she just...
Takimoto-san, do you have a second?
I see that you haven't changed.
Well, I'm sorry I tried talking to you, too.
But compared to when I first started,
I think you talk with me a lot more now.
A-Aoba-chan, it's a bit easier to talk to you.
What?
Gee, thank you.
Aoba-chan, Hifumi-chan, good morning.
You're both early.
Good morning.
How was Ko-chan before?
Yeah, she used to be silent,
cold, and a bit unapproachable,
but that's what made her so cool.
That's not what I was asking.
Let's see.
This one time, she got a
candy from one of her senpais.
You can have one.
Thank you.
It's not very good.
That's way too honest!
Not that she's any different now.
She's always been really good
and worked really hard, but...
1 every -2-days-
day!!
She wasn't very good at communicating.
But she can't be a leader like that,
so she's been getting better at it.
It's not exactly the right
kind of communication,
but it just makes her cuter, don't you think?
It seems that when it comes to Yagami-san,
Toyama-san can't communicate well.
I mean this for everyone when I say this,
but I'm really happy that you're
able to get along with Ko-chan.
Thank you.
N-Not at all.
It's not like I'm forcing
myself to get along.
I didn't realize she was being considerate.
I wonder if I should act more
immature around her from now on.
I think you're just fine the way you are.
And I think Ko-chan is just being herself.
Maybe she's too shy to act too cheerful,
so she hides it by acting like a child.
I see.
After hearing her stories,
I prefer the new Yagami-san over the old one.
That's good to hear.
I—
I... want to...
change, too.
But...
I like you just the way you are!
I'm serious!
Good morning.
That's some bag.
I'm not going home for a while,
so I brought some changes of clothes.
You're not going home for a while?
Well...
I get more work done at night?
So she still prefers to work alone.
I'm cheering for you.
Oh, thanks...
You okay?
Sojiro.
Do you think...
I should change?
Sojiro's Food
Should I do what Aoba-chan said...
and act more childish?
What do you think of a more mature me?
What do you think?
Before I joined the company,
I thought Yagami-san would
be a more perfect person.
Were you disappointed?
No.
It's good to know she works hard.
It makes me want to work hard!
Yeah.
I'll work hard, too.
Next Time
"Like... The Release is Canceled?"
Next time: "Like... The Release is Canceled?"