Stare...
Gulp...
Okay.
Is this the last of the
villagers I asked for?
It was so, so hard.
Good job.
I'm going to give you a designing job now.
Here's the profile.
What?!
Aoba-chan, you're designing a character next?
Y-Yeah.
We had to do it last year, too.
It was right when our team had formed,
so we were forced to do a contest.
A contest?
We all came up with designs and
shared them with the group.
I couldn't come up with anything,
and my head started to hurt.
Oh, yeah. You overheated.
That's when I realized I just
like making characters move.
What kind of character are you designing?
Let's see, an eighteen-year-old girl
who just joined a circus troupe.
Her light-colored hair in pigtails
is her distinguishing feature.
She's sincere and energetic,
but slightly airheaded, as well.
Wait, this sounds familiar.
That's definitely Aoba-chan.
She guides the main characters
to the next dungeon...
And she gets killed by
bandits in the process?!
Poor girl.
Character designing is hard.
Maybe I need some references.
I wonder how she's doing.
Pigtails
You have them on your head!
Noogie
How are you doing?
Not good at all.
Let me see.
I see, you're just brainstorming.
None of them feel quite right.
And I've been so busy with work
that I haven't been drawing at all.
If only I'd known this was my next project.
Stop making excuses.
You're right.
I'm sorry.
Yagami-san, were you in
a contest at first, too?
Yeah.
I remember how frantically I drew.
That's how you got the job to
design the main character, right?
Yeah.
Oh, that's right.
I was already the main
designer when I was your age.
Though in your case, you have to surpass
me first, so you won't have it easy.
Wall
But that's why Ko-chan's
senpais didn't like her,
and they picked on her a lot.
Hey!
What do you mean?
It doesn't feel good to have the
main design stolen by some new hire,
fresh out of high school.
I-I acted a bit arrogant, too.
That's why she came to me to rant every day.
Rin, stop.
I think I kind of get it.
When I discovered that you were
the main designer at my age,
I felt a bit bitter...
and a bit envious, too.
Oh, what am I saying?
I need to grow up.
If I were in your shoes,
I would've felt the same way.
Because I love this job!
Did you have fun making the villager models?
Oh? Y-Yes.
I knew it wasn't an important job,
but I loved it.
I see.
That's good.
I put your villagers on the map,
and it's up on the server
now, so take a look.
O-Okay.
Amazing!
I didn't know they looked
like this inside the game!
It's important to feel bitter about defeat,
but when you have fun,
it really shows in the product.
I think that's what's important.
Yeah.
I had fun adding motion to your models, too.
A lot of people from planning,
motion, and programming were
involved in this project.
I may have the job that
gets recognized the most,
but I can't make everything alone.
That means your designs, too.
So don't forget that.
I-I'm suddenly feeling nervous
from the responsibility.
By the way, if I become the main designer
and become Yagami-san's supervisor,
I'll start by taking off the honorific.
Hey, Yagami. Come here.
That's when I'll leave the company.
Same here.
What about you?
I can't say for sure.
Why?
I'm bitter, too.
Then stay bitter.
Yagami-san, I have a design!
Okay, it looks good.
Does she have a name?
Yeah, I did come up with one, but...
But...
It's really embarrassing to say her name.
Holding it in will only make it worse.
Her name's Sophia-chan!
Sophia-chan, huh?
Wait, is this me?
Did you just notice?
Unbelievable!
I hate you, Yagami-san!
Sophia-chan, don't be so grumpy.
Good work.
Tomorrow's Saturday,
so you can get some rest.
Thank you.
Do you have any plans?
I'm going to a movie with a childhood friend.
Really?
That's nice.
I'm going to sleep all day tomorrow!
Mom, I'm hungry!
You're still in your PJs?
Why don't you get dressed?
But it's the weekend.
Mom, I want noodles!
I'm working hard every
day and earning my pay.
I want to really rest up on the days I can.
You're just like your father.
No!
Traffic Rangers
Signal Three
Hero Show
Everyone!
Thanks for coming!
Come back to cheer us on again!
Of course, Signal Three!
They're so awesome!
Iijima
Yun-neechan!
There, there.
What happened?
Miu hit me!
Miu, you're not supposed to hit.
Ren took my... doll... first!
Fine, I get it! Stop crying!
I'll take you somewhere
nice if you stop crying.
You were still asleep?
I'll make you some food.
Can I come in?
You don't have to.
You have to take care of yourself.
It's good.
Thanks.
I wonder how the others are
spending their weekend.
I have to go!
I'm leaving!
I haven't seen Nenecchi in so long.
She's childish, selfish, and a klutz,
and I think everyone calls her
a middle schooler at college.
Oh, no.
Did she invite me today because
she doesn't have any friends?
Aocchi!
Sorry to keep you waiting!
Nenecchi, I'm always here for you!
What?
How rude!
Sorry.
It was just a guess.
I-I have plenty of friends!
I only invited you because I thought you'd
be lonely without anyone your age at work.
O-Of course.
You're so nice, Nenecchi.
D-Don't flatter me.
Let's go buy our tickets.
We'll lose the good seats.
Yeah.
One student, and... one adult.
No!
Two adults!
Which one is it?
One student and one adult!
You should take advantage of the lower price.
It's not fair for you to pay
more when we're the same age.
Then do you want to take
the average of our tickets?
Fine, I'll pay for a bit of yours.
Popcorn!
I want popcorn!
They have salted, caramel, and...
The seasonal banana caramel flavor?
That sounds good!
Really?
Can I have the salted popcorn and melon soda?
So conservative.
Banana caramel is disgustingly sweet.
The flavor name didn't give it away?
We're giving out light
sticks to small children.
Here you go.
Thank you!
I want one.
I want one, but I can't have one.
I'm an adult!
I bet you can get one, Nenecchi.
Here you go.
I can have one?
Of course.
She actually got one.
You can have one, as well.
Wait, me?
I'm not sure how I feel about this.
You swing it during the movie
to cheer on Moon Ranger.
Cool, I didn't know that.
But I'm glad you could come today.
Oh, why's that?
Because if I invited my
friends to watch this movie,
they'd really treat me like a child.
So you're aware of your childish taste.
Is this Magical Girl Moon Ranger
really worth watching in secret?
Of course!
It's nothing to scoff at just
because it's made for kids.
It's going to be a major hit soon!
Does anyone at your work
like anime like this?
Or does everyone just play games?
I'm sure they don't just play
games, but I don't know.
My coworker who has a lot
of figures on her desk might like it.
You can decorate your desk with figures?
She has a ton of toys at her desk.
Maybe she's here in the theater.
No way.
I'm already out.
You're so fast.
You can have some of mine.
Really?
It'll probably make me fat.
It'll Probably Make Me Fat
Actually, that's okay.
Why?
Because!
Oh, it's starting.
You're here, Moon Ranger!
Help!
How dare you make kids cry?!
I'll make you pay!
Mega Particle Requiem Shoot!
Impossible.
Wow, the story was so good.
I was actually a little moved.
I even swung the stick.
Mega Particle Requiem Shoot!
That's wrong.
They're both wrong.
Mega Particle Requiem Shoot!
But it was actually good,
so I kinda want a pamphlet.
But I don't have the guts.
Are you not buying anything, Aocchi?
Wow, she's brave.
But it's a bit embarrassing for me...
Why are you blushing?
Shut up!
What are you buying, Nenecchi?
The pamphlet, the OST, and a poster...
Are what I want, but I don't have money,
so I can only afford the pamphlet.
I got my first paycheck the other day.
Want to borrow some money?
N-No.
Lending and borrowing money
will destroy our friendship.
I'm surprised you even know that.
But you're worried about our friendship.
I like that.
O-Of course.
Compared to the merchandise...
But I really want the merchandise, too...
Wh-What if you buy them for me,
and I take them off your
hands when I have the money?
What?
If you don't come get them,
it'll ruin our friendship.
I'm sure it'll be fine!
Starting today, your job will be to
make a 3D model of Sophia-chan.
Sophia-chan's an important NPC
who'll even be used in events,
She's sincere and energetic, but slightly airheaded, as well...
Short Gloves
Bloomers
so make sure you make her
flashier than the villagers.
Tights
Guides the main characters to the next dungeon and gets killed by bandits
Silk hat
Flashier?
There're only so many pixels
you can use on the screen,
so we adjust the character
density based on importance.
But Sophia-chan's going to die, right?
That's out of our hands.
Ko-chan, we need to go to a meeting.
Oh, right.
Organized
Whatever
Which one should I strive to be?
You'd better not be having weird thoughts.
What do they talk about in the meetings?
Oh, you don't know, Aoba-chan?
You can look at the proceedings
on your computer.
What?
I didn't know that.
Basically, the team leads and
directors meet up to make sure
there aren't any problems.
What happens when there are problems?
Like... the release is canceled...
That would be terrible!
But it's pretty rare.
*It's Common
Well, Iijima-kun,
how's your progress?
What are you talking about?
I'm imitating a meeting!
I'm on schedule with one monster a week.
How is your progre—
Excited
Never mind.
You look like you want to be asked.
How are you doing, Aoba-chan?
W-Well, I think you should ask Hajime-san first.
So basically, I'm doing well.
Okay.
How are you doing, Aoba-chan?
You didn't react!
And you say you're from Kansai?
I've had some delays,
but I got the green light on my design,
so I'm starting on the model today.
Aoba-chan, you're such a good
girl who even reports the delays.
U-Um...
Hajime-san's looking at me with envy.
No, I'm not.
Hifumi-senpai, are you doing well?
The fact that the number
of characters left...
and the number of days left...
don't match... scares me.
Wow, you're right.
Meeting in Progress
We're going to be busy.
I'm sorry.
I messed up the math.
I'll have to ask the character team to stay
some nights or come in on the weekend.
Fun fact: a company order to come in on
weekends earns you PTO, so it's kinda nice.
Way to make light of a situation.
I'll come on the weekend, then.
Me, too.
And you, Aoba?
What's PTO?
We have to start there?
Look at what I got!
A sleeping bag!
You're going all out.
You're staying the night
and coming on the weekend?
Just the first time.
I want to put a lot of time into Sophia-chan.
I even brought a change of clothes!
You sound like you're enjoying
yourself, but this is overtime.
I know!
At night, only turn on the
lights for your section.
Okay!
Boo!
Jeez.
If she didn't pull pranks like that,
I could actually respect her.
Whoa!
I didn't recognize you for a second.
You're cute, even when you dress like a slob.
Okay!
Let's do this!
Hour
Later
2 Hours Later
3 Hours Later
4 Hours Later
Aoba!
Where am I?
At work!
If you have a sleeping bag, sleep in there.
You're gonna get sick.
Oh, that's right.
I'm going to sleep soon, too.
Good night.
Ta-da!
Bear sleeping bag!
Bear!
Sleeping at work feels kinda weird.
And it's interesting to see something new.
I can't go to sleep with them watching me.
Yagami-san.
I can't sleep.
Wh-What's that?
It's a bear sleeping bag.
If you can't sleep, you can sleep with me,
or the meeting room is a private
room, so you can sleep there.
I'll go to the meeting room.
Okay, good night.
Good morning.
Morning.
Is Aoba-chan out for breakfast?
Meeting Room 1
Occupied
Aoba! Wake up!
Everyone's coming to work!
Aoba!
What?
You went to go watch the
Magical Girl Moon Ranger movie?
Yeah.
My childhood friend invited me.
I went, too.
Right after watching a hero show.
Really?
Mega Particle Requiem Shoot!
No, it's supposed to be
You guys are both off.
Don't tell me... you went, too, Yun?
My brother and sister begged me
to go, so I had to tag along.
That's it.
You had to go?
Really?
Really!
Is Moon Ranger popular?
Of course!
Everyone on my social network
talks about it every day.
That's because you just follow
people with the same hobbies.
Next time:
"Please Train the New Hires Properly."
Next Time
"Please Train the New Hires Properly"