We have a
check-up next week!!
Don't forget!!
Preliminary questions for
Takimoto Hifumi     at 14:00 in
Iijima Yun               Meeting
Shinoda Hajime       Room 1
Sorry to bother you, Suzukaze Aoba-san.
Oh. Yes?
I'm from the programming team.
We're getting errors from your NPCs.
I'm sorry.
They all seem to be careless mistakes,
but there are a lot,
and it's quite troublesome.
I-I'm sorry.
Is this an important NPC?
Oh, yes!
I just finished it.
It's very cute.
Thank you.
But this has errors, too.
That's going to be problematic.
Errors?
Where?
Right here.
It tells you the error with details.
You're right.
These errors show up in the game, as well,
so could you make sure it's error free?
I thought it was fine because
the designs were going through.
No one told you about that?
Yagami-san didn't tell me anything.
That wretch.
Small errors can sometimes
cause large errors.
I'm sorry.
Since these are visible errors,
it's my fault for not correcting them.
I'll fix them right away.
Undoubtedly.
Please fix them immediately.
How typical of artists to only
pay attention to appearances.
S-So long as you fix them,
I'll have no problems.
I compiled the errors into a list,
so please let me know when
you're done fixing them.
Okay.
So I know I've seen you a few times.
May I ask for your name?
I'm Umiko.
Is Umiko your last name?
I-I'm sorry.
I'm Aha...
Aha-san?
Aha...n.
Hey, Ahagon!
Yagami-san?
Don't call me by my last name.
I tell you every time.
But Ahagon's a perfect name for you.
No, it's not!
Ow!
Ow.
Ow. Ow. Ow!
Don't shoot people
who aren't wearing goggles!
Ahagon-san?
That's a rare last name.
You write it like this.
Ahagon
I'm from Okinawa.
I see.
But, Suzukaze-san,
please call me Umiko.
Are we clear?
Y-Yes.
Ko-san, please train the new hires properly.
You're making more work for everybody else.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
Don't feel down.
It was partly my fault.
She's much nicer than she acts.
I bet she's feeling down,
thinking she said too much.
I said too much.
Suzukaze-san looked pretty scared in the end.
I'm sure she hates me now.
Come to think of it,
she looked like a monkey who felt bad.
What am I saying?
But if she is a monkey,
she should be happy if I
give her toys or snacks.
Though I've never had one as pet.
I see.
Umiko-san came and gave you a word?
It was my fault.
I didn't notice the errors.
But I'm so glad she didn't shoot me.
Umiko-san doesn't usually shoot people.
Only when you make her mad.
You know, her collection's incredible!
Oh.
I guess you two are a bit similar.
I suppose Umiko-san might
be a bit short-tempered.
A little birdy told me,
at last year's check-up, the nurse
was taking too long with the shot,
so she just tried to put it in herself.
I'm sure it's just a rumor.
Rumors are always exaggerated.
Knowing her, it might not be just a rumor.
I agree with Takimoto-kun.
Hazuki-san!
That sounds like something
Umiko-kun would do.
She showed up out of nowhere again.
I wish she'd stop shooting
people with airsoft guns,
but it's great to have
reliable staff like her.
I see.
Sorry to bother you, Suzukaze-san.
Ahago—
Umiko-san.
Thank you for coming.
Thank you for putting
in the fixes so quickly.
They're perfect.
Really?
I'm so glad.
And I think I said too much
earlier, so I'm sorry.
She really felt bad about it.
This is something I treasure,
but I'd like you to have it.
I can't!
It was my fault to begin with.
I'd feel bad.
No.
Please don't worry.
But...
Here you go.
What? What is this?
Oh, it's an empty shotgun shell.
It's the real deal.
Isn't it amazing?
I got it from an American soldier back home.
It doesn't have any monetary value,
but you can still smell the gunpowder,
and it gets your blood pumping.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I digress.
Here you go.
It's for you.
Oh, thank you.
I still have much more to see at my desk,
so feel free to stop by if you're curious.
Okay.
Though unfortunately,
I don't have any real guns.
It would be a crime if you did.
Thank you so much.
I'll take care of it.
I didn't know you were
into military stuff, Umiko-san.
I know.
Would you like to play airsoft sometime?
It's really fun.
Oh, no.
I'm terrible at sports, so I'm sorry.
I suppose you need to be athletic.
Guns aren't light, either.
Yeah, so I'll...
Then how about FPS games?
What are FPS games?
They're shooter games.
played in first-person view.
Even beginners can play those games.
But don't I need good
reflexes to play those...
Not at all.
I think it'll be too hard for me.
Positioning is more important than character
control, so it's all about experience.
But...
When you discover the fun of killing
other players, you'll be addicted.
I think she likes me.
But if you don't like PvP,
there's also co-op where you
cooperate with other players.
When you clear a mission through
teamwork, it's extremely satisfying.
However, you have to start by watching
the good players from the back.
Is she going to be done soon?
What's going on?
Are you going to play airsoft, too?
No, she was just telling me about it.
Yeah, it can be a bit
difficult for beginners,
but with an experienced player like myself...
Until you get mad and start
shooting friendlies, too.
In what world would I ever do that?
See?
You get mad so easily.
You're the one who makes me mad!
It's almost time to go home.
I'll let you experience
just how fun airsoft is.
Experience?
I'll show you to my secret training field.
Look at this, Aoba.
The view is beautiful.
Wow.
It's getting me excited.
Why are you here, too?
Come on, let me join.
I want to know about your hobby, too.
Well, whatever.
It's not like I have anything to hide.
Welcome to my secret training field.
Wait, Umiko...
I have permission to do this here.
Please don't worry.
I'm all ready!
U-Um...
Please be gentle with me.
Yes.
Open your legs a little more.
Aim carefully and pull the trigger slowly.
Be calm.
And squeeze.
I got it!
Well done, Suzukaze-san.
You have talent.
Wow, this feels great!
With practice, you'll even be able to do this.
Incredible!
I bet even I could do that.
Are you being serious?
Dead serious.
Can I borrow them so I can try?
It wouldn't be exciting
to just lend them to you.
I have an idea.
Um...
Isn't this dangerous?
This is how they did it in the West.
We're using soft, colored pellets,
so there's no danger.
I've always wanted to try this.
Are you ready?
Ready.
One...
Two...
Three...
Four...
Five...
Six...
Seven...
Eight...
Nine...
Ten!
I can't hit you if you dodge.
I'll get hit if I don't dodge!
Ahagon! Ahagon! Ahagon!
Are they friends or are they enemies?
Please Deposit
Used Robes
Here
Once you've changed into these robes,
please wait in the lobby.
I didn't know they did company
check-ups at hospitals.
I've never had barium before.
I'm so excited!
Wait, do we get barium?
That's only for older people.
Darn.
It's better to not do it!
Though I don't speak from experience.
Hey.
Your bra's cute, Aoba-chan.
What brand is it?
I don't know.
I don't pay attention to brands.
Maybe there's a label somewhere.
Is this it?
I don't really feel comfortable
talking about that stuff.
Wow.
This robe is kinda thin.
It doesn't have pads either,
so my breasts really show.
Okay, I'm ready.
Oh, they have it easy.
Toyama-san.
Hey, girls.
Wow!
Yagami-san!
Are you okay?
She looked at her own blood during the test,
and she started to feel sick.
N-No.
That's not it.
Be careful.
Th-That... nurse...
Wh-Wh-What did she mean by that?
Takimoto-san.
Y-Yes?
First, I'll take your blood pressure,
and then take your blood.
Don't worry.
Just calm down.
O-O-Okay.
Let's take some deep breaths.
Hifumi-senpai, that's for giving birth.
S-Suzukaze-san!
Yes?
I'll measure your blood pressure first,
a-a-and then take your blood.
O-Okay.
Your blood pressure rises
when you're nervous,
s-so let's start with a few deep breaths.
O-Okay.
I-I don't have much experience yet,
but I know the textbook inside and out,
so please feel at ease!
So this is what she meant.
Okay, your blood pressure
measurement is done.
I bet it's high.
Now, let's take your blood.
L-Let's wait just a bit!
Let's calm down first.
Y-You're right.
Let's take a few deep breaths.
Not her, too...
I'm sorry.
One of my patients collapsed earlier.
So I'm a little nervous.
I know.
I think that's my manager.
Is that so?
Please tell her sorry.
She had thin veins, so it took
me a few tries to get it right.
Oh, but don't worry.
I can see your veins.
I can do this.
Ready?
It's done.
Give me the old nurse!
I'm going out for a bit.
Can you take care of things while I'm gone?
Oh, yes.
No problem.
Will she be okay?
Your back is open.
That wasn't fair.
It's over.
It didn't hurt that much.
Welcome back.
N-Next up, Anamine? Awane?
That's me.
It's Ahagon Umiko.
W-W-Well, I'll take your blood
pressure and then your blood.
Let's see.
Wait. How do I do this?
Of course.
Just remember the textbook.
N-Next, I'll take your blood.
Blood Drawing
Are you prepared for this?
Wait a minute.
I don't feel comfortable
with how you're acting.
Can I really trust you?
Don't worry.
I've memorized the textbook.
Wait.
I've never had a dark-skinned patient
before, so I can't see the vein.
Goodness, you're so slow.
I'll do it myself!
You definitely can't do that!
It was all true.
I'm so glad nothing bad happened.
So true.
Of course nothing bad happened.
But the true test has yet to come.
I'll measure your waist.
I've been on a diet, and I
didn't eat all day yesterday.
Next person, please.
Thank you.
That's good.
There's the number.
Wow, your waist is very tight and pretty.
Oh, really?
Thank you.
Do you do any sports?
Just a little exercise.
Though I don't do anything too much.
Wow, she's right.
Your abs are so pretty.
Hey, that tickles.
Hajime.
C-Can I touch it, too?
Sure.
You win!
Come again?
Wow, your waist is pretty, too.
And nice abs.
Thank you.
I put in the work every day.
Oh, every day?
So do you go...
Yes.
Airsofting.
We get some laborious work
at the programming team,
so we need to maintain fit and
healthy bodies to prevail.
You sound so professional and admirable.
Hazuki-san.
Are you okay?
Well.
I took barium.
But I'm not used to it.
Umiko-kun!
Can I sleep on your lap?
Your thighs are so nice and tight.
Want to die?
It's weird.
I feel like a different
person after meeting you.
This is so relaxing.
I feel the same.
No!
This isn't like that at all.
I was able to be honest with myself.
I'm so grateful.
Thank you.
I feel so rested.
Want to grab something
to eat on the way back?
I'm starving.
I'm in!
Thank you, Yagami-san!
What?
I didn't say I'm paying.
I'll take something with low calories.
I have a meeting, so I'm heading back.
Unfortunately, I have to go back.
I have to go over this month's schedule.
Schedule, huh?
We're going to be getting part-timers soon.
Part-timers?
For debugging.
We need to ask for some outside help.
With the development deadline coming up,
we're only going to get busier from here.
So please join me for some
airsoft while we have the time.
Like I've said before,
I'll totally pass!
Really?
You guys have company check-ups?
Did you get taller?
I haven't really grown.
How are you doing?
I have finals coming up, so I've been busy.
Once I'm done with those,
I'll be on summer break, though.
Summer break?
I wonder how many days off I get at work.
Is it going to be hard to take days off?
Yeah.
I heard we need to hire some part-timers.
But I should have time on Sundays,
so let's go play again.
Aocchi
Aocchi's working hard.
I wonder what it's like
to work for a company.
Good work this week.
How was your check-up, Suzukaze-san?
I got all As.
But don't overwork yourself.
I'll be careful.
Next time:
"It's Summer Break!!"
Next Time
Whose voice was that?