Yay!
I'm done with finals!
It's summer break!
Oh, hey, Aocchi.
How long's your summer break?
Let's go play!
College is awesome!
I have two months of summer break.
Aren't you jealous?
Aocchi?
Apparently, I don't get a break.
Sorry.
We're getting busy going
into the final phase,
so we don't get a break until we're done.
Then you're gonna be busy working?
Yeah, but it only makes the game better.
You should buy it when it's out.
Of course I'll buy it.
Sorry!
My lunch break is almost over!
See ya!
I wonder if she's okay.
No experience necessary!
Love your work and gain experience.
Nice to meet you.
My name is Umiko, and I
will be your supervisor.
You'll be starting your
part-time shifts today, and...
Wait.
We're missing someone.
Goodness.
Being tardy on the first day is unacceptable.
I'll have to see if I can fire her.
U-Um...
Over there.
I'm fired?
What's your name?
I-I'm Sakura Nene!
I'm sorry I'm late!
I'll overlook it today,
so be punctual in the future.
O-Okay.
We make our game on this floor.
We have about three teams working right now.
I can't see Aocchi with all the walls.
Stop jumping!
This is the booth where you'll all be
playing the game and debugging.
The game you'll be testing is Fairies Story 3.
Wow!
No way!
It's still unannounced,
so please keep confidential
information within the company.
I already knew because Aocchi told me.
Something on your mind, Sakura-san?
N-No!
I didn't know anything!
That's the quick rundown.
Anyone have any questions?
Sakura-san, you look a little restless.
Oh, do I?
Could it be...
that you're a spy from another company?
I'm just a college student!
I'm sorry.
Well, whatever.
If anyone has any questions, let me know.
I'll be back to check up on you, as well.
Aocchi's company seems pretty strict.
I'm really worried for her.
I-I'm gonna go use the restroom.
Yeah.
The balance is a bit off here.
I see.
Nenecchi?
Why am I hiding?
What is she doing here?
Is it just a look-alike?
You okay?
She's coming this way!
These are super rare!
That's definitely Nenecchi.
Y-Yagami-san, did we get a new recruit?
I didn't hear anything.
Oh, did the part-time debuggers start today?
Yeah.
I think Umiko-chan's in charge of that.
I see.
Knowing Nenecchi,
she didn't tell me about
it in order to surprise me.
But why would she work
here just to surprise me?
What's going on with you?
I've made up my mind!
I-I see!
Understood!
I've found her.
And she hasn't noticed me.
Time to surprise her.
Sakura-san.
What are you doing here?
U-Um...
Why are you sneaking around
the place without permission?
You must be a spy.
Come with me!
I-I'm going to get arrested.
Why isn't she coming?
Aocchi, help me!
Seriously?!
I see.
So she was your friend.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, as well.
You always make things complicated.
Why would we have a spy?
Why wouldn't we?
I joined here as a spy, at first.
What? Seriously?
It was a joke.
Hey, Aocchi.
Oh, sorry.
This is Toyama-san, the game's AD.
I'm Toyama Rin.
Nice to meet you, Sakura-san.
By AD, I don't mean assistant director.
Yeah, I know.
Art director, right?
A-Anyway, she's Yagami Ko-san,
a character designer.
Hey, nice to meet you.
Yagami Ko?
The character designer for the Fairies series?
Nenecchi, stop!
It's the real deal!
Sakura-san.
I-I'm sorry.
Thank goodness I wasn't arrested.
It's nice I get paid to
play an unannounced game.
This might be a great part-time job.
It froze again.
Jeez, how do I play the game
when it freezes so much?
It's your job to report that!
Aocchi!
It's almost lunch break.
Want to eat lunch together?
Yay!
Let's go!
Oh, and let me introduce my coworkers.
U-Um...
I'm Sakura Nene.
Nice to meet you.
She was so rowdy earlier, but she's so timid.
Is she your kouhai, Aoba-chan?
See?
I told you that you look more childish.
You're just a bit taller than me!
Yes! That's right!
And that means?
They both look like kids.
Thank you for the meal.
I should've bought dessert.
Oh, I'll be right back.
My, my!
What's a spy doing here?
I-I'm not a spy!
Hazuki-san, you, too?
Hazuki-san?
Yeah.
She's the director of Fairies Story 3.
Th-Then she's the most important person!
If a spy were as cute as you,
I'd tell her every secret.
I know.
I'll take your picture for your ID card.
Come on, get closer.
You can't use that as your
identification picture.
You don't need to say that.
No one's acting surprised despite
our strange interaction.
A-Aocchi's company is so weird!
I'm back.
Ta-da, here you go!
Wow, those look delicious!
Can I really have some?
We got them as Obon gifts
from one of our partners.
So we share them with
everyone in the company.
They're in the fridge, so feel
free to grab some for yourself.
This company is the best!
Every day, it's the same thing over and over.
Debugging is hard.
Sakura-san, were you slacking off just now?
N-No, not at all.
"Bugs!"
·Character clips through the counter at Gorudo's item shop.
·During a battle on sea, tapping the buttons while using
fire or light spells caused a hard lock (freeze).
·If you sell the morning star you bought in Oh Village
in the next town of Giiru, it sells for a higher price.
·When fighting the Bubbleman, the magic barrier seems too strong.
·If you go back to Ien Springs with Mystoria in your party,
you'll end up in a battle with Mystoria again (this causes a freeze whether you win or lose).
·The ice wand causes the Frost Giant a lot of damage?
·Even when you use holy water in the Kekero Forest, you still encounter enemies.
·Opening the window after entering the back gate at Gyameru Castle causes a hard lock (freeze).
"???"
·The inn in Rupi Village was...
·The "Blade of Darkness" should have been called "Sword of Darkness" in 1...
(The knight called it "blade")
·Using the Tome of Darkness while Conner-kun is present...
·Blue sapphire? Blue sapphire?
·The phrase that the soldier at Coldol Castle says was similar to Steng in game 2.
·The status of the imperial knights is similar to the
AGI of the lightly-armored soldiers in game 1, is that OK?
·The name of the place that Bald said he was from was...
·Sophie-chan doesn't die?
U-Um...
Something wrong?
No.
If you notice anything,
even the tiniest things,
please put them all on your report.
O-Okay.
Can't fight on an empty stomach, or something.
Hey, there's a pudding!
It's the last one.
Lucky me!
I won't let you lay a hand on Sophia!!
The Lost Forest Bandits
I just need to keep her in this
tight space and swing my sword.
Your Sophia-chan won't die!
Wow!
You found a way to keep Sophia-chan alive!
It doesn't let me get past this scene, though.
Oh, Toyama-san!
Look at this!
This is a bug, so let's report that.
I figured...
More importantly, Aoba-chan.
You're still on the clock, so don't
be away from your desk too long.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Sakura-san, I understand you're friends,
but don't call her over too much.
O-Okay.
Rin-san, do you have a second?
I have a question regarding some backgrounds.
Also, Hazuki-san was looking for you.
Oh, okay.
I'll be right there.
Rin, there's a crisis.
What happened?
My pudding is gone!
Oh, you scared me for a second.
But I put it in the fridge!
Rin...
Ko-chan, you're last.
Toyama-san seems really busy.
Oh, yeah.
We're putting out the beta version tomorrow.
The beta version?
Yeah, a sample to give to our publishers.
They determine if the game's playable
to the point we promised,
and if the quality is up to par.
Ideally, we want to give it to
them in a nearly completed state.
I see.
If this doesn't pass, we can't sell the game!
What?
So you better get busy, Aoba!
You're behind on your villagers.
I-I know!
I'll see you later, Nenecchi.
But seriously, whatever
happened to my pudding?
Ko
I need to apologize!
Sakura-san.
You're on the clock right now.
Please don't leave your desk too much.
Oh, but I...
No buts.
Okay.
Get back to your desk.
O-Okay.
Rin, I made up for Aoba's delay,
so can you take a look?
You're a lifesaver.
Thank you.
Oh, did you ever find your pudding?
Not at all.
Someone stole it?
I didn't realize our workplace wasn't safe.
It's not that serious.
Sure it is.
We need to have maximum efficiency,
even after we release the beta.
We need to resolve this
to keep our teams united.
What?
What can we even do?
I have a plan.
Good day, everyone.
Yagami Ko's pudding was stolen
from our fridge today.
If you took it, please come see
me at my desk. I won't get mad.
Oh, my God!
This only works on grade schoolers.
Oh, do you think so?
Yagami-san, can you check?
Okay.
Oh, I read the email.
Was it a really valuable pudding?
No.
Just a 100 yen one from the convenience store.
What?
You sent an email to the
employee list just for that?
See?
You turned this into something serious.
Something serious?
That wasn't my intention.
If I turn myself in right here...
I see.
So you were the thief.
How dare you take my pudding?!
I-I'm sorry!
I'm sorry, too!
Since you're friends with such a bad girl,
you must be one, too, Aoba-chan.
Aocchi.
I'll get Aocchi in trouble.
Get Aoba-chan in trouble?
Do you need something?
U-Um...
I...
Never mind!
Why did she run away?
The Next Day
Nenecchi, you look tired.
I'm fine.
Hey.
Oh, hello.
Is it okay if I sit here?
Sure, go ahead.
What's up with those bags?
You both look really sleepy.
We found a bug at midnight, right as we
were about to burn the beta version.
We were up till morning dealing with that.
Th-That's rough.
But we got it all sorted out,
so I think we'll get a good mark.
That's great to hear.
By the way,
this is for you.
Thank you for making up for my delay.
Wow! Thank you!
Did you figure out who took your pudding?
I still have no idea.
But I don't really care.
Well, I'm sure the thief
deeply regrets her actions.
Really?
Ko-chan.
Yagami Ko-sama,
I'm sorry for
eating your pudding!
Hey! My pudding!
I never thought I'd see it again!
Well, it's thanks to you, Rin.
You can have it.
Thanks.
That's great.
Isn't it, Nenecchi?
Y-Yeah.
Was my email a good idea?
I guess so.
I still think the thief should
come apologize in person.
You're harsh, Aoba.
Actually, she quietly came
to apologize yesterday.
Seriously?
Who was it?
Secret.
What?
My email might've made it
harder for her to say sorry,
and the pudding is a sign
that she feels bad about it.
Aoba-chan, don't be too
hard on the thief, okay?
I see.
I guess the thief was actually
a pretty sincere person.
You, too, Nene-chan.
Okay.
I'm sure she regrets it deeply.
Nenecchi, you're awfully quiet today.
What? No, I'm not.
Wow, this pudding is good!
I know, right?
I'm getting sleepy now that I've eaten.
Yeah, me, too.
Can I go home early today?
O-Of course not!
Stay the full work day.
Something wrong?
No.
I thought companies were a lot scarier,
but it looks like you have
a lot of good coworkers.
Right?
Yeah.
Another hard day at work.
H-Hold the door!
Safe.
Good work today, Sakura-san.
Sakura-san.
Y-Yes?
Thank you for staying so late again today.
S-Sure.
Sakura-san.
Y-Yes?
You noted things that didn't seem
consistent with the previous games
in addition to all the bugs you found,
and the planning team found it very helpful.
O-Okay...
Have a good evening.
Was she complimenting me?
Aocchi, did you mess anything
up when you joined?
I sent Yagami-san a message with emojis.
What?
I mean, I messed up, too.
We both need to be more careful.
Next time: "Do We Have To Come Into Work?"
Next Time
"Do We Have To Come Into Work?"