Yes, that's good.
I can't quite get the timing right.
Again.
Come on.
And she has panties on!
No bug found!
Hold it right there.
What were you testing?
Someone wearing something or not?
Well...
We can't have anyone without panties.
That would indeed be a problem,
but you're not supposed to be able to
see their underwear, so this is a bug.
Please note it.
Okay.
No, that's in the specs.
The secret specs.
What?
That's news to me.
Of course.
What's the fun in knowing you can do it?
The accidental panty shot.
That's where the dream is.
Not to mention it'd be a huge
waste to keep the panties
the artists designed inaccessible.
S-So true!
Very well.
Then please put "shots of
underwear" in the specs.
It'll cause confusion.
Would we call them "undie shots" then?
It doesn't sound quite right.
Umiko-kun's just being shy.
Don't comment on that.
You're not as mature as you act.
Shut your mouth.
Are you sick?
You okay?
Sorry.
I can't stop coughing.
If you're sick, you should go home.
You don't want to make everyone sick.
I'm fine.
It's just a cough.
And I can't take any breaks
when we're so busy.
Let's go home.
You have to get some rest.
I'll take you home by force if I have to.
F-Fine.
I'll go home by myself,
so you can go back to work.
No.
You're gonna work at home.
How'd you know?
Easy.
We've been together all these years.
I'm going to take Rin home,
so take care of the rest.
You guys can handle things
on your own, right?
We'll be fine,
but I didn't realize
Toyama-san was badly ill.
Please take care.
Not at all.
It's really nothing serious.
Let's go home.
You're gonna get my team sick.
Ko-chan, it's not that serious.
I-I'm the oldest member here... now.
Double Moon Shower!
Seriously, that's annoying!
Stop making so much noise!
Sorry.
I got carried away because
our managers are gone.
I have to say, I was really surprised
Yagami-san left early for Toyama-san.
Honestly, I've never seen her act so manly.
If I were Toyama-san, I might fall for her.
I thought Yagami-san was the type who'd say
things like, "Get better with willpower!"
She's pretty strict,
but she does have a soft side.
Goodness, you look dead.
I'm fine.
You're sweating a lot.
Let's wipe you dry and get you changed.
I'm too tired, so I'll just go to sleep.
No, you have to change.
I'm looking through your drawers.
Okay.
Hm...
How do the wrinkles on a coat look?
Hajime-san, can I borrow the Dandy Max
figure you have on your monitor?
Aoba-chan, you know who that is?
Y-Yes.
I watched it once on TV when I was little,
and it was interesting,
so it just kinda stuck.
I see, so you knew.
It's an underrated masterpiece,
so not many people know the movie.
The Real Figure series
is super well made, too.
I can understand why it piqued your interest.
Isn't it just perfect?
Um, I... Yes.
It does look like him.
Even just a copy of myself draws people in.
Even this doll that only
has 1% of what I have.
Dandy, dandy.
Oh!
The dandy talk!
Yes!
Oh, no.
I just wanted to see it for the coat.
You're being too loud again.
Thank goodness, a lifeline!
But if you're talking about
me, I can't stop you.
Fine, I'll join you in your conversation,
but only for a little bit.
Dandy, dandy.
I'm doomed.
You know it, too, Yun?
Hey! Are you talking about Dandy?
Th-This is crazy.
You know it, too, Nene-chan?
Come on.
My name was supposed to
go in the history books.
Dandy!
I'm surrounded by so many Dandy fans.
I'm so blessed!
Is it really something to celebrate about?
How did you feel when you
first watched Dandy Max?
Wh-What should I do?
"What is this?"
I know!
They're not supposed to be
messing around right now.
I-I have to... say... something.
U-Um...
What's with all the commotion?
You're still on the clock.
I understand you've loosened up a little
with Rin-san and Ko-san gone,
but please work quietly
during normal work hours.
That's common sense.
S-Sorry.
Sakura-san.
Go back to your desk.
O-Okay.
Sakura-san.
What did you come here to do?
Was it to see Suzukaze-san?
Are you here to play?
There is an
electrical inspection
this Saturday!!
No!
I was worried about Aocchi because she said
she had no summer break
and had to stay overnight.
You were worried about Suzukaze-san?
She spent a lot of time deciding
whether to come here or go to college.
She had been accepted into an art
college with her close friends,
but she chose to chase after her
dream and decided to work here.
I was worried that the company she picked
turned out to be a weird environment.
After working here, I see that
it's a pretty good place.
Pretty good?
The reason I'm always roaming around is...
because of my personality, but...
I would never fool around when it comes
to work that Aocchi is involved in!
I see.
Very well.
Your notes have been pretty thorough,
so I'll believe you for now.
However, no matter how sincere you may be,
people can only make judgments
based on your actions.
Do you understand?
Okay.
Sakura-san.
How long have you known Suzukaze-san?
Forever!
I mean, for a long time. We're neighbors,
so we've been together
from before preschool all
the way through high school.
That's pretty incredible.
I don't have any friends whom
I've known for that long.
Yeah!
I've only known Aocchi for that long.
She can be a bit of a klutz,
so she really needs me.
Here.
I made you porridge.
I heard a lot of noise over there.
Was everything okay?
Yeah. Of course.
All good.
I'm happy, but you can go back, Ko-chan.
We're busy.
Don't worry about me.
You should worry about getting better, Rin.
Can you eat it?
Feed me.
I said, feed me!
I think you're feeling better.
No.
I still feel lightheaded.
I don't want to drop it.
Jeez. This is the only time!
Here, open wide.
It's a little salty.
What?
How dare you?
So picky.
But it's good.
We can't come into work?
Yeah.
This weekend, they're doing
a checkup on the power lines,
and you won't be able to use the computer,
so you wouldn't be able to
do anything, even if you came in.
Rin-san and Ko-san both left early,
so I figured you didn't know.
It looks like I was right.
Yay!
That means you can take a
break this weekend, Aocchi!
Nenecchi.
But the schedule's tight.
Also, we've added underwear shots that
can occur upon zooming in to the specs,
so some models will need corrections.
I believe you'll get the official
notice through Rin-san later.
I found those.
That only adds more work.
Maybe I'll stay the night.
If I can't come in tomorrow, I'll stay, too.
M-Me, too.
If we have corrections to do.
You're all staying the night?
My team's not that busy, but...
if you're all staying the
night, maybe I will, too!
You make it sound like a party,
but this is work, not a sleepover.
Is it because I found something
weird that you have more work?
Not at all.
Don't worry about it, Nenecchi.
That's right.
It's not your fault, Sakura-san.
The blame goes to the person who
nonchalantly changed the specs.
That's good, I suppose.
I know!
I'll stay the night too and help
out by getting food and stuff.
There's no problem if I
stay off the clock, right?
I think you'd only get in their way.
It's more than enough that
we're in your thoughts.
Okay.
Don't work too hard.
Good night.
Be careful, as it's dark outside.
Sakura-san's a little weird.
Y-Yeah, I guess so.
But Nenecchi always lifts my spirits.
She said you guys go way back.
Yeah.
We've always been together.
It's only after finishing high school
that we've gone our separate ways,
but she's a bit of a klutz,
so I'm a bit worried if she's
doing fine in college without me.
It's nothing.
Sakura-san said the same thing.
The same thing?
It was nothing.
But just as Sakura-san
said, don't work too hard.
If you fall ill from working too hard,
then you won't get any work done.
I wouldn't want to make
everyone worry, either.
I'm tired.
I think I'll go home.
What?
How can you when the trains just stopped?
So?
I ride my bike here, so it doesn't affect me.
I'm so jealous you live close.
My house is a little far.
But you two both live
with your parents, right?
You're lucky you have the mattress
ready when you get home.
I never realized that, but you're right.
Just because I live with my parents
doesn't mean I don't do any chores.
In fact, if the trains operated 24/7,
people could go home whenever they wanted!
Actually, I think the people
who used the trains stopping
as an excuse to go home
will never get to leave.
I see.
Um... Would you like some chocolates?
Oh, I'll take one.
Me, too.
Are you worried about your weight, Yun?
Of course! Midnight snacks are bad!
B-But if you're tired,
you need some sugar.
I suppose.
I'm all caught up.
I'm beat.
Same.
I'm dead.
Staying overnight isn't very
efficient because you get tired.
I wonder what Yagami-san's made of.
She looks so thin and weak.
K-Ko-chan's just a hard worker, I think.
Then maybe I just don't have the will.
You're working hard just fine, Aoba-chan.
There's still time till the first train.
Want to sleep?
Or what should we do?
Yeah.
But I can't get any rest at work.
U-Um...
There's this thing nearby.
Relaxation Bath
That's great!
Nice idea, Hifumi-senpai.
Do you want to come, Hajime-san?
Sh-She's sleeping.
Hajime-san?
Wait.
Mega Particle Requiem Shoot!
Oh, I give up!
Where am I?
At work.
I feel so recharged.
So true.
It feels like this is what I've
been working for this week.
You sound like an old man.
But I totally feel the same way.
Are you okay, Hajime-san?
Are you crazy, everyone?
The midnight price here is crazy high!
I was shocked.
True, it was a bit pricey.
But we rarely come here, so who cares?
I know, but...
The new weapons from Signal 3
weren't exactly cheap.
With a new figure coming out next week,
I don't know how much I'll
have left this month.
Then don't buy those toys.
I can't!
That's what I live for!
How do you live life on the edge?
I'd be scared.
I feel the same.
Do you have any hobbies, Hifumi-senpai?
Do you buy costumes for cosplay?
Oh, no.
I only do the simple stuff.
You have a really pretty body line,
so I bet you look good in anything.
N-Not at all.
It's not fair.
Wh-What was that for?!
Sorry.
Looking at you pissed me off.
I don't get it,
but what goes around comes around!
Get back here!
They get along so well.
No, we don't!
Oh... Now you've done it!
You're gonna get it!
There!
N-No one splashes me.
Hifumi-senpai, gotcha!
I-I'm sorry, Hifumi-senpai!
No.
Thank you.
That felt so good.
And I got a lot of sleep, too.
Morning!
How was work?
Did you get any rest?
Nenecchi.
Hey, Nenecchi?
Morning.
I'm on my way home.
Yeah, I slept.
We all went to a bathhouse together.
What?
We weren't playing.
We were working!
What?
Yagami-san and Toyama-san aren't coming in?
Yagami-kun caught Toyama-kun's cold.
Toyama-kun's still healing up.
Will they both be all right?
They both work too much every day, anyway.
They need to get their rest.
Also, we should be careful of the cold,
so let's get some nutrients.
That looks delicious!
Would you like one, Sakura-kun?
Thank you.
I love you, Hazuki-san.
I know.
Why don't you take one to Umiko-kun?
I think she'll like it.
Really?
Really.
She's not so hard to please.
Excuse me.
Oh, she's not here.
I figured she'd be into military stuff.
Sakura-san?
I-I-I'm sorry.
Sakura-san, you're unbelievable.
Everyone, it was nice working with you all.
Nenecchi, what's going on?
Aocchi.
She's going to be working
next to me from now on,
so that she can focus on her debugging work.
You won't get to play anymore.
I'm scared!
We're reaching our final
development stage, Umiko-kun.
Indeed.
Is it turning out to be a good game?
It's so-so.
I'll need to write a new set
of specs to improve the—
Don't shoot me!
Next time: "Full-time Employment is a
Loophole in the Law to Make Wages Lower."
Next Time
"Full-time Employment Is a Loophole in the Law to Make Wages Lower"