I lost again!
Where do you want to go?
I want to eat something good.
You're so bad.
One more! One more!
Hey, isn't this cute?
Yeah, it's so cute.
Asagaya. Asagaya.
Excuse me!
I'm getting off!
I'm sleepy, and I don't feel rested.
It's Saturday, but I have to go in to work,
so it doesn't even feel like a Saturday.
Which animal do you want to see?
The giraffe!
The giraffe?
Yeah!
I love giraffes, too.
Really?
Elephants are cool, too!
I love elephants, too!
I feel sad.
I enjoy my work, but it still kinda sucks.
Don't look!
It'll only make you feel depressed!
Y-Yagami-san!
What was that for?
Sorry.
You looked like you were spacing out.
You okay?
I think I'm a bit sleep deprived.
Don't hesitate to tell me when
you feel super overwhelmed.
Okay.
All donuts are half off today!
Donuts Half Off!
Do Do Donuts
Half off!
It's now or never!
I've heard good things
about that donut place.
Really?
I bet everyone's in the office,
so let's buy some for everyone.
Good idea!
I'll go get in line.
She doesn't act sleep deprived.
Do Do Donuts
Oh.
Hifumin's the only one here?
Hifumi-senpai, good morning.
Good morning.
Wait, what?
Oh, these?
I-I thought... I'd bring
everyone some sweets.
What do you know... We both got donuts.
Four boxes...
I think we'll just have to give
some to the other teams, too.
Too bad Nenecchi doesn't
work on the weekends.
Yeah, part-timers can't work on the weekends.
Why can't part-timers work on the weekends?
Oh, it depends on the company,
but they're paid by the hour, so if
they worked overtime and weekends,
they'd get paid more than you, Aoba.
W-Wait a minute!
Is being a full-time employee just
a loophole to make wages lower?
We can talk about that some other time.
I know!
I'm gonna send Nenecchi a picture of
these donuts and make her jealous.
You can be kind of a tease.
Well, I'm gonna take a
box to the design team.
Can you take a box to Ahagon?
Okay.
Oh, I was just laughing because Nenecchi
is being bitter about the donuts.
A-Aoba-chan...
Are you the kind of person
who's... mean to her friends?
What?
I-I don't think I... am... probably...
I only do this to Nenecchi.
I see...
I want to be friends with her,
but if we become too close,
she might... become mean to me.
Hifumi-senpai, you're twitching again.
You're funny.
Anyway, I'm going to take a box to Umiko-san.
Oh!
I-I'll go... too.
Really?
Then, let's go together.
Y-Yeah.
I guess she's not... that mean.
They look so good!
Food bomb
Aocchi, no fair. I hate you~
I want donuts.
Aocchi, no fair!
No fair! No fair! No fair!
Mommy! Hurry up! Come on!
Now, now. No running.
We're going to be late!
Don't worry.
The Signal Three show
doesn't start until lunch.
I'm going to join the
Signal Three when I grow up.
And I'm going to protect everyone from evil!
Is that so?
I'll protect you, too, Mommy!
Wow, thank you!
Yay!
Mommy, come on! Hurry!
Today's Saturday.
It's Saturday, but Aocchi has to work.
Excuse me.
Oh. You couldn't have come at a worse time.
Welcome to the programming team's booth.
Y-You all look really tired.
Yeah, but I enjoy it.
It's like a war zone.
We've received more bug reports than we
anticipated, so we have our hands full.
Sakura-san's given us very
detailed reports, too.
I see.
So Nenecchi's working hard?
Even the design team thinks highly of her.
She's noted things only a hardcore fan
would know and has been very helpful.
She's always loved games,
and the Fairies series
is one of her favorites.
I see.
Well, I only have a problem
with Sakura-san's... behavior.
I'll let her know you said that.
Oh, anyway.
We brought something.
It's from Yagami-san,
Takimoto-san, and myself.
Thank you.
We'll all have some later.
Thank you, Takimoto-san.
I-It's no big...
Huh?
Let me give you this empty
shell as a thank you.
You can use it as a pen holder.
Th-Thank you.
I'll take good care of it.
I know.
How about we do some airsoft sometime?
Don't worry.
I'll back you up—
Oh! I just remembered
we have some work to do.
We can talk about this some other time.
Hifumi-senpai, let's go!
They can even be like matryoshka dolls.
They should wake up soon.
Umiko-san's a good person, but she
can go on and on about her hobby.
So be careful.
I learned that the hard way.
H-Hey.
Thank you... for saving me.
Don't mention it!
It looked like you were uncomfortable.
I like it when she's nice.
But you look so cute when
you're uncomfortable,
so I wouldn't have minded
watching you longer.
Maybe I'll make you more uncomfortable.
Just kidding.
It was just a joke.
It didn't look like... she was joking.
Oh, good morning.
Aoba-chan.
Wait, why do we have more?
They were all half off.
So we got some for all of us.
We all had the same idea.
Good morning.
Thanks for coming in on a Saturday.
These are for everyone.
It's like a donut party.
Actually, I figured you'd get bored
if you only had sweets, so...
Are those rice crackers?
Yeah.
Sweet, salty, sweet, salty.
Sweet
Sweet, salty, sweet, salty,
sweet, salty, sweet, salty.
Salty
Sweet
The infinite loop of carbs,
and you can get a spoiled body like Mozuku.
Um... Hazuki-san?
Menacing
I can't!
There's no way I can lay a finger on these.
This is way too much for just us here.
We can take some to other teams.
Yeah.
I'll take some, too.
I don't like it when she's mean.
I think I'll pass this time.
Don't look at me like that.
Sojiro.
Sojiro, you'll be nice to me, right?
So cute.
Maybe I need to feed her.
You always look so tired.
I'm fine.
How many hours did you sleep last night?
Maybe four hours?
I started drawing after I got
home, so I went to bed late.
That's not enough!
You went to work last Saturday, too.
You're gonna die.
I sleep a lot on the weekends, so I'm fine.
You've been sleeping over at work, too.
Why do you have to work so hard?
I think your company is weird.
You wouldn't understand, Nenecchi.
I have a dream.
Besides...
Don't you have essays and
homework during summer break?
You come into work every day.
Don't you have a life?
You dummy!
And Aocchi suddenly got mad at me.
I didn't know she got mad.
I'm surprised.
Sympathize with me!
Aocchi gets mad.
Though it's pretty rare.
For example?
When I was getting bullied,
she got mad and defended me.
What a touching story.
Look!
Hey!
You boys!
Slowly
Stop!
Huff
D-Don't bully Nenecchi!
A-Aocchi...
But she was so mean today!
Well, I'm sure she got grumpy out of fatigue.
You two will make up fast, I'm sure.
I-It's not like I want to make up with her.
But...
If you finish this job with things like
this, your friendship might actually end.
I thought you were fine with it.
It's already lunchtime.
I'm hungry.
Oh, man...
I got so distracted and
couldn't get any work done.
Why did Nenecchi say that stuff?
Hey, what's everyone doing for lunch?
Sorry, I'm gonna grab a quick bite here.
Same.
Sorry.
Okay.
Hifumi-senpai isn't here.
I wonder if Nenecchi is by
herself if I don't invite her.
Whatever.
Oh, you're alone?
Yagami-san.
This is rare.
Are you alone, too?
Yeah.
Rin dumped me.
I see.
That was a joke!
What's up?
This morning, Nenecchi and I...
And you two are fighting?
Don't you think she said too much?
I'm just doing my best.
I totally get it.
My momm—
mother also calls me a lot.
And says things like, "You're always working.
Make sure to take care of yourself."
What a good mother.
Yeah.
I appreciate that she's
looking out for me, but...
They don't really understand, huh?
You looking at something?
Oh, no.
It's nothing.
I turned around for nothing.
I applied here because I
was worried about Aocchi.
How did things turn out like this?
You still have ten minutes
until your lunch break is over.
Ringmaster
In that case, please let Sophia
show you the way.
I can't leave things like this!
I have to make up with her!
Ao...
...cchi...
If you're looking for Aoba-chan,
she went to run an errand for Yagami-san.
I see.
Did Aocchi make all of these?
Oh, yeah.
Like forty or fifty?
You lay them out to make sure
they all have consistent quality.
But they're all just villagers
except Sophia-chan.
She joined pretty late,
so all the important characters
were already done.
But Aoba-chan's doing a really good job,
so I think she'll get to work
on better characters next time.
Nene-chan?
She's not assigned good
jobs unless she works hard.
I'm gonna work really hard.
I'm gonna work really hard
and learn how to do my job.
In order to make a new game.
Aocchi!
Nenecchi!
A-Are you okay?
Th-Thanks.
Um!
Wh-What's up?
You're working so hard with your
work, but I made fun of you.
I'm sorry.
Oh, no.
I'm sorry, too.
You were just worried about
me, but I got really mad.
B-But that doesn't mean it's
okay to overwork yourself.
I know.
I'll watch out for my health.
And I'm really happy that
you're looking out for me.
Th-Then it's fine.
O-One more thing!
I'm looking forward to
the finished game, and...
I also support you 100%.
So when your dream to be a
character designer comes true,
and you release your first game,
you have to give me your first autograph.
I don't know if it'll come
true, but it's a promise.
It will!
Oh, did you two already make up?
You know.
She finally understood how I felt.
Sakura-san.
Yes?
I think you should worry
about yourself first.
I-I-I-I'm sorry!
I hope you'll always be
the kind person you are.
Ko-chan looked really flustered.
Who's calling her?
It can't be!
I told you!
I work on Saturdays!
Mommy! I'm fine!
I'm not a kid anymore.
What?!
Don't come to my home!
My mom will often come and clean my home.
So that's why your home is always clean.
Are you implying I'm messy?
I'd like to meet your
mommy, one of these days.
But I don't call her "Mommy," okay?
Next time: "There Were Leaked Pictures
of the Game on the Internet Yesterday!"
Next Time
"There Were Leaked Pictures of
the Game on the Internet Yesterday!"