Tokyo Game Exhibit?
But isn't today Thursday?
Thursdays and Fridays are business days,
and they're set aside for
people in the industry.
I see.
And today is the day...
that Fairies Story 3 footage
goes out to the press.
Oh, but I saw pictures from a game magazine
that were leaked on the Internet last night.
Censored
Yeah, I know.
Anyway, you three should go to the show.
You're not coming, Yagami-san?
I don't have any time with
the deadline coming up.
We're pretty busy ourselves, too.
Don't worry, I'll overlook
delays related to the exhibit.
It'll be a good experience.
Looks like Hifumin's already there.
Go!
Stop sitting around and go!
Okay! We're going!
I want to go to the exhibit, too.
Nenecchi.
Sakura-san, you're dawdling again?
Umiko-san, can I go to the—
No.
We don't have any tickets for part-timers.
You have to stay here.
What?! No fair!
I'm too busy to go, too.
So stop complaining.
No!
W-Well, we'll be going now.
Have fun!
You let them go?
Yeah.
It's a busy time for sure,
but it's a rare chance to see an
announcement for your game in person.
I suppose that means you'll have to work
harder to make up for their absence.
What?!
Wow, are all the attendees
in the gaming industry?
This is only my second time
here on a business day,
and I'm surprised to see so many people.
Hey, come on! Let's go!
You didn't even want to come.
Let's go.
No new messages.
Have you gotten in touch
with Hifumi-senpai yet?
She hasn't replied.
She's usually really fast.
I wonder where she is...
I can't believe there's a really
good cosplay on a business day!
Is she a professional cosplayer?
Her outfit's incredible.
What game is it from?
Over here, please.
Thank you!
I love how you're a little mean, too!
The Fairies 3 booth should be around here.
Hey, there it is!
I won't let you lay a finger on Sophia!!
It's Sophia-chan!
Hey! That's the animation I added!
That's my monster!
It's Fairies 3.
The characters are so cute.
I'm so excited.
It's kind of embarrassing that
so many people are watching.
Yeah.
Hey, this is from Eagle Jump, right?
I loved their previous game.
This must be why Yagami-san told us to...
I see.
It's also the first time
Hajime-san and Yun-san
have had a game they made
go out to the public.
And they've been working on it a
year longer than me, who just joined.
It's coming out soon.
Hey, welcome back!
How was it?
Um...
How should I say it?
We'll do our best!
Okay, let's get to work.
Gotta make up for the delay.
They're so transparent.
Good for you, Ko-chan.
They're back already,
but Hifumin's still not back.
Wow, you're really good!
I'm okay.
Wow, that was the fastest clear!
Demo Section
Thank you.
Aoba, wake up!
You have work!
But it's cold.
Where's your winter suit?
Is it still at the dry cleaner's?
I forgot about it!
Is this too fancy?
This is too... childish.
I wear a suit every day, so I don't
feel comfortable picking an outfit.
What are you doing?
You're going to be late!
Mom, can you pick?
Good morning.
Whoa!
I didn't recognize you, Aoba.
Morning.
Did the game exhibit light
a new fire under you?
My suit's out for dry cleaning!
We're printing some original
design art on a game magazine.
Can I use your Sophia-chan as it is?
What do you mean?
People sometimes redraw their original
works for art books and strategy guides.
Though I don't really do that myself.
Some people fix a few things, too.
So they sometimes have character model sheets
that didn't exist during development.
D-Doesn't that just make it artwork
similar to original artwork?
Well... yeah, technically.
If you're going to redraw it for the books,
you don't have to put it
in the magazine this time.
Um... I...
I put my heart and soul into that
art, so please put it in as it is.
Okay.
Then it'll be your first publication.
My artwork is going to be in a book.
Good morning.
You look cheerful.
Oh, it's nothing!
My, you're dressed special today.
Do you have an interview, too?
An interview?
What do you mean?
A game magazine's coming
in for an interview today.
I just assumed because of how you're dressed.
Oh, yeah...
My suit is still...
Wait, is that why you're
dressed nicely today?
You look fabulous!
Thank you.
I brought you clothes, too, Ko-chan.
What?
I don't want them.
It's too much of a hassle.
Too much of a hassle?
I spent time picking them out for you!
You wear the same clothes every single day!
How about you dress nicely
like a lady sometimes?
She's right!
It's incredibly hard to choose an outfit!
Why are you upset about it?
Meeting Room 1
Hurry up.
They'll be here soon.
Strip!
F-Fine, but I don't want to be seen changing.
Turn... around.
F-Fine...
Just kidding.
I don't care if Rin sees me change,
but I don't wanna change!
Meeting Room 1
Ow!
What are you doing at the door?
Toyama-san asked me to watch the
entrance so you wouldn't run away.
Why are you so reluctant to change?
Well...
I'm uncomfortable looking fancy.
My breasts aren't big,
and I don't look pretty,
so I look better dressed like a guy.
That's not true at all!
Toyama-san picked out your outfit!
You'll be fine for sure!
I-I'll trust Rin, then.
Don't get your hopes up.
Meeting Room 1
I-It's normal.
Wow!
You look so cute, Yagami-san.
Yeah, you're so cute, Ko-chan.
S-Stop lying.
So cute!
Stop!
What's this?
Looking cute, Yagami.
Don't schedule an interview when we're
so busy with the deadline so close.
Interviews are part of your work.
This is for the company and for the game!
Rin, say something to her, too!
You're so cute, Ko-chan.
There was a picture in the interview section
of a previous game's strategy guide.
There it is!
Normally, you don't look as
ladylike as you do in this picture,
so I didn't recognize you when we first met.
It's not that you only look good in pictures,
but you're actually cute!
I'll get you back later.
I'll start with your shoot first, Yagami-san.
Okay, please smile for the camera.
Okay, thank you!
I want to get a picture for
the interview page next,
so can you pretend that you're talking?
There's more?
Like this?
Perfect.
You look cute!
Thank you very much.
You look cute when you're embarrassed.
I'm so glad I made her change!
Yagami-san, I'm done fixing
the models with errors.
Good job.
Then can you help debug?
Okay.
I have to say, it doesn't feel like
tomorrow's the development deadline.
It's peaceful.
Or like everyday.
You can thank Rin for
managing the schedule well.
Our tasks as artists are also
done earlier than other teams.
Seriously.
It's like the calm before the storm.
Can you not foreshadow anything like that?
Menacing
U-Um... Umiko-san?
Regarding the debugging for
the scene you asked for...
Did the game freeze?
Bingo.
I'm sorry!
I'm sorry, I lost my composure.
I think we can fix the bug in time.
Please report it to whoever's in charge.
Okay.
Also, everyone's going to be
staying the night tonight.
Can you go buy everyone some
energy drinks and food with this?
Yes, sir!
I don't trust you, so take
Suzukaze-san with you.
Please trust me!
Drugs
Medicine
I didn't know it was that tough over there.
It's intense.
Everyone looks really edgy.
Did you know, Nenecchi?
When you go on an errand,
you have to get a business receipt.
What's wrong with a normal receipt?
I don't know.
I'm sure it's fine.
We'll have a record either way.
You're right.
That does make sense.
Right?
Nutritional Supplement Drinks
Hey, there they are.
Energy drinks, energy drinks.
What should we get?
Wow, look at this one!
Froggy
Department Chief
Froggy President
Froggy
Demon King
Froggy Secretary
Froggy Manager
Froggy Demon King!
Wh-What in the world?!
It's way too expensive!
What?
But it's Umiko-san.
The cheap stuff won't work on her.
Umiko
Quality
What is this cheap stuff?
Is this water?
I bet that's what she'll say.
It's scary that it's probably true.
Right?
It has to be this one!
I guess it makes sense since some
alcohol cost 1000 yen a glass.
Then let's buy this one for Umiko-san,
and regular ones for everyone else.
We can buy snacks and
drinks with whatever's left,
and we'll have a pajama party!
You're staying the night tonight?
Just for tonight.
It's my last day, too.
Oh, yeah.
I'll miss you.
Wh-What's this?
I figured this is what you run on.
How did you know?
I can't get any energy unless
I get this exact drink.
Did you seriously think that?
Why do you sound so upset?
See?
I told you so.
You totally agreed with me!
Be quiet.
How did you let this happen, Suzukaze-san?
Also, it wasn't a problem today
because I was planning to pay for it,
but you have to get a business
receipt, not a normal receipt.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Sakura-san?
I-I'm sorry.
Oh, well...
I guess I'll try this.
I've never had this before,
so I am a bit curious.
Instructions?
How high-class.
I'm getting a bit nervous.
W-Wow...
I feel wide awake.
Seriously?
Do you want to try?
It tastes bad, like medicine.
That's because you're a child, Nenecchi.
Give it to me.
You're acting more childish than Sakura-san.
Deadline!!
I want ramen.
Deadline Today!!
Full speed ahead!
It's 3 AM, but every light is on.
It's so quiet, even though everyone's here.
Everyone's tired.
You've been working really hard.
Lately, with all the people sleeping over,
I haven't been able to take my clothes off.
I have no problem with that.
Are you done, then, Yagami-san?
Yeah, they told me not to touch anything.
So it's finally done!
It's been a long time, but it felt so short.
It was definitely short for me.
I only worked on it for like six months.
You certainly settled in here pretty quickly.
D-Did I?
You know...
It took me quite a while
to find my place here.
So I'm a bit envious of you.
Yagami-san...
Aocchi!
What's wrong?
It's after three, but I'm not sleepy at all!
Is it the Froggy power?
That stuff doesn't work that well.
But we got the Demon King one.
Uh... Say what?
Hey, I'm done with work, so they said
I can leave with the first train.
When do you plan to leave?
Um...
We should have it all done by morning,
so you can go home once that's confirmed.
There you have it.
Really?
Then, let's go home together.
Also, today's the deadline, so good job.
Yagami-san, please take good care of Aocchi.
Are you her mom?
You're still here. Nene-chan, thank
you so much for working till so late.
Not at all.
Thank you for having me over for tea a lot.
Of course.
Come join us anytime.
We'll have... snacks... too.
Let's talk about cool toys again.
Yeah, things should be pretty
calm here after today,
so you should come over to hang out.
Yeah.
I'm sure Mozuku will be waiting, too.
I'm so glad everyone's so nice here, Aocchi.
Yeah!
I'm gonna do my best at school, too.
Yeah.
Let's both do our best.
Thanks for working so hard.
Jeez, stop crying.
This isn't goodbye.
I know.
Everyone, please take good care of Aocchi.
Aoba-chan, she's a keeper.
Nenecchi, stop...
Aocchi, are you sleepy?
Yeah.
I wonder if the fatigue is getting
to me now that it's all done.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
The demon king lives strong inside me.
You just had a sip.
Aocchi, you can sleep.
I'll wake you up.
Okay, then just a bit.
Sorry.
Aocchi, you sure worked hard.
Where are we?
You said you'd wake me up!
The game's finally done!
I'm so excited!
You're like a little girl who's
excited right before a field trip.
Are you already used to
this stuff, Yagami-san?
Not at all.
But our schedule was pretty
good this time around.
Next Time
"One of My Dreams Came True!"
Next time: "One of My Dreams Came True!"