Fairies Team
9:15 @ Shinjuku East Exit
Okay
Okay!!
Let's see, the place we're meeting is...
I wonder what Yagami-san's doing.
Good morning!
You're early.
I'm the only one here.
You were looking at it intensely.
Yeah.
They really treat us well.
Sale starts at 10:00!
Yodabashi Camera
Wow!
End of Line
There's a small line already!
Hajime-san and Hifumi-senpai are
supposed to be here already.
But I don't see them.
No, look.
They're in line...
We're staff, so I thought
we'd receive a copy for free.
They want the extra goods.
Rin and I get them because we're leads,
but you only get the game.
What?
That's not fair.
We don't get them.
They had to cut costs,
so we only get the game, too.
I'm gonna go get in line!
Oh, me, too!
So we're all lining up?
End of Line
Please Line Up Here
Why?
Why are we lined up for the
game we created ourselves?
You didn't have to join us.
Yeah, but I don't want to regret it later.
Yeah.
But I'd be letting the free one go to waste.
What should I do?
You could sell it.
You're a genius!
Gimme a break.
This brings me back.
Start of Line
For our first game, we lined up like this.
You couldn't get the extra goods,
so I got in line with you.
You remember?
Of course I do.
It was just the two of us back then,
but we have a whole party now.
Yeah.
We do.
Fairies Story 3
Day 1 Sale!
We will now start selling Fairies Story 3!
Who's that?
Do you know her?
I think she just works here.
Thank you for waiting!
But it's nice to see a cosplay of Karen-chan.
Come on in!
No, if you look closely, the design is off.
Who cares?
It's the thought that counts.
See? Everyone loves it.
So cute!
I know, but it just bugs me.
Hey, Miss!
Can you strike a pose like this?
L-Like this?
Yeah, that's it!
That's the pose she makes.
You're very knowledgeable.
We're actually part of the staff.
She's so happy.
Don't tell anyone.
I guess it's fine.
Yeah.
Everyone looks so happy.
Let's hope they don't get disappointed.
Stop it.
I'm feeling sick thinking about it.
That's true.
It's nerve-wracking
to be on the selling side.
It's much less stressful just to buy.
Next customer, please.
Oh, yes!
Still...
This makes me so happy.
I've been looking forward to this, too.
Really? Thank you so much!
I mean, me, too!
Hey, they're back.
You should've just gotten in line with us.
I'm glad we didn't.
You told them you were staff.
Who cares?
This doesn't happen every day.
People are staring, thanks to you.
Really?
Am I a celebrity now?
No!
Did you buy two, Hajime-san?
Oh, this?
It's for Nene-chan.
For Nenecchi?
Speak of the devil.
Hey, gang!
I got the other store's extra goods!
You're a hero!
Good work!
Didn't even break a sweat.
When did they get so close?
There are store specific drama CDs
with different characters and stories.
Yeah.
They're all spin-offs of the main characters,
so you can't miss any of them.
We have the original audio
files at the office.
You're such a sad person.
It's all about owning limited edition copies!
You two are like twins.
You guys all bought the limited edition, too.
You get the game for free.
I wanted one as a memento.
Which drama CD does this store have?
Karen, the heroine.
I think that's why they
have her cosplay here.
What should I do?
I like Knight, too, so I want that, too...
Marketing is scary.
My favorite is his best friend, Conner-kun.
I didn't expect he'd turn to the dark
side and become the final boss, though.
Totally!
That was a huge surprise!
But I did like how his way of thinking
differed from the pacifist Knight.
So the one on one at the end...
H-Hey, Nenecchi!
Conner's the final boss?
Didn't she say she was staff earlier?
Shoot.
Let's leave.
Oh, no!
We're in trouble.
We're in deep trouble.
Maybe even fired!
We'll be fine!
Aoba-chan.
Look.
Wait, Conner's the final boss?
It's all over the Internet!
That's way too soon!
Th-That can't be us!
It's probably people who got the
game early and beat it already.
Oh, that makes sense.
Let's just say that's what happened.
Jeez!
Way to ruin the game's release!
Second round!
You were right.
The people who got them early are
posting their thoughts already.
When can we write about the story?
Looks like we weren't responsible, then.
Of course.
It spread way too fast.
Say what you want, but leaking
information is a crime.
You have to be more careful.
I-I know.
We'll be more careful now.
Right?
Yeah.
I won't say Sophia-chan dies—
You just said it.
Sakura-san.
What did you do this time?
Umiko-san.
What's up?
Did you buy it for the
extra goods, too, Ahagon?
Don't call me that.
Okay.
So, what did you do, Sakura-san?
N-Nothing.
Really?
Excuse me!
Which drama CD did your store have?
My favorite is Cruyff.
It's his backstory,
about his days in training.
Oh!
The man who's really good with his weapons?
So you really like weapons, huh, Ahagon?
I have places to be, so goodbye.
Oh, I almost forgot.
This was at the office, so I borrowed it.
Yagami-san, you look super cute!
I didn't know you could look like this.
You're really cute.
You look so timid, too.
So cute.
I'll have to buy that later.
I wonder if bookstores
already have them on sale.
I hate this!
Reception
Celebration Party
Hall
I didn't realize so many
people were involved.
They invited everyone in the credits,
including third-party partners.
Even I was invited.
What's more, one of the voice actresses
is here, so I'm gonna ask for an autograph.
Me, too! Me, too!
You two are well-prepared.
Hey, it's Yagami-san.
I'm Yagami Ko, and I was in
charge of the characters team.
Well... Uh...
I forgot what to say.
Sorry, I'm not used to this.
Just be yourself!
Yagami-san! You can do it!
I've been involved as a character
designer since the first installment,
and I've gone through a lot
over the past seven years.
There were a lot of hardships.
However, I only remember having fun
in the process of making this game.
I want to thank everyone who worked on it,
and let's keep making great games.
Next, please welcome our director, Hazuki.
I never thought I'd hear
a "thank you" from Yagami.
It didn't happen seven years ago.
I'm Hazuki Shizuku, the director.
Thanks to everyone, the game is selling well.
I think this will help us in moving forward.
Just as Yagami said earlier,
it's been seven years since the
start of the first installment.
Some of you have been
with us since the start.
Some have joined partway.
We were able to bring the game to a release
thanks to a vast number of people.
Thank you, everyone.
And now, a toast!
Cheers!
I'm surprised that Hazuki-san
gave such a serious speech.
She wasn't just some weirdo after all.
That's disrespectful.
Please enjoy the party.
Let's go get her autograph!
Yes, sir!
Those guys...
Aoba-chan...
Yes?
Can you come with me?
You, too?
Excuse me.
Can we get an autograph?
Sure.
Go, Hifumi-senpai!
U-Um...
I've been your fan since Moon Ranger.
Oh, thank you!
Mega Particle Requiem Shoot!
Right?
I know that move!
The movie was really good!
You're late to the party!
Aocchi, you should've asked
her to sign something.
Huge Sales Celebration Party
I'm fine.
Besides, I've already decided on a
person to get an autograph from.
Who's that?
Not telling.
What are you talking about?
Oh, good evening!
And now, the moment
you've all been waiting for!
It's time for the lottery!
Our grand prizes are the two PZ4
consoles donated to us by Hobundo!
Oh, I forgot to pick up a number.
You can get one now at the reception desk.
Really?
There are various other
prizes available, as well,
I'll be right back.
so if you don't have a number,
please head over to the reception desk.
She's so energetic.
Oh!
Yagami-san, your speech was really good.
Man, I was so nervous.
But I felt better after hearing your voice.
Hazuki-san! Again?
I forgot to get Yagami's speech earlier,
so I needed a replacement.
No, you didn't!
You did a great job, too, Suzukaze-kun.
You made Sophia popular.
Thank you!
Looks like Yagami was
right to give her to you.
I-I just gave it to her for fun.
I'll leave it at that, then.
I plan to make her the art director next,
so keep her in check for me.
That's incredible!
Wait!
Me? An AD?
Let Rin do it again!
I need Toyama-kun to become a
co-producer with the current producer.
It was her request.
She didn't say anything.
People wouldn't follow me.
You think so?
I won't force you to do it.
Just think about it.
Lucky Box
And the next number for
the third place prize...
Number 87!
Me! Me! Me!
From Ahagon-san of the programming
team, an N16 Assault Rifle model gun.
It's Umiko, not Ahagon.
Interesting that it's going to you.
Take it as my appreciation
for your debugging.
What?
I don't want it.
Wow, she said it.
I agree that a BK47 suits you better.
I don't even know what you're talking about!
It's a more dangerous weapon.
I don't really understand military stuff.
Maybe you'd have more interest if you
looked into the manufacturing history.
Really?
Then I'll be sure to read up on it
before the next work I'll be debugging.
Unfortunately, we plan to hire a
professional company in the future,
so we won't be hiring you next time.
Are you okay?
I can't draw, I'm not smart,
and I'm not creative.
Does this mean this is goodbye?
I think that's up to you.
Please contact me if you need something.
Umiko-san!
Don't come whining to me, though.
Let's get one on "shoot."
Okay.
Let's move on to the two grand prizes.
Oh, Yagami-san!
Huh? Where is she?
Yagami-san?
Are you curious as to why Yagami
doesn't want to be an AD?
She used to be an AD.
For Fairies 2.
I didn't know.
She must have been very young.
It was a difficult experience for her.
She's always such a hard worker,
so she ended up being
really strict with everyone.
Some people just couldn't take it.
A new hire like you quit in six months.
I still remember her
being depressed about it.
In the end, someone else took over,
and the game was completed,
but she strongly rejected
the position for the third game.
But...
I guess it means she's always
been a generous person.
Why do you say that?
Because if she didn't care, she wouldn't
get depressed over other people's pain.
Yeah, I agree.
Oh, didn't you want to talk to her?
Yeah, where did she go?
She's probably taking a break outside.
Go get her.
Yeah!
I'll go find her.
You really are taking a break.
Aoba.
I'm just not that comfortable around a crowd.
Then I'm going to take a break, too.
You're not that tired.
You can go back to the party.
That's not true!
I get tired, too.
And... Um...
Um, can I ask you a favor?
C-Can I have your autograph?
Oh.
That's why you came.
Sure.
Here.
Thank you.
One of my dreams came true.
You're making me blush.
I'm really grateful to you, Yagami-san.
You taught me a lot of things,
and you always subtly came to talk to me.
Those small things really made me happy.
I don't know how you were in the past, but...
But I know for a fact...
I know for a fact that you're
a supervisor I look up to.
So if you become the art director,
I will definitely follow your lead!
B-But we might not even be on the same team.
What, really?
Just kidding.
We'll probably be together.
But I feel more confident now.
A bit.
Thanks, Aoba.
Hey, they're back.
Goodness.
One of our partners was looking for you.
Oh!
Yagami-san, I should get your autograph, too.
Just be honest and say you want it.
Welcome back.
Thanks for bringing her back, Aoba-chan.
Of course!
Kirara Police Twenty-Four!!
Caught on Security Cameras
Kirara Police Twenty-Four!
La la la...
Ow.
Oh, sorry.
Hey, ****-san!
That's a pole!
Jeez, you drank way too much...
Yeah...
Are you okay?
But you're lucky there wasn't any
kollateral damage.
Just kidding!
Ahahahahahahaha!
Is everything okay?
Oh, I'm sorry.
It's already very late.
It's dangerous for young ladies to be out so late.
What are you doing?
Don't leave me beh—