Where? Where are you?
Pretty, pretty niece.
My pretty niece.
My pretty fr채ulein.
Budding flower and successor to
the Royal Order of Religious Knights,
Hellsing Organization,
Integra Fairbrook Wingates Hellsing.
Integra, you don't understand a thing.
I waited 20 years for my
brother, no, your father to die.
But then at the hour of his death,
he made you head of the family and died,
leaving a will which I cannot accept.
He shouldn't have done that.
It was an unforgivable act.
Hellsing is mine!
Integra...
If it should ever come to it...
If the situation is critical...
If you've been cornered by the enemy
and there's nothing else you can do,
go to the long forgotten jail
in the basement.
One of the legacies of
our Hellsing family is there.
A means for your protection.
This is the means for my protection.
I've found you, fr채ulein.
Uncle...
That's right, fr채ulein.
You want the Hellsing family so badly that
you'd be willing to go so far as to...
Right once again, fr채ulein.
The dead body...! It's...!
Bastards!
What's that? What did you just say?
Please, I'd appreciate it if
you tell us one more time...
Director of Hellsing...
Sir Integra Fairbrook Wingates Hellsing.
Very well, I'll tell you once more.
They're ghouls. The village
has become a ghoul den.
Ghouls are what becomes of non-virgin
humans who've been attacked by vampires.
They're much like zombies
controlled by vampires.
Which means
there's a vampire in the village.
Ghouls, vampires...?
That's ridiculous! You expect me
to believe an occult story like that?
Petty officials like you don't know,
and don't need to know.
But our Royal Order of Religious Knights,
better known as the Hellsing Organization,
has been fighting these
monsters for a very long time.
It's only natural you don't know as we're
a special operations agency organized
for the purpose of eradicating
the satanic monsters that wish to harm
our British Empire and Protestant Church.
There's a vampire in the village
that's controlling the ghouls.
The adversary is a monster.
Send in all the regular
troops and police you want...
You're just providing them with more food.
Only when a Dracula sucks the blood
of a female-virgin,
or a Draculina sucks the blood
of a male-virgin,
do the vampires breed new vampires.
Otherwise, people are no more than food.
They turn into ghouls and
become the vampire's servants.
I've lost the signal from
Search Party Squads 2 and 3.
What?
What's going on? Answer! Answer! Hey!
In order to keep the ghouls
from further multiplying,
you need to terminate
the leader vampire itself.
That's where we come in.
Hellsing will take care of the vampire.
You can't be serious.
One of our top anti-vampire
experts is already on his way
to the town of Cheddar.
The issue will be settled in
a matter of hours.
Who the hell is he?
When it comes to monsters...
especially vampires...
he's the greatest expert there is.
It's a great night.
The kind of night that
makes me want to drink blood.
Ah, the quiet...
It really is a great evening.
There's no use running.
No use firing your gun either.
Eddie...
Simon...
That's right. Your partners are mine now.
I'm going to make you
one of mine as well.
What I want is a loyal slave.
I don't want to create some
Draculina with her own free will.
Girls your age aren't usually
virgins nowadays, but...
I'm still going to rape you.
Then I'll take my
time as I suck your blood.
I'll have you join the other ghouls.
I'm going to make you my slave.
Who the hell are you?
A professional killer.
A professional killer?
You're a professional killer?
You can't be serious.
Have you lost your mind?
Kill him.
Are you dead already,
professional killer?
He's a vampire?
That's right.
Humans don't make very
reliable anti-vampire experts.
They injure quickly.
They die quickly.
Even their spirits are weak.
The most efficient way
to destroy a vampire
is with another vampire.
And the domesticated vampire
at the Hellsing Organization...
is first class, even amongst them.
How can he kill them like that?
Those bullets...
They're exploding 13mm shells
made out of a melted down
silver cross from Lanchester Cathedral.
They'll kill any freak they hit.
Why...? Why?!
Why would a fellow vampire
side with the humans?
Don't move, professional killer!
She's the only survivor.
Don't you want to let her live?
Come on, it's no big deal.
Help me escape.
Or at least look the other way.
Young lady, are you a virgin?
What are you talking about?!
I'm asking if you're a virgin.
You swine!
Answer!
Yes! I am!
You... miserable creature!
What's your name?
Your father called me...
Arucard.
In order to hit his heart,
I had to hit your lung.
Sorry, but it's a high caliber gun.
You won't last very long.
What do you want to do?
Father...
Mother...
Tonight... really is...
a great night.
Hey.
Where am I?
Holy smokes, it's a Police Girl!
A cop!
The fuzz!
The law!
I'm going to be raped...
or killed!
What's it feel like to be dead,
Police Girl?
But it was your choice.
The path of the Draculina.
I can't move.
Where am I?
Police Girl, how's it feel
now that you're a Draculina?
Fangs?!
You're too loud, Police Girl.
I don't care if you're a Draculina now,
you still must act like an English woman.
Draculina?
U-Um, excuse me, but where am I?
The Royal Order of Religious Knights.
Better known as
the Hellsing Organization.
We expel monsters. We are monsters.
So then I'm...
Of course you'll be working for us as
a member of the Hellsing Organization.
We've had a string of incidents
involving some suspicious Midians.
Take out the vampire, Police Girl.
They severed their victims' heads
and wrote with their blood.
This is a challenge to
Christianity and Christians.
They're thumbing
their noses at our church,
our country, and Hellsing.
The target is moving north on Route 17.
They're going around attacking
families they've pre-selected.
These goddamn freaks
must not be allowed to live!
Soon we'll be able to live forever.
As invincible vampires.
You can't even change into fog or a bat.
You can't even heal your gunshot wounds.
If you run out of bullets,
you can't even fight.
And you want to be a nosferatu?
Shame on you!
Don't let her get away, Police Girl.
Yes!
What's wrong? Make it quick.
She's incredibly fast!
She's already 500 or 600 meters away.
Think of yourself as having another
eye on your forehead and shoot.
Shoot like a human, and you'll
only be able to hit like a human.
But...
You can't miss.
The heart. A single shot
right through the heart.
But I don't have a scope,
and look how dark it is.
That would be a problem
if you were human.
But you're no longer human.
It's such a big gun, and yet
I hardly felt any recoil at all.
It's night, yet could see better
than in the day.
Well done, Police Girl.
And now, I'm having a conversation
through some sort of telepathy.
What on earth's happened to me?
I'm...
Not yet.
You still have a ways to go.
And a long ways to go at that.
Too many.
Far too many.
Too many vampire related incidents.
What's more, it's only third and fourth
rate small-fry who keep killing at random.
Nothing but pointless,
cheap and pathetic, foolish acts.
It's like someone is churning out vampires
as if it's the easiest thing in the world.
Hey, both of you, stop that!
You must never resort to
violence against your friend.
You can't go to heaven if you do that.
I'm sorry, Father.
Listen. The only people it's
all right to use violence against
are monsters and heathens.
All right, go back to your room.
Yes, Father!
-Let's go!
-Yeah.
What can I do for you?
What seems to be the matter?
I'm afraid there's been quite
a number of strange happenings of late.
Especially in England.
Yes. Seems there's quite
a cover-up going on.
It's a vampire.
Vampires have been turning up
repeatedly within their borders.
The numbers are clearly outside the norm.
Nothing wrong with that, is there?
Lots of English Protestants
have died, right?
No, they haven't.
I believe you're familiar with Hellsing.
They've performed better
than we anticipated.
Actually, it appears damage
has been kept to a minimum.
Those amateurs!
They're like a kindergarten
compared to us.
Catholics, the Vatican...
and us.
We've been continuing the fight against
them far longer than Hellsing has.
What is it you want from me?
If the trouble is in England,
we can let them handle it, no?
If it were in England.
So...?
This time it occurred in Ireland.
Northern Ireland. A local town, Badrick.
Hellsing is on the move.
We cannot just sit back and watch.
Brazenly sending in someone,
as if it were their own territory.
They're as shameless
and presumptuous as always.
That place doesn't belong to
the Protestants.
It's Catholic land, it belongs to us.
We hunt the vampires.
We can't allow them to get
a head start on us, Anderson.
And if I should run into Hellsing?
We are the only and absolute
instruments of God on earth.
We cannot back away from
a challenge from heretics.
"If anyone does not
love the Lord Jesus Christ...
let him be accursed. O Lord, come." Amen!
Police Girl.
They're not human beings.
They're puppets.
Might as well be pumpkins.
They're just puppets.
Aim...
One shot and it's over.
Police Girl...
When you aim, make sure to put
a hole through the heart or the head.
These people didn't become
ghouls because they wanted to.
There's no way to change people who've
become like this to how they were before.
We shoot them dead
quickly for their own good.
Sir... Yes Sir, my Master.
Looks like she's getting
the hang of being a Midian.
Holy bayonets.
A spiritual barrier?!
We are the agents of God.
We are the instruments of
his divine punishment on earth.
Our mission is to wipe out...
every last bit of flesh of
those fools who oppose him.
Amen!
Chief, a report from our
intelligence officer at the Vatican.
Rome... the Vatican...
The Vatican's Special Operations
13th Division,
the Iscariot Organization, is on the move!
Iscariot.
The Vatican's unofficial
special operations unit.
The single most powerful
fighting force they have.
Professionals at exorcism,
suppressing heathens,
and exterminating heretics.
The 13th Division, named after Judas...
It isn't even supposed to exist.
How many?
They've only sent in one person.
The Paladin, Father Alexander Anderson!
Father Alexander Anderson?
What will happen if he
runs into Arucard and the girl?
I'm going to Badrick too!
Get my gun, my sword,
and two bodyguards ready!
Yes!
Walter, I'll leave negotiations
with the Vatican to you.
Certainly.
Paladin Anderson,
Professional Killer Anderson,
Bayonet Anderson,
Judge Anderson the Beheader,
Angel Dust Anderson...
His origins, race, and age
are all a mystery.
There's only one thing known about
him other than his many nicknames.
The fact he is a specialist
in fighting monsters.
Just as Arucard is our trump card
in the fight against monsters,
he's the Vatican 13th Division's
ace-in-the-hole for dealing with them.
The monster killing
Paladin, the annihilationist!
Put Arucard and the girl
in front of him...
and he's bound to do something.
It's a lovely moon, you monsters.
You make such lovely
cries of agony, young lady.
But you won't die from that.
That's because not a single
dagger pierced your heart.
It's been a while since I've gone
vampire hunting. I have to enjoy it.
Vatican 13th Division.
Special Operations Organization,
Iscariot.
That's right, you Hellsing lapdogs.
So you're the miserable Arucard?
The one who sides with humans
even though he's a vampire.
Hunter of vampires...
Hellsing's garbage man.
What did you do with the vampire here?
I've dealt with him.
He was a piddling, two-bit small-timer.
I didn't even have time for fun.
You two are the only ones left.
Is that so?
You're a brave Father to
pick a fight with a vampire.
And to do it head on,
even though it's night.
You didn't even try to
catch me by surprise.
But you're a fool.
Master.
Don't talk.
You've been stabbed with holy bayonets.
Recovering under your own power will--
What the...?!
Amen!
Regenerator...
That's right.
Our race was engineered and manufactured
in order to fight you creatures.
Amen!
Master!
Hurry! Knowing Iscariot...
No, knowing Arucard,
it's probably already started.
This thing is Hellsing's trump card?!
The best vampire they've raised?!
You must be kidding me!
He's a complete joke!
Those Protestants
can't do anything right.
Oh, she's still able to move
even after all that damage.
It seems I may have taken
the Draculina a little too lightly.
Master...
You're terrible.
Dragging me into this...
Leaving me all alone...
I can't believe this is happening.
Where do you think you're going?
There's no place to run.
Dust to dust. Pulvis et pulvis.
You are nothing more than dust.
And to dust you shall return!
Amen.
I have to go! I have to escape!
I got to get out of here and tell Integra!
What's this?
That's a spiritual barrier, little girl.
It's impossible for you
Midians to penetrate it.
Now be good and let me
slaughter you, you goddamn monster.
He's going to kill me.
He's going to kill me!
I'm going to die!
This is no time to lose your head,
Police Girl.
Master?
Take my blood, Police Girl...
and you shall not be the vampire
only treated like a slave.
Truly you shall be one of our kind.
You shall suck blood wisely...
Stroll the night on your feet.
Be the eternal "No Life King."
Drink my blood, Police Girl.
No... Seras Victoria.
It's over.
That girl belongs to us.
What do you think you're doing...
Iscariot Paladin,
Father Alexander Anderson?
Director Integra.
Sir Integra Fairbrook Wingates Hellsing.
To what do I owe the honor of having
the Director make an appearance herself?
Father Anderson.
This is a serious violation
of the agreement.
This place is supposed
to be under our control.
Withdraw immediately!
If you don't there is going to be
a crisis between the Vatican and us.
I don't care if you're the 13th Division.
We will not allow such indiscretions.
Withdraw? Did you say withdraw?!
We? The 13th Division Iscariot,
the agents of divine punishment on earth?
Don't take us lightly, you whore!
We'd never retreat
from you filthy Protestants!
You're the ultimate in bio-engineered
regeneration as well as healing?
You monster!
You're all too weak,
every single one of you.
There's nothing to discuss.
I chopped the head off that
garbage man you're so proud of.
I decapitated him.
You chopped his head off?
-That's all?
-What?!
Take your hands off Integra, you monster!
You don't have a chance, Father Anderson.
I'd back off quietly if I were you.
What are you talking about?
I'm just about to finish you all off.
Then you'd better make it quick.
If you don't get a move on, that person
you decapitated will come back to life!
What?
You didn't drink it, did you, you fool?
You cut off his head? Pierced his heart?
Don't put him in the same
class as those other vampires.
Those things won't kill him.
Just as you are the fruit
of anti-vampire technology,
he is the greatest of the undead,
which the Hellsing family took
100 years to so proudly make.
The vampire, Arucard!
Master!
Now you understand.
Well, what are you going to do, Anderson?
I see. I'm not prepared
to kill him as I am now.
We'll meet again, Hellsing.
Next time, I'll kill you all.
That was close...
Are you all right, Arucard?
Yeah.
It's been a while since
I had my head plucked off.
So that was Father Anderson
from Iscariot?
It's a cross-border combat violation,
according to the agreement.
He attacked a member
of the organization...
committed acts of bloodshed.
The Vatican owes us big for this.
However, they're not
the ones we're fighting now.
A huge organization working in the shadows
is behind this string of vampire attacks.
Then give me the order.
Tell me to wipe them out.
Tell me to annihilate them.
Tell me to turn them into dirt.
That's what you should do,
my Master, Integra
Fairbrook Wingates Hellsing.
When the time comes, I will.
Really?
It'll be my pleasure.
My great pleasure.
My great, great, pleasure.
Hey.
Why didn't you drink the blood?
Why didn't you drink it?
I'm not sure.
But I felt like if I drank the blood,
it would mean the end of something.
You nitwit.
But perhaps that's all right.
Maybe it's okay to have someone like you.
Someone who's scared to walk at night.
Why did you make
the Police Girl one of you?
Why indeed...
As a bit of entertainment?
A spot of fun?
A passing fancy?
No, it's none of those things.
Perhaps your human
capriciousness has rubbed off on me...
after spending so much
time with you people.
Come, Police Girl. Don't dawdle.
Yes, sir. My Master.
But, my name's not Police Girl.
It's Seras Victoria.
Shut up you coward.
You're a Police Girl.
"Police Girl" will do just fine.
You're so mean!
Master!
Or perhaps you could call it
a "No Life King's" sentimentality.
No, a "Count's..."
Ladies and Gentlemen,
let's carry on
with the plans for the war!
For the next war!
For the war after the next war!
Subtitle translation by
Charlie Sullivan