All flesh is like grass.
All human glory is like grass flowers.
The grass withers, the flowers fade,
but the word of the Lord endures forever.
Am I defeated?
Yes.
You are defeated.
There's no such thing as
a never-ending nightmare.
Your castle and your dominions are gone.
Your servants are all dead.
The girl's heavenly host has
disappeared without a trace.
She will never be yours.
Count, you have nothing.
You are a pathetic No Life King.
You have nothing.
Nothing!
A dream...
It was a dream?
Utter nonsense.
Comrade Integra...
Something quite significant
must have happened
for you to convene
a round table conference.
Sir Hellsing.
Yes.
The number of vampire attacks has been
rising steadily over the past few months.
We can't hush this up any longer.
We can only spin this thing so far.
What's going on?
Yes.
A thorough investigation
of the vampires and ghouls
defeated so far has yielded...
What is that?
A transmitter, or some similar device.
They were embedded in
the vampires in numerous places
and are thought to have
both examined and reported
on all their conditions,
actions, mental states, and battles.
What?!
These attacks are not
occurring spontaneously.
There's someone behind
the scenes who's controlling...
the vampires.
And another thing...
What?
Something else?
Ghouls.
Traditionally, ghouls are what
non-virgin men and women
whose blood had been
sucked by vampires turn into.
It's different this time.
During these attacks, not one
new vampire has been created.
Even adolescent boys and girls
who were clearly virgins
have all turned into ghouls.
What's more, ghouls are
supposed to cease to exist
along with the blood
of their host vampire.
In the Badrick attack,
despite the fact that the
Vatican's Father Anderson
had already destroyed the vampire...
When we stormed the place,
it was crawling with ghouls.
What does it mean?
Whoever it is that's pulling
the strings behind this...
knows about vampires and ghouls.
Just like us.
Walter...
What is this?
What is it? It's a coffin.
Why... Why is this thing in my room?
It was on order by Sir Integra herself.
"You can't have a vampire
who doesn't sleep in a coffin."
Or so she said.
And my bed...?
I disposed of it. Naturally.
No!
Walter!
GRINDING TEETH
Why,
it was on Mr. Arucard's orders as well.
Master?
Yes.
You haven't drank a sip of blood
since you became a vampire.
So, if you don't sleep in a coffin made
out of the earth from your birthplace,
you will only continue to grow weaker.
Is it not something you feel
comfortable doing yet?
You imbecile.
Master...
You chose the night.
You've turned your back on
the sun and started to walk the night.
There's no turning back
to the light of day.
Mr. Arucard, I was hoping
to deliver this to you just now.
What have we here?
An anti-Midian combat-use
13-millimeter pistol. The Jackal.
It's the first pistol to use
its own custom bullets.
Not the converted 454 Casull
shells we've used up until now.
Thirty-nine centimeters in length,
ten kilos in weight,
and holds six rounds.
Not something the human race
is able to handle anymore.
Custom bullets?
Exploding steel shells, 13mm.
The casings?
Pure Macedonian processed silver casings.
And the bullet itself...
Exploding-type or mercury-type?
Mercury bullets which have
gone through all the proper rites.
It's perfect, Walter.
Much obliged.
I could even kill Anderson
with this thing.
Wow. It's amazing.
Miss Seras, your weapon
has also been newly made.
A 30mm anti-Midian cannon. The Hallconnen.
It uses two kinds of shells.
Depleted uranium and
exploding steel incendiary.
With the exception of tanks,
it destroys all ground or air weaponry.
What the hell is this thing?!
The guy's friend is a doctor.
One of those plastic surgeon types.
There's this patient who's fucking crazy.
He asks to have a hole drilled in his head
and a glass plate put in so you can see
his brain floating there.
And the doctor does it.
Then the guy has a plastic
horn implanted in his head.
Now he's a monster!
What the fuck was he doing, right, bro?
Shut up.
You're always yammering
before we do a job.
You should be quiet and cool.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Same old shit. I know. I know.
Failure is not permitted.
Failure?
No fucking way!
I could do this in my sleep.
What are you doing here?
This place is off limits.
I beg your pardon.
We're on a tour of little known spots.
This mansion isn't open to the public?
This is private property.
Please leave at once.
-Very well.
-Yes sir.
You don't look so hot.
Are you all right?
Well then, ciao.
Hold your fire! Hold it!
Stop!
Bro, these guys are fucking idiots.
Are you sure about this?
It's a test.
Just an insignificant, ordinary test.
Those guys, as well as us two, are
nothing more than a process to him.
A test, huh? Whatever.
Fucking worthless!
I just wanna kill them
and drink their blood!
I don't give a shit
about Hellsing or Arucard.
Just fucking kill 'em!
What? What's going on, Integra?
This is the control room! Sir Integra!
What is it? What happened?
It's an attack! An enemy attack!
What?!
We're cut off from the outside world!
There's a battle going on now
at the first floor entrance!
Drive them back! Buy time if you can't!
Roger!
Who are they? How many?!
Tell me the situation!
The enemy is...
They're... ghouls!
Ghouls!
Goddammit! Why won't they die?!
Goddammit!
Up, up!
Down, down!
Left, right! Left, right!
There's only one invincible
motherfucker and that's me.
I'm getting a fucking hard on!
A ghoul army...?
We need to buy time!
First priority is our evacuation!
Secure a path to the heliport!
What was that sound?!
I'm afraid it was the sound of
the helicopter being destroyed.
They know our every move.
Sir Integra, we can't hold out!
They are right there!
Security Office, what's going on?
Hey! Hey!
Hello, hello. Can you hear me?
Good afternoon, all of you
at the round table conference.
Can you hear me, little miss Hellsing,
you fucking bitch whore?
We're the Valentine Brothers.
I'm the younger brother, Jan.
Nice to meet you.
We're in the middle
of a late lunch right now.
Thanks for providing us
with all your people.
The dear members of your force
are going to be turned into our shit.
Now we're coming to kill you.
Have you pissed yourself?
Started saying your prayers?
Are you ready to tremble in
the corner and beg for your lives?
Well, you still might have
time to kill yourselves.
Seriously, take my advice.
Bye now. I love ya!
What's going on, Integra?
Ghouls are targeting headquarters!
The enemy is coming.
It appears we've had a security leak.
Don't be so nonchalant!
Walter, where are you?
I'm in Miss Seras' room in the basement.
I already have a grasp of the situation.
It'll be four to five hours until
Military Police reinforcements arrive
upon noticing
our disrupted communications.
In the meantime, current forces will
have to defend the conference room.
What should we do?
There's only one way
to the conference room.
Please fortify the entrance.
I propose that we divide
Arucard and Seras into 2 teams.
One team
will provide defense for you there,
the other will go on offense.
How does that sound?
How will you get here?
The passageway is full of ghouls.
How did you get to Arucard
in the basement 10 years ago?
The ventilation shaft!
Correct. Please wait for a little while.
We'll be there momentarily.
Very well then.
Walter...
They ate my people.
This I will not forgive!
There must not be even one left standing!
Most certainly not, Sir Integra.
Are we about to witness the
return of Walter, Angel of Death?
Um, what are you talking about?
You'll know soon.
An old man and a rookie. Together,
that should count as one, right?
Looks like we can have
a little fun this time.
I wonder if there are any
normal people in this organization.
Stop making such a racket.
What?
Hello, hello. Can you hear me, bro?
It's Jan, commander of
the great Hellsing killer army.
Oh yeah!
We've finished taking
over the first and second floors.
Now all that's left is to crash
the conference on the third floor
and kick the shit out of that
dumb bitch and the old farts.
Proceed accordingly,
and don't let your guard down.
I'm heading for the basement now.
Let's find out what you can do...
Arucard.
What's going on?!
The enemy will be here shortly.
They've taken over the first and
second floors as well as the roof.
There's no place to escape to anymore.
You're responsible for this!
Sir Penwood!
This is not the time
for that kind of talk.
When it comes down to it,
it's every man for himself.
Isn't that right, Integra?
Yes.
They're ghouls, and they're armed too.
It's no use.
We're all... We're all going to die!
It's someone's bum!
Are you all right, Miss Seras?
Seras! Walter!
Sorry, we're late.
Oh my...
The defense forces have
been virtually wiped out.
I don't know who thought of
arming and organizing these ghouls...
...but whoever it was certainly
knows what they're doing.
Walter, give it to me straight.
Are we done for?
No. Never!
Compared to what Sir Hellsing
the First faced a century ago,
this wouldn't even be considered a crisis.
We will attack with Arucard
coming from the basement,
and the two of us,
coming from the third floor.
Just as you have ordered...
not a single one of them
will be left standing.
Let's teach this young man
just how expensive our tuition is.
They use some pretty fine leaves.
This is what they call bourgeois.
It pisses me off.
It truly pisses me off!
The gap between rich and poor
in England is way too fucking big.
I can't just simply kill that bitch.
She needs a lesson on
blue-collar suffering,
and I'll give it to her, right up her ass.
I know you're there.
Even if you hide,
I still sense your powerful aura.
Even if I hide?
I don't run or hide.
I just got a little tired of waiting.
Nice to meet you, Arucard.
I'm Luke Valentine.
I'm someone who worships you.
Little miss Hellsing, we're coming now.
I'm going to rape you, and kill you,
and then fuck your dead body again.
We'll kill every one of you,
and then torch the place.
Then I'm gonna go back home,
jerk myself off, and go to bed. Okay?
Did I miss?
Guess I really have lost my touch.
Walter C. Dollneaz.
The Hellsing family's butler.
Formerly in charge of
garbage disposal at Hellsing.
Fire!
They're slow.
Ghouls are ghouls, after all.
A nice idea,
eyeing their stubbornness, but...
they're still a far cry from
being an invincible army.
Have you already pissed yourself?
Are you saying your prayers?
Are you ready to tremble in
the corner and beg for your life?
Well lookie here!
I was just thinking how boring this was.
We were winning so easily!
March!
Miss Seras, commence direct support.
R-Right.
Second round. Fire the
incendiary grenade with VT fuse
into enemy ranks!
R-Right!
You fucking bitch!
Drop dead, old man!
You bastard!
Go to hell!
Are you all right, Walter?
It's not like the old days.
But where did you learn
that submission move?
Well, I am a former police-girl.
You bitch! So you're a vampire, huh?
I didn't hear about someone
like you being in Hellsing.
What the fuck are you doing?!
I'll ask the questions.
What's your objective?
Who's pulling the strings?
Why, I was just passing by.
I don't know a thing.
Forgive me? Guess not.
Young man... Next time it's the left.
We came here to attack...
the Hellsing Special Operations Agency
and the round table conference...
and to destroy Arucard.
That's what we were told to do.
"We"?
Did you say "we"?
Yes, I did.
Right now, my older brother's
beating the shit out of Arucard.
Up until now, I've heard your name
a number of times during
my missions, Arucard.
How absurdly strong you are.
How you can writhe
in an ocean of blood with perfect grace.
How you're a Nightwalker
living outside the world of humanity.
You're purer than the darkness of night.
A pitch-black monster
within pitch-blackness.
And now I know.
All those rumors about you were true.
When I was human, I feared you.
And when I gave up
being human, I admired you.
You are the trailblazer of immortality.
Even after you dissolved into darkness,
I kept on chasing your shadow.
That's rubbish.
There aren't any immortals in this world.
Exactly!
The legend of your immortality ends today.
I will kill you and go beyond my dreams!
I'm not like the other instant vampires!
I'm going to surpass you
and become number one!
I was born for this day.
Check!
What the hell...
is that gun?
Your reflexes are amazing.
I told you! I'm not like the
others that came before me.
I have all of your abilities.
No! I have that and a lot more!
We were born to kill you.
So hurry up and fucking die.
You're in no position to do anything.
You really are a feeble old man.
All right, time for
the cannibal show to begin!
Go on and stuff yourselves!
What in God's name...?!
The party's just begun.
No!
Welcome to Hellsing.
Good God...
He doesn't even dodge the bullets.
Could he be indestructible?
No, there's no such thing in this world.
Surely he's suffering
more damage than I am.
I can win this!
I can beat this Arucard!
This is great. I haven't
had so much fun in ages.
What's your name again?
Luke... Valentine...
Luke Valentine.
I recognize you are more
than a Category A vampire.
Releasing control-restriction system...
level 3, level 2, and level 1.
Recognizing approval of Situation A
according to Cromwell invocation.
Commencing limited lifting
of ability use restrictions
until enemy before me has
been rendered completely silent.
Well then, time to educate you as to...
how a real vampire fights!
What the...
What the hell are you?!
What's the matter?
You've only had your legs severed so far.
Come on, attack!
Send out your slave demons!
Transform yourself!
Put your legs back together and stand!
The night's only just begun!
Hurry! Hurry! Hurry!
Hurry, hurry, hurry!
The fun is about to start!
Hurry! Hurry!
You're a monster!
Now I see what you are, you little punk.
You're a failed and worthless creature!
Shut up, you Hellsing-plaything!
You've reduced yourself to becoming
a dog for the Church of England.
You're not fit to...
Quiet!
You're...
dog food.
I guess that's how it ends, punk.
You were shit as a man.
Now you'll become dog shit.
The guy upstairs didn't
seem to amount to much,
but looks like they're having
a harder time of it than I imagined.
My men...!
Even my men have been turned into ghouls!
Seras!
You can stop now. That's enough.
Enough... Please... stop...
Checkmate, sonny boy.
Go ahead and kill me, you old fart.
Not now.
First, I need to know
who put you up to this.
Then I'll kill you
in a most generous manner.
You're too soft, aren't you?
Hey there, bitch!
No more wisecracks. I'm angry.
Who are you people?
Why did you do this? Who led you here?
Answer me!
Answer!
You already know.
It's the device that was embedded in me.
Even now,
it's sending information to them...
about the failed operation,
and even this conversation right now.
You think they'd let me live...
when I'm about to tell
you fucking everything?
See. I knew it!
I will tell you idiots one thing!
Try as much as you can, you bitch!
Mill... en... ni... um...
Millen... nium?
Are you all right, Miss?
Yes, I'm fine.
But please put them
out of their misery, will you?
Yes.
No. You mustn't do that, Walter.
That's the commander's job.
Sir Hellsing, it's your duty.
Sir Islands! That's going too far!
It's unacceptable to say
that nothing could have been done.
You should have been
prepared for this somehow.
You are entirely responsible
since you're the leader.
The fact they died or survived as
these creatures is your fault.
Sir Islands!
Walter.
I won't ask for your forgiveness.
It's all my fault.
Walter, find out about
this "millennium" thing.
Quickly and thoroughly.
Yes. Of course.
We'll have to pay them back
a trillion times to settle this.
Out of the 96 members of
the London Headquarters,
only 10 are left.
And 8 of whom are alive because
they were away from headquarters.
When all is said and done,
the only ones to survive
were you and myself.
What about Seras and Arucard?
Don't they count?
No, since those two are already dead.
Indeed. I see.
What about Millennium?
We asked the British Intelligence Service
and the National Public Safety Commission
to search through the unsorted
book stacks at the British Museum.
However, there's
no information worth looking at.
In America, Japan, and France,
there were seven occult and
military enthusiast associations.
As well as a Star Wars
related club in Los Angeles.
Star Wars?
Millennium Falcon,
the name of Han Solo's ship.
So the bottom line is,
we pretty much have no idea.
I'm sorry.
Only thing we know for sure is
the meaning of the word itself.
A thousand years.
No, there's another thing.
What?
Don't you remember, Walter?
Millennium Empire.
A group that half a century ago sought
the glory of a 1000-year kingdom...
and plunged the entire world into war.
Hitler. Germany.
Nazis. The Third Reich.
It's all right gentlemen.
Let's resume the experiment.
Subtitle translation by
Charlie Sullivan