Miss.
With regards to recruiting new members
of the Hellsing Organization,
I've decided to hire a group
of professional mercenaries.
Mercenaries? Can we trust them?
They're only in it for the money.
Yes...
but these aren't just any mercenaries,
they're true professionals.
As long as they have a contract
and get their money,
the Wild Geese
will never break their word.
That fucking bomb almost killed us!
We're on the same side.
They're incestuous bastards,
that's for sure.
They've probably got 12 younger sisters.
That comes out to two a day,
not including Sundays.
Don't cry, lose your head,
shout or despair.
We're lost numbers.
They never counted us to
begin with. We're disposable.
And if we die, they'll just replace us.
There's no shortage of people
who're willing to kill for money.
Captain, the Palace has fallen as well.
That was too easy!
Can't they put up
a little more of a fight?
That means the civil war is over
and we're out of a job.
I've got a lead.
Where?
Not another sand trap I hope.
You don't have to worry about that.
This next one is in the city of fog.
Captain Bernadotte,
what the heck is this?
Has a war started in London?
Since when did we become security guards?
Are we just stroking some fat cat's ego?
I can't believe this.
I don't know how to put this,
so I'll give it to you straight.
We're here to get rid of monsters.
Get rid of monsters?
Yeah, right.
It's true.
Your enemy is a vampire
who gains immortality
by drinking human blood.
Our job is to carry garlic and holy water,
put a wooden stake in its heart,
chop off its head, burn its corpse,
and sprinkle its ashes at the crossroads.
For more information,
read your Bram Stoker.
That's ridiculous.
There's no such thing as vampires.
You just don't know about them.
Or to be more precise,
you've never been told.
Formed 100 years ago, our Royal Order
of Religious Knights, Hellsing...
has been working in secret
for a long time
with the intended purpose
of fighting vampires.
If you still don't get it,
then take a good look for yourselves!
That is your enemy, a vampire.
What?!
Hold on a sec, you're a vampire?
Yes, well... I guess I am.
They're laughing at me, aren't they?
Then why don't you show
them some proof, Police Girl?
Roger!
Please, go ahead.
If she's a vampire, then I'm Frankenstein.
SMACK
Captain!
She's a monster!
I didn't see it coming, not even a sign!
She just poked me in the forehead
and my whole head's swimming.
Is she really a vampire?
She really is.
She may be the lowest of the lowest rank,
but she's a card-carrying vampire.
What a bunch of lily-livered cowards.
You think we can use these people?
I'm sorry, Miss.
I tried to stop him, but...
They're going to be guarding my bed.
I wanted to see who they were.
That aside, Miss...
We received this in the mail.
A letter?
The head of the Vatican's
Special Operations 13th Division...
Iscariot Organization...
Enrico Maxwell.
What time is it, Walter?
It's just past three o'clock.
They ask to meet with us
and then show up late.
Are they luring us into a trap?
Not even they would try something
in the middle of the day in public.
Especially when they're in
the very heart of enemy territory.
You really have to come here
in order to appreciate this place.
They've maintained everything perfectly.
Just as you'd expect of the Royal Museum.
Yes, you're quite right.
What's this? Are we late?
It would appear so.
Oh, hello. Sorry to keep you...
Don't come any closer!
What business brings the Vatican here?
And not just the Vatican, but its
murderous Iscariot Organization.
Oh, this is no good.
Looks like we're not well-liked here.
First, let me introduce myself.
I'm Iscariot's leader, Enrico Maxwell.
It's an honor to meet you.
I don't care who you are.
Tell me why you're here.
Now, now, there's no reason to get upset.
We didn't come here today
to fight with you.
You expect me to believe that?!
After you trampled over our agreement...
sending Agent Anderson to
Badrick in Northern Ireland...
where he attacked our agents,
killing two of our men.
I almost got killed myself.
Don't tell me you've forgotten!
And so what?!
What did you say?
Don't let my politeness get to your head!
What difference does it make
if two or two million of your
vile Protestant soldiers die!
If his Holiness the Pope
hadn't ordered us himself,
we wouldn't be here
talking to you filthy creatures.
So stop your whining and listen,
you Protestant sow!
You called her a sow?
Nothing like the 13th Division
to put the fear of God in you.
Even your insults are despicable.
You've been doing it for 2,000 years now.
Some things never change.
Nosferatu Arucard,
"garbage disposal man"...
"Joker Assassin."
It's the first time I've seen
you with my own eyes.
It's a pleasure to meet you, Arucard.
It's a pleasure to meet you too, Maxwell.
And goodbye.
Did you think you could
call my master a sow...
and leave this place alive?
I'll shoot you dead, human!
Oh no, I'm so scared.
I can't talk with a terrifying bodyguard
pointing a gun at my head.
If that's how you want to play,
I have an idea.
Let's make it an even fight.
Anderson!
"Ask of me
and I shall give thee the heathen
for thine inheritance
and the uttermost parts of
the earth for thy possession.
Thou shalt break them with a rod of iron.
Thou shalt dash them in
pieces like a potter's vessel.
Be wise now therefore...
O ye kings, be instructed,
ye judges of the earth.
Serve the Lord with fear
and rejoice with trembling.
Kiss the Son, lest he be angry,
and ye perish from the way...
when his wrath is kindled but a little.
-Don't! Stop it, Anderson!
-Blessed are they...
that put their trust in him."
One swing of my sword
and it'll all be over.
If we ignored an enemy
standing right before our eyes,
we wouldn't be Iscariot or the Vatican.
That's why you're you.
And the same goes for me as well.
Let's do this, Judas Priest!
This time won't be
like the last, vampire!
No! Stop it, Anderson!
Hi! Everybody, this way.
-Right this way, everyone from Japan!
-What's this priest doing with a sword?
That must be an avant-garde type of art.
Everyone from Japan...
My granddaughter is a big fan.
Grandpa!
-...this way.
-Grandpa! Grandpa!
This way!
This isn't the time or place to fight.
Yes, I guess you're right.
I'm going to head back and sleep.
Getting up midday makes me tired.
Chief, I'm going back to Rome.
It's a most excellent museum.
Next time, let's bring the orphans.
Yes, of course.
Next time, I'll kill him.
I swear I'll kill him.
Looks like we both have to contend
with some difficult subordinates.
Isn't that right, you pig?
Well, I'll just have to swallow it.
Shall we go talk at the outdoor cafe?
Very well.
Well done!
Thank you!
We know there's a certain word
you've been desperately
trying to learn more about.
And so far your search has
been completely fruitless.
You've done your homework.
It's just like you said.
Millennium, right?
This is a so-called
Special Operations matter,
but we do have some information
regarding the name "Millennium."
Do you want to know?
Do you really want to know?
Do you really, really want to know?
Please.
This is Millennium.
Going back 50 years to World War II.
Nazi soldiers fled from defeated
Nazi Germany en masse.
The entire operation began
right before the war ended.
Obviously, if they'd fled
while the war was ongoing,
they would have been deserters.
And the vast majority of these soldiers
fled to South America,
where there were a number
of pro-German states.
That's Millennium?
Yes.
The Millennium we know of refers to both
the name of the classified plan
and the military unit...
that carried out
the transportation of people and supplies.
You're wondering how
we know all this, aren't you?
That's right, because we helped them.
The Vatican gave them its full support.
It looks like
they've finally figured it out.
They know about Millennium.
Figured it out?
They still don't know a thing.
You seem to be enjoying this, Major.
Yes, I'm enjoying this.
I'm enjoying this immensely.
It's a struggle. Think about it.
We're going to have
a desperate, bloody struggle.
Isn't this wonderful?
It's a struggle... A struggle.
I assume you've heard?
Yes, I heard.
The Nazis... I can't believe it.
I thought I wouldn't hear
their name again after 50 years.
Is it really that surprising?
I had a feeling they
might be involved in this.
I knew I'd seen
this same dark cloud before.
Really, why's that?
Why? You're asking why, Walter?
The only ones who would use
the undead in actual combat are...
you all, them, and myself.
And their undead research institutes
were completely destroyed 50 years ago.
The two of us killed
every last one of them.
Right. We did, didn't we?
I remember now.
That's why I don't want to grow old.
For us John Bulls, growing old
is one of life's pleasures.
Arucard,
we're flying you to South America.
We're not so kind
as to stay out of the ring
when someone's so clearly picked a fight.
That's what makes you John Bulls.
And it's why you're no longer
the power you once were.
Unless it takes perseverance to
achieve, it's not worth working for.
Arucard, Walter's told you?
Yes.
You have only one order.
Search and destroy. Over.
As you wish, my master.
A vampire having a glass
of wine in broad daylight
while enjoying a leisurely
trip to South America?
This isn't anything like the legend.
But the legend holds
true on some accounts.
SOB, WEEP, MISERY, PAIN...
Someone please open this thing...
Someone help me!
I reserved a suite.
Yes. Mr. J.H. Blenner.
I have your reservation right here.
We've prepared
the penthouse suite for you.
Over here! Over here!
I'm in the penthouse suite.
Roger.
Hey, over here.
He's in the penthouse.
Excuse me sir, is that your luggage?
Sir, I'm terribly sorry, but...
we don't allow such...
such large personal belongings to be...
Everything's fine.
But it's just that... we...
The size of your luggage... it's too...
Everything's fine.
Everything... is... fine...
Everything is just fine.
Let's go.
Hurry up and bring my bags.
What the hell was that? Magic?
Or maybe some type of love beam.
This is so unfair!
They put me in a 30 dollars a night motel
and he gets to stay here.
The inequity! Damn you bourgeoisie!
Cheap hotels have their own charm.
Is that right?
Red Glove to White Sock.
The guest has entered the hotel.
I repeat.
All right, we'll start
the investigation tomorrow.
I'll come by for you in the evening.
You vampires prefer
working at night, don't you?
I can hardly wait.
I said I can hardly wait.
I see. There's nothing we can do about it.
Hellsing and the Vatican
are now in the same boat.
It won't be easy...
cleaning up after the mess
we left 50 years ago.
I'm sorry to always give
you such unpleasant tasks.
Your Holiness,
don't look at it that way.
Please, use Iscariot
in whatever way you like.
And as far as dealing with the sinners,
let's have
them fight it out with one another.
They'll dig their own graves and
conduct their own funerals as well.
Seras, wake up.
Seras.
Who are you?
I am your gun, the spirit of Hallconnen.
No!
No, don't run away. Don't run away.
You've been working hard,
so I've come to give you my support!
Now go ahead and
ask me anything you want.
Don't hold back.
Then, Spirit of Hallconnen,
there is one thing I'd like to ask.
Suffering many misfortunes,
I'm in the most dreadful plight.
Will my life continue to be
plagued by such misfortunes?
Uh-huh.
Wait, Seras! I didn't mean that!
I take it back!
Seras, listen well.
It's not a time to sleep.
Something very dangerous and
bad is about to happen to you.
What do you mean bad?
I mean terrible.
Dangerous?
I mean dangerous.
No!
Wake up.
Good morning.
Get up. There's something
interesting going on.
The lights?
That sounds like a...
What?!
This is NKT Brazil's Julia Eduardo...
-What the...?
-...tensions continue to...
-What the hell's going on?!
-...Hotel Rio de Janeiro.
Just 30 minutes ago,
two armed terrorists killed several
of the hotel's employees and guests.
They are holed up on the top floor...
having taken over
a dozen people hostage.
Yes, regarding that
I will get in touch with them...
No, I don't think that's the case.
You want to go to war that badly?
You warmongers.
Here's the latest on the terrorist
incident at the Hotel Rio...
Let's see you dance, you freaks.
Show me some hell.
It's time for war.
The snipers are in place.
SWAT teams Yanan and Dagaran
are both ready to go.
Send them in!
Commence storming operations!
The two terrorists on
the top floor are heavily armed.
Commence storming operations immediately.
They are to be shot on sight.
I repeat. Do not worry
about apprehending them.
Shoot on sight.
You're okay with that,
right, Mr. Tubalcain?
Good, good, very good.
There's nothing more you can do,
if you want to go to paradise.
Dagaran Team, secure the 12th floor!
We're all set. Secure the 12th floor.
Quito Team, secure elevator floor.
We're all set. Floor secured.
It seems a police SWAT team
has stormed the building.
What's Arucard going to do to them?
To him, they're merely obstacles
standing in the way
of his primary objective.
I think it's pretty obvious what he'll do
to anyone who tries to
oppose him using force.
Even if they're humans?
Even if they're just ordinary humans?
Have you forgotten, Miss?
He is a certifiable monster.
Rear guard, set to go.
Advance guard,
Team Dei Romeo, storm the floor!
Roger! We're moving in!
You dogs...
I see. You certainly pack a punch.
However...
Dogs can't kill me.
Only humans can kill monsters.
It won't open.
You're a monster!
So I've been told.
And what are you, who stands before me...
a human?
A dog?
A monster?
M-Master...
Seras, prepare for battle.
But...
What's the matter? Get a move on.
But... Master...
They're humans.
So what?
They're humans!
And so what, Draculina?!
When someone's firing at you,
it doesn't matter whether
they're human or not.
They came here simply
to be killed, slaughtered,
and sent to their graves
where they can rot.
That's all. That's all this is.
There's no getting around it.
It is the one truth
which nobody can deny...
not God, the devil, or you!
But, even so, they...
That's just the way it is.
They...
Master...
Come on, Seras.
Follow me into the darkness,
you little scared cat.
Master...
Yes!
It's a direct line. You think it's...?
Who is it?
It's your servant, Integra.
Give me the order, my Master.
What did you do to
the SWAT team they sent in?
I killed them.
I wiped them out.
There's not one of them left.
Now give me the order, Integra.
The police department's senior levels
are under their control, aren't they?
This siege, they're simply
carrying out their orders.
These people I'm about to kill
may be ordinary humans...
but I can kill them.
I'm ready to strike them down
without hesitation
or the slightest regret.
Why? Because I'm a monster, that's why.
What about you, Integra?
My gun is pointed,
my sights are trained,
my magazine is fully loaded.
I've pulled the slide
and removed the safety.
But...
you have to pull the trigger.
So what are you going to do?
I'm waiting for my order,
Director of Hellsing...
Integra Fairbrook Wingates Hellsing.
Don't underestimate me, foot soldier!
I gave you my order!
Nothing's changed!
Search and destroy!
Any force that stands in
your way is to be squashed!
Don't run and hide!
Through the front door
and blow them away!
Crush all opposition!
Reduce them to smithereens!
Roger.
Yes, that's the final fig leaf.
This is wonderful indeed.
You're giving me a hard-on, Integra.
In that case, I'll come out swinging.
Watch carefully, Sir Hellsing.
M-Master...
Walter, do you think
I made the right decision?
It's not my place to say
if it's right or wrong.
I'm merely the butler.
I'm here to serve you, my lordship.
Now, shall I make us some tea?
We do have
some fine quality Ceylon leaves.
Headquarters...
This is the second wave on the top floor.
Help us! Help!
He's a monster! Damn it!
Headquarters...
Headquarters... Fucking shit!
We're in hell! Goddamn it!
So then, that's it?
This is nothing.
The bloodbath has just begun.
He's not even close to being finished yet.
In that case, how shall we proceed?
I don't care how many locals die,
but this isn't working.
I'm not having any fun at all.
What's the point of sprinkling
a watering can over a raging fire?
Give word to Tubalcain Alhambra.
Tell him to prepare for attack.
Remedy the situation
however he sees fit!
Quick! Pull back!
Withdraw! Withdraw!
He's coming! Hurry! Run!
Quick, get in! Come on!
Shut it! Hurry!
You idiot!
What are you doing?!
Shut it! Hurry!
Open sesame.
Mission accomplished, soldiers.
Now goodbye.
It's been five minutes
since the SWAT team went in.
The situation inside is unclear.
Roll camera!
What a most splendid declaration of war.
I love this.
It's war. We can go back to war now!
Look at him.
He's so hideous,
it makes my spine tingle.
That's what we want.
Someone who dances
between life and death,
who bridges the gap
between sanity and madness.
He looks as spirited as ever.
He's evil like us,
this visitor from the night,
this undead comrade.
My fellow soldier, my noble vampire.
Oh, I can hear the symphony of war.
I haven't heard that sound in a while,
the chorus of the fiery pits of hell.
Oh my, your table manners
are absolutely exquisite.
You certainly live up to
your reputation, Arucard.
My name is Tubalcain Alhambra.
My friends call me the Dandy Man.
Are you the one who
sent in those poor souls?
Oh, you mean those
unfortunate men up there?
Their superiors were idiots,
that's why they ended up that way.
Even if all their troops are killed,
these people want to become immortal.
They're hopeless idiots.
There's no such thing as immortality.
Those poor souls did
help me in some small way.
How many of those prized shells
do you have left, Arucard?
I don't need the song and dance.
What are you going to do, Dandy Man?
We're taking your life.
You'll become
just another worthless sample.
That's right. Us, Millennium's.
I see.
There's absolutely no helping you people.
Which is why it makes perfect
sense for me to fight you.
Didn't you learn anything from
the first time we destroyed you?
You're trapped.
You can't get away.
Arucard the vampire, you're nothing.
Tubalcain is fighting him.
If anything happens to him, they won't
be able to hold their end of the bargain.
According to our reports...
I still haven't quite earned my pay.
Well, shall I go get the chopper?
I can't stop the bleeding.
Those cards
and his powers are impressive.
Amusing. Very amusing.
They're quite amusing, these people.
Say there...
Are you ready then, Arucard?
Now go back
to that lovely home of yours
in the lowest pit of hell.
What's so funny?
I'm just so happy that...
there are still people in
this world as stupid as you.
Millennium?
The Last Battalion?
That's right.
It's the crazy Major and
his cold-blooded Kampfgruppe.
The world is still ripe with madness.
Come on, sing and dance, Alhambra!
Let's hear you squeal like a pig!
Squeal? Me?
You still don't get it, do you?
If only the world were as
simple as you think, Arucard.
You really have gone soft
in the head, haven't you?
Trying to run and hide again?
It's no use.
You little bitch!
Don't fuck with me!
Who do you think you are?
Squeal like a pig!
Checkmate, Tubalcain.
Now, allow me to keep my promise.
Permit me to fulfill my duty.
I want you to tell me everything.
Yes, let your blood do the talking.
So it's war?
That's right, it's war.
A huge war without any
distractions or interruptions.
Master! Master!
This is...
Master...
Arucard, Seras!
I'm here to pick you up!
We kill our enemies.
We kill our allies.
We kill the people
we're supposed to protect
and lay waste to the countries
we're supposed to govern.
We even kill ourselves
and it's still not enough.
We're incorrigible warmongers,
you and me, Major.
Hurry up. Or rather, please hurry up!
That Alhambra looks like
an old rag, doesn't he?
He really is strong, isn't he?
Outrageously strong!
Stronger than any of us imagined!
I-I'm sorry.
I assume this means that
we still have more work to do...
No! Don't be ridiculous.
Rather, I'd say we're on
the verge of a huge success.
The things we've learned here today
will serve us well against Arucard.
We've gained a means to
a most extraordinary being, a Midian.
Not a person anymore, a Midian.
That is to say, our 50 years of
hard work are about to pay off.
We will build monsters,
turn them into soldiers,
organize them, train them,
supply them, militarize them,
and command them.
We are the Letzte Bataillon,
the Last Battalion!
Magnificent! Grand Professor!
I am most grateful.
Well then, gentleman!
This most delightful show
draws to a close for now.
It's about time we headed back to
our beloved home, don't you think?
Captain, we're ready to turn around.
Hurry. We've kept the old folks at
the opera house waiting long enough.
We need to get there
as fast as possible...
since I'm sure they're
about to explode with anger.
I see. This is serious indeed.
I'll fly her at full tilt, Major.
Prepare for starboard turn.
Engage the flaps!
Confirming. All flaps engaged!
Height is good.
-Starboard 20!
Destination, Jaburo, Panterschanze.
We're coming, you old timers.
I don't give a damn how many
hundreds or thousands
or millions or billions
of people try to stop me.
No!
All those who stand
in my way will be killed.
Welcome to this crazy time
You have arrived in the era of madness
Subtitle translation by
Charlie Sullivan