Arucard...
Wake up, Arucard...
Who are you?
I am the essence of your gun,
Jackal Willis.
S-Stop! Stop that Willis!
Listen to me!
Please, hear me out Willis!
Where is this place? I'm leaving.
This is my space.
This is Willispace Willis.
You can no longer leave this place Willis.
For the rest of your life,
you will remain here Willis,
appearing in odd productions,
whether entertaining
or not, I cannot tell Willis.
Also, my mass is not 10 kilograms...
...from now on, it's 16 kilograms,
if you please Willis.
What?
You're going to run pell-mell with
me through the Nakatomi Building,
help me rescue a chunky
gangster with a samurai sword
getting ass-raped and
voiced by Tessho Genda,
and blow up a meteor
together with Steve Buscemi,
sweeping the Golden
Raspberry awards Willis.
Also, we're going to
get jerked around by a kid
with a long name who can see ghosts,
roll our taxi to catch Milla Jovovich...
He was an imposter.
That sure was a close call.
You always have to be on guard
against sneak attacks and betrayal.
You should pick your own
weapons as much as you can.
Now then, it's time to wake up.
Seras and Integra are waiting.
Ah! There you are, General de Gaulle!
What?
Damn, I missed.
Hello, I'm Christopher Walken.
I'm Tom Berenger.
Together, we are the Dogs of War.
Get out.
I'm Maximillian Schell.
I say kill them all.
Get out!
Hello, I am the Emperor.
Who are you?
Hello. I am the Fourth Protocol.
That makes no sense.
Hello, I am the Negotiator.
Good luck to you.
At last the sea lion has crossed
the ocean and climbs up upon the land.
General! Communications with the
Central Intelligence Command
Center has been cut off!
I cannot reach them!
What?!
We've lost contact with the
London BTN control station, as well.
We're also cut off from
civilian communications
and phone lines in the
metropolitan area.
There's no contact
from Ark Air Force Base!
We're cut off from the Atlantic
Fleet and from Fleet Command.
No contact with National Defense
or Defense Intelligence Headquarters.
General, we've received word
that a civilian craft has spotted
airships moving north
over Newfields, south of London.
Airships? Did you say airships?
Impossible. Are you telling me
that they're starting a war?
That's exactly right.
Integra...
A war has begun.
Maximum speed! Onward!
Faster! Faster, faster!
Rev the engines until they burn out!
Faster! Faster!
Flat-out! Flat-out!
Run flat-out toward the spires
of the city dimly seen ahead!
Flat-out! Flat-out!
Run flat-out toward
the clamor of the great strike,
still in our memories!
Hey, hold on a minute, now...
Bugger off, will you?
Stuff it! Listen, you...
Hey, Jansen, say something, will you?
The moon...
The moon...!
That's awesome!
All battalion members, achtung!
Gentlemen, night has come.
You who are invincible
remnants of the last army,
and long-serving recruits,
the night of the fulfillment
of your vows has arrived.
Welcome to the eve of war!
All right then, everyone,
please have a look at your handbooks.
On page three of Operation
Sea Lion, Second British Landing,
please look at the heading
"London Explodes! Crack Battle Vampires."
Huh?
Uh-oh...
Oh, dear, what is it, Schrödinger?
Doc, I'm sorry, I forgot my handbook.
My word. What are we to do with you?
Look on with the captain.
Zorin... Lieutenant Zorin Blitz...
As you command.
Our objective is to bring
down Hellsing, and Arucard.
The men under your command
will be the vanguard unit.
Take Zeppelin 2 and rush
over to Hellsing headquarters.
Acknowledged.
But do avoid anything too drastic.
Wait for the arrival of
myself and the main force.
There should be no great bother.
Hellsing will be as helpless
as babies without Arucard.
Do not take the women too lightly.
Do not take Integra Hellsing
and Seras Victoria too lightly.
Integral Fairbrook Wingates Hellsing...
She is the Hellsing's scion.
The current head of the greatest
family of vampire hunters in history.
She is the one that Arucard
recognizes as being his master.
Then there is the policewoman,
the vampire Seras Victoria. She is...
something of a miracle.
You might also say something of a joke.
This is something that not even
she herself may be aware of.
And that makes it all the
more entertaining, does it not?
They are both terribly
inexperienced and imperfect,
and as a result, I would
argue that like Arucard,
they are worthy of
being called an archenemy.
Zorin, I will say this again.
Do not do anything too drastic.
Wait for my arrival.
Acknowledged, Battalion Commander.
Very well. Then let loose the floodgates.
Let loose the floodgates
of the dark waters of war!
Our first objective is
the entire London area.
The west bank of the Thames,
the Houses of Parliament, Big Ben,
the Office of the Prime Minister,
the Ministry of Defense,
Buckingham Palace,
Scotland Yard, Westminster Abbey,
Piccadilly Circus, Soho, the City,
Southwark. Burn it all down!
The central government houses,
St. Paul's Cathedral!
Major, what about the Cabinet War Rooms?
Blow them up, of course.
They're repulsive.
Don't leave a single fragment remaining.
What shall we do about
Trafalgar Square, Major?
Burn it. Bring down the statue of Nelson.
The Tower of London,
the British Museum, the British Library.
Destroy them all. They're repulsive.
What about Tower Bridge?
Bring it down.
London Bridge, too. Like the song.
And the Imperial War Museum?
Blow it up.
Destroy everything that you see,
and devour everyone that you see.
Eat and drink to your heart's content.
This imperial capital of eight million
will be reduced to your supper.
Come, gentlemen,
let us kill, and be killed.
Let us die, and give death.
Now, let us have a toast.
As of tonight, from this moment,
the banquet at last begins.
What are those?
Is this a movie, or something?
Take a picture, quick!
Prosit!
More.
Ready the next salvo of retrofitted V1s!
Prepare to drop the Waffen-SS!
Sir!
All retrofitted V1s fired!
The result is a crippling blow!
Crippling! Crippling!
Not yet.
More.
More fruits of battle!
Beautiful.
Like hell shining.
We are monsters. Down there
is the only place we can live.
Down there
is the only place we want to go.
Commence ground combat operations.
Deploy paratroopers!
Here we go, frontline swine! Off to war!
Fünf...
Vier... Drei...
Zwei...
Eins...
Huh? Who are you?!
Please do not try
anything funny, Sir Hellsing.
As of now, this facility is under
the control of Millennium.
Lt. Colonel, what is the meaning of this?
Shut up!
This is the meaning of this, General.
It's great to be a vampire.
How lucky I am, to be able to
capture Sir Hellsing here like this.
What's so funny?!
Your joke is laughable.
You're all such newborn vampires,
while we're the institution
of your annihilation.
To think that baby frogs
who still have their tails
would face a snake,
and call themselves lucky...
D-Damn you...!
You can claim your Iron Cross
from your corporal in the next life.
Bitch!
Walter, to work.
As you wish, Madam.
Now then, I shall take
you to task, youngsters.
You old geezer!
Begging your pardon.
Traitors.
Are you all right, Sir Penwood?
Huh? Yeah...
I was convinced that you had betrayed us.
I may be powerless against them,
but I am not a coward.
The entire city is under attack!
We cannot reach the Chiefs of Staff!
We've lost contact with roughly
150 primary military installations
and command centers throughout Britain!
Either that, or they're engaging
an unidentified enemy force!
The same as this bunch.
This place is sure to be
one of their targets of attack.
We should flee at once, Sir Penwood.
German soldiers are
dropping from the airships!
It's the Waffen-SS!
What?!
Sir Penwood, we must flee.
A horde of vampires will be
sweeping in at any moment.
You... You return to your
organization as quickly as possible.
You have a task
that only you can carry out.
I-I cannot run.
That's the last thing I can do.
This place has very little
ability to command remaining.
Are you trying to get yourself killed?
It's possible that
communications may be restored,
and we may be able to issue orders again.
There may be a base somewhere,
fighting off the enemy,
waiting for orders to come from us.
I-I am the commanding officer here.
I cannot very well leave.
I am a powerless man. A nervous Nellie.
A man so hopeless,
not even I understand what
I am doing in a position like this.
I'm someone who has
lived off of my family name,
who has
never had to struggle for anything.
I have always had my positions
and tasks handed to me.
Which is why I think that I must
at least accomplish my task...
this task which I have been given.
Go on. Off you go, Integra.
You have... Hellsing has a task
that only Hellsing can carry out.
It is loaded with blessed
atomized silver tip rounds.
They should be more effective
against them than ordinary iron.
Farewell, and good hunting, Sir Penwood.
Yes. You, too, Sir Hellsing.
The rest of you,
hurry and get out of here.
We only need a minimum of personnel here.
In fact, now, you know, in all candor,
I may be enough on my own.
All of you, get out of here. Quickly.
W-What? What's so funny?!
Hurry up and run away! That's an order!
I will try once again to
reach National Defense.
Start finding us a line.
Gather ammunition and weapons!
Form a garrison. Hop to!
Sir!
Hey, hold on, now...
Set up barriers
at all the entrances. Hurry!
What did I say to you, you fools?!
There's no need to
accompany me during this!
What are you talking about, Admiral?
You can't work a single
console here, can you?
Please, sit where you always do, sir.
You'll get in the way of our work.
Thank you, men. Thank you.
Reassessing damage reports.
Form ranks, and go make
direct contact, even if it's on foot!
Open up a line to our
foreign branches, as well!
I want more intelligence!
We're leaving, Walter.
As soon as possible.
As you wish.
We'll charge through the city.
You can do that, right?
As you command.
I will accomplish my task.
As a Hellsing, I swear it...
you miserable vampires!
Damn it! Damn it!
Damn it!
Damn! Damn! Damn!
Cruising for girls, in this sea of flame?
It's abysmal. A hell on earth.
But it's no more than
a shadow of things to come.
Well done.
You have fulfilled your duty.
Now rest.
Hurry, Walter. We're taking vengeance.
Integra Hellsing spotted.
She is traveling at high
speed along Regent Street
toward Hellsing Manor.
Capture her.
Capture her!
Calling all soldiers...
This is Vice Admiral Penwood,
British Security Special Command Center.
I am transmitting in the hopes
of reaching someone out there.
This facility will soon fall.
The monsters are almost upon
the other side of our doors.
I now deliver the final
orders from this facility
to whomever is
listening to this transmission.
Resist, and fulfill your duty.
The new head of the family?
You?
Walter, this girl?
"This girl"?
What a thing to say, Sir Penwood.
Or, er, um...
I am the family head, Integral Hellsing.
I have killed my uncle,
and taken my place as family head.
I would like you to stop
referring to me as "this girl."
M-My apologies. I am sorry.
My father, while he was alive,
told me that if I needed anything,
I was to ask Mr. Penwood.
Y-Yes! Arthur! Whenever anything
came up, he would always say,
"Give me some newer model guns!"
or "I need a helicopter."
Always with the impossible demands.
My goodness gracious!
Not to be outdone by my father,
I, too, believe I will have many requests.
I thank you in advance.
You put up a good stand,
you good-for-nothings.
What's so funny, human?
Good for nothing? From you,
who are good for even less than I am?
Farewell, Integra.
I enjoyed our time together.
S-Stop!
No way!
I cannot honor that request.
Walter...
Yes?
Hurry!
What is it?
Miss Integra,
please back the car up at once,
and find another escape route.
Walter...
As fast as you can. As fast as you can!
Do not turn back for me. No matter
what happens, run as fast as you can.
Walter...
The way I am now,
I do not know how long I can
hold out against that fellow there.
Walter...
I order you to come
back alive, no matter what!
As you command.
I knew it.
I knew it was you.
That is correct, young man.
Long time no see, huh, butler?
55 years, isn't it?
I must say, you always...
Always show up to bother me
when it is dinnertime.
Integra Hellsing is on the move.
She has altered her route,
and is moving at high speed.
Attention, all available squads!
Go after her! Go after her!
Integra Hellsing is by herself. Repeat...
Go after her! Capture her!
Capture her! Capture her!
There she is!
Panzerfaust! Zielen...
Feuern!
Integra Hellsing!
By order of the battalion
commander, say your prayers!
Hmph, you don't know
when to give up, fräulein.
No matter how hard you struggle
or try to escape, it's hopeless.
Give up. There is no longer
any place here in London,
here in Midian, where you can
run or hide. Give up, human.
Run? Hide?
Hopeless?
Give up?
Give up, you say?
Indeed, that does sound
like something you would say.
You, who could not bear to remain human.
Well don't go selling us
humans short, you monsters.
Come on! I'll fight you!
Fine by me!
W-Whad id did...?
M-My body id cubbing abard...
B-Bayonets!
It's you...! From the
Vatican's Iscariot, Section XIII...
The Assassin, the Guillotine Judge...
The Regenerator, Angel Dust...
The Bayonet Father...
Alexander Anderson!
Facing down a horde of monsters
while sporting a bloody nose?!
"Come on"?! "I'll fight you"?!
Did you hear that, Heinkel?
Did you hear that, Yumie?
There's no doubt about it.
This is... This woman is...
These people are...
our sworn enemies!
Our archenemies!
Father Anderson, the orders
we have received at this juncture
were to just observe.
Moreover, rescuing Hellsing there
is a serious breach of orders, is it not?
So what am I to do,
stand here and do nothing?
We are to be the ones who crush them!
We are the only ones who may crush them!
No one else may have them!
No one else may interfere!
No one else! No one else!
You're with Iscariot.
You won't stand in our way!
Hold your tongue.
The dead do not speak!
Do the dead walk before my eyes?
Will the undead raise an army,
fall in, and advance?
Those who abandon the natural order,
embrace a heretical order,
and propose to pass by
here would presume that we...
That Iscariot...
...that I would allow it to happen?!
You will die, not trembling
before me, but as straw before me!
Amen!
I ask of you, who are ye?!
We are Iscariot! We are Judas of Iscariot!
Then, Iscariot, I ask of you,
what have ye in your right hand?!
Daggers and poison!
Then, Iscariot, I ask of you,
what have ye in your left hand?!
30 pieces of silver and straw rope!
Then...!
Iscariot, what are ye?!
We are apostles, yet not apostles!
We are believers, yet not believers!
We are adherents, yet not adherents!
We are heretics, yet not heretics!
We are those who do
naught but submit to death,
who merely bow our heads,
begging the Lord for forgiveness,
striking down the enemies of the Lord!
Lowly soldiers of death,
brandishing daggers in the night,
and administering poison as supper!
We are apostles, a flock
of apostles, we are assassins,
we are Judas of Iscariot.
At the appointed hour,
we cast our 30 pieces
of silver to the holy place,
and with our straw rope,
we hang ourselves about the neck!
Thus do we desire to
descend into hell en masse,
form ranks in squared formation,
and engage...
the 7,405,926 demons of hell!
My nemesis...
My master...
I am drawn to you...
and I shall continue my dream, as well.
Onward, to the battlefield!