This is my new home.
Teacher,
for what reason am I here?
Why do my father and
mother not come for me?
Is it because I am the mistress' child?
I don't need any friends.
I don't need any pals.
I don't need my father or mother.
I will become great.
I will become great. I will become great,
and get even with everyone.
Director...
Director!
Please wake up, Director!
Director Maxwell!
Anderson and the other
paladins who went on ahead
have secured Integra Hellsing.
They have engaged the Last
Battalion in pursuit of her.
Tch, that hell-bent crusader.
I ordered him to just observe,
and to avoid confrontation.
Look how it burns.
Almost like purgatory.
The capital city of London
has been devastated.
Not since the Blitz has it been like this.
There is no estimating the number of dead.
Nor is there any telling
just how many are undead.
It's God's punishment.
The fools gloated as they waxed strong in
their heresy, and this is what they get.
It serves them right.
Indeed.
What about America?
Utter chaos.
The White House is burning even now.
Also, a presidential aide
turned into a vampire,
right in the middle of
a congressional session,
killing the president and
13 of his cabinet members.
That sounds about right.
Our American branches
are still under deployment.
If the damage spreads, take action.
Otherwise, we will not get involved.
Their confusion works to our advantage.
Let it drag out as much as it will.
However, up to now,
that's all the activity they've shown.
Why might that be?
I'm not interested in why.
As long as they stay out
of our way, that is enough.
I am only interested in
Britain, Hellsing, and Arucard.
That fatty... that fat major is
beyond even the Vatican's interests.
I won't have it.
We will hit them as hard
as we can from the sides!
Yes we will. We will reclaim Britain
from the pagans and
the monsters for Europe!
We are free to kill
the pagans and the monsters.
That's what my teacher taught me.
From the Order of the Sword of
Courland, 340 strong reporting!
From the Order of Calatrava
la Nueva, 118 strong reporting!
From the Order of Santo Stephano
di Toscana, 257 strong reporting!
From the Order of Malta,
2457 strong reporting!
We are reporting as
ordered by the Holy Father.
Concurrently, we elevate Bishop Maxwell.
You are now an archbishop.
We, the members of this corps,
form the Knights of the 9th Crusade.
We hereby entrust all command
authority to Archbishop Maxwell.
Amen! I fully take this
upon me, body and soul!
Our target is London,
dead capital of the British Empire.
Let our zealous subjugation,
Reconquista, now commence!
Amen!
Amen! Amen!
To think that I, a member of Section XIII,
after being called a demon spawn,
hated, cursed, and left destitute,
would be made an archbishop,
in command of a military force...
Director!
What is it?
H-Here...
The British carrier in the Atlantic...
It's moving?
It has set sail? That's ridiculous!
After the fire it sustained,
it's on the move?!
It's speed is quite slow.
Just a few knots,
but it is definitely
on the move. To London.
Arucard...
...is coming.
No matter. Hellsing, Millennium,
and Arucard will be no more. In the end,
we will be the ones
raising our ringed fists high.
All forces, move out! Our time as
the agents of God's punishment
has arrived!
Each one of them is charging
into hell with a joyous heart.
Just who among them
will be able to survive in there,
in that scene of carnage?
I'm sure that each one of them will,
without question, die with a joyous heart,
within that twilight.
There's that old, familiar smell...
The smell of men being impaled...
The smell of women being hewn down;
the smell of babies being burned to death;
the smell of the aged being shot to death.
The smell of death.
The smell of war!
Here I come, Major.
Zorin, start your attack.
Acknowledged.
Restart Zeppelin 2's engines!
The Zorin Blitz squad is now attacking!
Target Hellsing headquarters!
How many remain?
Half have been taken from us.
They're better than we thought.
Thermite!
Incinerate the bodies of the Nazis!
Leave no trace of them!
I'm leaving.
Where are you going?
To my mansion. I have a task to carry out.
A task as commanding officer.
I have to go now.
I cannot allow that.
We are taking you into custody.
Light me.
Light my cigar, will you?
You're so inconsiderate.
Light me.
Er, um... Do you realize
the position you're in?
Light me.
You can't threaten me.
I'm going home to my mansion.
Shoot me if you wish.
Stop, Yumie.
I-I'm just no good with these types.
What is wrong with me?
W-We could all tie her up,
a-a-and take her away, couldn't we?
Let's shoot her!
I can hear you.
Is that what you want, Section XIII?
Is that what you want, Anderson?
Absurd. Forcing an unarmed woman
to act against her will as a group?
Sounds like the act of rapists.
Well then, I'll be leaving.
But it's not safe for a woman on
the road at night. Take me home.
All right. We will take you home.
Huh?!
I'm in a hurry. Let's go.
Hold on!
What is this?
I don't like what happened here.
W-W-What do we do?
The chief is going to get mad at us again.
W-We do have her secured
like this, in a sense.
We won't get yelled at.
That's just sophistry.
Shut up!
Heinkel, find us a car.
We're sitting ducks like this.
Yes...
Are you sure about this, Father Anderson?
This will call your
accountability into question.
I don't care. This is for the best.
Maxwell's methods are too clever by half.
We will be over Hellsing
headquarters momentarily.
All right. All personnel,
prepare for battle!
Incoming support fire from
the flagship. Retrofitted V1s.
The Deus Ex Machina is
running interference for us, huh?
Give Hellsing a whole bellyful of them!
What is this?
What?
What are they doing to us?!
We're being sniped at!
The fire is coming
from Hellsing headquarters!
It's her.
The retrofitted V1s
have all been shot down!
That's impossible. There were
24 of them, all fired at the same time.
Searchlights! Light up
Hellsing headquarters!
Please, do not do that!
They will shoot at us!
It doesn't matter! She can already see us!
You've shot them all down, young lady.
That new equipment is in
top form, huh, young lady?
The Hallconnen II 30mm semi-auto cannon.
Maximum range of 4000 meters;
gross weight, 345 kilograms.
We're pulling out all the stops
against these jokers, young lady.
Mr. Bernadotte, would you mind
not calling me "young lady"?
I do have an actual name, Seras.
Sorry about that, young lady.
Tell me...
Can you see London, young lady?
Yes, I can.
Piccadilly Circus, Soho, and
Covent Garden have turned to ashes.
Our London is now...
...synonymous with Hell.
I couldn't stand London.
I thought it was a stuffy old city.
I didn't think
it was the city for me at all.
Even so, when we would go out and party
at this cabaret on the weekends,
the beer was cold, and tasty,
and the bartender
was this idiot who liked
the most ridiculous dirty jokes.
The hookers in the whorehouses
were money-grubbers,
and there were a lot
who were hard on the eyes.
But you know,
they were all nice to us,
and they all had this
pitiful look in their eyes.
The lady at this restaurant on
Versailles Road would always serve me
fish and chips,
without me ever ordering it.
She said it was because I was a foreigner,
and that it was the local
delicacy, time and time again.
I told her it was too greasy,
and I couldn't eat it,
but I didn't want to offend,
so I gagged it down,
each time, hard though it was.
I couldn't stand London.
But still, those people...
The bartender, the hookers, the old lady
had nothing to do with this conflict.
They had nothing to do with this war,
or Nazis, or vampires.
That major guy,
and Section XIII,
and the Last Battalion,
and those of us in Hellsing
were none of their concern.
But now, there they are,
dead bodies eating dead bodies.
That's something I just can't accept.
Seras, let's avenge them.
Let 'em have it. Let those guys have it.
Mm-hmm, all right.
All right, Chief. All right!
Target the enemy flying dreadnought,
and prepare to open fire!
Fire!
We're taking fire!
Let 'em have it.
Let those guys have it.
First, third, and fourth blocks hit!
Explosion in ready room 2!
Aft engine mounts 4
and 5 have been shot off!
Flight capacity down 32 percent!
Lieutenant!
We have to...
We have to turn the ship around!
It's too late!
This ship's light armor is
as good as a paper balloon
against that much firepower.
This huge hulk can't escape.
Bring us down! Land us! Crash-land us!
Hit Hellsing headquarters... No, hit her!
Hit Seras Victoria!
No! Get out of there, Seras!
The wide-area suppression
incendiary burst grenade launcher,
Vladimir...?
We're out of control!
W-We're falling!
Oh, she did it! She did it!
-Tallyho! Tallyho!
-All right!
They're not through yet!
That's right. They're not through yet,
ladies. Keep your eyes open.
They're coming.
They escaped just before they crashed!
That's impossible!
They're not even scratched!
That's right.
They aren't human. They're monsters.
Captain...
Young lady, you stand down and rearm.
Yeah!
Just you watch, young lady.
Let us show you how geese fight.
All right, the foreplay is over.
Here they come, geese.
It's time to go to work. Rock n' roll!
There are 42 surviving soldiers!
Those warheads were not
just run-of-the-mill bombs.
We've lost more than half our
personnel, and all of our heavy arms.
Even so, our spirits are high!
Your orders, Lieutenant Zorin Blitz?
It is enough. It will be
enough to kill all of them!
We'll kill them.
We'll kill them all!
Young lady, vampires
are what they are, right?
Folks with inhuman reflexes
and physical capabilities,
possessing a beastlike thirst
for blood and terrible strength.
They can sense a human's
bloodlust, read their moves,
escape their notice,
and move sharp-footedly.
They can avoid firearm
and sword attacks easily,
attack their opponent,
and feast upon their blood, right?
Well, how does this sound?
Mines! They've got mines!
They've stopped. Do it.
Bingo!
That's what happens when
you look down on humans.
Th-They set those traps?
Traps? It's the fools' own fault
for charging in here, head-on.
They're mindless,
motionless, emotionless devices.
And they aren't single points,
but a full-scale frontal attack.
60 claymore mines with blessed ball
bearings, all detonated at the same time.
Go ahead and dodge that, if you can.
We're not all that great
at fighting, you see.
It's a messy affair, so we don't
come out and fight in the open,
not like you soldiers.
Third floor, grenade volley.
Rapid-fire shots! Lay down a line of fire!
Don't let them raise their heads up!
A whole sheet of it!
Put down a full-scale attack!
Rifle squads, concentrate all of your fire
into a hail of bullets
in one place at a time!
Captain!
We have halted the enemy's advance.
They're pinned down behind the hills
and aren't moving an inch.
They're cooking something up.
But for now, that will do.
As long as they can't get
near us, we'll end up on top.
This is the first time
we've done any house-sitting.
Any that we're getting paid for.
If we let those scary old men
into the house, we lose.
Because we're not all that
great at fighting, you see.
Are they going to withdraw?
Ordinarily, they would.
If they were ordinary people,
they would withdraw.
They already would have,
no doubt about it.
But those guys ain't human.
They're monsters.
What the...
What is that thing?!
-What is that?!
-That thing is huge!
What is it?!
H-Hey, have we lost our minds?
What's the matter?!
What are you doing?! Keep firing! Hey!
Why aren't you shooting?!
Hey, what's going on?!
H-Hey, what kind of trick is this?
Th-This... This cannot be happening!
-Save me! My leg! My leg!
-It's a monster!
My arm! My... My arm!
Help us!
I-I can't move!
It can't be... This isn't happening...
I don't know what this is, but,
there's something inside me
that's telling me that...
I told you about the other eye
inside your forehead, right?
That's your third eye.
Let go of your human eyes.
They are a matter for humans.
But you are no longer a human.
You are not human.
An illusion...?
It's an illusion!
-It's a monster! Help!
-My leg! My leg!
-My arm! M-My arm!
-Snap to! Please, snap to!
It's just a vision!
-Help me!
-I-I can't move!
It's a vision! An illusion!
Impossible! This can't be happening!
There's no way this can be!
Captain, it's an illusion!
This is an illusion!
Captain!
W-What...?
M-My arm... It's there...
W-What was that?
What's going on?
W-What was that just now?
Please, snap out of it!
It was an illusion.
It was witchcraft or something!
Witchcraft?
You say it's an illusion? That thing?!
Yes!
Correct, it was an illusion.
Nicely detected, Seras Victoria.
However... However, it's too late!
This ain't good.
We've lost the front quarter.
This is the front entrance.
We're being overrun by enemy
soldiers here, and they're coming in!
Gather our forces together.
Those who have split off, take it slow,
and pull back while fighting.
All remaining soldiers, assemble here!
Bring as many explosives
and grenades as you can carry.
Young lady...
Y-Yes?
We'll barricade ourselves
in this part of the building.
We'll take up defense,
and young lady, you're on offense.
We will defend this place.
While we do, young lady,
you will dispose of them.
Y-Yeah!
You're our ace in the hole,
young lady. Take care of them.
Before those guys cut us to ribbons.
We're counting on you.
R-Right!
Oh, there's one important thing I forgot!
Seras!
Yes?!
Close your eyes!
W-W-What are you doing?!
Captain, no fair!
Yeah, no fair!
All right, let's go, you guys! Hurry!
That's abuse of power!
Sweet! In that case...
Me too!
-Me too!
Nitwits!
Young lady Seras...
Don't go dying, now. Don't you die.
Captain, and the rest of you...
All right, go on!
Off I go!
She's a fine girl, huh?
Yeah. She's so good, it's ridiculous.
If we let that girl die,
we'll disgrace our manhood.
It will land us in hell, get me?
You're right.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, that's the truth.
You bet, you bet.
Well, I hate to say this,
but I need your lives.
This will be the place
where you lose your lives.
Consider your posts to be your graves.
Captain, listen here.
Ordinarily, this is where you'd say,
"Anyone who wants to run, run now,"
or you'd let your subordinates flee,
staying behind by yourself,
or something like that.
What are you talking about?
You're all ungrateful sons,
who became merchants
of war for the fun,
and for the pocket change, aren't you?
-That's about right.
-You've got our number.
That we are.
Now then...
Let's go die, you dogs.
Let's go die,
while yelling out, "Fuck! Fuck!"
with our bellies full of lead,
writhing in pain.
You're probably right.
No doubt.
Absolutely no doubt about it!
It's not over yet.
The war is still just getting started.
It will grow more and more terrible.
Oh, yes, it would not do otherwise.
Now, you're going to pay.
Now, you cannot be saved!
Verein!
Sturm! Sturm! Sturm!
Damn them!
Now, die already, you scum!