What is it? Why are you crying?
Th-The kids at school told me
"You're the child of a killer,"
and "Your family members are
killers who go to war for money."
They're right. It's true.
Serving as mercenaries
has been the family trade
for eight generations now.
From the time of your grandpa's
grandpa's grandpa's grandpa.
Your own pop died when
he was in Columbia, didn't he?
He got in over his head, making
money to pay for you to be born.
Don't tell me you didn't know this.
G-Grandpa... Grandpa,
did you kill people, too?
Yeah, I did. A whole lot of people.
W-What for?!
Why would you kill other people?!
Why else do mercenaries fight? For money.
Whether the objective
of the people we fight for
is an idea or principle, to bring
down a system, or to prop one up,
to be the aggressor,
or to be the defender,
for homeland, for family,
for a woman, for drugs, for food,
there are many reasons.
We don't know what they are.
We just know that they're important.
But I think that you can take care of all
that stuff without having to take up arms.
Or should I say, do you need
a reason like that to take up arms?
I think that earning the pennies
they pay is reason enough.
On the other hand, the few
pennies they throw our way
is enough for us to risk our lives over.
We head out here and there to the world's
battlegrounds over those pennies,
where we kill
and get killed for those pennies.
What's more, we don't do it
because we're told to do it,
it's because we enjoy it.
Those pennies we earn on the battlefield
are worth more to us than our own lives,
or the lives of others.
Our family line really is a line
of human scum, considering.
Sorry, but you can't help it
if they pick on you at school.
But hey, I bet the time will come
soon enough for you to understand.
After all, you are our grandson.
It's true. You were absolutely right.
Yep.
Hurry! Find anything that can
be used to make a barricade,
and fall back to the final line!
Roger!
Contact B Wing, too! Look sharp!
Help me! Help me! Help me!
They're pouring in, damn it!
Fire! Fire! Fire!
Our bullets!
Our bullets won't hit!
Fall back! Fall back!
Medic! Medic!
Damn it all, we've been cut off! Shit!
Oh shit, oh shit, oh shit!
This is B Wing. Captain,
our route of retreat has been cut off!
We cannot join up with you.
Nonsense! Get over here,
even if you have to crawl!
We're preparing
to hole up in the round table room.
This is the most reinforced spot.
We'll be able to hold here.
They'll pick you off too easily
over there! Don't give up!
We'll wait with the barricade open!
Do anything you can!
No, we can't Captain.
We're all wounded, including myself.
He's already dead.
Hurry up and dispose of him.
He's gonna become a ghoul.
Water... Give me some water...
We'll hold out here as long as we can.
Please, close up the barricade.
Good hunting, and farewell.
You dumbass!
Damn it, so that's it, huh?
All right then, damn it, die.
Later, then. It's been fun.
That goes double for me, Captain.
Well, we're going on ahead.
Over and out.
Close up the barricade.
Upend this huge round table
and add it to the barrier.
I don't care
what you use, just pile it on!
Captain, what about the men in B Wing?
They've had it.
I see. That's too bad.
We're done for! It's all over now!
Shut up, you dumbass!
I've had enough of
fighting against monsters!
I can't take it anymore!
Integra and Arucard have forsaken us!
What are you talking about?
You can't get out anywhere
and nobody's letting you out.
I'm leaving! I've had enough!
Where do you plan to go?
Your grave is right here.
This ridiculously huge
building is your grave marker,
and your grave keeper is
that fearsome Miss Integra.
Your epitaph will read,
"These badass mercenaries
defeated the evil Nazis,
and now lie here
like the badasses they are."
But that's going to change, thanks to you.
Because of your whining, it will be,
"Gutless pussies kicked the bucket
here, while crying like women."
You can't be serious!
You're going to die here like a man,
even if I have to force you!
You take the money
and you do the fighting because
you like it, right, soldier?!
Then you will fight
and die because you like it!
Damn it! Damn it! Fuck! Fuck!
Besides, there's still no
guarantee that we're going to die.
We are the defense.
Go on, now,
hurry and get the barricade up.
The offense
is currently scoring our points.
Damn it, hit them! Damn it! Damn it!
Come on, you monsters!
Bring it on, you monsters!
Don't run away! Fight!
Here they come. We're done for.
Keep it together!
Burn it! Burn it!
Kill them all! Kill them all!
This is the power of Hellsing?
These are their royal knights?!
What a laugh that is!
That way.
Small-timer, you annoy me.
This is impossible! My... My house?!
Father!
Father, welcome home.
M-Michelle...?
N-No, that's not possible...
You... died!
You died, didn't you?!
What's the matter, Father?
Why the stern face?
It's a vision... It's a vision!
This is...
This is another illusion.
Damn it! Damn it!
Is this more of that witchcraft?
Michelle, are you just a vision, too?
It's not real!
None of it's real!
It's completely fabricated!
Death is the only cure for a fool!
Sergeant, how about that one?
Oh, hang on a second.
Judging by the sourness,
hmm, type A, with a negative Rh.
Let's see, I bet I'm right this time.
Amazing! Right on the money,
right on the money. Well spotted.
The richness is what's different. See?
Is that right? Amazing.
It tastes different going down.
Also, type A is more, how can I say...
I-I'll take care of them.
I'll... I'll...
I'll take care of all of them!
My eyes! My eyes!
Damn, they got us.
Medic! Over here!
Bring those chairs over here! Hurry!
Block it up, quickly!
The barricade! Hurry!
Damn them! Damn them!
Idiot! Don't expose yourself!
Damn it...
We're... We're done for!
Shut up, you dumbass!
Even if we surrender,
they'll still torture us all to death.
Those guys are monsters. They'll eat us!
Redistribute the remaining ammo.
Captain, here. This is the last of it.
We're out of blessed silver bullets.
Kill me! I've had it!
I can't see! Kill me!
Captain! I can't take it!
I don't want to die!
Shut up, will you?
I'd really rather not die, either.
This is just like that one time.
In Uganda, Jang Wijde,
and the right-wing-held
positions at the airfield?
Our reinforcements
showed up in time back there,
but this time... Damn, it's no use.
Enough of that blather,
Deputy Chief. She's coming.
I'm sure she's coming.
That's the kind of girl she is.
Damn them and their rockets.
They still have those damn things?
Everyone, report!
Deputy Chief, give me a damage report!
Deputy Chief!
Deputy Chief! Hey, Deputy Chief!
I'm exhausted...
Permission to rest ahead of you?
Yeah. Rest well. See you later.
Bulls-eye. Shall we charge in?
No, not yet. Hit them one more time.
We only have one Panzerfaust left.
It's our hole card.
I don't care, do it! Blow them away!
Blow that pathetic bunch to bits!
Jawohl.
Damn...
Do it!
Direct cannon support? It's you!
Captain...
Yeah, she's here, as promised.
Our girl is really here,
to single-handedly kill all the monsters.
Ah, damn it.
What a hell of a fine girl
she is, that's for damn sure.
I should have kissed her,
by force if I had to.
Seras... Seras Victoria!
You're the only one left!
So what if I am?!
It's an illusion, an illusion!
It's not real, it's an illusion!
It's an illusion! It's an illusion!
Seras is causing more problems, is she?
Yes. When one of the
boys took a toy from her,
she hit him with a rock.
It's an illusion! It's an illusion!
She hasn't taken to any
of the other teachers one bit.
The effects of the incident
must still be hard on her.
Still, if she causes any more difficulty,
this orphanage will no longer
be able to look after her.
Don't let her rattle you.
Go deeper...
Why do you want to be a police officer?
Can't you think of any
other path for yourself?
No.
You're too stubborn.
Sure, your father was a fine policeman.
But you have many other possibilities.
It's almost as though you're
squandering your chances.
It's just a vision...
Go even deeper...
All right, Seras, listen to me closely.
You must not come out
of here, no matter what.
Mum...
Mum... Mum...!
Have you croaked? Have you croaked?
Hey, you, have you croaked, copper?
Are you dead? Are you dead?
Yeah, he's good and dead.
Filthy pig! You filthy pig!
You feel sorry now?
This is what happens when
a flatfoot sticks his nose in too deep!
You got that, lady?
You little brat!
That filthy little brat! Damn it!
Hey, get up. We've gotta get out of here.
It hurts! It hurts, damn it!
This is more than I bargained for!
Now I'm gonna rape the old lady.
Get real, she's dead.
Not a problem. She's still warm.
Good morning, Miss Seras.
Did you have pleasant dreams?
One more! One more!
You're a tough chick!
What are you, an insect? A frog?
What is this? You're not at all
what they told me you'd be.
You're trash. A big sloppy mess.
Now then, it's about time for you to die.
I think I'll slice off that head of yours.
Die!
Shut up, you hag!
What?!
Have some more!
Chill, you ugly troglodyte.
Hurry, Captain!
This way! Hurry, Captain!
You got it.
Captain... Berna...
Don't try to talk.
Damn it...!
Mr. Bernadotte... R-Run!
You've done enough, Mr. Bernadotte...
I told you to keep quiet!
-Son of a bitch!
-Damn it!
-Captain!
Yeah!
You trash...!
You scum, trying to be a hero...!
Mr. Bernadotte...? Mr. Bernadotte!
Dumb... Dumbass...!
Mr. Bernadotte!
If you came to save me,
and I... I end up saving you...
...we're screwed, huh...?
Mr. Bernadotte...
That's what you get
for not paying attention.
I finally stole a kiss from you.
B...Ber...
Hey, don't cry, Seras.
You're a tough girl, ain't you?
Now devour me. Devour me,
and let's get her, together, Seras.
You dummy.
I told you not to cry, didn't I?
Your eyeballs have been
gouged out. You're such a fool.
Your arm has been lopped off, too.
You're falling apart.
Such a foolish girl.
Ah, damn it.
Damn it all.
You're such a fine girl.
If I can die to protect her,
that's okay with me.
Captain...
It can't be... Damn. Damn!
Tear-jerking, isn't it? Eh?
When a piece-of-trash insect like that
buzzes around making a pest
of himself, that's what happens.
Now then, you've really gone and
done a number on us, haven't you?
Well now, what shall we do about that?
R-Reinforcements!
A detached force?
Let's squash these
pesky bugs under our palms!
Such is the end for the life of an insect!
Not again! Not again, damn it!
You called him an insect, didn't you?
You called him a bug, didn't you?
You'll pay for this.
You'll pay for this!
You'll pay for this...
Off I go, Captain Bernadotte.
Off I go.
Off I go!
What...?
The lieutenant's spell...!
Together we go.
Together we get... We get those guys!
What is this? What's going on?
My soldiers are trembling
with fear. These vampires,
who swarmed the battlefield,
while under heavy fire,
and are members of the
battle-hardened Waffen-SS...
...are frightened by
a single girl before their eyes.
Frightened by a girl,
who is wounded from head to toe!
What the hell... is this?!
F-Fire! Fire! Fire!
This is bad...
This is bad!
I'm not sure what's going on here,
but this is bad!
I am not about to
drink one drop, one speck,
one microliter of your blood!
I won't do it! I won't do it!
Deeper... Deeper...
Deeper... Even deeper... Even deeper...
...even deeper!
W-What is this? Who is that?
This isn't right! This... This isn't her!
Who is this? What is this?
This isn't right! It's not her!
Her memories...
her mind... it's all mixed up!
What is this?
Who is this? Whose mind is this?
Him? That man I called an insect?!
Blood is the currency of the soul,
the coinage of the will.
This is what it is to
suck blood, and what it is...
...to offer blood.
Are you okay? Are you still alive?
Schrödinger!
Don't act so surprised.
I am everywhere, and yet nowhere.
Zorin, I am here to deliver
a message from the major.
"Stealing marches and first strikes
are the rewards of a soldier.
Ah, of course. Which means
that going against orders,
losing precious soldiers,
and dealing with inept underlings
is the reward of the commander."
That's what he said. Normally,
you'd be blown to cinders by now,
but the major and Doc have gotten
their hands on this fascinating toy,
and they're all wrapped up in it,
with no time to bother with you.
This monster is both Seras Victoria,
and not Seras Victoria.
This vampire will be performing
your execution. Bye, now.
Away with you! Out of my presence!
Out of my mind!
Is that...
Is that the same girl?
I'm off.
You're off? Where are you going?
I made a promise to the captain,
that we would get them.
Which is why
I'm going off now, to get them.
Oh...
Right. Captain, this is where you died.
Right here. But you're in there, too.
Hang on a second.
Yes, sir!
Sir!
The sky was starting to get light.
Dawn was approaching.
Not paying heed even
to the light of the sun,
she flew off, like a bow fully drawn.
Toward the dead city...
...for a raid at daybreak!
This is it. This is what I wanted to see.
Ah, it's so wonderful.
Zorin died, Major.
Just like a bug.
I knew it. Such a foolish little girl.
The destruction has begun.
It makes the heart leap, huh?
You're a terrible person.
You brought everyone with you,
and you're planning to send every
last one of them charging into hell.
That's what war is.
Hell is right here.
I take without end,
and am taken from without end.
I destroy without end,
and am destroyed without end.
As such,
I have overcome days of aspiration
and nights of resignation
to stand here now.
Behold,
our destruction is coming...
...together with victory!