Aerial Cruiser 3, the Arthur Seys-Inquart,
has been downed!
We've lost signal!
Blister is expanding! Cannot sustain lift!
Cruiser 2,
the Alfred Rosenberg, is in flames!
We cannot contact the landing party!
Platoon 7's blips have been wiped out,
and we've lost contact!
Have they been wiped out?
Wiped out?!
What is going on down there?!
Major!
Major, sir!
Your orders? Major?
What a racket. Be quiet.
Keep it down and enjoy
the act's climax, at least.
You're all sobbing
over the loss of your units
like you're young girls going
through your first time.
Captain...
Sir!
Distribute firearms and ammunition
to surviving crewmen on all ships.
Issue hand grenades to
those who cannot stand.
But... But sir, there aren't enough guns
or ammunition for all of them anymore.
Then give them pipes,
or munitions, or anything else.
Arm the troops and assemble them.
Once that is complete,
we will all charge together.
It will be fun. Very fun.
We'll charge in headlong as
we sing the "Horst-Wessel-Lied."
What fun!
Zum letzten Mal
Wird nun Appell geblasen!
Zum Kampfe steh'n
Wir alle schon bereit!
What's the matter? Why aren't you singing?
I've had enough of this!
We are not the SS! We're the German Navy!
We are here with you
to face the British forces!
But I have had enough!
This is no longer a battle!
I cannot send my men to die any longer!
You've come this far,
and still you do not realize
the true nature of our conflict?
Well, it does not matter.
Insubordination is the essence of war.
It's no use, Doc. I can't hit him.
Your sharpshooting is as dull as ever.
How did you manage to
get into the Schutzstaffel?
Major!
Mm-hmm, shoot him.
He is a defeatist.
Arm the remaining crewmen, Lieutenant.
I leave anyone who will not
follow orders to your discretion.
Instruct them in the
fundamentals of our conflict.
He who comes to strike down another
must be struck down by another.
Besides, the mission has all gone
according to plan, hasn't it?
This war has never once escaped
the tiny grasp of the palm of my hand.
Master...
Who...
Who... is that...?
Ah... that... is me...
God, I will in no way
beg for mercy from you.
Fight!
All of you, fight for the sake of God!
God will not help those who beg for help.
He will not save those who beg for mercy.
Those are not prayers,
but mere petitions to God.
You may die.
Fighting is prayer itself.
At the end of such an astonishing
prayer, God will descend.
Jerusalem will descend!
Tattered, fractured, rent, and scattered,
prayer after prayer after prayer,
God will descend before our
miserable... our wretched selves,
from out of Heaven!
So then...
So then, did they descend?
Either God, or Jerusalem?
What's the matter? Answer me, King.
The king has gone mad.
They all died. They all died.
For you, for those who believed you,
for your paradise, for your god,
for your prayers, they all died.
You killed foe, you killed friend,
the people you were to protect,
the country you were to govern,
man and woman, elder and child,
until even yourself...
Incorrigible. You are an absolutely
incorrigible monster, Count.
If, nevertheless, you will
trek through capitulation...
Master...!
A voice... calling to me...
Master!
Who is it that calls me?
Oh, it's you.
Master!
It burns.
His world... burns up.
Master! Master!
Keep it down, policewoman.
Your voice carries out as loud as ever.
Almost like that of a resounding song.
Master!
Anderson...
I would not have minded
being defeated by you...
...had it been that day...
Had it been that wasteland at sunset,
on that day, 523 years ago...
I would have given you my heart.
But I cannot do that any longer.
You cannot defeat me!
At any time, it is only a human
that can defeat a monster.
It must be... a human!
Integra...
There are many
undead monsters in the world.
Looking at them, I had a thought.
Do they really wish to be undead?
Most of them
desire conflict... A gory battle.
As it is, this is nigh unto sobbing for,
or craving, what they want.
This is a cry out of desire for death.
Nosferatu, the No Life King.
His castle, his land, his subjects,
the souls of his loved ones,
as well as his own soul...
everything and anything he ever had
vanished,
and he became a specter, merely walking
from one conflict toward the next.
But as for me, Integra...
That terrifying,
immortal monster appears to me
as a terribly wretched, wretched child,
broken down and crying weakly.
You are me!
You are me! I was also the way you are!
I was also the way you are!
Do not weep, fiend.
Were you chased by a child?
You became a fiend because
you didn't want to cry, right?
It is because a man cries
until his tears dry up
that they become fiends, and
are reduced to being monsters,
until that's all they are.
So then, laugh.
Laugh arrogantly
and insolently. Like you always do.
I pass on. You keep living on.
How much longer must your
miserable self keep living?
Until the greatness of my past
is demolished
by the greatness of my future.
But hey, I will see you soon,
my archenemy,
someday, in Limbo.
I hear voices.
The voices of children...
I hear their voices at play...
The children... I must go...
They're all waiting... Maxwell...
You mustn't cry... everyone...
Say your prayers... before bedtime...
Amen...
Amen.
W-Walter! Is that you, Walter?!
This is trash.
When people die, they become trash.
And trash has no need to be mourned.
Isn't that right, Integra?
Walter...
Walter, what have they done to you?
What have they done?
They captured me, made me
a vampire, brainwashed me,
and sadly enough, forced me to
fight against my former master.
If that were my answer,
would it satisfy you, Seras?
I stand here without having
been given orders by anyone.
I stand here as myself.
I stand here as Walter C. Dollneaz.
I am planning to cut you up here,
at daybreak, with full intent to kill.
Walter...
Why, Walter?!
Do not call me by name!
N-No, don't!
I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
Who cares about
your master-servant business!
Makes no difference to me!
Spatial constriction?!
Shimabara Sword Style, Shoki!
I got you!
You got nothing. I got you.
With the cry and strike that it may be so,
I slip my way out of this world...
Yumie!
No one can stand in my way.
I will allow no one
to interfere with my revolt.
Sir Islands...
Has Her Majesty
been secured in the Casemate?
Yes. The nuclear sub Nereid
is headed this way.
If the damage spreads any further,
we will have her flee to Canada.
What is the status in London?
It is the height of chaos,
the same as before.
Penwood's last message was
the last official communication.
Penwood, eh?
Yes. Penwood.
That fool. That was
uncharacteristically heroic of him.
Everyone made light of him,
saying he was a fool,
but who knew how great
a fool he actually was?
They'll pay. How dare they
take away our great friend!
How dare they take away our great ally!
Yeah, they'll pay.
Those Nazi lowlifes! Those maggots!
We have to make sure
we take vengeance for him.
We can clear the vampires out of
our installations across the land
with about a half-days' worth of time.
All thanks to the strike teams
you positioned ahead of time.
However, the problem is London.
It's all we can do right now
just to erect the blockades.
Her Majesty and the powers that be
are considering a counterstrike
that includes the final solution.
Nukes?
That's right.
A phase that renounces London, involving
three Trident SLBMs from the Nereid.
However, that is a last strategy.
A nuclear strike on our own
people would be infamous.
Besides, Her Majesty has faith.
London is still in the heat of battle.
There are still those who are fighting.
Yes, fighting indeed.
Including that daughter of Arthur's.
Islands, when the younger members
made accusations toward Penwood
concerning the traitors who
were at the Round Table,
you categorically
rejected them, didn't you?
That's right.
He was incompetent,
but he was a man among men.
If it came to treason, he would
have surely taken his own life.
Then who was it? You and I are the
only ones from the Round Table left.
Was it you? Or was it me?
Don't be ridiculous.
If I were to turn traitor, I would put it
in writing and circulate it to all of you.
I do have misgivings
about one thing, though.
When Arthur... When Integra's
father died, I cautioned them.
His brother, Richard, was a dangerous man.
He would definitely try to kill Integra,
and claim the family name for his own.
"Don't take your eyes off of Richard,
and don't take
your eyes off of Integra, either."
I warned the butler,
the Hellsing Family butler,
Walter C. Dollneaz.
But then, the night of the attack,
where was he?
What was he doing?
Arthur realized how dangerous Arucard was,
and locked him in the basement.
However, that evening,
when Richard was pursuing Integra,
she released him,
and she became his master.
What if all of these events had
been leading toward that end?
What if he was acting toward
that goal from the beginning?
And if so, how long has he been
against us? 10 years? 20 years?
Or perhaps, since September
of 1944, in Warsaw?
He shot through my cheeks!
Why, when he could have killed me?
"Don't interfere." Is that it?
He took pity on me! Pity! Pity!
Does he not consider me
to be a fighting force?
Am I a defeated soldier?
Does he not even regard me as an enemy?!
Heinkel!
Are you all right, Heinkel?
I'm fine! Never mind me, see to Yumie!
It's hopeless.
Yumie has had it.
Yumie... Yumie...!
Damn it! Damn it,
damn it, damn it, damn it!
That bastard!
That bastard! That filthy butler!
Give me that!
The gun! Give me your gun!
You can't go injured like that, Heinkel!
I don't care! I don't care anymore!
I'll kill him! If nothing else,
I'll kill that filthy butler bastard!
I'll kill him! I'll kill him!
Get up! Get up
and fight, Hellsing! Arucard!
Hey there, Reaper!
You once said Englishmen looked
forward to growing old, didn't you?
You said that you declined any glory
that wasn't easily won, didn't you?
In your aged form, you were billions,
even trillions of times more attractive.
What an ugly form that is.
Have you become a reaper,
both body and soul?
That's right.
This world is but a single night's dream
within a much larger battleground.
At the moment of daybreak,
I have at last become its Reaper!
Get up and fight, Arucard!
You and I are both
just dogs now. Running dogs.
Dogs which do not bark for themselves.
Orders! Give me your orders, my lord!
I can kill.
Without the slightest hesitation,
and without the least regret,
I can strike someone dead.
That is because I am a monster.
And you are... Integra.
I will stand with guns readied.
I will take aim with them.
I will load ammo in their magazines,
pull back their slides,
and I will release
their safeties. However,
any killing will be done at your will.
Now, what will it be?
Your orders, Director of Hellsing,
Integral Fairbrook Wingates Hellsing?!
Speak! Speak! Speak! Tell him, fräulein!
Speak! Speak! Speak! Speak!
Speak up! Speak up!
Speak! Say it!
Start talking! Tell him, my lady!
Search and destroy!
Search and destroy! My servant,
I have given you an order!
Nothing has changed!
Lay waste to all forces that oppose us!
Keep pressing forward and smash
through any obstacle in your way!
No matter who that may be!
No matter what that may be!
No matter... who...
...that may be...
Ah, she said it! She finally said it!
She told him! She told him!
Yes, my Master.
Outstanding! You truly were
a master worthy of my service.
I am no longer going to ask
"Why?" or "What happened?"
You have now become my enemy.
You have become an enemy of Hellsing.
You have become an enemy of Britain!
That's what you've done!
You must be defeated!
You must be destroyed!
Well said, Integral Fairbrook
Wingates Hellsing!
I was wrong to call you an amateur.
I won't do it again.
You have now at last become my enemy.
You have become a powerful
force worth beating,
and my great and wonderful archenemy.
Destiny has shuffled the cards.
Come to me! I call!
Das Dritte Reich.
Seien Sie herzlich willkommen.
Go on. Go ahead. Go and kill them.
Go, conquer, and put an end to this.
Yes. Off I go to conquer.
M-Master...
Go on, Seras. Our master needs a retinue.
Go and bring an end
to the man's long dream.
It has been 55 years.
Morning has now come.
I will bring an end to my
long night with this man.
Walter...
Um, this may be strange for me to say,
but... um... thanks for all you've
done up to now. Take care.
You, too.
Hurry!
Right!
Walter, farewell!
Farewell. Farewell, and die.
Welcome, madam.
I'm holding all jokers.
I'm putting an end to all of this. I call.
Fine women, aren't they?
You are now mine. You are my...
You are the beloved servant of
my dear master, and myself, alone.
No longer your own.
Are you angry, Reaper?
Get angry! Get angry!
This fools' dance
I've had with you ends today!
Chew on this!
Like you said, once upon a time...
there are no such things
as immortal freaks.
Your words are true!
As of now, they don't exist!
I will kill you until you perish.
That won't work!
Black Dog, Baskerville...
Stay your bark, mongrel!
So, what is next? What will you do now?
Arucard the Vampire,
you're just a simple vampire!
Who is it that made that gun?
Have you forgotten?
That was for
bringing down Anderson, wasn't it?
And I am not Anderson.
-Hmm?
-What's this?
Oh, it's him!
Let's see, who is that again...?
Oh, it's that guy! With the brother!
That is Luke.
Warrant Officer Luke Valentine.
It looks as though he was swallowed
by the dog, and kept there.
With the dog dead, its control over him
changed, and he manifested himself.
W-What is this?!
What happened? What is happening?!
Imagine, you showing up here,
Luke Valentine...
If you fancy yourself a minor Nazi,
then I will let you fight!
My body... won't hold out... Already...?
No, we agreed.
We agreed, and I struck back.
We agreed, and this is what became of me!
It's you!
You must be hard to stomach.
A half-digested failure at
becoming even excrement.
Quite the amusing marionette
you've acquired, Walter!
No! No, not yet! I can't die yet! Not yet!
I still haven't defeated Arucard!
Sure enough. He didn't
have any time left, anyway.
It was quite
a reckless procedure to undergo.
Nay!
Everything that we could
have given to him, we gave.
Everything that we could have
taken from him, we took.
His life, his master,
his loyalty, his devotion...
He staked them all,
and it still wasn't enough!
And so, he even borrowed money
to stake from scoundrels like us.
Even if, by doing so,
the interest is so exorbitant
that with the morning's light,
and the cock's crow, he is ruined.
For 50 years,
he has staked
everything to take on Arucard.
Just like we have. He staked
it all on one night's battle.
Destiny has shuffled the cards,
and you get one hand.
You are only dealt one hand!
You're taking on the joker!
So then, what are you, Walter C. Dollneaz?
Not too shabby, Luke Valentine!
You deserved better
than to be fed to my dog.
Checkmate!
My puppet has been beaten, has it?
Even so!
I've got you cornered.
It's over, Arucard!
Yeah. Let's put an end
to this fools' dance.
Quickly... get to his heart...
His heart... His heart...
No... This isn't right...!
Yes, you missed. What a shame.
I thought I was empty.
This half-eaten dog food
is surprisingly tasty.
What's the matter, man in black? Stand up.
I can't have you giving up on me
after just one punch, kid.
Because you used a deviant
method of becoming a vampire,
your regenerative and
restorative powers are lagging,
and your body is being pulverized.
Now then, what is to become of you?
You can no longer maintain
that form, can you?
Not like during your heyday.
So, what will you become?
Will you revert to
being an old man? Or rather,
will you become a kid again?
Hey there, Walter! It's been 60 years!
What do you think you're doing?
Stop screwing with me!
I am not screwing with you.
You are the one screwing around.
I am just sticking around for your
parlor tricks, your child's play.
The form you take on means nothing to me.
Just like I told you 60 years ago.
Not to mention the reason
why you betrayed us, perhaps.
You have a poor memory, kid.
There is nothing here.
In the end, the final analysis,
this is just a schoolyard spat.
That is why we became kids...
both you and I.
Such is the true nature of war.
If you cannot overcome that,
you cannot be yourself.
To that end, you must turn everything
upside down and sell it at a loss.
Yes, who I was 500 years ago...
Who I am now... Anderson... the Major...
You wanted to fight me, right?
Otherwise, you couldn't take even
one more step forward, right?
You don't know the way
to move forward, do you?
Are you afraid of becoming useless?
Are you afraid of growing old?
Are you afraid of being forgotten?
John Bull? Don't be ridiculous.
You're the one screwing around.
You are a kid. You haven't
changed at all in 60 years.
You're still just a skinny little urchin.
Now, bring it on,
you filthy brat!
Subtitle translation by
Steve Simmons