They're really making
a spectacle of things, huh?
My master, my servant.
Every which way, they are all written off.
Now, what is the final tally?
We are nearly to the climax.
Now it's Hellsing's turn.
It's been a long time!
Are you my death? Are you our deaths?
Everyone is dying with a smile.
Yes. They came here to die, after all.
If they want to die so badly...
If they want to die so badly,
then just hang yourselves!
You could have
hanged yourselves, 50 years ago!
I'm afraid we could not
have had that, fräulein.
There is no way we could
settle for simply dying.
That is just how incorrigible we are.
There is nobody in the whole
world that has need for us.
Everybody in the whole world
is trying to forget us.
But even so,
we are still needed by ourselves.
We are not about to just "simply" die.
We need more than that.
Our deaths require that there
is something more than that.
Something more, something more!
Such is how we have come this far.
And now we are here!
Something more!
There must be something else!
Some other place where we can fight,
some other enemy
somewhere for us to fight!
The world is vast. It is filled
with menace and marvel!
It is rich to overflowing
with conflict and gunfire!
There is no doubt that
somewhere in this world,
there lies a battlefield
fertile enough to support us!
Our deaths require something...
Something even more.
Otherwise, we would be
compelled to march on endlessly.
Just for us to die. That is
why you are precious to us!
Such is your value to us!
You are magnificent!
The Order of the Royal
Imperial Church, Hellsing!
You are what makes it
worth it for us to die,
and you are what makes
it worth it for us to kill.
Miss Integra, please go on ahead.
Seras...!
Quickly!
Go find the Major! We must not let him...
we must not let men like him
say another word!
Don't get killed.
I won't permit that, Seras.
I absolutely won't permit that.
Hmph, such a faithful dog.
Well done.
Hmph, you sure placed a bet
with some long odds, Walter.
Your card's about to burn up
and fall to the ground.
My master will see to your master.
My comrade will see to your comrades.
And as for you,
I will kill you.
Such a cruel end.
I have no interest in matching you
in the fight you staked your life on.
You are nothing but a simple traitor.
A simple one!
In my entire life, I have never
abided a single traitor.
How long do you think I will
comport myself fighting one-on-one?
You will die all too easily.
To say nothing of me being hungry.
I am unsure whether even I will
be able to devour all of this!
Everything has ended up
exactly as you desired, Major.
Yes. Everything is as I wish.
He has again
begun constructing the ramparts.
I have won.
From the outset, I never
considered him to be human.
In fact,
I don't even think of him as a vampire.
He is a castle,
as well as a mobile territory.
A population comprising
a river of death,
led by the will of their tyrant.
How does one defeat such a thing?
How does one slaughter such a thing?
I have pondered nothing else,
day and night.
That is the one and only way
that I wage war, after all.
War! War! Between him and me!
One must fight
with one's whole body and soul.
What is it that I have?
What is it that he has?
Being able to change his body,
employ familiars,
wield power to control minds,
regenerate his body,
and drink the blood of others,
all to shield his own life.
That is who he is.
I have nothing.
The reason being, I am human.
It would be fantastic to
become a vampire, wouldn't it?
Being able to live without end,
and to continue to fight without end,
must be rapturous, yes?
But I cannot do that. And I never will!
Immortality is wonderful.
Powers are brilliant.
The soul's life is assimilated,
and its currency is blood.
Get lost!
My mind, my soul, and my
life all belong to me alone.
The joining of life with another...
The merging of life...
The unification of minds...
The true nature of vampires...
How magnificent!
It must surely be magnificent.
It must certainly be joyous.
But you must be joking.
I'll have absolutely no part of it!
What's mine is mine.
Every last hair, every last drop of blood.
I am me. I am me.
I am me!
I envy you. So brilliant, so beautiful.
That's why I adore you,
which is why I hate you.
Which is the whole reason why you
are my enemy. I count you my enemy.
I have finally found my archenemy.
For my war.
And so, we began
our tireless preparations,
for the next 50 years.
Meow.
All is in readiness. All for this moment.
The Last Battalion, and the
Knights of the 9th Crusade,
and Anderson,
and the werewolves, and Walter,
and everything else over our
50 years has been for this moment.
Once Arucard unleashes Level 0,
discharges all of his lives,
and he becomes all alone in his castle,
can Anderson defeat him?
Can Walter defeat him?
Nay, I think.
He is a terrifying vampire,
all by himself.
He is a man who attacked all of
London by himself a century ago.
He is a man who fought the Ottoman
Empire by himself 500 years ago.
And once he starts drinking blood again,
everything will come to nothing.
Such guile!
In both life and death,
he scams everything.
And right now,
he is indeed in the thick of it.
What does one do to kill such a mad king?
Trample past wave
after wave of his numbers,
and destroy his almost limitless
forces to claim his head?
No!
He will drink blood once again.
The king is a big eater.
His greatest weapon is also his weakness.
Past and present, the tyrant has
gulped down his poisoned drink
for the sake of his own pride.
It's no use...
He's too strong...
No use...
Hey, now, are you serious?
This ain't like you.
Get up. The woman I know
didn't know when to quit.
You're such a hopeless bitch.
Snap out of it, you bloody fool.
Okay, now that your eyes are opened,
let's go, young lady! Let 'em have it!
Let's get this guy together!
Not just a point!
A surface! Take out the whole surface!
Got him!
No you haven't!
This is just too much. He's a monster.
He's as good
as a real-life wolfman, ain't he?
A werewolf!
A gold tooth...
Tooth fillings...? Then, all of this is...
It sure is.
The stuff they stole turning
Europe upside down 50 years ago.
Everything from gold bullion
to wads of money to watches,
all scattered about.
That filling you've got was probably
pulled out of some poor fellow
in a concentration camp somewhere.
Which is to say, that's the
kind of people these are.
They aren't even so much
as a military force.
At best, how different are they
from a band of killers?
I wouldn't even rate this bunch
as high as shit.
An invincible force? Knights of steel?
Ha! Don't make me laugh!
A silver tooth?
Y-You mean...
What a kindhearted mutt.
He's asking you to kill him with that?
S-So then, he intentionally led us here?
I get it.
He's a war dog that wants to die.
What do you say we end his misery?
If he's a war dog, Mr. Bernadotte,
then you've got no room to talk.
Without a doubt.
Also, please don't go smoking
inside of me.
Here he comes!
Don't run. Take him head-on.
Right!
Go! Conquer him! Let him have it!
When he attacks,
he is also flesh and blood.
Not yet!
He's predicting our moves!
It doesn't matter.
Mm-hmm. Let's go!
Yeah! Get him!
I've got you this time for sure!
Wolfman, sir, this is payback from
a certain someone 50 years ago.
Take it.
That's what you get for messing
with another man's woman.
Your collar has been sent flying.
Farewell, war dog!
It's almost like...
It's almost like a child
having an enjoyable dream.
That's right. I'm sure this evening
has been a whole night's
dream come true for them.
Mr. Bernadotte...
Yeah, you're right.
Let's go and finish this.
All dreams must come to an end.
Go!
Major!
Hey!
I'm so glad to finally be
able to see you in person.
Unfortunately, that gun won't be enough.
Call it a commander's discretion.
I thought you might be
late for this little feature,
but luckily, you're in time.
This is to be a one-night show.
As long as I'm going to see it,
I should be with a pretty lady,
in the most exorbitant seats.
Stop screwing around!
Enjoy this.
This is the production of the century.
Our story has not been told since 1898.
That's because Nosferatu Arucard...
is about to be eliminated.
What?!
There's all-you-can-eat,
and then there's this!
Now! Shall we do this, Walter?
Not yet... My battle is not over yet...
It's not over yet! Major, stop this!
Make it stop, Major!
No, it's over now. It's too late.
It's too late, for everything.
It's too late, you fool!
It's now too late for everything.
You are no longer able to triumph.
The chance is now virtually forever lost.
I have given you a golden opportunity.
Two chances of a lifetime...
to physically bring down Arucard.
The only two golden opportunities
there have been since 1898.
An armed Schutzstaffel,
consisting of 1000 vampire troops...
The 3000 of the Ninth
Airborne Mobile Crusade...
Not to mention Iscariot...
Not to mention the werewolf...
Not to mention Anderson...
Then there's
the half of your life up to now.
The moment created
from all of that sacrifice
is the only moment when
it is possible to kill Arucard.
Nonetheless, your wires have not
reached in that far, have they?
Exactly how many lives
does Arucard have now?
One million? Two million?
You can no longer beat him.
Your life has now been in vain.
Don't go spacing out, kid.
Pull it together.
Only a few
tens of thousands of tries to go.
If Anderson was unable to beat me,
then there's no way that you,
a pale little brat, could spend 50,
or even 500 years agonizing it out,
and somehow be able to beat me.
You are beaten, Arucard.
I have won.
You are beaten, Arucard!
Beaten? Who, exactly? Me?
Lose? Me, lose, you say?
Me, defeated by you people,
Professor Hellsing?
I am never beaten. There is
no way I can be beaten. Ever.
What?
What am I looking at?
What... is this view? What is this sight?
Ah, that's it...
That's it...
That's right...
The light of the sun
was like this then, too...
The view when I died is always like this.
And I think, again and again,
who knew the light of the sun
was as beautiful as this?
"Out, out, brief candle!
Life's but a walking shadow..."
What?!
What is happening?!
What did you do?!
I've done it all.
He absorbed
Warrant Officer Schrödinger's life.
That is nothing other than assimilating
Schrödinger's
"life essence" into his own.
He is a self-observing Schrödinger's Cat,
possessed of his own will.
His very existence is that of
an equivocal Cheshire Cat,
bounding about within a certain world.
As long as he is aware of himself,
he is everywhere, and he is nowhere.
However, now,
he has been dissolved into millions
of other consciousnesses and lives.
He can no longer
recognize himself as himself.
So then what happens?
He is now nowhere. He is
neither alive, nor is he dead.
Right now, Arucard...
...is just a lump of imaginary numbers.
Arucard!
Do not close your eyes!
Open your eyes!
Arucard!
I order you... Arucard!
Do not disappear!
No... This is farewell, Integra.
Arucard!
I gave him all that I had...
...but all that he was is now lost.
I have lived my life for this day.
I have lived entirely for this moment.
In my war, which has been a string
of losses, this is my first win.
You... You...!
Yes, it's nice, isn't it? So this is...
victory.
So it will be you two...
that will kill me.
He's dead! He's dead!
He's gone! He's gone...
Damn it!
Is this what I was hoping for? Is this it?
Is this it?!
Die! Die, die, die!
You've done at least enough
to earn this! I'll kill you!
Yes... this is my fate.
A fitting fate for a traitor.
I will die... with no further ado...
Vampire my ass! Reaper my ass!
I will kill you like it's nothing!
Shoot me again... Shoot me...
Yeah! Yeah! I'll plug you good!
Die! Die!
Yeah! I'll shoot you! I'll shoot
you up! I'll shoot you, all right!
You are free to shoot me.
However...
...you are not the one who will kill me.
Wait! Hold on!
Wait! Wait!
I'm gonna kill you!
I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
I'll kill you!
I have... to go...
Well, pleased to meet you, fräulein.
I am merely stating the obvious.
Yes, it will be you two.
It will not be Arucard that defeats me.
It will be me that defeats Arucard.
My archenemy is Arucard,
and right now, your archenemy is me!
Now, bring it on! Here is your enemy!
He is right here!
You are over there...
and I am here!
Here I am.
Seras, shoot him.
Shoot him! Shoot him!
Search and destroy!
Doc made it too strong.
The Acht-acht!
That's fantastic! I love it!
It's over, Major!
So... it would seem.
But hey... not just yet.
Is that... Is that what you are, Major?!
That's right.
This is me.
A machine!
Do not speak... in such... rude terms...
young lady.
I am decidedly human.
Monster...
You are a freak.
No, I am not. I am human.
There is one thing that
makes a human a human...
and that is their will.
I am not a pitiful monster like Arucard,
who must continuously
take into himself others,
using the currency of blood,
to go on living.
Do not lump me in with that weakling.
As long as I have my will,
then even if all that I am is a brain,
floating in a glass jar
of culture medium...
Even if all that I am...
are memory circuits in a giant computer...
then I am human.
A living creature with the soul...
mind, and will of a human.
And even if he may smile in
the appearance of a young girl,
or kneel down in the form of
a battle-hardened warrior,
full of sentimentality, he is a monster.
Which is precisely why I hate him
from the bottom of my heart.
I reject the vampire Arucard!
He is a monster that looks like a human,
and I am a human
that looks like a monster.
I am me.
You and I are...
You are not the same as me.
In all of the warring in this world,
that has been everything.
Ever since mankind
was born into this world.
You, too, believe yourself
to be different than I am.
Our declaration of hostilities
was completed long ago.
Now, let's wage war.
That's the first time I hit anyone.
Ah... this is good...
A good war... This was a good war...
Die. You must die.
Was it a good war, Major?
This is not even a war.
After being nearly dead for
60 years, you have just expired.
You must die. It is absolute retribution.
Whatever you may profess humankind to be,
you are no longer the least bit human.
You are simply a genuine monster.
And at any time, it is only a human
that can defeat a monster.
Monsters are defeated by humans.
That is because only humans
have "defeating" as their goal.
Not for the joys of fighting.
Because it is our duty to carry out.
You are not human.
That is why he is coming back!
Is it over?
No, it's not. Not at all.
Technology advances thanks to science.
My research makes great strides!
No! No! My research made great strides!
What do I do? What do I do?
What? What?
Not yet... I can't reach it yet...
What am I doing wrong? What am I missing?
That's it! Someday...! Someday...!
The whole world... Every last
person will have their share!
This miraculous science!
These scientific miracles!
Where do you think you're
going, Grand Professor?
No, no, Doc. You must
not be such a poor loser.
W-Walter!
The remnants of the remnants of
the Nazis? It's not even laughable.
Why, you... misbegotten scum!
You're quite the esteemed
misbegotten scum yourself, Doc.
You, and all of the things
you make, including me.
The farce is over.
The performers must now disappear.
Isn't that right, Grand Professor?
Farce? Farce, you say?
I don't want to hear it from you!
How dare you, you defective merchandise!
It's a one-night, one-act farce.
Both this war, and this world.
I just... I just wanted to play the
best role I could amidst all this.
What a cruel end.
Arucard was right. I'm a disgrace.
Defective goods like you...
A failed creation such as you...
dares laugh at us?!
I will not have the likes of you
calling my research a farce!
I will not have you laughing
at the Major's battalion!
Not by you!
Not by any "thing" such as you!
My theories have made leaps forward!
My research has made leaps forward!
The science has been put into practice,
and keenly moves forward!
Someday, I will overtake this!
Someday, I will surpass Arucard!
You shouldn't be so absurd.
You, and I, and everyone else dies.
All defective goods die.
Shut your mouth!
Mina Harker.
Yes, indeed. This was your teaching aid.
The one being from whom Arucard...
Dracula drank blood, and was drunk.
"The beginning of everything."
It was said that Dracula was defeated by
Hellsing, and returned to being a person.
However, Arucard did not die!
Arucard is still inside of her.
No matter what becomes of her,
he exists deep inside her.
It's the vampire blood, which neither...
consecrated host, nor holy water,
nor crucifixes have any effect on.
That's why you started from there.
An imitation Arucard.
To that end you exhumed her,
and stripped her already skeletal
body even further to the bone.
But ultimately, all you did
was create knock-off copies.
If that isn't a farcical comedy,
then what exactly is it?
And poor Mina...
Strike everything, and take our leave
both you, and me.
At pinball!
Ah... damn...
I sure did want to beat that guy.
Farewell, Madam.
Walter!
Walter has just passed on.
Right.
Let's go back. Let's go back, Seras.
Back to our home.
Fly!
The simultaneous
US-British bio-terror attack,
also known as the "Airship
Incident," 17th Report.
The casualty count for the US, including
all cabinet officials, stands at 64,300.
For Britain, 3,718,917.
Don't you have
your fencing training today?
Are you sure you won't attend?
Yes. I'm going to stay here for
a short while longer, then go.
If the events of 30 years ago
were to happen again,
since it will be my task to bring them
to a resolution without taking up arms.
Hmph... Islands, when you make that face,
you look just like your great-grandfather.
Hold it! That's the match!
Lady Integra wins!
Well done, well done. Your skills
have not diminished one bit.
Section XIII, I thought I asked you
to wait in the reception room.
Yes, well, simply waiting
around is not in my nature.
And no matter how long I waited,
no one ever brought me any tea.
I grew a little bit weary of it.
I can't just have you wandering around.
You will go back there.
Yes, yes, all right, I shall return.
Chief Makube, the security inside
the manor is as lax as ever.
We could beat them now.
Young fool. You must be blind.
Huh?
Yow!
That hurts, you know! What the hell!
What was that?
One of Seras Victoria's shadows.
It envelops the whole region
of the hall, including ourselves.
But, in exchange for myself and the chief,
we could take out half the Round Table.
No, not yet! We have lost too much.
After the Ninth Crusade,
the Vatican has lost too much power.
Look, just wait.
We have waited for 500 years.
Another century or two is nothing.
The next crusade will go more smoothly.
That's all for today. You are dismissed.
Sir Penwood, good work.
Oh, er, yes, ma'am.
You have a fine form. It's getting better.
No, I still have much to learn.
Thank you very much.
Um, did grandpop... I mean,
my grandfather, also learn fencing?
Your grandfather...
sliced this way and that through
the approaching Nazi forces,
and was truly peerless in all of Britain.
He cut every approaching enemy
clean in half,
until ultimately,
he strapped bombs all over himself,
and blew himself up, taking
an enemy airship with him.
He was the guardian deity of Britain.
My left eye was lost as
a result of his lethal blades.
-That's not true, is it?
-It's the truth!
It's truly the truth!
It's true!
It's true, so I would ask you for
the funds for a new helicopter.
Not again!
If you please.
Yes, ma'am...
If you please!
How cruel!
That was rough. Both to
him and his whole family.
You're almost acting like
you're the Mafia, aren't you?
It's all right. I have to make them work.
Starting now, I have to
make them work extra hard.
Once I die, Hellsing will be through.
Then, those other gentlemen
will have to bear the load.
From then on, they will bear
the load under a state-led ministry.
The way it should be.
This is not the time for one
family to lead the organization.
Besides, I'm getting a bit tired.
Eh? You don't look that way to me.
When I looked in the mirror this
morning, I spotted a new wrinkle!
And, when I saw the wrinkle, I...
remembered Walter.
Fight on, Madam!
What is this?
Don't get so depressed!
Don't you get depressed!
Are you still down?
Can you not get over him?
Please don't talk about dying.
If you like, I could drink your blood.
See this? I'm imitating the master--
That was nothing to kick me over, was it?!
Don't even joke about that, dummy!
You haven't changed in decades!
And what is
Arucard up to, anyway, the idiot?!
He hasn't come back once, has he?!
You said he was coming back, didn't you?!
He will come back. I can tell.
He has sucked my blood, after all.
Sure, he's coming back, you say,
but it's been 30 years. 30 years!
You're a vampire,
so it may be fine for you.
I never get more wrinkles, so yeah.
You are a bad girl!
Is that what you say?
Is that how you talk to me?!
I-I'm sorry! Forgive me, forgive me!
What is it, Master?!
That was a harsh welcome.
And as noisy as ever.
Master!
Your return is late, Arucard.
What have you been doing?
I have been killing off...
the lives that are inside of me.
Three million, four hundred twenty-four
thousand, eight hundred and sixty-seven...
I've been killing off all but one of them.
I am now right here.
I am now nowhere, and I can
be everywhere.
Hence, I am here.
You're late. You're worse than late.
You're late, Arucard.
Hmph, I'm sorry.
Were you trying to drink my blood?
Yes... I was.
I haven't eaten anything in
30 years, and I'm hungry.
I am an old woman now.
I...
That is all right.
Hmph...
Welcome back, Count.
I have returned, Countess.
Subtitle translation by
Steve Simmons