Shut up!
Ow...
W-Wha?
Hey, Jet.
I'm asking ya, how much
longer before we land?
How long ya been standing there?
I've been here for a while.
I see...
What're ya spacing out about?
Where's my bounty?
Can't you land quickly so I can
hand over that musty-looking fugitive?
What, you haven't even
gotten permission to land yet?
I know. You guys are so obnoxious.
Don't rush so much!
And take care of the
airport end for me.
I thought Ganymede was your homeland.
Were you perhaps thinking about some
woman in the past that cried over you?
...or perhaps a woman
that made YOU cry.
Didn't ya hear me when I said
you're being obnoxious?!
Yes...
This is Ganymede police.
Donelly?
Oh, Jet! Jet, it's you!
There is no mistake...
The top of your head's gotten rather
lonely, but it's still Jet all right!
Long time no see, Donelly.
I'm surprised that you're working
around here. Has it been...
Seven years? Eight?
What the hell's up with you
to come back so suddenly?
I wanna hand over a bounty.
Wanted ad number EX41285.
Baker Panchorero.
To think you're a bounty hunter...
You, who was called the Black Dog...
...a mad dog that never let
go of things bitten into?
I thought YOU had already retired.
Hey, I'm still an active officer!
Don't judge things on YOUR time
scale, you Rip Van Winkle you.
- He used to be a cop? That explains...
- That example is completely reversed!
- What?
- I'm just glad to see yer still kickin'.
...why I don't get along with him.
- Yeah, you, too.
Oh yeah... what was her name...
You know...
I know! Alisa!
GANYMEDE ELEGY
She's got a little joint
in the port of Marvis.
A small bar called "La Fin"...
But in this recession, I hear
she's got a lot of debts to pay...
I'm sure there are a lot of problems
for a woman trying to live alone...
Sense of justice and duty, huh?
First time in a while he's home,
of course he's gonna go visit.
You're totally wrong if you think
your old woman still thinks about you.
You're totally wrong yourself if you
think every other woman thinks like you.
Justice and duty, duty,
THREE O'CLOCK TEA!
Really, men...
...are hopeless romantics.
Hey, why are you
rubbing that stuff on?
Beautiful skin is maintained by
continued effort that seems futile.
Do you understand?
I know! Futile! Useless!
This is...
...La Fin, right?
Yeah... and you are?
An old friend.
I was in the area for
the first time in a while...
Alisa... isn't here.
Jet?
That can't be...
Are you really Jet?
Rhint...
...he is my guest.
It's all right.
You don't mind?
I don't...
Anyway...
How about it? You want a glass, right?
You're my last customer.
I'm closing shop.
The number of ships decreased,
and this area has gotten desolate...
I'm thinking of moving to a new town.
Are you all right?
On the new island cities,
mortgage is expensive.
Are you able to manage all that?
That's so like you to
worry about such things.
I'm planning to change
myself in the new town.
Don't worry...
Rhint is here with me...
That guy that was just here?
Something on your mind?
Yeah.
To tell the truth,
I already have 3 kids...
I'm just kidding. It was a joke!
Rhint is just my boyfriend.
How are you doing?
Have you gotten married yet?
I live and wander with
a group of weirdos.
And on top of it,
I'm a bounty hunter now.
Do you remember?
Where's Jet?
Doing personal stuff.
You're his partner, right?
Yeah.
I've got news on a bounty,
This hasn't been
publicly broadcast yet...
Rhint Celonius.
A thug in the port of Marvis.
Last night, he contacted
financial broker Law Rentzuo.
This guy was another tough guy...
...but he was killed!
And so?
Rhint... is Alisa's gigolo.
I thought I'd warn you guys.
And how much is the bounty?
Back then...
when I got home from work...
You always waited for me.
That was all I needed.
But that day...
When I came home,
only that watch was left...
...and a small note with
one word: "farewell".
For some reason, I didn't feel sad.
It just lacked reality.
And I gradually felt something
inside me go numb...
After 6 months,
I made a bet with myself.
That I would leave this
planet if you didn't return...
...by the time this clock stopped.
I didn't come here to blame you.
I just wanted to know...
...why you disappeared back then.
You seem to think that
time on Ganymede had stopped.
That's a story from long ago...
I've... forgotten it.
I don't need time that stands still.
Farewell, Jet...
A bounty hunter? Then can he be?
Rhint...
He's after me...
I have a bounty on my head...
It's all over!
It's not your fault.
It's because I borrowed
money from a guy like him...
...and you protected me...
I can't be saved if I get caught.
I...
...killed a guy...
Let's get outta here...
Let's get outta here,
just the two of us!
This must be because
I have good karma...
Sorry, but it's business.
Steer for me, please!
Hey? What's wrong?!
I'm after a bounty worth 1.8 million.
- What?!
- Here, I'll send it to you.
He's a bounty?
Yeah, a secret bit of info from Donelly,
He apparently killed a loan shark.
Dammit!
I'll do this. You can go back.
You're not gonna let him go, are ya?
This is the land where I was a cop...
I'm the Black Dog...
Once I bite, I never let go.
I have no regrets about her, but I'll
settle this score on my home turf.
Sense of justice and duty, huh...
Can you hear me...?
Stop the boat, now!
Jet?
Stay away!
Please, let us go!
There are other bounties to find!
Even if I let you go,
someone will come for you someday...
If you run, you will
become an accomplice.
Stay away!
You still have time.
Don't worry about me anymore!
You were like this back then, too...
You decided everything.
And you were always right...
When I was with you,
I never had to do anything.
All I had to do was hang on to your arm
like a child, with no cares in the world.
I wanted to decide how to
live my life by myself...
Even if that was a mistake...
Let go! I don't wanna
go to prison! Let go!!
Help! Help me, please!
Be strong...
...and protect her...
Self-defense seems to
be how they see it.
What are you going to do now?
I won't be going anywhere anymore.
I will wait in my store... for Rhint.
It won't take long...
...because time is flowing along.
An unseen terror
assaults the Bebop crew.
COMING EPISODE
Caught by the venomous fangs of the
unseen enemy, another victim falls.
What is the identity of the fearsome
enemy that refuses to show itself?
A symphony of shivers that will send
you into the deepest trenches of terror!
Next episode: Toys in the Attic.
Once the channel is set,
you will no longer be able to escape...
TOYS IN THE ATTIC