It'll be great! It'll be awesome!
It'll be the best, so try it!
Wha...? Like, right now?
Of course! Didn't all your stuff arrive?
I mean, it's all here, but...
You aren't able to play, right?
Well, my mom's telling me
I gotta focus on the next test.
So just go ahead and play without me for now!
I'll pass you up in a jiffy.
Risa! The water's ready, so take a bath!
Okay!
She's calling me. Anyways, just give it a go!
It's the best! You're totally gonna love it!
"Risa"
H-Hey, Risa!
Jeez!
And here I've basically
never played a game in my life...
I only bought this because
Risa talked me into it.
I mean, how can I say no
to those sparkling eyes of hers?
Oh, well. I'll just set things up.
"Defense and First Battle"
"Please enter your name."
First thing is a name, huh? Hmm...
I could always use my name as is,
but I wonder...?
I've got it! Since my name is Kaede,
I'll go with Maple!
Yup! That settles it!
Next up is starting equipment?
Great sword, one-handed sword, mace, staff...
Hmm. I've never been that great
at moving around and stuff.
Besides, I'd like to avoid getting
hit since I don't wanna get hurt.
Should I just pick
the staff and be a wizard?
Huh?
"Great Shield" "Short Sword"
"Suitable for a tank.
Offensively lacking, but number one in defense.
Taking no damage won't be a pipe dream."
Offensively lacking,
but number one in defense?
Huh?! If I raise defense enough,
I won't take damage?!
Sweet! I'm going with that!
Now to distribute status points?
Everything I've got goes into defense!
Okay! I think we're good now!
"Now being taken to starting area."
Great!
Jeez, VRMMOs sure are
something else these days!
I'm slow! Why?!
Oh, yeah!
Hmm? Vitality was defense, right?
Strength is power, agility is speed...
Oh! I can't walk fast
because my agility is zero!
Whoops! I goofed up big time!
What now? Should I log out
and redo it since Risa's not here?
"5 minutes later"
Oh, well! Let's fight some monsters
since I finally made a character!
Um, which way to go?
Oh... Um, excuse me?
Huh?
Excuse me! Um!
Hmm? What is it?
Um, I wanna fight some monsters,
but I don't really know where I should go.
Oh! You must be a newbie!
There's monsters in the forest to the west.
It's a good spot to raise levels at the start.
You can just stand around
and they'll come right to you.
Thank you so much! I'll check it out!
Good luck!
What's up, Frederica?
Oh, Drag!
I was just telling some newbie girl
a good spot to get levels.
Hmm?
There's sure a lot of people around these days.
Come on, let's get moving too.
Payne's already here.
Right on time, just as expected.
Everyone else walks so fast!
It's gotta be my agility.
Oh! This must be it!
Okay! I wonder if this is a good spot?
Hey monsters! Come at me if you dare!
It's adorable!
Wha...?! I'm sorry!
Ouch!
Wait, no?
Whoa, cool! That didn't hurt!
That's 128 vitality for you!
Well, Mr. Bunny? Like these abs?
This doesn't hurt one bit!
Come on, what's the matter? Bring it!
Go on, keep at it! Hit me! I'm right here!
Fight me!
"1 hour later"
Come on! Put your back into it!
Wait a sec, Mr. Bunny.
"Acquired [Total Defense]."
"Total Defense"
"Having this skill gives the user 2x VIT.
[STR], [AGI], [INT] require 3x the points to increase."
"Total Defense"
"Having this skill gives the user 2x VIT.
[STR], [AGI], [INT] require 3x the points to increase."
Two times the vitality.
In other words, I've got 256 vitality?
And all I did was play with Mr. Bunny!
Okay! Sorry to keep you, Mr. Bunny!
Mr. Bunny?
Mr. Bunny!
"Level has increased to 2."
I wasn't even trying to beat him either!
Oh. I can assign five more status points now.
At this point, why raise anything but defense?
That settles it! More defense!
'Cuz I don't wanna get hurt!
I wonder what kind of monsters are around here?
I don't want to fight anything cute again,
so let's hope the next one isn't.
You're kidding me!
That didn't hurt!
That tickles!
It burns!
I can't defend against poison!
Tactical retreat!
"Acquired [Poison Resist - Weak]."
Huh?
I've got it! Getting hit by attacks
builds up resistance!
In that case...!
I think I'm done for!
Ugh!
"[Poison Resist - Weak] advances to
[Poison Resist - Moderate]."
Woo-hoo! I'm getting stronger
against poison just like I thought!
It got me!
Oof!
You fell for it!
Woo-hoo! That was a tough fight,
but I finally won!
Talk about a fearsome opponent!
But wicked monsters are simply
no match against my wits and bravery!
"Acquired [Giant Killing]."
"Level has increased to 8."
"Acquired [Forest Queen Bee's Ring]."
"Forest Queen Bee's Ring"
"[VIT +6]
Self-Recovery: Restores 10% Max HP in 10 minutes."
"Forest Queen Bee's Ring"
"[VIT +6]
Self-Recovery: Restores 10% Max HP in 10 minutes."
Oh? It's a rare item!
"Forest Queen Bee's Ring"
"[VIT +6]
Self-Recovery: Restores 10% Max HP in 10 minutes."
Gives plus six to vitality...
Oh! It recovers HP while you wear it too!
And um, let's see...
I got 15 more status points,
so let's throw that into vitality too.
Giant Killing, huh? Um...
Hmm. I guess it'll be active all the time.
Which means, together with total
defense from earlier... Four times?!
What a day!
Huh?
What the heck's going on there?
"Acquired [Meditation]."
"When used, restores one percent
of Max HP in 10 seconds.
Effect lasts 10 minutes."
Under requirements it says:
"While being under attack"...
While being... under attack?!
"Level has increased to 11."
"Acquired [Provocation]."
"Provocation"
"Draws enemy attention to a certain area.
Cooldown is 3 minutes."
"Hold aggro from 10 or more monsters at once."
That was a rush. But I did learn a new skill,
so I guess it's worth it.
Oh, yeah. Since I got 10 more status points,
I'll put them into vitality again.
I think I did pretty good for my first day!
Yup! I'll call it quits for today!
"Do you wish to log out?"
That was so much fun!
No way! It's already that late?!
Oh crap! I had homework to do!
"Saw a sick great shielder"
"1. So sick"
"2. Wut?"
"Saw a sick great shielder"
"1. So sick"
"2. Wut?"
"3. Sick how?"
"4. They were fast asleep in the west forest
with giant centipedes, caterpillars,
and wolves all around 'em"
"4. They were fast asleep in the west forest
with giant centipedes, caterpillars,
and wolves all around 'em"
"5. ??"
"6. That would kill anyone,
great shielders included"
"7. They have wicked gear or something?"
"8. Looked like starting equipment to me.
How can u sleep with poisonous bugs all over you?
Makes me sick just to think about it"
"9. Isn't total damage negation
the only way to live through that?"
"10. Who was it?"
"11. Some cute girl not even 150cm tall.
Prolly low AGI by how slow she walked.
By the way, I tried what she did
and melted instantly"
"12. She max out defense or something?"
"13. Maybe she unlocked a hidden skill"
"14. We'll have to keep digging for info.
If she's a top player, we'll find out
her name eventually"
"15. Report back if you find out anything"
"16. Thanks for the info!"
I'm back for more today!
If Risa won't play,
I'll just have fun all on my own!
Everyone looks so stylish.
And here I am still in starting equipment.
Oh! He's a great shielder, too!
Um!
Excuse me! Um...
Hmm? Wha...?!
Um!
Where can I get a cool shield
like the one you've got?
Oh, this?
Yeah! Your great shield is so cool!
Well, thanks.
This one was made to order.
I had a crafter make it for me
in exchange for money.
Oh, I see.
Shall I introduce you to one?
Please do!
So she's a newbie after all.
Never thought she'd straight up talk to me.
"Iz' Workshop
Welcome"
Oh? Welcome, Kuromu!
Who's this?
Um, hello!
I couldn't help but kidnap her
when I saw she's a great shielder newbie.
She's very cute.
Kuromu, you say you kidnapped the girl?
Huh?
Perhaps I'll report you then.
H-Hold your horses!
That was just a figure of speech!
I know that. I'm only joking with you.
It's bad for my heart, so please don't.
And you should know better than
to follow suspicious people!
Um, all right.
I'm not suspicious, you know!
So? What brings you here?
This girl was saying how she
wants a cool great shield,
so I thought I'd introduce her to you at least.
I see. My name is Iz.
As you can see, I'm a crafter.
But I mostly specialize in smithing.
I do synthesis and such, too.
Oh! Um, I'm Maple!
Maple, huh? Why is it you picked a great shield?
Um, I don't want to get hurt,
so I thought I should raise my defense.
I see, I see. Well, vitality gear
sounds right up your alley.
It would take 1,000,000 gold
at the least though.
What do you have on you?
U-Uh, only about 3,000.
That won't quite be enough.
But it'll add up before you know it.
So much for looking cool, I guess.
The "Poison Dragon's Labyrinth" is to the East.
There's all sorts of treasure you can get there.
The monsters are a bit strong though.
Check it out sometime.
If you're lucky, you might be able
to loot some good equipment.
All right! Thank you very much!
Let me add you as a friend
since we know each other now.
That way we can talk anytime.
Thank you so much! Can I get you too, Kuromu?
Sure. I'll split some of
my potions with you, too.
A gift for a fellow great shielder.
"Kuromu" "Remove"
"Iz"          "Remove"
You don't think she'll head to
that dungeon all on her own, do you?
No way, that's absurd.
Finally, it's dungeon time!
It's starting to feel like a real adventure!
I wonder if there's a poison dragon
in the "Poison Dragon's Labyrinth"?
I'm sure I'll be just fine!
I've got poison resist and potions!
Is this the entrance?
Here come slimes!
You're asking for it! Eat this!
I managed that somehow!
"Acquired [Shield Attack]."
I would've preferred
an actual attack skill, but...
Seems like the boss should show up soon.
Is this the poison dragon?!
My shield and sword!
I can't defend that?!
In that case...!
I've gotta time it!
Again!
If I can just keep this up...!
"[Poison Resist - Moderate]
advances to [Poison Resist - Strong]."
It's still not good enough!
Will this work or will I
run out of potions first?!
This is my last potion.
"[Poison Resist - Strong]
advances to [Poison Immunity]."
I did it!
Your attacks are useless on me, poison dragon!
Oh, but I can't exactly attack you either.
What now?
I told you, it's useless on me!
Hey, take this!
Shoot, it doesn't do anything!
It worked!
This is not tasty at all.
Oh, thanks for using your breath!
It gave it some spice and
toned down the pepper flavor!
Woo-hoo! I'm victorious!
"Acquired [Hydra Eater].
[Poison Immunity] advances to [Hydra]."
"Level has increased to 18."
I got 20 status points!
Let's put all those into defense too!
This hydra eater skill lets me use
all of the poison dragon's magic?
In other words, I finally have
my first real attack skill!
And poison is perfect for me!
If I poison my opponent,
I just have to outlast them!
Oh, right! What'd I get?!
"Acquired [Replica of the Dark Night].
Acquired [Armor of the Black Rose].
Acquired [Crescent Moon]."
If it's broken, it gets stronger and
goes back to normal! And it's one of a kind!
Which means I'm the only person to have this!
This is awesome! So cool!
Nice! I'm gonna keep playing
and specialize in defense!
'Cuz I don't wanna get hurt!
"Do you wish to log out?"
Right?! Isn't it awesome?!
Yeah! But I'm not that good
since it's only my second day!
Hey, hurry up and play with me, Risa!
It won't be long now!
Once proficiency tests are over, I can log in!
Oh, but make sure you study
for the tests too, Kaede!
So that you're not the one
banned from games next!
Ah, good point!
I know, right?
Man, seems like she's having fun.
"Risa Shiramine"
"Saw a sick great shielder"
"241. I ran into her today.
In fact, I added her as a friend"
"Saw a sick great shielder"
"241. I ran into her today.
In fact, I added her as a friend"
"242. Huh?"
"241. I ran into her today.
In fact, I added her as a friend"
"242. Huh?"
"243. How?"
"244. I logged in and was wandering around when
she just ran over and talked to me lol"
"245. Shield girl has max social skills"
"246. And?"
"247. She said I had a cool shield so I said I'd
take her to a crafter and she followed me"
"248. Did you form a party?"
"249. Max defense? Any hidden skills?"
"250. Here's what I know atm
Said she picked great shield and is raising defense
Basically, she's a super nice girl We oughta watch over her
My name's Kuromu by the way"
"251. You're Kuromu?!
We've got a top player, boyz!"
"252. There's a famous one among us!"
"253. I'll chime in if I see her around"
"254. Can everyone help keep an eye on her?"
"255. Aye aye!"
"256. Aye aye!"
"257. Aye aye!"
"258. Aye aye!"