Provocation!
And then... Shield Attack!
Shield Attack! Shield Attack!
Acquired skill [Great Shield Mastery IV],
[Evasion], [Parry].
Acquired skill [Savage].
If I eat those, maybe I can
build explosion resist!
Paralyzing Shout!
T-Time to dig in!
Ooh! It's just like candy
that pops in your mouth!
It's not so bad if I close my eyes!
Acquired skill [Bomb Eater].
Acquired skill [Devour].
Devour? That's an unexpected bonus!
I'll stick that one on my shield's skill slot!
I really hope Risa joins me soon!
"Defense and Friends"
I wonder what skill I should aim for next?
Kinda wish I could move faster somehow.
Then again, my plan was
to specialize in defense.
Yo!
Risa!
Morning, Kaede. Get used to the game yet?
Yup! I figured out eating
solves all my problems!
Um, Kaede? What exactly are you playing?
Yeah? An event?
Yup! I heard they're holding
the first event today!
It's a battle royal of players!
Hmm.
Players who get top place earn
a special, limited-edition item!
You know, stuff like that
is impossible to resist!
Oh, yeah? Looks like you're more
into the game than I thought.
Hmm. It's 'cuz when I hear
limited-edition, I've gotta have it.
Special prizes have always been your weak point.
Argh, jeez! I'm totally dying to log in!
That's why I'm gonna crush
tomorrow's proficiency test!
Whoa! All these people are for the event?!
Rawr!
Welcome! It's time to begin
NewWorld Online 's very first event!
It'll last three hours on a map
specially made for today!
By the way, I'm the game's mascot, Dorazou!
For you new players, nice to meet you!
Let's start the countdown!
Three! Two! One! Zero!
Good luck, everyone! Rawr!
This is...?
And here I was scared we'd
be thrown right into battle!
It's not like I can run and catch anyone,
so I'll just wait right here!
Hello there, Missy.
It's a pity, but you'll soon be
a beautiful sacrifice for me.
My name is Christmas Rose!
Also known as the White Rose Knight!
Sure...
Your lovely eyes shall be filled with tears,
but please don't think ill of me.
Now, I attack!
Huh?
Hurray!
Now then, back to drawing!
Even if you can repel the first attack...!
...you'll never dodge the second and third!
We are the Trio! People call us
the Blazing Brothers!
Jet Stream--
Paralyzing Shout.
Shit! How dare you hit us
with a surprise attack!
You scoundrel of a--
You black-armored devil!
Not even our second and third
assassin were enough to--
Phew! Great shields might be
stronger than I thought!
Um, isn't that broken?
She's still going strong even after 100 people!
The shield's status effect is owning them.
Has she not been hit?
How is that shield even legal?
Huh?
What?!
How does a morning star
bounce right off her head?
Whoa, so many people...
Hydra!
She's a monster.
What could her stats possibly be?
She does nothing but counters.
If she can't move fast, doesn't that
mean her agility isn't much?
But her defense is out of this world.
Hey, there's one hour left!
Currently in first place is Payne!
Second is Dread! In third is Maple!
Yippie! I'm in third!
As of now, if you defeat a top three player,
you get 30% of their points!
Their positions will be marked on the map!
Ugh, that's annoying. Really?
Um, in other words, everyone
will be coming to hunt us down?
There she is!
Come on, surround her!
She's mine!
Hmph. She's naught but a newbie.
I'll teach you how fearsome the battlefield is.
Don't hate me for this!
Huh?!
I'm sorry that didn't work.
Deadly Breath!
Shoot, it's poison!
--Crap!
--Run away!
--I need antidote!
Paralyzing Shout!
Rawr! It's over!
Result: There's been no change
in the top three players!
Woo-hoo! I'm so awesome!
Let's kick off the interviews with
our third-place winner, Maple!
Huh? Uh, um...
Anything to say about the event?
Um, uh... I took a pounding but I liked its.
--Did she trip over her tongue?
--She sure did.
Rawr! Congratulations!
Here's a commemorative medal!
Thank you very mush!
For crying out loud! I'm so embarrassed!
Huh? Third place? For real?
Yeah, I'm surprised myself.
Wait a sec. What level are you, Kaede?
I'm level 20.
And you got third? How?
What kind of character are you?
A great shielder focused on defense.
But the thing is... I wonder
if I should tell you about it?
Huh?! What kinda monster did you make?
That's Kaede for you. Always the airhead.
Huh? You think?
Of course I do!
It's gonna be rough trying to pass you up.
B-But if you just do the same thing as me--
Bzzt! You do you and I'll do me.
Then what are you going to do?
If you're being a tank, maybe I'll roll
a wizard with long-range attacks.
Though if I'm gonna party with you,
that's way too conventional.
All right, I've decided!
I'm gonna be a swashbuckler!
A swash... buckler?
Yup! They evade the enemy and
make their attacks do nothing!
Oh, that's cool! But I'm already a shield class.
What's the point of us both defending?
No matter what kind of fight we land in,
we'll take no damage!
Not even a scratch!
Well? Doesn't that sound cool?
Nice! Real nice!
I wanna party with that concept
in mind, so swashbuckler it is!
I'll keep raising my defense more!
Oh, but don't get caught up in that too much.
There's no point if you end up losing.
If it comes to it, it's better to cast down
your shield to live another day.
Yup! Got it!
But, did you get permission
from your mom to play?
Awesome! That means we can play together today!
"Saw a sick great shielder"
"435. Here're Maple's stats from the event
3rd place Deaths: 0 Damage taken: 0 Defeated: 2028"
"436. All hail the walking fortress"
"437. It's like she's simply raising vit or something"
"438. Basically, her defense is so high that all
attacks do nothing. People who hit her get
nailed by a status effect from that mysterious
shield that converts them to MP"
"439. That's insane"
"440. Walking fortress, no. Last boss, yes"
"441. So cute and strong. She's the best"
"442. Think she's strongest 1v1 atm? Besides Payne, obviously"
Ooh! So this is what it's like!
Isn't it great? I was pretty shocked
when I logged in, too!
I figured Kaede-- Oh, shoot!
Is there a monster?
Not that. It's bad form to use real names.
So remember to call me Sally.
My real name in reverse. Sally.
Sally! Sally, it is! Okay, got it!
Now then, first things first!
"Sally"
Oh? You spread your points
in all sorts of stats!
That's normal, you know!
But I decided not to touch vitality,
HP, and MP for the time being.
Why?
Because if I can evade all damage,
I don't really need HP and defense.
And I don't know if I'm using magic yet,
so I'm keeping MP low.
A lack of strength can be
compensated by weapons to a degree.
But since I want to be really fast,
I put most of mine into agility.
You really gave it some thought.
People that aren't meat shields
have a bit more to consider.
I hope I can get some specialized gear soon.
Oh, but that shield of yours, um...
Replica of the Dark Night.
Yeah! Replica of the Dark Night.
It eats up all enemy attacks, right?
But that means you can't acquire skills
which require you to get hit.
Yeah. Which is why I asked about
commissioning a shield
from a crafter I met the other day named Iz.
And she said...
Well, if you're able to bring
me enough materials,
I could make you one for around 1,000,000 gold.
My Replica of the Dark Night is black, so...
...I was thinking I want a white shield next.
In that case, you should try
the underground lake south of the city.
I'll need scales from the white fish
that swim in the lake for materials.
So she said.
Okay! Let's go check out this underground lake!
What? Really?
Of course! Oh, but first, we gotta
buy fishing rods somewhere.
Hey, wait up! You're too fast!
Whoops, sorry.
That's too fast for her?
In that case...
So fast! That's 60 agility for you!
Hold on tight! If we run into monsters,
it's all you!
All right!
Uh-oh! Three wolves straight ahead!
Paralyzing Shout!
Devour!
That's my third-place champ!
Whoa! That was super quick!
You may worship me.
As you wish, Master Sally!
"2 hours later"
Finally got a third.
Ooh, I caught another!
I only got three. Meanwhile,
you're on your 12th...
What did you expect with zero dex?
And I just started playing, so...
...just skinning these little fish
I catch is giving level after level.
What are you at?
Six.
Acquired skill [Fishing].
My first skill is fishing?
So much for calling you the strange one.
You have a bunch of stat points, right?
You're not using 'em?
Maybe once I get some more skills.
'Cuz skills might steer
what fighting style I use.
You sound like such a veteran!
I've played a lot more games than you, at least.
Whoa! I think I hooked a big one!
Gah, come to Mama!
Twenty-five in total, huh?
Well? Is it enough?
Can we go another hour?
Sure!
But I wanna try something out,
so do you care if I free dive?
I'm good at swimming in real life.
Does that matter here?
Yup! If you're a good swimmer
in real life, good at climbing trees,
or even just have good reflexes,
it makes a difference in-game.
It's all a part of player skill.
Be back soon!
Good luck!
I wonder if she's okay?
She's been down there for like ten minutes.
Welcome back! How was it?
Got some! A big haul!
Whoa! You're letting me have all these?
I don't need 'em. You can just
help me out sometime in exchange.
All right! Whenever you need!
Say, Maple...
Hmm?
I found a small cave at the bottom of the lake.
What? You mean...?!
I wonder if I can get down there?
With zero agility, I doubt you can swim.
Guess I'll just have to do it alone.
Right now?
Not quite. Once I raise my level
and swimming skill a bit.
Which is why...
Okay! Let's come back here every day then!
That's how I'll pay you back!
I knew you would say that! That's my Maple!
Oh, please!
How long was I under?
A whole 40 minutes!
Great! I mapped out the area,
so I think I might be ready!
Seeing as how I advanced
to [Swimming X] and [Diving X],
that's probably the highest I can get for now.
It'll get ugly if I can't beat the boss
within 20 minutes.
What if I message you using
the friend function after 20 minutes?
So you know the time.
Nice idea, Maple! Could you?
Leave it to me!
I'm counting on you!
There's air! Lucky me!
Wha...?!
Oh? Now that's what I'm talking about!
Bring it on!
Slash!
Wind Cutter!
Water Ball!
Power Attack!
So much for air.
Will I make it?
She's not answering.
Will she be okay?
Calm down! Focus!
C'mon, let's do this!
Wind Cutter!
Take another!
Final one!
Man, having to play serious
really takes it out of me!
I was hoping I wouldn't have to resort
to my serious mode, but...
Well, I won, so whatever!
Now then, let's have a peek at what's inside!
Open up, baby!
You look totally awesome!
Right?!
You had me worried there!
I thought you lost and got
sent to the starting zone!
I'm sorry!
Now that I've got a bunch of skills,
I can party with you at the next event!
Yeah! Let's enter together!
An announcement!
We'll soon release the second level of content!
In order to reach it, you must
clear an exclusive dungeon!
For further details,
read the announcement on the site!
That's all for now!
What's "second level" mean?
The level we're on right now is level one.
It means there's another world
to come just as big as this one.
You mean there're more
incredible monsters out there?!
Oh, yeah! So exciting!
And swashbuckler's the hardest class to play!
But that's exactly why it fires me up!
You've gone full gamer on me.
Huh?
What? Sally?!
I didn't get any boots,
so I need to go buy some!
Let's get back to the city, Maple!
"Saw a sick great shielder"
"543. It showed Maple was partied
in my friend menu today"
"Saw a sick great shielder"
"543. It showed Maple was partied
in my friend menu today"
"544. I think I saw 'em"
"543. It showed Maple was partied
in my friend menu today"
"544. I think I saw 'em"
"545. What could you tell?"
"546. Don't know her name, but she was with
someone in starting gear and they got along well
so I'm thinking they're friends IRL"
"546. Don't know her name, but she was with
someone in starting gear and they got along well
so I'm thinking they're friends IRL"
"547. But what gear?"
"548. Short sword I think"
"548. Short sword I think""
549. That's unexpected"
"547. But what gear?"
"548. Short sword I think"
"549. That's unexpected"
"550. One would think wizard or archer"
"551. Not a great combo if they're fighting together"
"552. If it's Maple's friend,
maybe she's just a newbie too"
"553. A newbie? Maple's 'just' a newbie"
"552. If it's Maple's friend,
maybe she's just a newbie too"
"553. A newbie? Maple's 'just' a newbie"
"554. That's a good point"
"555. Two Maples grouped up sounds terrifying"
"556. But short sword
means she specced agi, right?"
"555. Two Maples grouped up sounds terrifying"
"556. But short sword
means she specced agi, right?"
"557. Doesn't sound OP to me"
"558. I'm sure we'll hear more about her eventually.
Should be another event soon enough"
"559. True. We can find out her play style then"
"558. I'm sure we'll hear more about her eventually.
Should be another event soon enough"
"559. True. We can find out her play style then"
"560. Can't wait for the next event! I wanna see what she's got!"