"• Changed some explanation texts
and categories of the main menu's tutorial
• [Graphics Settings] now can be tuned between
five levels from the previous three"
"• Skill Revisions
Skill [Devour] has been revised as follows:
Implemented a usage limit.
Can be used a maximum of 10 times per day."
The only things that affects us
are some of the skill fixes.
They limited the number
of times you can use Devour.
Yeah, it's just ten times a day!
Well, I saw it coming.
A shield that eats everything
and gives you MP is way too strong.
Ugh, and then there's the whole thing
about defense-piercing stuff.
They just fixed it so even you take damage now.
I guarantee the developers did it
as a countermeasure to Maple.
And the AI improvements are to make sure
there're no more Maples to come.
It would destroy the game's balance
if everyone got Total Defense.
But, hey. While on one hand
you can take damage now,
doesn't that make it cooler?
All the damage effects coming out
will make you feel even more invincible!
Take this!
Gah! She's not falling no matter what we do!
She's a monster!
It's my turn now.
Hydra!
Well?
That sounds awesome!
"Defense and Reaching Second Level"
Aw, they limited me.
What should we do?
Beat the dungeon to reach Level 2?
That's fine, but...
Since I've always just gone to the lake,
I still haven't seen much of Level 1.
I'd like to check out
some places I haven't seen.
Now that you mention it,
there's quite a few places I haven't been.
Then let's take a look around today!
We might come across something cool in a shop!
Right!
Oh! I think I'll buy this skill!
"Cover Move"?
Yup! If you're ever in a pinch,
I'll be able to shield you right away!
Come again!
Thanks for waiting!
Ooh, a weapon store!
Huh?
Hey, Big Sis! Shouldn't we buy
good weapons to start out with?
Hmm. But if we spend too much,
we won't be able to afford potions later.
They're so cute! They remind me
of back when I was a newbie!
You know, we're still only newbies ourselves.
Oh, right!
Let's buy weapons! Weapons!
Um, well... But...
C'mon, Big Sis! Decide already!
Maple! Still have some money?
Yup! Just what's left over after
paying Iz to make a new shield.
Then, do you wanna see what that's all about?
Welcome! Please have a seat!
You're quite the celebrity now.
Huh? What was that?
It's nothing. Pop!
Whoa, there's so many choices!
Got that right!
"Strawberry Tart" "The sweetness and
texture of shortbread and almonds topped
with strawberries and delicious cream."
Oh! It says this one's seasonal!
"Strawberry Tart" "The sweetness and
texture of shortbread and almonds topped
with strawberries and delicious cream."
I'm picking that!
"Strawberry Tart" "The sweetness and
texture of shortbread and almonds topped
with strawberries and delicious cream."
Then I'll go with this.
I've brought your order!
Ooh! It's just like the real thing!
Please enjoy!
Thank you!
It's chow time!
Delicious!
I bet this would be so pricey in the real world!
And no need to worry about the calories either!
So true!
I wonder when the next event will be?
Wouldn't it be great
if we could pair up together?
Wasn't the first event a battle royal though?
Yeah. And I don't really want
to fight you, either.
They announced a new event not long ago.
Huh?
You're Maple, aren't you?
You got third place last event.
I am, but who are you?
Come on, at least remember my name!
I was second place. Dread.
And I was fifth place. Drag.
I saw you talking with Frederica.
Nice to meet you.
Uh, nice to meet you.
Who's this Frederica?
Remember asking someone where
to fight monsters at? That's her.
Ahh!
You really surprised her good.
She never thought the newbie she
gave advice to would land third place.
Well, I mean... I was just
really lucky, that's all.
Oh, you're right! It says the second event
will start next weekend!
"2nd event begins!!"
Oh, you're right! It says the second event
will start next weekend!
We can party, too!
Thank goodness! We can do it together, Sally!
If we ever cross paths, go easy on us, 'kay?
But Dread placed second
and Drag got fifth, right?
You two must be pretty good!
You know it.
But even with the both of us,
we're really no match for Payne.
Payne?
You don't know Payne?!
He's the one who placed first by a huge margin.
And he reached Level 2 faster
than anyone else. The guy's incredible.
Whoa! To think there's people that awesome!
It sure is a wide world!
Now then, we're off to build up some levels.
And you guys?
There's still places we haven't seen on Level 1,
so we're looking around.
Since we don't really have anywhere in mind,
do you have any suggestions?
Suggestions? Let's see...
If you have time for it,
how about the north forest?
After nightfall, I hear there's a quest
to get the Super Speed skill.
However, it might be high difficulty
for girls like you. What do you say?
We'll do it!
I wonder what he meant by
"it's high difficulty for girls?"
No idea! But when he puts it like that,
it fires me up!
You okay, Sally?
This is a game! This is a game! This is a game!
No worries! I'm good!
You don't seem good to me at all.
Wanna run? Let's run! Let's do it!
Hmm? Oh!
Ooh, what pretty flames!
There's even a green one!
What?!
Over there! Let's go inside!
Is this what he meant by it
being difficult for girls?
I happen to be a girl, too, by the way.
This place is falling apart. Want me to explore?
It's all you.
You've been scared of ghosts since forever.
I'll never complete the quest like this!
Good grief. I wonder if I should just log out?
I don't think they'll bother us
if we stay inside.
Eep! No!
S-Something's there! B-By the table!
The table?
This is...? Looks like there's a basement.
It hurts! It hurts!
He doesn't seem like he's hostile.
Maybe he's the quest giver?
What now?
Since he's saying he's in pain,
maybe I'll fix that.
Potion!
It hurts! It hurts!
Huh? That didn't work.
I could... try healing.
Okay! Go for it!
It hurts!
Heal!
It worked!
But I guess it's not enough
unless you keep at it.
Heal!
This is the last I've got!
Thank you...
Do you think this means he's resting in peace?
Seems that way. Hmm? Oh! Look!
It's the Super Speed skill!
I think we did the quest just now!
It's getting late. I think I'll
log out for today after this.
To be honest, there's somewhere else
I wanted to go though.
What's this place?
Fireball!
A never-ending sunset area.
I hear you can come here anytime
and see this scenery.
Seeing the sunset after nightfall
sure is a strange feeling.
What's that?
It says [Matter Red Mother of Pearl].
Oh, there's another!
A souvenir, maybe? I don't know
if they're used as materials, but...
...maybe they're just to sell?
I think I'll keep it and treasure it!
Yeah. Seems like a waste to sell it.
Today was so much fun!
Tomorrow, it's back to leveling up
and gathering skills.
Let's at least get to Level 2 before the event.
Oh, yeah. What's the other place
that you wanted to go?
Well...
You'll have to look forward to it.
Hey, what gives?! Tell me!
Not happening. Not till Level 2.
Sheesh!
You've done it now!
Take this!
You little...!
This entrance leads to the second level.
All right! Let's head on inside!
Should I go this way?
That's fine!
It's coming!
Leave it to me!
Devour!
Yippie!
There's more coming!
Devour is just way too good!
But I used it four times just now.
I've only got six more uses today!
Whoa! That surprised me!
It's a bear this time?
Maple, defend us!
Right!
Mirage.
Huh? Wha--? What?!
--Where did...?! But I was holding my shield!
--Good luck!
Huh? What was that?
A skill called Mirage. I wanted to
test it out before the event.
Oh?
Let's keep pushing ahead! Let's go!
This is...?
The boss room, probably.
Here it comes!
Okay!
Hydra!
Huh?!
My bet's on the magic circle!
There's gotta be something to it!
I'm gonna go investigate!
Can you keep it off of me?
All right!
Provocation!
Wind Cutter!
That's it! Attack those apples!
Hydra!
All the apples fell off!
Wind Cutter!
Nice! Got him!
Time to pull out the big guns!
Maple!
Looks like she'll be out for a while.
Oh, well! Guess I'll do it alone!
Double Slash!
Fireball!
Is this a bad spot?!
Wind Cutter!
Now you're finished!
Power Attack!
Sh-Shoot! I've gotta attack!
Huh?
I wrapped things up while you slept.
Talk about a total letdown.
Now, now. You'll have a chance
to redeem yourself here on Level 2.
Maple!
Huh?
Oh! Iz!
You came to the second level, too?
Yes, and I already have a shop here.
Is this a friend of yours?
Yeah, this is Sally!
Hello! Maple has told me
all sorts of things about you!
I'm the crafter, Iz. Nice to meet you!
Oh, right! I completed the item
you asked me to make!
Really?!
Thank you so much!
Incredible! So pretty!
I'm rather proud of it myself!
What will you name it?
Snow White! I'll call it Snow White!
"Equipment/Armor" "Skill"
"[Body]" "Armor of the Black Rose".
"[Right Hand]" "Crescent Moon" "Hydra"
That's such a lovely name.
"[Left Hand]" "Snow White"
"[Legs]" "Armor of the Black Rose"
"[Accessories]" "Forest Queen Bee's Ring" "Toughness Ring"
I maxed out its vitality as much as I could.
All so it would better match your playstyle.
Lucky you to get it in time
for the second event.
Yeah!
Now, to celebrate the occasion...
Hmm?
This must be the place you were talking about!
I'm guessing something happens once we sit.
Let's both sit down at the same time then!
Okay!
Ready, go!
What's this?
Whoa! Huh?
"Today's Special
Small Piece of Sky
Please enjoy your meal."
A Small Piece of Sky...
It says, "Please enjoy your meal."
How is it, Maple?
Mmm! It's like eating strawberries,
oranges, and apples all at once!
Hmm. As for this...
Sally! Your hair is glowing!
What?! Your eye color's all weird, too!
Huh?
You think it'll go back to normal?
Probably. Just give it some time.
It's only been one month,
yet it feels like I've come so far.
To think you were so reluctant at first.
Those days are way in the past!
I hope we end up doing well in the second event.
Yeah!
I'm a little nervous,
this being my first event and all.
There're just as many people as last time!
I guess nearly everyone participates in events.
Oh, Kuromu!
Hmm? Ah, it's been a while!
You've got a new shield, huh?
Yeah! I'm planning to save Devour
for when I really need it!
Is this the rumored friend of yours?
Yeah, this is Sally!
Huh? Rumored friend?
Uh, forget it! It's nothing!
Listen! With this event, we'll bolster
the reputation of the Flame Emperors!
I promise you. As long as you're with me,
you will taste only victory!
As members of the Flame Emperors,
hold pride in your heart!
Follow me to the ends of
the Earth and beyond the skies!
Will not our fierce flames scorch
whatever stands in our path?!
Yeah!
Ooh, they're pumped up!
That's a group called the Flame Emperors.
Emperors?
--Kingdom of the Flame Emperors.
Their leader's a powerful Fire Wizard.
--Take heart! We are comrades of the flame!
--Kingdom of the Flame Emperors.
Their leader's a powerful Fire Wizard.
--Take heart! We are comrades of the flame!
--Her name's Mii. She came in fourth,
but she's a force to be reckoned with.
--Harness the flame in your heart!
This event is no one's but ours to conquer!
--Her name's Mii. She came in fourth,
but she's a force to be reckoned with.
--Harness the flame in your heart!
This event is no one's but ours to conquer!
--Oh, Mii? That's a cute name,
but she sounds awesome!
Rawr!
The countdown for the second event
will begin momentarily!
This time, the event is a treasure hunt!
The items to be found are 300 silver medals
scattered around the map!
"2nd Event Explanation Rawr!"
Collect ten of these
for a gold medal!
"2nd Event Explanation Rawr!"
Gold medals can be exchanged for skills
and gear after the event is over!
Oh. It's just like the one I got last time.
The top ten players from last event
already have one gold medal each.
Killing players for medals is A-OK!
You can always search for medals
if that's not for you!
Huh? It wasn't a commemorative medal after all!
I was ninth place, so I got a medal too.
Be careful it's not taken from you.
Right!
Let's start the countdown!
--Five! Four! Three! Two! One!
--Let's do our best!
--Yeah!
--Five! Four! Three! Two! One!
"The 2nd event begins!"
"1. The 2nd event begins!"
"2. Woo!"
"3. Can't wait!"
"1. The 2nd event begins!"
"2. Woo!"
"3. Can't wait!"
"4. Good luck, Maple!"