Whoa! Incredible!
Yeah. It's pretty enough to give me chills.
It's just you and me for one whole week!
It's our own exciting adventure into the wild!
That's just in-game time though.
It's just two hours for real.
Well, I guess that's true.
Anyways, let's aim to get 20 medals between us!
Let's get searching then!
Yeah!
"Defense and Second Event"
Easier said than done.
All we've found is grass and more grass.
Think there's any hints and stuff?
I wonder...
You usually get items from boss drops
or hidden treasures in mazes.
What do you think?
Wha... Huh?! Maple?!
Hey! Sally!
Wh-Where are you hiding?
Down! Down here!
Down?
What's this? A trap?
Sally! Hey!
You all right?! It looks like a big drop!
You take damage?
Oh, I'm totally fine! No damage!
Yeah, of course not.
Hey! I think this tunnel extends even further!
Extends?
Hold on a sec! I'm coming down!
Think it's a hidden dungeon?
Wanna look?
Of course!
Whoa! We found something!
Are you ready? I'll open it.
Yup, okay!
It's empty?
No, there's gotta be something.
Cover Move!
Nice one, Maple!
H-Huh?!
Cover Move!
A knockback?! You okay, Maple?!
"Damage"
Zero damage times anything is still zero!
It's my turn now.
Super Speed!
Double Slash!
Wind Cutter!
Power Attack!
Double Slash!
You sure you wanna be chasing me?
Hydra!
Woo-hoo!
That was rather quick.
Sure was. So? What was that weird move of yours?
You mean Cover Move? Cool, right?
You take double damage using it,
but now I can keep up with you!
"Cover Move"
I bet you're the only one
to use it as a movement skill.
Huh?
I'll open it.
Okay! Go for it!
Yippie! Medals!
And two of them, too! Two medals!
It's all thanks to clumsy Maple,
who managed to fall in a hole!
G-Give me a break!
Nobody could've seen it coming!
But we might go far if we can keep this up!
Yeah!
That's gotta be a teleport circle there.
Let's head back outside.
Okay!
Now then, what to do next?
Let's keep marching ahead.
I doubt it's all grass the whole way
to that huge mountain.
You're right! Let's go!
Yup!
We made it!
This is so weird...
It's snow, but it's not cold at all!
Yeah. Only in games, right?
That's...
Maple! Come ove--
Kuromu?
Oh, it's Maple! Which means
you're, um.... Sally, right?
Yeah.
Ah, we have no intention of fighting.
That's right!
We don't wanna start anything.
I don't wanna fight against
people I know either.
If that's what Maple wants, so be it.
Had you posed a threat,
I would've stamped you out.
Oh, man. You're a scary one.
Still, lots of people think snatching medals
through PvP's the way to go.
Have people been giving you trouble?
Yeah. The first day was a total bust.
We were hoping to hit it hard today
and get back on track, but...
Doesn't look like more than
one party can enter that.
Talk about bad luck.
Figures we'd find it right after you.
Say, um... Sally?
Hmm?
Do you mind if we let them have it instead?
What?
Um, I don't care, but... You're fine with that?
Yeah! I mean, we already got medals yesterday.
And I kinda owe Kuromu one
from back when I started.
All right. If that's what you want.
It's all you, Kuromu! Go on ahead!
Are you sure?
Usually it's first come, first served.
It's fine!
Okay then. Thanks.
No complaints if we're swimming in medals!
I won't complain!
We'll take up your offer then. Let's go!
Yeah!
Goody two-shoes.
You know, doesn't that seem like
it'd be a boss fight?
It just might be. What should we do now?
Climb down the mountain and look somewhere--
What?
I think it opened again.
Why? Can't only a single party go inside?
There're two possibilities.
One's that there's gear or medals
waiting right at the entrance,
and that's all there is to it.
Otherwise, they got completely
obliterated by a powerful monster.
What do you think?
Let's go.
All right. But there's no knowing
what waits inside.
Maple. Be ready to use Devour.
Right.
There's nobody here?
Yeah...
I can tell it's a tough one.
But... I refuse to lose.
Cover!
Maple!
Don't worry, it's non-piercing!
And I can't be using Devour for this either!
The attack pattern changed?
It's time for a counterattack!
Not good!
Cover Move!
Nice timing!
Super Speed!
Cover Move!
Hydra!
How's that?!
It didn't even budge!
No way!
Cover Move!
My Devour!
How many left?!
Five more!
That must be piercing!
Meditation!
Heal!
Let's go!
Mmm!
Concentrate!
Slash!
Got you!
Torrent!
Hydra!
Cover Move!
Cover!
Only one more Devour.
Yeah, I know.
Here it comes!
Cover!
Huh?!
Maple! Over here!
C-Cover Move!
Cover!
Maple!
I'm okay! Do it, Sally!
I won't let the chance
Maple gave me go to waste!
The Mirage skill.
How'd you like the trick up my sleeve?
Hydra!
Woo-hoo! We won!
I'm whipped.
Oh, man. What happened at the end there?
I thought you were done for.
I got a new skill at the very last moment.
Um, is this it?
"[Stout Guardian]:
A Great Shielder exclusive skill
acquired when covering an ally
while having less than 10% HP.
Once a day, you're able to withstand
any attack and survive with 1 HP."
I see...
Y-You're saying we'd be goners
without that?! You're at 1 HP?!
I guess so!
Heal! Heal! Heal! Heal! Heal!
This must be crafting material!
Maple! Come here a sec!
Got it! Cover Move!
Whoa! There're five medals! And... eggs?
Yeah, but I don't think
they're from the boss bird.
The colors and patterns are different.
Can we take these with us?
Seems like it! Which do you want?
I like green, so I'll take this one!
All right. Then I get this one.
"[Monster Egg]
Hatches when it's warmed up.c
[Monster Egg].
Hatches when it's warmed up?
Not much info there.
You think we'll be able to tame them?!
They might follow us like pets!
Pets?! How cool!
Mommy's gonna hatch you soon!
Let's teleport out of here first.
I think we can pick where we wanna go.
Somewhere we don't have to fight would be nice.
I'm with you there.
Ah! Silverwing was beaten!
Silverwing? Wasn't that basically
impossible for players to beat?
We packed it with so many lethal skills,
it's basically an evil prank!
Who?! Who beat it?!
Look here!
Maple?! Seriously?!
Come on! Silverwing should've been impossible!
Unbelievable! Her mobility
should be nonexistent!
The eggs! You're telling me
she ran off with the Monster Eggs?
What's inside?!
The fox and turtle.
Well, it could've been worse.
Argh, unbelievable!
I can't believe Maple got 'em.
Everyone check the skills
she can get using medals!
Make sure she can't combine
any skills in weird ways!
Roger that!
This means more work for us...
Sweet! I got a medal!
Oh, yeah! I almost forgot PvP
was an option, too!
PvP! A true test of one's skill
is battling other players!
It fires me up!
Think we're doing it right?
Oh! Maybe it'll work better if we
warm it with more of our skin!
Whoa! I'll check out the bottom.
You wait here.
Sure! All right!
Um, to Maple: "I just reached the bottom.
Sorry to keep you waiting."
Huh? "Look out below. You might want to move"?
The heck is that?
My eyes! They won't stop spinning!
What'd you do?!
It's Venom Capsule.
It traps the target in a poison
capsule that it can't escape.
I thought it might hold up since it
traps things, so I gave it a shot.
Oh! It'll eat away your HP
without Poison Immunity
so if you go in one, be careful!
I will not go in one!
Hey, Maple. That's...
Hmm? Ooh, a medal!
Maybe it was hidden on the cliff?
Woo-hoo! Check it out, Sally!
Get away from me!
Turtle!
Turtle?
They're adorable!
A ring?
"[Bridge of Bonds].
Equipping this will allow certain
monsters to fight alongside you."
Let's try it on!
That tickles!
Oh! Now we're able to see
the status of these guys!
"Please enter a name."
First, we've gotta give 'em names.
I've got it! I'm naming this one Syrup!
Together, that makes us Maple Syrup!
Then, I'll call you Oboro. How do you like that?
Nice to meet you, Oboro!
It has 15 agility?!
Oh, that's faster than you.
Syrup! Bite!
Oboro! Fire Tail!
Ooh! Level up!
Only level three after all this?
Hmm? I think mine acquired a new skill.
Hibernate and Awaken?
Oh, Syrup did, too!
Hibernate lets them recover inside the ring.
To call it out, you use Awaken. Makes sense!
Now we can always be together!
The desert is no place for Syrup!
And Oboro would get covered in sand.
Ooh! We can take a break over there!
Let's hope it's not some mirage.
You're Maple who placed third?
Y-Yeah. Um, and you are?
Sixth place isn't worth remembering?
What?!
You have one, don't you? A gold medal.
"The 2nd event begins!"
"546. How's the event going for y'all?"
"547. pissed as hell i climbed that
huge mountain and found jack squat"
"548. There was a magic circle in front of the shrine thing that
teleported us to some bird monster that whooped our ass.
If you didn't see anything,
it means someone must have beat it."
"549. wat?"
"550. You're Kuromu, right? If you can't beat it,
no one can. Actually, on second thought..."
"551. i bet i can guess who did"
"552. lol! Well, we did run into another party at
the summit. It was Maple and that friend of hers."
"553. yup. i knew it"
"554. They probably went in right after us.
It's a good chance they're the ones who cleared it."
"555. I bet Maple steamrolled it. You thinking
maybe her friend is a monster too?"
"556. no chance in hell they're both that OP"
"557. You sure about that?
It's Maple's friend after all! lol!"
"558. Good point."
"559. u got me"