You have one, don't you? A gold medal.
Huh?
What?!
Two against one is bad odds.
Think we'll let you escape
after picking a fight?
Super Speed!
Huh?
What?! W-Wait for me!
"Defense and Spoils of War"
How do you have Super Speed?
Perhaps you're underestimating me?
I withdrew because I'm certainly not.
First of Sword - Heat Haze!
What?
Everyone has that reaction the first time.
I can't stop!
M-Maple?!
Huh?
What the--?!
Maple!
Where are we?
What was that about?
Huh?
"Cursed chains linking three people together.
Those bound by the chains share the same
fate--all dying should one of them perish."
"[Binding Chains]"...
If anyone dies while bound
by the chains, everyone does.
And it's unbreakable.
Ugh, that's rough.
Don't worry! I'll protect you no matter what!
Yup. I'm counting on you.
I feel out of place here.
Let's call a truce for now.
That's right! We all have to work together!
Let's all just get along!
My name's Sally.
I guess we're in this together. I'm Kasumi.
Maple here!
We may need to clear the dungeon
in order to break the chains.
Ugh! Depending on the boss, we might be doomed.
Wh-Whoa!
S-Sorry.
Sorry, Maple. You okay?
I'm fine! Hmm?
It's a medal! Yippie!
Uh...
Maple's the one who found it,
so it's fine if Maple keeps it.
But we're all together...
You're surprisingly kind.
But whoever finds something should keep it.
That's right. No hard feelings.
Okay, got it!
I wonder if this is an exploration-type
dungeon since we found a medal?
Hmm. If you ask me, I prefer dungeons where
you beat the boss
and that's all there is to it.
Uh-huh! Me, too!
Yeah. I'm better at fighting anyway.
As long as it's nothing like that big bird!
Big bird?
Oh, well you see...
Two days ago, we fought this boss
with crazy HP and it really took...
Which way do you think we go?
Hmm? What's wrong?
Shh!
I don't think it's a monster.
Huh? Why not?
I tried to check its HP bar,
but it wouldn't come up.
Which means it can't be killed.
It must be a mechanic
you have to stay away from.
Not good.
We'll be trapped!
Hmm?
Super Speed!
What? Wait!
Huh? What's the problem?
Now there's nowhere to run.
Look! There!
But it's way up there...
What do we do?!
Sally, use Leap!
But it's too high!
I've got an idea! Hurry!
Leap!
I knew I wouldn't reach it!
Third of Sword - Lonely Moon!
I'm really glad that worked.
Thanks, Kasumi. I couldn't have
reached it with my Leap alone.
Well, same goes for my Lonely Moon.
It only worked because of your Leap.
Now then...
Oh! Hey, look at that!
Guess this means we cleared it.
We made it in one piece!
Yeah.
Ready? I'm opening it.
Sure.
Oof!
Whoa!
What now?
I have no use for shields.
You can have it, Maple.
Then you take the staff and
spear since we won't use 'em.
Yeah, those are all yours.
Thanks.
The skill scrolls are all the same thing,
so we can split those evenly.
That leaves...
May I, Maple?
Yeah! Of course!
I figured.
Here! This one's yours!
Are you sure?
I already picked one up in the cave,
so now we have one a piece!
Thank you.
Whoa, it's already nighttime outside!
I knew we were in there a while,
but day four's already over?
I'm sorry, Maple. Sally.
Huh?
For challenging you like I did earlier.
If you wish, you can do as you please with--
D-Don't worry about it!
PvP isn't against the rules!
If Maple doesn't mind, I don't either.
I'm not in the mood to fight.
But...
Oh! Let's add each other as friends then!
Since we know each other now!
All right. May we meet again.
Well, good luck with the rest of the event!
Yeah, and you too!
Nine more medals in three days?
Is it doable?
If we target players with medals maybe.
I see...
Well, just keep that in mind
as one of our options.
Yeah! Plus, I think I'll be fine with it
if we can't collect enough!
"Day 5 - Morning"
"Medal"
"Medals"
"Day 5 - Afternoon"
"Medal"
"Medals"
"Day 5 - Afternoon"
"Medal"
"Medals"
"Day 5 - Evening"
"Medal"
"Medals"
"Day 5 - Night"
"Medal"
"Medals"
"Day 6 - Morning"
"Medal"
"Medals"
What has she done?
No! Anything but that!
There! Perfect game!
I lost yet again!
Hmm?
Oh! Welcome back, Sally!
Uh, yeah.
Um, who's this?
I'm Kanade. Maple and I just finished
making a sandcastle together.
That was fun, right?
Right?
Isn't this a bad idea?
Hmm? I think it's fine.
Yeah. Because I'm still only level five.
I'm not proud of it, but I'm weak.
Don't care about medals either.
Oh, really?
I'm happy as long as I have this.
What's that?
Something I got after finishing
a puzzle in an old library.
Took four whole days.
This staff comes with a skill.
Huh? Staff? That cube is...?
That's rare! What skill?
It's called Akashic Records. When it's used...
What? What?
It's a secret!
Aw, shucks!
Of course it is.
Let's play again when the event's over.
Can I add you as a friend, Sally?
Uh, sure!
And as a token of our friendship... Here.
This is?
A book I found that might be
a hint for the event.
"Heart of ancient days.
To gushing well ye shall converge.
In light dim it shan't emerge.
If hero conquers, foe decays.
In tranquil waters ye submerge."
I wonder what it means?
Have you figured it out?
Yeah, right away.
Huh? Tell us!
No way. You've gotta think and figure it out.
The whole fun of puzzles is solving 'em!
At least Kanade told us these ruins
have something to do with it.
Heart of ancient days. To gushing well
ye shall converge. Hmm...
Gushing well... Gushing well...
What if we filled the fountain
with water? With your skill.
But just using Torrent would
only fill one fountain at best.
Torrent isn't all we've got to make water!
Don't tell me you mean...?
Torrent!
Hydra!
Well, I guess it's a liquid of sorts. Hmm?
Did that work?
It's so bright!
It's like we're in the middle of the ocean!
I can't see a boss yet,
but given the situation...
It's coming!
Yeah!
Maple!
Leave it to me!
Huh?
Something's off!
It didn't take any damage!
Huh? Why not?!
We might have to hit the main body itself!
I see...
But you know I can't swim or dive!
I couldn't attack even if I wanted to!
Oh, I know!
Hydra!
Let's make the pretty sea into a poison sea!
Oh, did we beat it?
Well, that was easy, so whatever.
We teleported into water?!
O-Oh, no! I'm drowning!
I'm not? Huh? I can breathe here!
What a neat place!
I wonder if this must be the "tranquil waters"?
Yeah. It's so peaceful and calming here!
Woo-hoo! A medal!
Hey.
Man, Mii from the Flame Emperors
is something else! So charismatic!
Her group's grinding medals like it's their job!
Hey!
But if we're talking solo players,
Payne's where it's at!
He's so used to fighting,
PvP's a piece of cake for him!
Hey, would you guys face reality?
Yet again, Maple just--
Stop! I don't wanna hear!
She beat Sea King this time?
She's out of control, guys!
She's becoming more of a last boss
than the last boss itself!
Just one more day. What are we at?
Two more medals to reach our goal. Seems tough.
Hmm. It's not much time, so we might
end up having to target players.
I guess we don't have a choice.
Maple, listen...
Hmm?
I'll do it alone.
They'll be less cautious with just me
since everyone knows your face.
Um, but...
Meanwhile, I need you to protect our medals.
It would stink if both of us died.
Oh, yeah! Sure! Leave it to me!
I'll leave Oboro to keep watch with you.
Thanks! You be careful!
Well, I'll be back!
Good luck!
It's been so long--I think I'll let loose.
Oh? There's someone.
Let's do this!
You got it, Sis!
Squall Strike!
Double Slash!
Y-You little...!
No way!
Sis!
Shit!
What the--? What are you?!
Goodnight.
Aww, not even a single medal.
Onto the next one!
Come on! Keep it up!
That's it! Bite him good!
I'm done for!
Good work! Good work!
You'll be strong in no time!
I wonder if Sally's doing all right.
Just two from that?
I guess not many people have 'em.
Maybe we just had really good luck?
Now then, let's head back!
Awesome! We hit our goal of 20 medals!
We can spend the rest
of the day just hiding here.
Okay! Oh, yeah!
I raised their levels by fighting
weak enemies in the cave!
Oh, that's sweet!
Thanks!
Kasumi?!
I heard voices coming from in here.
What brings you to this place?
Being the last day and all,
there's widespread PvP.
I thought I'd hide for a while.
In that case, come and hide with us! This way!
O-Okay.
Hydra!
Now no one will step foot in here!
That's true.
Yeah.
Ugh, the hell's this?
No way we're going in. It's a poison cave.
But you know there's gotta be
medals and treasure in there!
We're not high enough for that.
Let's not push our luck.
I wonder what kind of boss is hiding back there?
Woo-hoo! I win again!
Huh, what? How are you so good?
Let's switch! I'll win this time!
Play me if you dare!
Rawr! Rawr! Good work, everyone!
That's the end of the second event!
Players with more than 10 medals
will be given a choice to choose a skill,
Whew! It's over!
so don't anyone log out just yet!
It sure is.
It's finally over.
"Medals Held"
"Medal"
"Medals"
Impressive!
Yup! It's all thanks to grouping with Sally!
But more importantly...
Hmm?
We went all sorts of places!
We met all sorts of people!
We fought big bosses! We even solved a puzzle!
It was a super-duper jam-packed week!
We did so much more than ever before!
In other words?
I had a blast!
"Event Complete"
"Medal"
"Medals"
It's the new Megamorph skill Syrup learned!
Come on, please work!
Psychokinesis!
Turtle!
What?
Yippie! It worked after all!
Um, so... The skill you earned
from gathering all those medals is...
Yeah! Psychokinesis! I wanted to
fly through the sky with Syrup!
Oh... Hold on a sec!
Acid Rain!
"The 2nd event (Part 2)"
"563. Apparently there was a massacre on the 6th night of the event.
Some think it was a roaming monster with short swords and blue
armor. Or maybe it's a player? In any case, tons of people died."
"564. I heard about it from my friend
who was there. He ded."
"565. Short swords and blue armor rings a bell.
You know what comes to mind? Maple's one friend."
"566. Yeah, but people can't just dodge swords
like that. Then again, part of me thinks if
they're friends with Maple, anything's possible."
"567. It'll come kill you in your sleep...
THE NIGHTMARE OF DAY 6!"
"658. One of the medal skills got me thinking.
[Fortress] gives 1.5x VIT so Maple probably
stacked skills like that for insane defense."
"569. I bet she picked that one up too.
It's right up her alley. She's beefing up even more."
"570. Get this. I was in an empty desert and what do I see?
Maple and friends riding on the back of a
gigantic turtle... Through the sky...
Raining acid hellfire everywhere..."
"571. Error. Does not compute."
"572. I dunno either. You know what's weird?
Turtle. Flying. Acid Rain. That's wack."
"573. You know how Maple's
got the nickname 'walking fortress?'
I say we change it to 'flying fortress.'"