I guess I didn't get much sleep last night.
Morning, Kaede!
Oh! Morning, Risa!
It feels like forever since
we've been to school.
Sure does. It's only been
one night in real life though.
Kaede, you best be careful today.
Huh? Why?
Your in-game habits might sneak up on you.
This was the first time you've spent
a week in game, right?
That's a good point.
Okay! I'll be careful!
Kaede... Kaede?
Huh? It's my turn to keep watch?!
Kaede Honjo...
That's why I said to be careful.
Ugh, that was so embarrassing!
Whoa!
Oh, sorry!
Kaede!
Huh?
Never mind! Never mind!
You're just as nimble in real life!
Kaede!
Hmm?
Replica of the Dark Night!
Huh?!
You all right, Kaede?
A break from gaming might be a good idea.
"Defense and Reinforcements"
It's been three days!
Welcome back, Maple!
While you were away, some brand-new
features got added to the game!
Some brand-new features?
Yup! There's a new insect called a Bright Bug
that appears in some zones.
If you can catch one, you earn
the right to buy a guild house!
A guild house?
You know how there're buildings
you can't get into?
You can make one of those your own home!
What?! That's awesome!
We've stayed in lots of inns and huts, but...
...now we can have a home base!
L-Let's go looking for a Bright Bug then!
I thought you'd say that.
Ta-da!
I snatched one while you were on break!
Ooh! That's my Sally!
With all the gold we've got,
we can buy a house whenever!
Awesome! Sally, you're awesome!
Praise me even more!
It sure is tough finding the perfect house.
All the good ones are too
expensive or already taken.
It's 'cuz there're tons of guilds
expanding lately.
Really?
Yeah. For example,
the "Flame Emperors" we saw before.
The guild master Mii's been recruiting
like mad with that charisma of hers,
and they're totally massive now.
And some winners of the first event
formed "Order of the Holy Sword."
Payne's the guild master,
plus Dread and Drag are in it, too.
There's also that Frederica person
Drag was talking about.
By the way, rumor has it that
Payne's already level 60!
Level 60?! And here I am
just barely crossing 30!
I'm about the same.
At this point, Payne's probably
the number one player by a long shot.
Payne, huh?
Hmm?
What's that?
I think it's still up for grabs!
This might be the one!
It kinda reminds me of a hideout.
It's bigger than I thought!
You like it, Maple?
Yeah! I think it's great!
Let's seal the deal!
As of now, this house is officially ours!
Woo-hoo!
Thank goodness! Syrup and Oboro like it, too!
Thing is, don't you think it's
a little big for just us?
This guild house lets us recruit up to
50 people! What should we do?
Let's invite Kasumi and Kanade!
I knew you'd say that.
I'll shoot a message their way.
Thanks so much, you two!
I really appreciate the invite.
Had I known you two made a guild,
I would've been asking to join it.
Good to know. I'm glad you're in.
Huh? It's Kuromu and Iz!
Oh! If it isn't Maple and Sally!
Yo!
You on a date, perhaps?
Give me a break! We were out
collecting materials.
Hmm? Isn't that Kasumi who
placed sixth in the first event?
And that's...
Kanade, a friend of mine!
Nice to meet you.
Same here. It's a pleasure.
Aha! Are you guys thinking
about forming a guild?
Yup! Actually, we just got finished
adding them to ours!
I know! Kuromu and Iz!
Would you like to join, too?!
Us?
Hmm...
If it's you two running the guild,
I would love to try it out!
Me, too. As long as it's okay
with the other members.
Kasumi? Kanade? Well?
Sure. Fine by me.
Thank goodness! You don't mind either, right?
Of course not!
Let's get everyone registered then!
What a lovely house this is!
Agreed! It seems so cozy in here!
Maple's the guild master, right?
M-Me?
Of course! You're the one who picked
the house and members after all!
No complaints here!
Introduce yourself, Guild Master!
Huh? Uh, um...
I guess this makes me your guild master, Maple!
I'm good at poison and defense!
I hope we all get along!
Now all that's left is picking a guild name.
You should decide. You're the guild master.
You think? In that case...
"Maple Tree"! The guild name
will be "Maple Tree"!
So this is the famous flying turtle!
That's right! His name is Syrup!
I can see why you're the talk of the town.
You think we're that famous?
You're super famous! Haven't you noticed?
I guess it just hasn't sunk in yet.
Oh! There's the mine you were talking about, Iz!
Thanks for the lift, Syrup!
We should be able to get
lots of materials in here.
Yeah! We're counting on you, Kanade!
Leave it to me!
Akashic Records gave me [Mining V] to use today.
I'm sure we'll dig up a ton!
But I might not get the same skill tomorrow,
so let's get as much done as we can today.
What a neat item!
Getting a random skill every day
reminds me of a slot machine!
We've got company.
Leave the defense to me!
You two focus on mining!
Got it!
It's all you, Maple!
Double Slash!
Sally's pretty frightening, too.
We don't even have a chance to fight.
Could've left item gathering all to her.
Fireball!
Sweet! Got some!
I wonder if this is enough?
At any rate, this'll be great
to top off the guild fund!
What's that aura of yours?
It's the [Sword Dance] skill.
Dodging attacks gives me bonus strength.
Still can't hold a candle to Maple though.
Huh? Just how high is Maple's vitality anyway?
Why don't you ask her yourself?
I think she'd be happy to tell you!
Time to show what I'm made of!
Can you believe that's a Great Shielder?
I know, right?
It's the same for me.
I may lose sight of what's
normal being in this guild.
Me, too. So much for my respectable play style.
I think we've all been infected by Maple.
Let's do our duty and collect items
for the guild master!
'Cuz we don't wanna disappoint her!
--Yup!
--Yeah!
Without further ado, I'd like to begin
Maple Tree's first guild meeting!
Kuromu tells me he has a suggestion to make!
As everyone knows, the admins
made a new announcement.
It's about the third and fourth events
plus the upcoming third level.
That's a lot of stuff.
With the influx of people,
the admins must think it's worthwhile.
The third event is in one week.
There's gonna be a special monster
to fight and collect what it drops.
It seems like a simple concept.
The real issue is the fourth event...
The guild competition.
That's right. Just like the second event,
in-game time will be sped up.
But people who are busy that day
might not be able to log in.
Maple Tree only has a few members.
Even one of us gone
will hurt our guild's chances.
Here's what I suggest: We can address that
by recruiting more members.
You're right. It's worth thinking about.
The more comrades, the better.
As the guild crafter,
I'm not too swamped with work either.
In that case, let's go ahead
with Kuromu's suggestion!
I know we've gotta find more members,
but where do we even start?
When it comes down to it,
that's for you to decide.
Ugh, such responsibility!
There's the bulletin board. People use it
to recruit for guilds and parties.
"Guild Recruitment                "Guild Recruitment
Damage Spec Needed"            Healers Wanted"
"Party Recruitment
We want your damage!"
"Party Recruitment          "Party Recruitment
DPS only plz!"      Players needed for item hunt"
"Party Recruitment
Melee dps wanted!"
"Guild Recruitment
Everyone welcome to join"
Looks like damage is in popular demand.
That's always exciting!
"Guild Recruitment
We want high lvl tanks!"
Hmm. I'm not seeing anyone promising for us.
Might be tough recruiting on the second level.
Wanna check out the first level?
I doubt there's any strong players
still chilling down there.
It's okay if they're not!
As long as they're fun!
"Party Recruitment
DPS only plz!"
Shall we go then? We'll probably have
more luck than here.
Whoa, it's been a while!
We haven't had much need to come back.
Nostalgic, huh?
I'll go check around!
Okay!
Yet another party said they don't want us.
--Maybe maxing out was a bad idea.
--Hmm?
Cheer up, Big Sis! Once we get
stronger, someone will want us!
It's those girls from before...
But it's so hard to level
with both of us maxed out!
Yeah... But we've already come this far,
so it's a waste to start over.
I know, but what else can we do?
Um, do you have a minute?
What is it?
Um...
Just so you know, we don't have any rare items!
Uh, no, no, no! I don't wanna fight you
for your stuff or anything! Um...
Um... Oh, yeah! Would you like
to party... Party?
No, my guild! Wanna join my guild?
--Huh?
Um, thanks for offering, but we're
pretty weak and still only beginners.
It's fine, it's fine! I'm the guild master!
We have room for you!
Maple? Who are those two?
These are some girls I scouted!
Scouted?
I don't mind if that's who you want.
But what do you two think?
What should we do, Yui?
Hmm...
How about we sit down somewhere and talk?
Isn't that cafe we went to nearby?
Oh, yeah! Let's go there!
Well? Let's get to know
each other over some tea.
Should we go?
Yeah.
It's yummy!
What a nice place this is.
Right? It's our treat today,
so eat as much as you like!
I'm Sally, and this is Maple.
What about you?
I'm Yui. My big sister here is--
It's May.
Um, both of you maxed something out, right?
Yeah. Me and my sister maxed out attack.
But our agility is zero and we walk so slow.
I get that! Zero agility
is so inconvenient, right?
Except in real life, we're both on
the small side and not very strong.
Kinda reminds me of Maple.
You're not caught up in min-maxing
what works the best.
That's true.
Are you maxed out, too, Maple?
That's right! Vitality all the way!
She's famous on the second level.
I'm not so sure about that.
Then maxing out can be successful after all!
You might not wanna use Maple
as a reference point.
Well, Sally? Can we add them in?
Yeah. Sounds good!
Most of the flaws with maxing strength
vanish with Maple in the mix.
If they level up before the event,
it'll work out!
So it all comes down to how they feel about it!
We would love to.
Sorry for shocking you,
but this way is much faster!
Speaking of which, I've heard rumors
about a player that flies on a turtle.
You'll have to get used to this kind of stuff.
This is just the tip of the iceberg
of Maple's wackiness.
This place takes me back!
I got flattened the last time though!
Since we need you to come to the second level,
we're gonna form a group and beat the boss.
R-Right.
I don't know if we can.
The two of us aren't strong at all.
I'm sorry if we get wiped.
Oh, you've got nothing to worry about!
I'll take care of it, so just take a seat.
Okay! Sally knows what to do
since she beat it before.
W-Will Sally be all right?
You're up against a boss!
It's fine, it's fine! Just watch!
Oboro!
Oboro, Shadow Clone!
Oboro! Look at all the things you can do!
Sally's way too good! How does she dodge that?!
And she's using clones!
Why is she blue?
That would be Sally's [Sword Dance] skill!
Tsk! It recovered! What a pain!
Maple!
It's okay!
Fireball!
Wind Cutter!
Double Slash!
There! All done.
Sh-She really beat it by herself.
Maple was amazing, too!
It's too early to get excited.
Our guild is full of awesome people.
I'm wondering if it's really all right
for us to join a guild like yours.
It's totally fine!
You'll get strong in no time, too!
So there you have it!
Please welcome our newest
guild members, May and Yui!
It's nice to meet you.
To think the two of you both maxed strength...
That's Maple for you. She always
picks out the strange ones.
The guild competition is still a ways off.
Starting tomorrow, let's pile the levels on you!
Let me know if there's anything
I can do to help!
Sure! Thank you very much!
We'll do our best!
--Huh?
--What?
Oops! So sorry!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
Um, you don't have to worry about that! Okay?
Whoa. That's max strength for you.
Such destructive power.
May and Yui, huh?
It's true... They do remind me
of Maple quite a bit.
What if those two end up becoming just like her?
Hmm? What's up, Sally?
Hmm? Oh, it's nothing!
Just thinking how much fun
this might turn out to be!
I know! I can't wait!
"[NWO] The Watchers of Fortress Maple thread
(Part 1) [Flying Fortress]"
"125. Yo!"
"[NWO] The Watchers of Fortress Maple thread
(Part 1) [Flying Fortress]"
"125. Yo!"
"126. I just wanna say I joined Maple's guild."
"127. I'm so jealous! You shithead!"
"125. Yo!"
"126. I just wanna say I joined Maple's guild."
"127. I'm so jealous! You shithead!"
"128. What's the scoop? You gotta know something."
"129. Tell us as much as you're cool with."
"130. Feels wrong since I'm one of them now."
"128. What's the scoop? You gotta know something."
"129. Tell us as much as you're cool with."
"130. Feels wrong since I'm one of them now."
"131. C'mon! Out with it, bro!"
"132. Fine! The rumors about Risa dodging like
crazy are true. She doesn't even use a skill
either. It's just pure, insane reflexes.
Also, she has some sort of aura now."
"133. And who called it? I did! The untouchable
blue monster from the second event was Risa!"
"134. Risa is evolving. Risa learned Aura."
"133. And who called it? I did! The untouchable
blue monster from the second event was Risa!"
"134. Risa is evolving. Risa learned Aura."
"135. Any other new members besides you?"
"136. May and Yui. They've maxed attack,
which might be cool once they're better."
"137. Wait, so they maxed out too?"
"136. May and Yui. They've maxed attack,
which might be cool once they're better."
"137. Wait, so they maxed out too?"
"138. Your guild is full of lunatics."
"139. Well, Yui and May are only beginners,
so it'll be a while until they can pitch in."
"140. Cool. Keep us in the loop."
"141. Good luck. You're gonna need it."
"142. Thanks. So true. If I don't step up my game,
I'll just be a shitty version of Maple! lol"