May, Yui! I need you guys to attack it!
Got it!
Great! Hydra!
Woo-hoo!
Did a new magic circle appear
'cuz it's your second time through?
Yup! This one takes you back to the city...
...and this one back to the entrance!
Come on! Let's go back and do it again!
Okay!
"Defense and Upgrades"
A time trial?
Yeah! Because it gets pretty boring
doing the same thing every time.
I was thinking we should see
how fast we can clear it!
The shorter it takes, the quicker
we'll be able to level up, but...
How's that gonna work when
all three of us have zero agility?
I've got an idea! Drink this!
What's this?
A poison resist potion?
See!? Having zero agility
doesn't matter anymore!
Y-Yeah, but...!
My head's spinning!
Go for it, you two!
R-Right!
Hurry up with Hydra!
This time we're doing it different!
Huh? We won?
Quick, through the magic circle!
Three minutes two seconds! So close!
We almost broke three minutes!
Um, Maple?
How did you just...?
A skill called [Devour].
We beat the boss way faster, right?
Yeah...
Thing is, I can only use it ten times a day.
Let's try to beat our time
with the other nine I've got left!
A-All right.
I'll try not to get dizzy!
In that case, let's go!
Yay!
As of today, May and Yui have
officially reached level 20!
That's wonderful! You guys worked hard!
You sure gained a lot in one day!
Thank you!
But there's more than just that!
Did something else happen?
Our last run cleared it faster
than 2:30. And so...
...we got this skill!
[Conqueror] and [Destroyer]?
"Conqueror"
"Having this skill gives the user 2x STR.
[VIT], [AGI], [INT] require 3x the points to increase."
Conqueror gives the user twice the strength!
"Destroyer"
"Allows two-handed weapons
to be equipped in one hand."
Conqueror gives the user twice the strength!
To get it, you have to beat the boss
a number of times within a time frame.
Destroyer lets you take weapons
that are usually two handed...
...and equip them as one-handed weapons!
You need to clear a dungeon
within a certain time to get it!
Huh? You're saying you guys have
two times the strength now?
And you can hold two-handed weapons
in one hand now?!
Yup!
And it's perfect for them
'cuz they're maxing out attack!
Uh, you guys awake?
It's just, being with you and all, I figured
they'd find some weird skills, but...
This blows my expectations away.
Now May and Yui have some legit firepower.
Firepower!
You think so?!
Sounds like you need new weapons!
Hold on a sec. The best thing
I've got on hand is...
This! Crystal Hammer!
"Crystal Hammer"
"[STR +25] [Size Boost]" "Increases the target's size.
Lasts 30 seconds. 1-minute cooldown."
Awesome!
You sure we can have these?
Of course! I'd love if you used them!
Thank you so much!
I hope we can help you guys out!
Hey, guys! Good morning!
Huh? It's just you two?
Everyone else left already.
Kanade's at the library.
There's apparently some quest
that needed doing today.
Kasumi's out collecting materials
for me as a favor.
Sally's with May and Yui
hunting monsters and such.
She wanted to teach them how to
dodge attacks even with low agility.
Yeah? Everyone's going all out!
I was just about to leave as well.
Unless I get new skills or something,
I feel like my worth will dive-bomb.
Oh! In that case...!
Hmm?
Never thought she'd lend me her little partner.
Sure, I'm grateful, but your master
trusts people a bit too much.
If I felt like it, I could easily
steal you and ditch the guild.
Turtle!
No, no, no. I'm not really going to, all right?
Still, there're a lot of jerks in the world.
Being a game veteran,
I've gotta watch over those guys.
I just want 'em to enjoy the game, that's all.
Turtle!
Hmm?
A hidden dungeon?
Size Boost!
Whoa! Just one attack...!
We really can hold two!
But we've gotta work on
your evasion though!
You're awesome, Sally!
You cut it so close!
Even with low agility, you can dodge
attacks if you see 'em coming.
I'll teach you everything I know!
Okay!
Now for the last piece.
Is it another new staff?
It's the same type as the one I've got.
Huh? Whoa...
They merged into one!
Let's try it out.
Spell Stash!
Whoa! That's pretty cool!
I can store spells or skills
that take MP in the Spell Stash,
and use them whenever I want!
Should I give it a shot?
Store Fireball in the Spell Stash!
It takes 30 minutes to be stored, huh?
Guess I'll just wait.
Oh?
Hmm, hmm. It takes twice the MP.
Fireball!
That time didn't take MP
and it's instant cast, too.
Basically, you pay MP in advance
to use a skill instantly.
Which means if I use Akashic Records,
I can store any skill I get
as long as it takes MP!
I am such a lucky duck!
If I botch this attack, it'll run away.
Skill [Shear]!
Success.
Having said that, I only got one.
Hmm?
"Maple"       "Sure could use your sword."
"I'd appreciate it if you"
"came quickly."
Maple's here, too?
U-Um, Maple?
Thank goodness you came!
What are you doing?
I was thinking I'd help collect materials...
...and I learned a new skill
while playing with all the sheep!
Uh, I get the picture. Just a sec...
Shear!
You saved me!
What skill did you get exactly?
Um, it's called [Wooly]!
Watch, I'll do it again!
Wooly!
Now we can collect as much
sheep wool as we want!
And I thought of this, too!
If I combine it with poison magic...
...enemies can't get close! Isn't it smart?!
But I can't get close either now.
Huh? Wha...? Help me!
I can't get rid of this on my own!
Someone's gotta clip all this fur!
Sorry, but I can't till the poison ends.
You're kidding!
My goodness. I could just watch this forever.
Shield Attack!
So this dungeon's called "Grave of the Dead"?
In order to enter, you have to have died
and revived at least four times. Hmm.
I'm pretty much the top player
as far as dying goes.
But hey, mastering
the great shield is a tough job.
"Spirit Cannon"
"Can only be used with [Megamorph].
A long-range frontal attack."
Turtle!
"Spirit Cannon"
"Can only be used with [Megamorph].
A long-range frontal attack."
Hmm? Did you learn a skill?
"Mother Nature"
"Calls upon earth, vine,
and tree to attack and defend."
Hmm? Did you learn a skill?
"Mother Nature"
"Calls upon earth, vine,
and tree to attack and defend."
Turtle!
Oh? Those seem quite powerful.
I should get something for clearing it, too.
"One-of-a-kind equipment awarded to the first
player who defeats a dungeon boss
solo on their first encounter."
"One-of-a-kind equipment awarded to the first
player who defeats a dungeon boss
solo on their first encounter."
"Unique Series"...
It's good! It'd be perfect if it didn't
seem like it's gonna curse me.
Maybe it's about time I start
getting a little crazy myself.
Turtle!
Everyone's out leveling today!
I wonder what I should do?
It's been a while since I went on my own,
so let's go somewhere new today!
Huh?
You okay?
I'm sorry I can't do anything for you.
What's that? An NPC that
gives out a quest maybe?
--Um...!
--Uh...
Are you a knight?
Uh, er... I dunno?
Miss Knight! Please, help my daughter!
We have no way to repay you,
but please! Please!
"Quest [Benevolent Knight]"
I knew it.
I'd feel awful if I didn't, so...
Thank you so much!
My daughter needs medicine,
but I don't think I can get there myself!
I can guide you there, so take me with you!
All right! I can be your escort!
To complete this, the mother has to reach
the destination without dying.
Should we start by heading outside the city?
Yes! The Spring of Purification
is to the northwest!
If you could just take me there...
This forest is full of dreadful monsters.
Please be careful, Miss Knight!
All right!
I get the feeling it won't
matter much if we're flying.
Thank you so much!
Now I can save my daughter!
Thank goodness! Let's head back!
Whoa!
Thank you for protecting me!
I was so close to dying back there!
Huh? What's wrong?!
If not for you, those dreadful monsters
would've gotten me for sure!
How can I ever repay you?!
Ah, I get it. Escaping the forest
was supposed to be kinda difficult.
That's why her dialogue seems so weird.
You risked your life for strangers like us!
You're such an incredibly kind knight!
Uh, I feel like I should apologize.
Well?
Yeah. It's a little better.
But your cough is still awful.
Dear me, what to do?
Hmm?
"Quest [Benevolent Knight 2]"
Oh, I see. This must be
one of those quest chains.
Miss Knight! You'll help us again?!
I can't just give up now. What do we do next?
I've heard there's a ring
that heals the body,
and it's found near a large
city in a distant land.
If you could just find that for me...
A large city? Could she mean
the city on the First Level?
"Acquired [Forest Queen Bee's Ring]."
Which means the ring might be...
Miss Knight! You actually found it!
So fast!
Oh! How could I ever thank you enough?!
Huh? That's all there is to it?
I can't imagine all the trouble
you went through to get this!
Thank you so much!
Uh, I really didn't do anything.
Let's put this on your finger.
Huh? What's wrong?!
Oh, no! What happened to her?!
Huh? Oh... Go figure, right?
"Quest [Benevolent Knight 3]"
Miss Knight! You're going to
lend us your help again?!
Well, since I've come this far...
What should we do now?
I believe she went to the Temple of Darkness.
There she is!
Careful!
Cover Move! Cover!
Hydra!
What now? I can't use Venom Capsule
while protecting the mother!
And there're too many to Devour!
Huh? What?
The holy water she drank
must have taken effect!
You mean from that spring?
Yes!
My daughter must have been
possessed by a demon!
Um, let's figure this out.
Regardless if you fail the first quest or not,
maybe you get the next quest.
But since I finished it no problem,
the girl could drink the holy water,
so the ghosts all got wiped out.
How could I possibly thank you enough?
But now my daughter won't open her eyes!
I haven't the slightest idea what to do!
In other words, I bet there's
another quest coming up.
"Begin quest [Benevolent Knight 4].
OR
Begin extra quest [Loving Sacrifice]."
Extra quest? Loving Sacrifice?
"Benevolent Knight 4" "Loving Sacrifice"
A church in ruins...?
There's an old church in the south forest.
It might mean that one!
All right, wait here!
Hmm?
What's this?
"Long ago, an archangel who fought monsters had
their wing stolen and turned into a monster
themselves. This is a piece of their stolen
wing. Return it to revive the archangel."
Miss Knight, what's that?
I don't know, but I'll try it out!
Whoa!
Miss Knight! What's this?!
Thank you. I was protecting
this child from monsters,
but I had my power stolen and
was unable to leave the child.
R-Right...
It almost cost this poor child their life.
As thanks, I will bestow you
with a part of my power.
Huh? Mom?
That was a weird way to end things,
but I guess this means case closed.
"Acquired skill [Loving Sacrifice]."
Acquired skill [Loving Sacrifice].
What?
Hey, Iz! Do you think you could
make me a new set of gear?!
Sure, but...
Ta-da!
Ooh! That's the new gear Iz made for you?
It looks great on you!
It's like a whole new you!
You look lovely, Maple!
So pretty!
There's more to it than this, right?
You could've just showed off
your new gear at the guild house.
You know me so well!
Actually, I wanted everyone
to see a new skill of mine!
A new skill?
Loving Sacrifice!
I had the same sort of reaction.
Here they come!
What's going on?
This is her new skill.
Every party member within [Loving Sacrifice]
is protected by [Cover].
Um, then as long as we're
standing in this light,
we essentially have
the same defense as Maple?
Yup! I take a good hit of HP initially though!
This is way overpowered.
As long as Maple's alive, it means
the rest of us are practically invincible.
Plus, downing Maple herself
is a feat that's next to impossible.
As long as we're with Maple...
...you're saying we're kinda immortal?
By the way, what's your vitality at?
Um, I'm not sure.
I know I went over 1,000 though.
Maple is truly our guardian angel!
Now then, about the guild competition...
Besides Flame Emperors,
there's another guild that concerns me.
Maple Tree.
Maple's guild, right?
Never thought that one lost newbie
would end up being this strong.
Isn't that blue-armored girl from
the second event in Maple Tree, too?
She seems pretty dangerous.
It all depends what the event is.
We can crush 'em with our resources.
At worst, Payne can always do something.
Everyone in our guild is powerful
in their own right.
We won't have problems if we get poison resist.
What scares me most is the unknown.
We need to research our enemy.
You're such a worry-wart.
There's a third event scheduled
before the guild competition.
Which is why we'll keep an eye
on Maple and her Maple Tree...
...and see how they fare.
"[NWO] The Watchers of Fortress Maple thread
(Part 1) [Flying Fortress]"
"158. Guys, Maple is an angel."
"[NWO] The Watchers of Fortress Maple thread
(Part 1) [Flying Fortress]"
"158. Guys, Maple is an angel."
"159. Yeah, we all know."
"160. u must be new here"
"161. Maple's our angel and always will be."
"162. Lemme try this again. Maple got a skill
that turns her into a blue-eyed blonde-haired
angel with halo, wings, and the whole shebang."
"162. Lemme try this again. Maple got a skill
that turns her into a blue-eyed blonde-haired
angel with halo, wings, and the whole shebang."
"163. Wat?"
"164. HOW?! Where did she get that skill?!"
"165. No clue. She always ends up finding weird
skills the second I take my eyes off her."
"166. SHE'S ALREADY GONE
2ND FORM ON US?!"
"167. You know she'll have a final 3rd form tho"
"168. I'd put money on her having a 4th."
"169. Can we just make her last boss
already and be done with it?"
"170. Dude, no. We've already got one of those."
"171. You mean the only player
in the whole game who's over 60?"
"170. Dude, no. We've already got one of those."
"171. You mean the only player
in the whole game who's over 60?"
"172. Payne, right?"
"173. Question is, who wins in a fight?
The player that's a high-level monster or
the player that's got crazy monster skills?"