It's finally time for the third event?!
I hope this cowvent is fun!
What's that again? "Cowvent"?
It's an event to defeat cows and collect
their bells, right? So, cowvent!
I hear the more bells we get,
the better the reward.
Seems pretty normal as far as events go.
Listen up! Attention, please!
Thanks to all the wool everyone
gathered, I'm finally done!
Ta-da!
It's adorable!
Yeah! Not to mention warm!
There's a bonus on event drops
depending on how much wool you use!
--B-But...
--Hmm?
This is simply too cute!
C-Couldn't you have picked out
a different design or something?
I'm afraid not!
'Cuz I wanted to see you guys
dressed in fluffy gear!
You're looking good, Kanade!
This is nice! Thanks, Iz! I really like it!
We're gonna use the hammers Iz gave us...
...and lay waste to the cows!
--Yay!
--Everyone sure is cute....
--Turtle... Turtle! Turtle!
--Hmm?
Tur... tle?
Hydra!
"Cow"
That's one for me!
"Defense and Third Event"
It sure is a pain searching
for cows with low agility!
"Cow"
Whew! I'm off to a pretty good start.
Hmm? From Sally? Let's see...
"To be honest, I'm a little
concerned about Maple."
"Yeah. Maple's not exactly suited
for this kind of event."
--"I'm worried she'll do something weird
if she's all on her own."
--Wait up, cow! It's too fast!
--Come back, cow!
In that case, let's all send Maple
some advice for the event!
--Agreed!
That was fast!
Ugh! There's so much competition! Hmm?
It's hard to collect 'em,
but stay focused and do your best!
It's tough with all the people in the fields.
Just relax and have fun.
There's too big a crowd to get much done.
Still, keep at it till the cows come home!
Mm-hmm, I see!
In that case...!
Thanks for the advice, everyone!
I'll do my best!
All right! Let's head for that mountain!
"Cow"
Woo-hoo! My plan worked!
I can rack 'em up if no one else is around!
"Cow"
--Turtle... Turtle... Turtle... Turtle...
--Huh? Syrup? Wait up!
M-My head's spinning!
Turtle?
I'm okay, but thanks for your concern!
H-Huh?! Since when did all
my devours get used up?!
Did I do that? I'm so sorry!
I'm so sorry! I'm so...
Huh?
I wonder how this ended up here?
Hmm? Isn't that...?
I knew it! It's the church from before!
I was so caught up in the quest,
I never explored this place.
Is there anything here?
Huh? Wh-What?!
Hmm?
So my meal has come?
Huh? Meal?
Once I defeat you, I will consume your body...
...and feast upon your power!
Well, I'll eat you, too!
That doesn't do a thing! Huh?
Wh-What's this?!
Whoa! There's more!
Fine! In that case...!
Wooly!
You're not so scary if I'm in here!
Um, these chains apply... [Hex]?
Never heard of that status effect. Anyways...!
You're up, Syrup! [Awaken]! And [Megamorph]!
Turtle!
Topped with [Psychokinesis]!
Oh, yeah! Syrup, let's try the new skill
of yours! [Mother Nature]!
Turtle!
Whoa, awesome!
Next up, gimme a [Spirit Cannon]!
Tur...
...tle!
--...tle!
--That's it, Syrup! Give 'em hell!
C-Curse you!
Unforgivable!
--...tle!
--What?
Geh! Th-That's disgusting!
Eep! I'm on fire now?!
"Cow"
I wonder how Maple's doing?
Well, I'm sure she's not anywhere too crazy.
It's cramped! And dark!
Am I in its belly?
Whoa! My armor's melting!
I'm not taking damage though,
so I guess I'll just beat it and escape!
It's so sour! So tangy! And so...!
So bitter!
And that's that! Burp!
Turtle!
I'm back! Huh?
"Seeping Chaos"
"Acquired skill [Predator],
[Seeping Chaos], [Atrocity]."
Woo-hoo! I got new skills!
It's called [Seeping Chaos], huh?
That sounds pretty cool!
I'll throw that on my armor set!
The others will be so surprised!
Nice work! Let's do this!
Yeah!
Heal!
Thanks so much, Misery!
Of course. Good work.
"Cow"
You and your traps are impressive
as always, Markus.
I don't know about that.
All I did was set a few traps.
She, on the other hand...
[Flame]!
"Cow"
The mission was a success!
It's all thanks to your hard work and bravery!
--You've put your faith in me, followed me,
and for that, I thank you!
--She really has a presence when she speaks.
--You've put your faith in me, followed me,
and for that, I thank you!
--No wonder people follow her.
--I'm glad to call you my comrades
and proud to fight beside you!
--Indeed. I suppose that's what
you'd call her charisma.
--I'm glad to call you my comrades
and proud to fight beside you!
--Long live Mii!
--We'll follow you anywhere!
--Leader!
So it ended without a hitch?
Yeah. Being the third time and all,
we've hit our stride.
We're opening up Level 3 now, right?
So much work! I wanna lie in my bath...
What about "her"?
"Her," huh?
We've gotta keep a close watch on Maple.
She's got her wacky blimp, her [Wooly],
she ate Hydra, became an angel...
and now a demon?!
What do you guys think?
She can't possibly defy logic again, can she?
Yeah. There's just no way.
If it was that easy to get powerful,
we'd be in a real pickle!
I'm sure it'll be fine!
--Maybe...
Good work, everyone!
"Holy Sword" and "Flame Emperors."
It's no surprise they're at the top.
And I heard both of 'em went to Level 3 already.
It just opened, too. Talk about fast.
Sorry, guys. I didn't contribute
very much this time.
But still, you got a reward, right?
Oh, yeah! I got the [Counter] skill!
You helped out plenty!
This event was geared towards
people with high agility!
"Cow"
Besides, there's no need to fret.
We all gathered enough to earn
a fantastic guild reward.
We all did...
...the best we could!
That gives everyone in the guild
three percent more strength, right?
It'll stack up before you know it.
It doesn't really matter to Maple, though.
Zero times anything is still zero.
That's what you think!
Did you do something crazy again?
Come on! Onward to Level 3!
We've gotta beat this guy to reach Level 3?
Yeah.
It doesn't look like some pushover either.
Um, it's all you.
Leave it to me!
Shall we get started?
[Predator]!
Wha...?
[Seeping Chaos]!
I see. So that's how it is...
She has more appendages every time I see her.
Let's not fool ourselves.
She's basically a monster.
That's fine... As long as she's a friend.
Watching Maple never gets old!
You're amazing, Maple!
And now for the finisher! [Atrocity]!
This is harder to control than I thought!
Um, is that you in there, Maple?
Yup! Hold on a sec!
What... was that?
Um, it's called [Atrocity]!
"Atrocity"
"Maximum HP set to 1,000."
"[STR], [AGI] increased by 50."
Um, it's called [Atrocity]!
"When HP reaches 0, skill is canceled
and user returns to original state."
It gives 50 strength and agility,
and though equipment effects don't work,
"Can only be used once per in-game day.
While in use, equipment effects are ignored."
you get 1,000 HP, and
even if it runs out, you go back to normal!
Is she done being human then?
Yeah, she's given up. Entirely.
At this point, there's no use
trying to make sense of Maple.
Mm-hmm.
Now I can protect everyone
even better than before!
So this is Level 3!
It feels completely different
than Levels 1 and 2!
How cool! It's a machine world!
Let's go separate ways and check out
what kind of zones are around.
All split up?
We don't know much since we just got here.
Lets us cover more area.
All right. We'll meet up in two hours.
Roger!
Whoa! There's so much stuff!
Huh?!
A-Are you okay?!
Water...
Could you please spare some?
And food, possibly?
Sure! Here!
Thank you.
As a token of thanks, I'll tell you a story.
Huh? O-Okay!
Think it's a quest or something?
Turtle!
In the center of this city
towers a grand building.
That is where the Machine God lives.
He's the one who created our
flying machines and such.
But not a single person understands
how any of his machines work.
People have torn them apart to learn,
but there's nothing at all inside.
Not even a single screw, gear,
or spring to speak of.
Th-That sounds kinda scary in a way!
The real story starts now.
You see, the Second Generation
is the one there now.
The Second Generation?
Yeah. This city was once brimming
with normal machines.
To us, who knew nothing of machines,
the First bestowed us hopes and dreams.
But one day, something happened
while I was out of town.
When I saw a pale light erupting
from the city, I hurried back at once.
But the city was filled with all-new machines,
and everyone had completely
forgotten the First.
What's more, the old machines
were nowhere to be found.
That's the end of my story.
Nobody remembers the First anymore.
Hmm. Do you think it means
the Second hates the First then?
That's the end of my story.
Nobody remembers the First anymore.
I guess that's all he'll say for the quest.
Thanks for telling me that wonderful story!
Think it's a rare quest or something?
I should run it by Sally and the others... Huh?!
Watch where you're flying
that turtle! Turtle...?!
I'm sorry!
Let's go to a less-crowded area, Syrup!
Turtle!
Look at all this fog! Um...
Huh? Where are we?!
What?!
[Atrocity]!
Thought I was dead there!
Where is this anyways?
"Graveyard of Dreams"
Graveyard of Dreams?
Syrup! Thank goodness!
Whoa!
I am... king of machines.
Of great wisdom... and faraway dreams.
Huh? I think I started something!
I am... king. A once upon... king.
He who was weeded out.
Wh-What happened?
--I am the... king of junk.
--Whoa!
He who sleeps among scrap.
Making dreams and miracles... into rubbish.
I'll make you... rubbish, too.
Are you broken?
Let's knock some sense into you!
Syrup! [Mother Nature]!
Turtle!
This glowing part's the problem!
[Seeping Chaos]!
In this moment my thoughts are mine...
...I bestow you this, brave soul...
Using my power, defeat he...
who I... once was.
Huh?
Put me... to... sleep.
B-Bestow me what?! Hold up!
It is futile.
Wh-What?!
Huh?!
Shoot!
What the heck's that?!
Huh?
[Machine God]?
All right!
[Machine God]!
[Deploy Armaments]!
[Commence Attack]!
Take this!
Whew!
Huh?
Wha...?!
What the heck is this?!
"[NWO] Third Level Released!!"
"129. Cleared much of Level 3 yet?"
"130. Not even close.
Did find a good dungeon for loot though."
"131. The west cliffs, right?
The place is legit."
"132. These damn flying machines
are too rich for my blood."
"133. True dat"
"134. Every guild needs one asap. You can
cover so much ground, it's not even funny."
"133. True dat"
"134. Every guild needs one asap. You can
cover so much ground, it's not even funny."
"135. True dat"
"136. Anyone else get wrecked flying today?"
"137. Wrecked?"
"138. ????"
"139. Was flying around and got pwned by
a big fat beam out of nowhere. RIP me"
"140. Seriously? Hit a trap, maybe?"
"141. Something the devs put in
to block off-limits areas?"
"142. Dunno. No clue."
"143. Just gonna put this out there...
Anyone else thinking what I'm thinking?"
"144. On it. I'll see what I can find out."