She's got something to show us,
but it can't be what I'm thinking, right?
At this point, nothing will surprise me.
Same here.
Can't wait!
So excited!
I don't wanna draw too much attention,
so I'll hold back a bit!
[Deploy]! Left Arm!
Here we go!
Whoa! That's cool!
That was wonderful, Maple!
Okay then. That just happened.
It's yet another new appendage.
This time she's a mecha?
I guess it's okay...
As long as she's a friend...
How was that?
Nice! You're our secret weapon!
Aw, shucks! Ouch!
"Defense and Fourth Event"
You're really getting into it.
Yeah. The guild competition isn't far off now.
Not that we need to level up
any more than we have. Huh?
Where's Frederica?
She's out scouting Maple Tree.
And not Flame Emperors?
Like I said before,
her guild has too many unknowns.
I think you're worrying a lot over nothing.
Take this!
Splash!
Oh, you asked for it!
Don't forget us! Splash!
Sorry!
It's all right!
These swimsuits Iz made
for us are so wonderful!
Not to mention they give
a little bonus to swimming.
I wonder what kind of event
the guild competition will be?
The event's still not for a while.
It's a good chance to refresh our skills.
It's a good chance to do
some leveling up, too, yeah?
My preparations are complete
and I'm all set to go.
Oh, my!
Don't mind if I do!
I wonder if this will be enough?
Hmm?
I like it! And they all even
come with [Unbreakable], too!
"Reverse Alchemy"
"Magic Workshop"
"Cutting Edge"
"Reverse Alchemy"
"Magic Workshop"
"Cutting Edge"
Wow! This lets me make items anywhere!
"Reverse Alchemy"
"Magic Workshop"
"Cutting Edge"
Perfect for me!
Whew! That was so much fun!
Is something wrong?
Now then...
Hey! You over there!
How about you come out already?!
You noticed?
With you staring at us for so long,
it's no surprise.
H-Huh?! Staring at us?!
Sheesh, it's not like that!
W-Wait a sec. Aren't you Frederica?
Howdy. Been a while.
Why'd you come here?
Oh! To play with us?!
Not a bad idea!
To scout us, right?
You're gathering information
to prep for the guild competition.
Well, I have a proposition for you.
What's that?
Would you like to have a little duel?
And what would be the point of me doing that?
How about the loser has to
give up guild information?
I need info about Flame Emperors
and your Order of the Holy Sword.
I can't just let you walk away
after spotting you.
Seems like a better option
than fighting four of us.
All right. You're on.
But if I lose, I'm only telling you
about Flame Emperors. Got it?
Okay.
"Request a duel?"
There. It's done.
I'll see you soon.
Whoa! Wh-Where'd they go?!
It's a duel, Maple.
I think there's some sort of system for that.
She'll probably come back once they're done.
All right then! Let's fish
or something while we wait!
Okay!
[Firebolt]!
Hmm. She won't be easy to hit,
but it's not as if I can't.
I'll finish her off once I learn
a little more! [Firebolt]!
Lucky break! [Firebolt]!
[Super Speed]!
She's coming at me?!
[Multi-Barrier]!
[Multi-Firebolt]!
[Coax Attack]!
Huh?!
She made me use it.
[Coax Attack]? Never heard of it.
In that case... [Multi-Waterbolt]!
[Coax Attack] must have a cooldown.
Evading all attacks is
an insanely powerful skill.
No way she can use it back to back!
[Multi-Stonebolt]!
Have I got her?
[Cascade]!
I see how it is.
I can't believe she made me
resort to [Cascade].
All right! I surrender!
Huh?
Um, okay.
Just like I promised, I'll talk
a bit about Flame Emperors.
Markus the Trapper, Misery the Cleric,
and Shin the Split-Sword?
Mm-hmm!
Flame Emperors has plenty of other
good players besides Mii, you know.
And seeing how I kept my promise, bye now!
Ugh. I never should've let her
force out [Multi-Barrier].
Still, if we fought any longer,
I'd have revealed too much about myself.
Besides, I got to see her secret skills.
And I told her about Flame Emperors, too.
Let's hope they go at it
and crush each other!
He who controls information
controls the battle!
Huh? Fake skills?
Yup. [Coax Attack] lets you manipulate
enemy attacks to your will.
And [Cascade] lets you repel
every attack for a while.
That's easy enough to say, but pulling it off
with your own skill is absurd.
Why would you do that anyway?
Having false info hurts 'em
more than having none.
Isn't Frederica one of the top-rankers?
Yet you pulled off a bluff while fighting her.
Well, it's easy to pretend you're
the underdog when you're way better.
Oh, it's about time.
Rawr! Thanks for your patience!
It's time to explain the rules for
the guild competition, so listen up!
As I mentioned before,
in-game time will be sped up.
There's no joining or breaks
while the event is ongoing!
This time, the event will last five days!
It's a little shorter now.
Guilds will be classified
as large, medium, or small.
"Large"  "Medium"  "Small"
Guilds will be classified
as large, medium, or small.
"Large"  "Medium"  "Small"
Each group earns points
a little differently.
It looks like we're classified as a small guild.
Each guild will be given a base and
must protect an orb placed within.
"Point"
Each guild will be given a base and
must protect an orb placed within.
"Point"
If you bring an enemy orb back to your
own base, you can earn more points.
"Point"
If you bring an enemy orb back to your
own base, you can earn more points.
For every six hours you hold
your own orb, you get a single point.
"1 Point"
For every six hours you hold
your own orb, you get a single point.
But small guilds will get two.
"2 Points"
Taking an enemy orb and defending it
for two hours earns you two points.
"2 Points"
Taking an enemy orb and defending it
for two hours earns you two points.
"2 Points"
The guild you took it from
will lose one point.
"-1 Point"
The guild you took it from
will lose one point.
Essentially, it's a battle for orbs.
Um, so that's one point to hold
your own orb for six hours.
Uh, but two points for small guilds.
And if you keep a stolen orb
for three hours, it's two points.
The other guild loses one point.
Basically, whoever defends well
and can snag orbs the best wins!
An orb that's stolen returns back
to base once any points are earned!
"Point"
An orb that's stolen returns back
to base once any points are earned!
But if it's taken back within the three hours,
there's no gain or loss of points!
Oh? If your orb's stolen,
it will come back automatically.
Looks like you can see where
your orb's at with the map.
Guess it means if you steal an orb,
you've gotta watch out.
It's all about defense.
"[Death Penalty]
1st time: Stats decrease 5%
2nd time: Stats decrease 10%"
By the way, there's a death penalty.
"3rd time: Stats decrease 15%
4th time: Stats decrease 20%
5th time: Eliminated"
I see. Five deaths and you're out?
"Orb will no longer spawn for guilds
with no remaining members."
\It gets harder the more people you lose.
"You cannot steal the same guild's orb
more than once per day."
Especially for small guilds like ours.
That's it for the rules!
Whew! I'm tired from talking so much!
If you don't understand,
just pull up the menu again!
Best of luck, everyone! Rawr!
We probably need to keep
more people on defense,
but it's gonna be tough for us.
What's the problem?
We lack enough people for offense.
Same goes for defense.
The problem for small guilds
is that we get no rest.
Enemies can attack at any point,
including at night.
Oh, right. 'Cuz it's an all-out war this time.
As it goes on, they'll learn our secrets.
We're in trouble if they ever find
out your skill's usage limits.
Gah! Good point!
It's a matter of how long
we can preserve Maple for.
On defense, let's have Maple, Yui, and Mai.
Okay!
You too, Kanade.
Whatever you want.
Our attackers will be me,
Kasumi, and Kuromu.
And we'll have Iz as backup at the base?
Yeah! Let's do that!
We've got time before the event,
so let's go level up!
Yeah!
"[NWO] The 4th event begins! (Part 2)"
"489. The bigger issue is
dealing with Mii, their guild master."
"490. Can't do squat when she's with
the damn MP battery known as Misery.
Gotta split 'em up somehow."
"491. Holy Sword is too high level to
deal with. Just avoid 'em at all costs."
"492. What about Maple?
How do you beat that?"
"493. You don't. But luckily,
she can't catch you."
"494. And if she attacks?"
"495. It'll be a slaughter like
the last boss in a starting zone."
"496. Gotcha."
All right! Let's do our best!
Let's aim for the top! Top ten!
Let's do it!
Now then! It's time for
the guild competition to begin!
So this place is our base?
We'll head out and go attack.
Right. Let's follow the plan.
Take care now!
What the hell?
You little...!
Eep!
Eek! No!
It's a disaster!
What's wrong?!
It's...! It's...!
Thanks for showing us the way.
Guys! Get 'em!
Come on, bring it!
She's as agile as ever.
If only I could do that, too!
All of our girls are scary as hell!
What... the hell... is happening?!
What the--?!
That's one down for us.
Kasumi, could you carry this back to base?
Roger that.
I'm gonna go scout out the area!
Be careful.
Yup!
Maple's obviously a given,
but Sally's quite a monster herself.
Yeah.
I'm grateful we're comrades with all my heart.
Yo!
Huh? Invaders!
It's okay! They're alone!
[Mirage]! [Leap]!
Up above!
[Super Speed]!
What are you doing?! Find her!
Our orb!
Where'd she go?!
O-Over there!
That's it. Right this way.
--What the--?!
--There she goes!
Ooh! Look at her go!
I'm having fun just watching this.
[Vanish].
E-Enemies!
It's a huge attack!
Meet 'em head on!
Give us back our orb!
You've got some nerves, thief!
You're the ones who came to steal ours!
Where's the woman in robes?!
Our guild doesn't have any women!
Thanks for number two!
Faster...
I've gotta hurry up!
I think one of the bigger guilds is gonna win.
There's no chance in hell for a small guild.
By bigger guild, you mean Order of
the Holy Sword or Flame Emperors?
I'm cheering for Holy Sword all the way.
Oh, look. Here they come.
Shall we get to it?
Have at 'em!
[Fissure]!
[Stampede]!
[Burn Axe]!
[Ground Lance]!
[Multi-Sunbeam]!
Whew! We sure made a mess!
A flawless defense. Now we just wait
for the others to come back.
Hmm?
Hey, guys. Change of plans.
Take the orb and head on back.
B-But...!
Hurry up.
Y-Yes sir!
It's been a while.
You've gotten a lot stronger.
How do you figure?
I trust what my instincts say.
[Super Speed]!
Heh! I see you got it, too! However...!
Hmph.
Was that... a hunch?
If I start doubting myself, I'm done for.
[Godspeed]!
[Cascade]!
He's gone.
Was that him just saying hello?
Well, I showed him [Cascade], so it's all good.
Will we be all right?
You think they'll get past the traps?
I'm sure it'll be fine, Markus.
Besides, we have trusty guildmates here
even if they manage to.
I'm still worried. She'll get mad
at me if we lose the orb.
See? More attackers fell for
your traps and got blown away.
That's Markus the "Trapper" for you.
But still... All I've done is
set my traps and wait.
No need to worry. Mii is snatching orbs
enough for the both of us!
[Flame]!
[Eruption]!
[Inferno]!
Here's an MP potion.
Thank you. Go and fetch the orb.
Ma'am.
I'll go after them.
Take our orbs and return to base.
[Flare Accel]!
[Vanish].
[Flame]! [Flame]! [Flame]!
[Fire Lance]! [Fire Lance]!
[Fire Lance]! [Flame]!
They got away...!
I'm sorry, everyone!
I'm so not cut out to be a leader!
I've had enough!
Ugh! The next time we meet,
you won't get away!
So this is that woman's base?
It has to be. This is where my...
This is where our orb is!
Let's head on in!
By the way, isn't this the first time
we've fought together as eight?
Now that you mention it, yeah.
Maple, if you please.
Roger!
Get our orb!
For our pride and our orb! Attack!
Did we get 'em?
What the hell?!
Don't be afraid of some--
Volley! Volley! Volley!
You little...!
Wh-Why didn't it do damage?!
I-It's hopeless! Tactical retreat!
[Paralyze Laser]!
Cowards!
Whatever. Good night.
Tsk! I'll at least take one of you with me!
Impossible! How?!
Is that Maple?
All right! Let's keep it up!
"[NWO] The 4th event begins! (Part 7)"
"213. This competition's got
everyone pumped up!"
"[NWO] The 4th event begins! (Part 7)"
"213. This competition's got
everyone pumped up!"
"214. Who's the front runner you think?"
"215. Holy Sword all the way, bro! Payne's
so jacked, no one stands a chance!"
"216. You wish! Mii and her guild
are gonna roast all you flamers!"
"217. What about Maple Tree?"
"218. The question of Maple
is one for the ages."
"219. She's such an oddball,
it's anyone's guess."
"220. Ain't her guild small? They got
no chance to survive make your time."
"221. I'm still cheering for 'em tho"
"220. Ain't her guild small? They got
no chance to survive make your time."
"221. I'm still cheering for 'em tho"
"222. ^"
"223. ^"