Enemies! They got our orb!
Chase 'em! Get it back!
Over there!
--He's cornered!
--Nice one!
Cut 'em off from that side!
[Wind Cutter]!
Impressive as ever.
Didn't even need skills or magic
going up against that many.
Drag? You should've lent me
a hand if you were here.
I didn't exactly have time for it.
How many you get?
Who knows? It was a pain to keep track.
Maybe around 20 or so?
If you felt like it, couldn't you just
wipe out all the guilds on your own?
I'm not sure. One of them
might actually put up a fight.
Maple Tree, huh?
"Defense and Attack"
Whoa!
--Ten orbs, guys! Ten! What a big haul! Woo-hoo!
--It's only the first day and we're on a roll.
--Splish splash hurray!
They disappeared!
They returned since it's been three hours.
That's more points on the board!
It's too early to celebrate.
We're aiming for top ten.
Thing is, we're 17th place.
Well then, guess I'll head out again.
Huh? Already?
It'll get harder to ambush when it's light out.
Keep it safe.
Take care!
Good luck!
Be careful!
Will she be all right?
She should have rested a bit longer.
She wants to get as many orbs
as she can while she's able.
There's a high chance for small guilds
to get wiped out early on.
But if their orbs vanish,
we can't get any points from them.
So while guilds like that are still around,
she's raising our rank as much as possible.
Otherwise, there's no way
we can compete with the big guilds.
Even so, I feel like she's
pushing herself way too hard.
It's Sally we're talking about.
Maybe she has a reason for it.
I think I'll go and gather orbs, too.
Huh? What made you say that?
'Cuz I've been stuck inside
since the event started.
I wanna sightsee.
So you say. But really you wanna
lighten the load for Sally, right?
Lemme know if something happens. Later!
Kanade has such a kind side.
[Spell Stash].
[Titan Arm].
What the--?!
Enemy attack! After 'em!
There they are! Over here!
[Flare Accel]!
Wonder if I should snatch a few more?
With all the orbs we've got, won't
more people come to take them back?
We don't have to sit pretty and wait.
Wanna set up an ambush?
I'll come too.
I think we've got defense covered
with Maple, May, and Yui here.
All right! Go for it!
Be careful!
Just like I thought.
They're swarming in from all sides.
I'll take the ones on the right. You go left.
All right.
[Super Speed]!
She got through!
Don't let her get away!
Oboro, [Fire Tail]!
That sure took it out of me.
Ten orbs, huh?
Not sure if it'll get us top ten though.
I'm worn out. Wanna head back, Oboro?
We're surrounded!
Iz! Any more bombs?
Don't worry! I've got more
where that came from!
This many's gonna be rough!
Kuromu!
It's my lucky day!
I thought you were a goner! Was that a skill?
[Dead or Alive]. I get a 50% chance
to stay alive when I reach zero HP.
You're a god of death now.
So you gave up being human, too?
Seriously?
[Fourth of Sword - Whirlwind]!
You're there, aren't you? Come out.
Yo! You sure went all out, Kasumi.
Split-Sword Shin. Long time no see.
Since the first event, right?
You know, I was gonna invite you
into Flame Emperors.
Sorry about that. Maple got to me first.
I still can't believe you beat me last time.
But this time, I'm gonna win!
[Split-Sword]!
I can't shake 'em off! These guys are good!
Oho? Is that Sally?
Frederica?!
I came to see what was going on.
Our recon squad said there was
a solo player causing trouble.
Looks like you've been pretty busy.
Sorry, but we'll be taking
those orbs you've gathered!
It's from Sally.
"Might die. Sorry."
What?
[Cascade]!
Magic attack!
[Coax Attack]!
[Cascade] lets you repel attacks
with a physical body.
[Coax Attack] lets you bend
an attack's trajectory.
Both of them should have a long cooldown.
A cooldown...?
They're not... skills?!
Those're just her normal reflexes?!
[Multi-Firebolt]!
Oboro! [Shadow Clone]!
What was that?!
This might be bad!
Frederica!
Reinforcements!
You made it in time! Thank you!
You really fooled me good!
To think you managed
to fake a skill like that!
Still, you're in no shape to fight
this many people, right?
[Multi-Barrier]!
Next time, I won't lose!
I'm sorry, Maple...
[Multi-Fire--
Sally!
Maple?!
I won't allow it! Never!
M-Maple?!
M-Magic attack!
Syrup, [Bastion]!
Turtle!
Maple?! How'd you get here so quick?!
I'll explain later! Hold on to me!
R-Right!
[Deploy Cannon]!
[Deploy Armaments]! [Commence Attack]!
[Hydra]!
Huh?!
What is that?!
This isn't over just yet.
Dread! It's an emergency!
I wonder if Maple made it in time?
I really hope she comes back soon.
Hmm?
Huh?!
I see. Then it's true that both
Maple and Sally are gone.
It's just you two holding the fort?
Well then. It's a pity,
but I won't be holding back.
We gotta tell the others!
But will they come in time?!
From May? What?
You don't have time to look away!
Our base is under attack!
Talk about terrible timing!
I'm ten minutes away from base!
I hope someone gets there!
[Aftershock]!
[Double Stamp]!
Sis, fall back!
Right!
You're too slow!
Sis!
[Aftershock]!
We're not much on our own,
but together...
...we're enough to beat even you!
Couldn't dodge that. You know,
you guys are starting to annoy me!
First, one...
...and two!
Maple!
We're sorry!
Messing with this guild
sure takes it outta you.
Maple?!
[Loving Sacrifice]!
AoE defense?
[Predator]!
Syrup, [Mother Nature]!
Turtle!
Okay, you've beat me this time.
But I'll soon be back!
And with my comrades, too!
We'll beat you as many times as it takes!
[Split-Sword] breaks a sword
into ten parts you control.
You're much better at it this time!
How come you haven't gotten serious yet?
Show me your techniques already!
[First of Sword - Heat Haze]!
That skill would be tough
to fend off without a shield!
[Seventh of Sword - Shatter]!
You've really upped your attack power!
But I have too! [Split-Sword]!
They doubled?!
This time, victory is mine!
[Origin of Sword - Void]!
Where is she?!
Right here.
Good grief, I lost again?
But I've only died once! I'll be back soon!
May we meet again during the event!
Maple made it in time?
Maple! Guys!
May, Yui! Sorry I was late!
You two did a great job!
Thanks to you, our orb is safe.
Thank goodness!
Maple. Did you take damage
for Syrup back there?
Uh, yeah. I guess piercing attacks
get through the defense.
All the damage gets passed on to me.
I'm just glad the orbs are safe.
Sorry I wasn't back in time.
It's okay! We only died once!
We're just glad to be useful!
I actually got saved by Maple, too.
Luckily, my bluff came in handy.
Oh.
Here. I got more orbs.
Me, too. Not as many as Sally though.
We've stolen 22 orbs.
If we can protect these for three hours,
we'll go way up in rank.
We wiped out everyone
who's come for their orb so far.
If people know we're dangerous,
fewer should try to attack.
I know it's a little early, but I think
it's time to proceed with Plan B.
Look!
Whoa!
I get it! So this is why you
were outside so long!
I've mapped all the terrain and
the location of pretty much every guild.
This will be perfect to execute Plan B.
Plan B--the big reveal of Maple.
Yup. Instead of Maple defending the base,
she'll go out and take orbs.
We can't use third level machines for
this event, but Maple can already fly.
You guys join her.
Okay!
We'll stir up the big guilds and cause
battles to give ourselves a chance.
I planned an attack order,
so the rest is all you.
As for me, I think I'll rest.
Sally?!
She's completely worn herself out.
We should let her sleep.
Maple!
Let's go!
Mmm!
Enemy attack! It's just one!
H-Hey, is that...?!
It's Maple!
W-We've got this! P-Protect the orb!
[Predator]!
We've come for your orb!
Gotcha!
What's the next one?
It'll be number ten!
We're on a good pace!
Who do we attack next?
According to Sally's plan, it's Flame
Emperors! The ones in second place!
All right, let's go!
Misery, have you heard?
Maple Tree is attacking
guilds one after another.
I know.
Seeing how Shin died and all,
I don't want to butt heads with that guild.
Maple, huh? Let's hope she doesn't come.
Markus! Misery!
There's a turtle flying this way!
Turtle? Which means...
She's come after all.
Have you told Mii?
Yeah. She said she'll hurry back.
Thank goodness. We just need
to buy her some time.
Now then, how many of my traps
will actually work on her?
I guess that was a bust.
That's Maple and her AoE defense for you.
But you prepared special traps
just for Maple, didn't you?
It got her!
Oh?
What?!
Seriously?!
--Markus.
--Huh?
How many traps are there that will work on her?
Three. But at this rate,
she'll break through 'em all.
So be it. Everyone head back.
Are you sure?
Misery and I will hold her off.
We'll try to keep her occupied for a while.
Go protect the orb.
Understood.
Good luck!
[Hydra]!
[Antidote]!
[Remote Trap - Stone Wall]!
[Remote Trap - Wind Strike]!
May, Yui! It's all you!
Got it!
[Aftershock]!
I guess this is the end of the road.
Mii!
"[NWO] The 4th event begins! (Part 7)"
"872. It's begun! The main event
we've all been waiting for!"
"[NWO] The 4th event begins! (Part 7)"
"872. It's begun! The main event
we've all been waiting for!"
"873. NWO PRESENTS: Maple VS Mii!"
"874. Bring on the guild master showdown!"
"875. They're both high ranked atm!
Flame Emperors is 2nd and Maple Tree is 7th!"
"876. Can Mii's fire attacks scorch
the walking fortress Maple?!"
"877. Can max-defense Maple conquer
Mii and the Flame Emperors?!"
"878. SO PUMPED!! qwerty FFFFFFFFFFFFFFF"