[Flame]!
Mii!
Go figure.
I can't say I'm surprised.
So you're this Maple I've heard of?
And you're Mii from Flame Emperors, right?
"Defense and Mighty Foe"
Here we go!
[Aftershock]!
[Flare Accel]!
[Flame]!
[Inferno]!
A knockback?!
If she doesn't come back...!
[Fire Lance]!
She won't make it!
We're done for!
[Cover Move]!
Are you two all right?!
Th-Thanks for the help!
I see how it is.
I'll take out those two first. Back me up.
--Got it.
--Roger that.
[Inferno]!
N-Not again!
[Remote Trap - Snare]!
Huh? Wh-What?!
[Cover--
Not this time! [Inferno]!
[Predator]!
[Holy Javelin]!
May, Yui! This way!
I've never seen that skill before.
To think she had more to hide...
Such a troublesome opponent.
[Fire Lance]!
We can't even get close!
And that's where we shine the most!
May, Yui! Back out for a minute!
B-But...!
And what about you?
We've gotta save you guys as our secret weapon!
All right.
Be careful!
Get back here!
Not on my watch!
I can use [Devour] if I get close! Let's go!
[Predator]!
You're too slow! [Inferno]!
Change of plans! Hit her with
a chain of piercing attacks!
Don't give her room to breathe!
Okay!
[Remote Trap - Phalanx]!
[Flame]!
[Holy Javelin]!
[Inferno]!
Whoa! It used up a bunch!
This is way too far to use [Hydra]...
Ugh! Talk about incredibly beefy!
Even our piercing attacks are barely
scratching her.
We'll be fighting forever at this rate.
Maple's getting pushed back.
What's wrong?
Mii! We're here to help!
Even Maple can't beat all of us!
Don't just rush right in!
You asked for it! [Spirit Cannon]!
Turtle!
[Flame]!
She's got even more skills?
All right! Close enough!
[Hydra]!
[Antidote]!
You need to let us fight her.
Stay back until I give orders!
U-Understood!
[Paralyzing Sh--
--[Inferno]! [Inferno]! [Inferno]!
--And I got so close, too!
[Holy Javelin]!
[Remote Trap - Snare]!
Argh, what a waste!
[Fire Lance]!
No matter who we're up against...
As long as we've got Mii...
[Flame]!
I never turn back.
My only thought is destroying those in my way!
You monster.
[Hydr--
Not happening! [Inferno]!
Gah! If this keeps up...!
The strongest shield versus strongest lance.
At this rate, the fight will never end.
What do we do, Mii?
Misery... Markus...
--Yes?
--What?
I'm using "that."
Buy me some time until it's ready.
Use all your traps and magic if you must.
Very well.
I'll do my best!
Flames of creation, origin of all.
She stopped attacking? Now's my chance!
--With crimson fingers you grasp
and engulf all that comes in your path.
--[Hydra]!
--With crimson fingers you grasp
and engulf all that comes in your path.
--[Activate - Stone Wall]!
--With crimson fingers you grasp
and engulf all that comes in your path.
--[Holy Javelin]!
--Scorching the earth and heavens in firestorm.
--[Remote Trap - Snare]!
--O' bright flame, dancing in darkness...
[Remote Trap - Frost Pillar]!
Infernal blaze reducing all to ashes...
--Sheesh! That won't work on me!
--More than anything, powerful.
--[Predator]!
--More than anything, ruthless.
--Would you just stay put?!
[Holy Wind]!
Burning brightly...
Any minute now...
Blazing fiercely...
--Oh, no! We're doomed!
--May your raging flames weave a snare...
--...and shackle my enemy in ferocious hellfire!
--All right! Here I come!
[Prison of Flame]!
Huh?! I'm trapped in here?!
Whoa! My [Devour]!
I'm taking damage over time?
Just in the nick of time.
Thank goodness. I was freaking out.
To think I was forced
to use [Prison of Flame]...
I know. Let's hope it takes her out.
Well, I'm out of traps, so it better.
Maple's in a pinch!
It's okay. Maple will pull through.
Yeah.
What to do? I'm not sure how
to escape and I'm out of [Devour]...
I didn't want to show this off,
but I've got no choice!
That's...!
[Deploy Armaments]!
Wh-Wha...?!
That's absurd!
Maple!
This time, it's my turn!
[Deploy Artillery]!
Maple!
[Flame]!
[Inferno]!
Chew on this!
[Fire Lance]!
Mii!
Let's retreat!
There's no way! We can't beat that!
I'm thinking the same thing.
For now, let's consider seeing
her trump card a win for us.
[Flare Accel]!
So be it. We've lost.
However...
To Shin?
I see! What a brilliant plan!
You won't get away!
Huh?!
[Target Acquired]!
[Infern--
[Deploy All Weapons]!
[Full Burst]!
Markus...
Misery...
[Flame]!
I'm out of MP?
But even so...
Don't think you can take my life
without paying a price!
[Self-Destruct]!
Huh?! You're taking me with you?!
This time, you're going down!
Phew! Didn't see that coming!
Ugh! And here I was told
to keep [Machine God] a secret!
Jeez, what a bummer!
Maple!
Hmm?
Thank goodness! You had us so worried!
But we believed in you the whole time!
Well, that's that!
Let's go and fetch the orb!
Right!
Eh?!
The orb is... gone!
Do you think they took it and ran off?
Can they do that?
It's not against the rules, but they
can't earn points if it's not in base.
Ugh... What to do...?
Wanna chase 'em?
Um, we actually had another idea.
What's that?
According to Sally's map,
there're a ton of guilds in this area.
And thanks to you, we're still
in perfect fighting shape, so...!
Let's take a bunch of orbs from all the guilds!
All right! Ready to run around
and grab us some orbs?!
Yeah!
Aww! She beat me!
Jeez! What the hell was that?! Huh?!
Oh. Looks like Mii revived, too.
What a total monster that was.
Yeah. But at least I--
Can you believe she even
survived Mii's [Self-Destruct]?
Huh?
According to Shin's report,
Maple seems to be just fine.
Eh?
--But they've secured our orb,
so no need to worry.
--Eh? Eh?!
--But they've secured our orb,
so no need to worry.
Eh?!
Mii, wait!
I swear! I'm gonna get her next time!
That's gotta be Maple.
Sounds like she's going all out.
It's almost time for us to meet up.
Let's hurry and get to the spot.
I'm sorry, Sally!
We searched all over for their orb,
but we just couldn't find it!
It's fine. You did plenty.
Now the Flame Emperors
will have to go on the move.
Having said that,
our pace has fallen quite a bit.
It's tough to compete with their numbers.
We just can't keep up with the large guilds.
We've been fighting the hard fight, but...
"Order of the Holy Sword"
"Kingdom of the Flame Emperors"
...we're barely holding on to 10th.
"Wizard Hideout"
"Rainbow Wings"
To be honest, we're in a risky position.
"Rapid Fire"
"Shambhala"
It's only a matter of time until
the lower ranked guilds come after us.
"Bulletin Board Bros"
"Rose Stars Brigade"
"Maple Tree"
There's not many small guilds anymore.
So tonight, Iz and Kanade can hold the base...
...while we go on the attack.
Day two and it's already do-or-die.
Maple and Kasumi should go with Kuromu.
May and Yui can come with me.
Got it!
All right! Let's go!
[Aftershock]!
Wh-What the...?!
I need to go faster!
I need to get more!
[Illusion]!
It's a fake attack!
It didn't even hurt! Huh?!
Wh-What the hell's that?!
[Disintegrate]!
They're counting on us to protect it!
Nobody's getting our orb!
Are we seriously doing this?
I agree. They won't expect us from above, but...
Here we go!
[Loving Sacrifice]!
D-Don't you think this is a bit crazy?!
I wouldn't do this in real life,
but here, it's not gonna hurt a bit!
That doesn't make it a good idea!
Whew! Guess I'm dead!
Welcome to the afterlife.
Now you can watch with the rest of us.
You think most of the guilds
are gonna get wiped out?
It's possible! Lots of the small ones
are crumbling already.
Oh! Not sure about Maple Tree though.
"Order of the Holy Sword"
"Kingdom of the Flame Emperors"
"Rainbow Wings"
Those Maple Tree guys are doing their best.
"Shambhala"
"Rapid Fire"
Flame Emperors is in a tough spot, too.
"Revolution"
"thunder storm"
"Maple Tree"
Even the big guilds vary more than you'd think.
Still, Holy Sword is sitting pretty at top.
Anyone else kinda hope
Maple Tree goes all the way?
Yeah. I'm sick and tired of all
the big guilds on the board.
You think they can? What if they do?!
It's Maple after all!
Did you guys gather any orbs, Maple?
Uh, not really.
There were lots of guilds without one.
That's a shame.
In the end, we only came back with two.
This is progressing faster than I thought.
It's not just small guilds.
The medium ones are nearly gone, too.
I think it's time we moved on to the next stage.
Mmm.
It's chaos out there.
The guilds are getting desperate.
That includes Maple Tree.
Maple Tree, huh?
They've got a nice collection of orbs.
Then let's take 'em off their hands.
Agreed!
I have one worry though: Holy Sword.
Agreed.
He did say he'd come back.
Yup. They'll want to settle the score.
I don't want to end the event
without paying them back.
It would be nice to fight
under ideal conditions, but...
But on the other hand,
seeing how we're both exhausted
and Maple's [Devour] is used up,
it's very likely they'll attack us tonight.
Still, Maple Tree has little reason
to meet us in battle.
In which case...
We need to take our orb
and leave before they come.
A big guild like that can't move very fast,
so they'll take a while to get here.
Are we ready?
You still wanna fight after saying all that?
I want to conquer this Maple.
And I don't think I'm the only one
who's excited by the thought.
We'll go as soon as we're ready.
Okay!
It's too early! Don't tell me...!
Just four of 'em?!
A small party of their top players
moves a lot faster than an army.
But to throw away their main advantage...
...and not overrun us with sheer numbers?
I figured we'd be more
than enough to defeat you.
They're taking us lightly.
Now that it's come to this,
let's duke it out already.
Howdy, Sally!
You won't be tricking me this time.
Come on and show us what you've got!
Hello, girls. It's time for round two.
Maple. I've always wanted to fight you.
Payne... I've heard you're
the strongest player there is, but...
...I will not lose!
Fight me!
[Loving Sacrifice]!
Don't think so!
Outta the way!
You okay?
Yeah! But what about Maple?
I'm afraid you'll have to fight me.
[Aftershock]!
[Earth Surge]!
A knockback?! I've gotta get back!
[Cover Mo--
You're mine!
Not in a million years!
Are you two all right?
Y-Yeah!
You better be careful or I'll snatch it up!
Iz! Kanade! Protect the orb!
[Multi-Barrier]!
[Dispel Magic]!
Whew! Got some tough cookies here!
H-He's incredibly strong!
Told you, didn't I?
We're more than enough to win!
[Defense Break]!
[Ground Lance]!
J-Jeez!
Maple! You should cancel it!
G-Got it!
Your head's mine!
[Godspeed]!
[Berserk]!
[Multi-Teleport]!
[Sword of Judgment]!
M-Maple!
"[NWO] The Watchers of Maple Tree thread
(Part 3) [Fortress Base]"
"772. Hey! Payne's finally on the move!"
"[NWO] The Watchers of Maple Tree thread
(Part 3) [Fortress Base]"
"772. Hey! Payne's finally on the move!"
"773. What now?! What's gonna happen?!"
"774. Dude, I can't take my eyes off this!
Dying early was a blessing after all!"
"775. Mad props to the wizard who camped me
so I could watch this action unfold!"
"776. U guys are seriously depressing."
"777. What? Think you're
too good to cheer for Maple?"
"776. U guys are seriously depressing."
"777. What? Think you're
too good to cheer for Maple?"
"778. NO U! Go~ Maple~"