[Sword of Judgment]!
[Stout Guardian], huh?
But how long can you really last
with only one HP?
[Predator]! [Hydra]!
That's nothing!
Maple!
Protect the orb!
[Multi-Firebolt]!
Maple! Use [Cover Move]!
Right! [Cover Mo--
[Super Speed]!
Iz!
"I Don't Want to Get Hurt,
so I'll Max Out My Defense."
"Defense and Bonds"
I can't use [Cover Move] and
drag the others into this!
You've got bigger concerns
than others right now!
Syrup! [Mother Nature]!
Turtle!
Such a useless struggle!
May, Yui! Stay close to my side!
Right!
Got time to worry about others?
[Power Axe]!
Kuromu!
Hmph. You've got a skill like Maple's?
I'm pretty tenacious in my own special way.
Wanna try your clone thing?
You're no match for my speed though.
Let me handle this. Go and help Maple.
Got it.
[Multi-Stonebolt]!
Kasumi!
Don't always expect to see it coming.
[Multi-Barrier]!
Shoot!
It doesn't matter how fast you are
if you can't move.
Oboro, [Awaken]!
Not happening!
Oboro!
Frederica! Keep her pinned down!
You've got it!
You're going nowhere!
[Arm of Steel]!
Well, ain't that cute!
[Smoke Screen]!
Kanade!
Dread, fetch the orbs.
On it!
Syrup! [Spirit Cannon]!
--Tur... tle!
--[Predator]! [Hydra]!
I'm going to end this with everything I've got!
[Sword of Destruction]!
Maple!
[Counter]!
She threw down her shield?
Payne!
Maple!
He took the full brunt of Maple's
[Counter] right in the face.
I know it's Payne, but still...
Still here.
You're kidding!
You're not the only one with [Stout Guardian]!
[Sword of Vanquishing]!
[Atrocity]!
I shouldn't have panicked. Oh, well...
For real?!
You're shitting me!
I guess this isn't a bad way to go.
Yeah, yeah, you win.
[Multi-Barrier]!
As if that would work!
We won!
We actually... won?
That was rough.
You took down the Payne!
You're incredible!
When you threw down your shield,
I thought you lost your mind.
Sally actually gave me the idea.
She said it might come in handy someday.
--Kanade!
--Iz!
Sorry for dying on you.
How'd the fight go?
Just fine! Maple gave 'em a beat down!
We did it, Kanade! Iz!
Huh?
Um, Maple?
Aren't you gonna go back to normal?
Oh... I can only transform once a day,
so it's kind of a waste if I do.
All our plans went out the window.
Day two is barely behind us, yet...
...we've already showed off
[Machine God] and [Atrocity].
All of our trump cards are out in the open now.
Which is why I'm thinking
we move to the next stage.
It works out since Maple used [Atrocity], too.
It's perfect timing to make her debut.
Since the other orbs returned to their base,
there's no need for us to hang out in ours.
Right now, Maple Tree is in sixth,
but there's still three more days.
At this rate, I can see the big guilds
eventually passing us up.
For us not to fall out of the top ten,
we need to make it hard for
the other guilds to gain points, right?
In that case, we just have to remove
orbs from the equation.
But for that, we'd need to--
Trim down the number of guilds!
All right! Let's go!
Looks like guilds are dropping like flies.
Yeah. Wouldn't be surprised
if some huge guild raided us.
Let's go.
Yeah. Let's check it out.
Guys, let's go!
Yeah!
Hey! Who let the boss out?!
I don't know! Don't ask me!
Turtle!
Don't let anyone escape!
We've gotta wipe 'em out
and get rid of their orb!
Maple Tree might actually be a top finisher.
There's hardly any orbs left.
Looks like they gave up on gathering orbs,
and plan to prevent anyone
from building any points.
Won't the other top guilds hop
on the bandwagon, too?
It'll be easier for them to secure a spot.
Still, I can't believe it!
Ever think you'd see Payne get beat?
So much for being an angel.
At this point, she's more like a devil.
It's so frustrating getting beat
by that little guild over and over!
And what was that thing Maple turned into?!
That thing is unfair, I say! Unfair!
It's not unfair. I imagine she earned it
fair and square in some event.
Well, sure, but...
You don't seem that upset for someone
who just got beat, Payne.
I wouldn't say that. I'll settle
the score someday.
But it can wait until later.
Yup. It's not like anyone stole our orb.
We're pretty much a given for first, too.
There's nothin' to fret about.
Th-That's true. Yeah.
We haven't really been beat! We didn't lose!
Even so, it is a little frustrating.
Payne!
I see... Understood. Thank you.
It's about to get interesting again.
What's that?
Seems like there's an all-out war over there.
That's over by Flame Emperors.
Huh? I wonder what's happening?
So that's how it is...
Maple! Head towards Flame Emperors!
[Inferno]!
Hold the line! Get healed by
Misery if you take damage!
That's Mii for you.
She collected so many orbs
that we're back in the running.
But she also made us that many more enemies.
Now we have less than half of our army.
They're trying to wipe us out in hopes
of their own guilds going up in rank.
But if anyone else joins the fray...
Shin, you're up!
Got it!
[Split-Sword]!
Come on, give me a break! No, no, no!
What's the matter, Mii?
It's a report from the scouts.
A monster thought to be Maple
is heading this way.
Maple?
All it took was Kasumi to beat me though.
What awful news.
We're already in over our heads with enemies.
And if you add Maple Tree on top of that...
If we're going down, let's take
as many of them with us as we can!
Agreed!
We pledged to follow Mii to whatever end!
Let's show 'em what we're made of!
Leave all the healing to me.
Come on! Didn't you hear our leader?
All right, all right...
Let's do this!
[Flare Accel]!
[Inferno]!
I've spent almost all my MP.
I guess this is it.
Wha...?
What the hell's going on?
I don't know, but it seems Maple Tree
is attacking our enemies.
Do you think they came to save us?
Like as in an apology for last time?
I doubt they're that soft-hearted.
They must have some other motive.
In any case, this is our chance!
We counterattack!
Mmm!
Phew, that was close!
I almost ended up killing Mii by mistake.
We didn't want to hurt
the Flame Emperors, right?
Yup! Our goal is to make sure as many
guilds get wiped out as possible.
Flame Emperors can help us out with that.
Yup!
Huh?
It's Payne and them!
They must've had the same idea!
Kanade, it's time to roll!
We're doing our plan?
Oboro, [Shadow Clone]!
[Phantom World]!
There're seven Maples?
What sort of skill is that?!
I'm grateful that she saved us, but...
Man, I don't even know what to say.
What the hell am I looking at?
The more I watch it, the more my brain melts.
That's why I said that thing is unfair.
I need to step up my game and
get myself some new skills, too.
It's only the third day,
but this thing is practically over.
True. There's just six guilds left
and all of 'em fall in the top ten.
And every guild in the top ten gets
exactly the same reward anyways.
There's really no point in fighting anymore.
Never thought it'd be such a brawl
that two whole days went to waste.
I think it's because Maple Tree
got everyone riled up.
All that's left now is to pick out some
highlights and put together a video.
Thing is, over half of 'em have Maple in it.
If only we could predict
what she would do next...
What's the plan? Should we nerf Maple
again so she's not as powerful?
I considered that,
but I'm thinking we leave her be.
Why's that?
Maple's basically the face
of the game at the moment.
She's drawn a ton of players into the game.
Not to mention people who grind and
build levels in hopes of fighting her.
If we make her weaker at this point,
nobody's gonna like it.
So we're taking a hands-off approach?
Yup! She's actually quite a cute player
if you're not busy trying to nerf her.
Who wants to take a guess?
What kind of craziness is Maple up to right now?
I bet she's chilling at base!
And playing board games with her guild!
Practicing how to fly with [Machine God]!
Sitting inside her giant turtle's mouth!
Munching on a weapon to see
if she learns a skill!
No, munching on her turtle!
All right, here it comes!
The answer is...!
Do it! Do it!
--Up you go!
--Whee!
Whew! It's finally over!
We got third place, too!
We beat our goal by a ton! Woo-hoo!
We placed higher than I thought we would.
But now we're gonna be a big target
when the next event rolls around.
Don't worry about next time! It'll all work out!
Seriously, I'm so glad you
told me about this game!
I think it changed my life!
But in a good way!
Keep up with your studies though.
If you get grounded from games,
we'll lose our guild master.
Oh, shoot! I forgot I've got
English tomorrow! I better review!
Without further ado, it's time to kick off
the party to celebrate the fourth event!
Maple Tree placed an awesome third place!
"3rd Place"
We all get five silver medals a piece!
What's more, we're all rewarded with
a five percent bonus to all stats!
Yeah, that's great and all, but...
Why are the rest of these guys here?
That's what I'd like to know.
We were on our way to go hunting as usual...
...when Maple here saw us
in town and insisted we come.
She was kind enough to invite us.
It would be rude to refuse.
It's the same for us.
Plus, we wanted to see what kind
of place Maple Tree was.
I've never been to an enemy guild before,
so I'm kinda nervous.
There's no sides when the fighting stops.
And we've already added them as friends.
True.
Well, if that's what our guild master wants,
we've got no complaints.
All right, everyone!
Let's toast for a job well done!
Cheers!
"3rd Place"
Rawr!
Now then, we've got some highlights
from the fourth event!
Volume One: "Maple Tree's Fierce Battle!"
"4th Event"
"Highlights"
"Maple Tree's Fierce Battle!"
"3rd Place"
"4th Event"
"Highlights"
"Maple Tree's Fierce Battle!"
Oh! That's the night I botched everything up!
I thought [Self-Destruct] would be
enough to get some payback.
You picked on the wrong person.
Maple, what's your vitality now?
Um, I think it broke five digits?
Well that explains a lot.
We didn't stand a chance.
Next time, we'll win.
Now we know the extent of Maple's skills.
It's Maple we're talking about.
By next time, she'll uncover
even weirder skills.
Take your eyes off her for a second,
and she'll turn into a furball
or monster or something.
I'm just playing the game normally, you know.
As if!
Huh?!
"[NWO] Saw a sick great shielder
(Part 23) [5-Digit Defense]"
"978. Cheers, all!"
"[NWO] Saw a sick great shielder
(Part 23) [5-Digit Defense]"
"978. Cheers, all!"
"979. Good work!"
"980. Saw the video. Hot damn, that was dope!"
"981. If you thought the highlights were sick,
you should have seen the party."
"982. Maple, Payne, and Mii
under one roof sounds insane!"
"983. What's really insane is
how freakishly strong they are."
"984. Dude, don't fool yourself.
You're well into freakish territory yourself."
"985. Hell, everyone in Maple Tree is nuts.
The only one who's relatively normal is Kasumi."
"986. There must be a [Maple]
skill that makes them weird."
"987. You've been infected by [Maple].
Acquired skill [Maple]."
"988. By the way, You Know Who
broke 5-digits in VIT."
"989. That's like 100x my STR!
ONE FREAKING HUNDRED!"
"990. 10 bucks says Maple already
found some new monster to turn into."
"991. Probably. She always manages to
pick up skills when no one's looking."
"992. Welp, boys. Guess we'll just
have to watch over her for eternity."
"993. Watch? No... Cheer her on? SIGN ME UP!"
"994. Agreed!"
"995. Me too!"
"993. Watch? No... Cheer her on? SIGN ME UP!"
"994. Agreed!"
"995. Me too!"
"996. Me 2! Me 2!"
"997. Aren't they announcing
another event soon?"
"998. At this rate, we won't be able
to take our eyes off Maple."
"999. Works for me. She's cute."
"1000. Max out that defense, baby!"
"I Don't Want to Get Hurt,
so I'll Max Out My Defense."