That's horrible...!
There's no helping it.
This was too much for her to handle alone.
But she came here knowing that.
But... that's too much!
This can't be right!
If she gives up, it's over.
But you have the power
to change fate itself...
All this inevitable destruction
and tragedy...
You can change it, if you want.
The power to do so lies within you.
Can I really?
Can I really do something to help?
Could I really change this ending?
Of course you could.
So make a contract with me...
...and become a magical girl!
It was all just a dream?
Kawashita yakusoku wasurenai yo
I won't forget our promise we made
Me wo toji tashikameru
I close my eyes to make sure
Oshiyoseta yami
I will move forward,
Furiharatte susumuyo
shaking off the surging darkness
Itsuni nattara nakushita mirai wo
When can I see the future that I lost
Watashi kokode mata mirukoto dekiruno?
Here in this place once again?
Afuredashita fuan no kage wo
Tearing up the shadow of anxiety
Nando demo saite
That floods into me many times
Kono sekai ayunde ikou
I will keep walking in this world
Tomedonaku kizamareta
Time that is endlessly ticking
Toki wa ima hajimari tsuge
now starts
Kawaranai omoi wo nose
With our everlasting passion,
Tozasareta tobira akeyou
And open the door that has been closed
Mezameta kokoro wa hashiridashita
Our awakened souls
Mirai wo egaku tame
Set out to paint our rising future
Muzukashii michi de tachi domattemo
Even if we get stuck on a troubled path
Sora wa kireina aosa de itsumo mattete kureru
The beautiful blue sky always waits for us
Dakara kowaku nai
So I won't be afraid of anything
Mou naniga attemo kujikenai
Whatever happens, I won't give up
EPISODE 1: I FIRST MET HER IN A DREAM... OR SOMETHING
Good morning, Dad!
Good morning, Madoka.
Is Mom up?
Tatsuya's waking her up right now.
Go help him, will you?
Okay!
Mommy! Mommy!
Morning! Morning!
Wake up! Mommy! Mommy!
RISE AND SHINE!
Huh?
Mommy woke up!
So what's been going on lately?
Hitomi got another love letter.
That's the second one this month.
Boys who don't even have the guts to
confess their love in person are no good.
And how's Kazuko doing?
It seems like Ms. Saotome's new
relationship is going well.
She gushes about him
all during homeroom.
It'll be their 3-month anniversary this
week, so I guess that's a new record.
Hmm, I guess we'll see.
They're reaching a crucial
juncture right now.
They are?
If it's not the real thing,
it's around this point in the relationship
that things start falling apart.
Well, if they make it past 3 months, they're
probably good a year at least.
Perfect!
Which ribbon should I wear?
Huh? But isn't this too flashy?
That's at LEAST as flashy as you should be!
A woman's appearance is the one thing
she can't afford to get looked down at.
Excellent!
That should make all your secret
admirers melt in adoration.
I don't have any secret admirers!
But you should go about as though you do.
That's the secret behind every
pretty girl's success!
Uh-oh!
Safe!
There, eat it all up now, okay?
Okay!
More coffee, honey?
Hmm, better not.
All right! I'm off then.
Have a nice day!
Now then, you'd better hurry too, Madoka.
Huh?! Oh, right!
I'm heading out!
Have a nice day, sweetie!
Have nice daaaay!
Good morning!
Good morning.
Madoka, you're late!
Oh! Cute ribbons!
You think so? They're not too flashy?
I think they look lovely.
So my mom said...
A boy who confesses his love with a letter
instead of in person is no good.
Your mom is just too cool, Madoka!
I mean, she's gorgeous and a successful
businesswoman besides!
If only I could make up my mind
to reject a boy so easily.
What an enviable problem to have!
It really is! I wish I could get a
love letter from someone too.
Just once!
Oh-ho!
So you want to become a beautiful,
popular girl like Hitomi, Madoka?
And you've decided to start changing your
image with these hair ribbons, huh?
You've got it wrong! My mom made me--
I see! You even got your mom to tell
you the secret to becoming popular!
How shameless!
Let me show you what happens
to bad girls like you!
No! Hey! Stop it! Stop!
My, such a cute girl!
But I won't allow you to go off and
become popular with the boys.
You must be my bride, Madoka!!
Noooo!
Ahem!
Now, I have something very important
to discuss with you today, class.
I want you all to listen very closely!
When frying an egg, should it be fried
sunny side-up or over hard?!
Mr. Nakazawa--what do you think?!
Huh?! U-um, well--
Th-they can be fried either way, can't they?
Precisely!
They can be fried either way!
And it should go without saying...
...that judging a woman's attractiveness...
...by the way she fries her eggs
is the gravest of mistakes!
Now, girls--
I want you to remember...
...that you must never date men who insist
they can't eat fried eggs done over hard.
Guess it didn’t work out.
Yeah, guess it didn't.
And boys--
You'd better not grow up so petty as to
fuss over how your eggs are done, okay?
Well, then!
Now that that's out of the way, let's
welcome our new transfer student!
Hey, shouldn't that have come first?
Come on in, Miss Akemi!
Wow, she's gorgeous!
Huh?
No way... It couldn't be...
Now, then! Why don't you tell your
classmates about yourself?
My name is Homura Akemi.
Pleased to meet you.
HOMURA AKEMI
Uh... Miss Akemi?
So, Miss Akemi...
What school did you come from?
A Catholic school in Tokyo.
Did you do any club activities
at your old school?
How about sports? Or cultural activities?
I didn't participate in activities.
Your hair is so beautiful!
What kind of shampoo do you use?
She has a mysterious air
to her, doesn't she?
Hey, Madoka, do you know that girl?
Maybe it was just me, but it seemed
like she was glaring at you earlier.
Well... Um...
I'm sorry.
I think today's been a
little stressful for me.
I'm not feeling very well.
Would you allow me to excuse
myself to the Nurse's Office?
Oh! Then let me show you the way there.
I'll come too!
No, you needn't trouble yourselves.
I'll ask the Nurse's Aide to take me.
Miss Madoka Kaname.
You are the Nurse's Aide for
this class, are you not?
Huh? Um, well...
May I ask you to accompany me?
To the Nurse's Office, that is.
U-um, I, uh...
How did you know I was the Nurse's Aide?
Ms. Saotome told me.
Oh, I see.
Oh, um, the Nurse's Office is...
This way, isn't it?
Yes, that's right.
Um, but... um...
It seems like you already
know how to get there...
Um... Miss Akemi?
You can call me Homura.
Homura...?
What is it?
Oh, um...
That's kind of an unusual name, isn't it?
O-oh!
But not in a bad way! I-I was just
thinking it sounded kind of cool--
Madoka Kaname.
Do you treasure the life you currently live?
Do you consider your family
and friends precious?
W-well... I... Yes, I do.
Both my family and my friends--
I love all of them, and consider
them very precious!
Do you really?
Yes, really! I couldn't lie about that.
I see.
If that's really the case,
then you wouldn't try to change the person
you currently are, would you?
Because if you do, you will end
up losing all of those things.
...Huh?
You should stay as you
are, Madoka Kaname.
Stay as you are, and as
you always shall be.
D-did she just break the
prefecture-wide record...?
You were so amazing!
Huh?! She said WHAT?!
It doesn't make any sense, does it?
Just when I was thinking she was someone
gifted with both brains and beauty...
...it turns out she's a crazy
New Age weirdo!
Exactly how far was she going to keep
up that weirdo character act?
Is that what gets her MOE?! How
the heck is that even exciting?!
Madoka, are you sure you've never
met Miss Akemi before?
Hmm... Well, the sensible
answer is, "yes," but...
What's that supposed to mean?
That you have met her before
in some "insensible" way?
Well...
Last night... I first met her... in a dream...
Or something.
Awesome! You’re acting like you’re
a anime character, too!
That's mean! This is really bugging me!
Well, it's all obvious now!
You must have known each
other in a previous life,
and were brought by fate across time
and space to meet once again!
You said you met in a dream.
What kind of dream was it?
It was... To be honest, I can't
really remember anymore.
I do know that it was a really
strange dream, though...
Then maybe you actually have met
Miss Akemi somewhere before.
Huh?!
Though you may not
consciously remember,
your subconscious could
have taken note of her...
...and later brought her
image out in a dream.
Isn't that a little far-fetched? I mean,
that's some coincidence!
I suppose.
Oh! It's already this late?
I'm sorry, I'd better go.
Piano lessons, right? Or is it Japanese
classical dance today?
Tea Ceremony lessons.
Even though Entrance Exams
are right around the corner.
I wonder how long Mother intends
to make me continue with them.
Whew! Makes me glad I wasn't born rich.
Should we get going too?
Madoka, do you mind if we stopped at
the music store on the way home?
That's fine. Buying another CD for Kamijo?
Sort of.
Well, see you later.
- Later!
- Bye-bye!
Help me...
Help me... Madoka...
Huh? What?!
Please... save me...
Who's there? Who is it?
THIS FLOOR IS CLOSED
DUE TO REMODELING
Save me...
Where are you?
Who are you?
Save me...
Is that you?
Save... me...
Homura...?
Get away from that thing.
B-but... he's hurt!
No! Please, don't do something cruel!
This has nothing to do with you.
But he was calling me!
I could hear him begging me to save him!
...I see.
Madoka! This way!
Sayaka!
Now, of all times...!
Wh-what is with that girl?!
Now she's attacking people in cosplay?!
And what is that thing?
It's not a stuffed animal, is it? It's alive?
I don't know.
I don't know what any of this
is. But we have to save him!
Huh?! Where'd the exit go?
What is this place?!
There's something wrong with this place.
The path keeps changing!
What is going on here?!
There's something over there!
This has got to be a joke, right?
I mean, I must be dreaming, right?
Right?! Madoka?
H-huh?!
What is...?
That was close!
But you're safe now.
Oh! You rescued Kyubey
for me, didn't you?
Thank you. He's a dear friend of mine.
I-I was called to him.
I heard his voice inside my head.
Ahh, I see.
Those uniforms...
You must be students at Mitakihara
Middle School too.
Are you second-years?
Who are you?
That's right, I haven't introduced
myself yet.
But before all that...
...mind if I wrap up a bit of work?
A-amazing...!
W-we're back...!
The witch escaped.
If you want to finish it off, you'd
better go after it right now.
I'll let you take it this time.
I have business here.
You don't read between the
lines very well, do you?
I'm telling you I'll overlook
what you did this time.
Don't you think it would be better for both
of us not to court needless trouble?
Thank you, Mami!
You're a lifesaver.
If you want to thank anyone,
it should be these two.
I was just passing by.
Thank you very much.
My name is Kyubey.
Were you the one who was calling me?
Yes, I was, Madoka Kaname.
And you, Sayaka Miki.
How do you know our names?
I came here because I have
a request for you two.
A... a request?
I want you to make contracts with
me and become magical girls!
“Soreja matane” tte te wo futte
I say “See you later” and wave my hand
Murini waratte samishiku natte...
I force myself to smile but I feel sad
Kousaten, shingou, tookuno kurakushon
Crossroads, traffic signals, horns from far away...
Shiranai darekano waraiau koe
And laughter of people I don't know
Kyou wa hitoride aruku kayoi nareta machi
When walking alone in the town where I’ve walked many times
Demo itsumo yori mo nanndaka jibun ga chotto chiisaku omoeruyo
But I feel that I am smaller than usual
“Soreja matane” tte te wo futte
I say “See you later” and wave my hand
Egao tsukutte samishiku natte...
I fake a smile and I feel sad
Honto wa mada hanashi tarinai kedo
To be honest, I wanted to talk with you more
“Soreja matane” tte kotoba de
I would say “See you later”
Mata aerutte uso wo tsuite
I lied when I told you I'd see you again
Itsumo dourino egao de iuyo
I will tell you that with the usual smile on my face
“Mata ashita”
“See you tomorrow”
I will grant you one wish--any
wish you desire!
Huh? Really?!
What kind of wish?
Anything you want.
I can grant you even the most
impossible of miracles!
EPISODE 2: THAT WOULD BE TRULY WONDERFUL
That would be truly wonderful.