I am Mami Tomoe.
I'm a third-year student at
Mitakihara Middle School.
And...
...I am one who has made a contract
with Kyubey -- a magical girl!
Another weird dream...?!
Good morning, Madoka!
Kawashita yakusoku wasurenai yo
I won't forget our promise we made
Me wo toji tashikameru
I close my eyes to make sure
Oshiyoseta yami
I will move forward,
Furiharatte susumuyo
shaking off the surging darkness
Itsuni nattara nakushita mirai wo
When can I see the future that I lost
Watashi kokode mata mirukoto dekiruno?
Here in this place once again?
Afuredashita fuan no kage wo
Tearing up the shadow of anxiety
Nando demo saite
That floods into me many times
Kono sekai ayunde ikou
I will keep walking in this world
Tomedonaku kizamareta
Time that is endlessly ticking
Toki wa ima hajimari tsuge
now starts
Kawaranai omoi wo nose
With our everlasting passion,
Tozasareta tobira akeyou
And open the door that has been closed
Mezameta kokoro wa hashiridashita
Our awakened souls
Mirai wo egaku tame
Set out to paint our rising future
Muzukashii michi de tachi domattemo
Even if we get stuck on a troubled path
Sora wa kireina aosa de itsumo mattete kureru
The beautiful blue sky always waits for us
Dakara kowaku nai
So I won't be afraid of anything
Mou naniga attemo kujikenai
Whatever happens, I won't give up
EPISODE 2: THAT WOULD BE TRULY WONDERFUL
Madoka...
I heard you got in late last night?
Yeah, I got invited over to an
older student's house...
Well, I'm not going to make a fuss
about curfews or anything,
let us know where you are
before dinner, all right?
I'm sorry.
People really can't see him...
Wow...
What a wonderful room!
I live here alone, so feel free to
make yourselves comfortable.
Though I’m afraid I don't have much
to offer as refreshments...
Oh, Mami! This is so delicious!
Seriously--insanely tasty!
Thank you.
Since you two have been chosen
by Kyubey as well,
it means you are now involved in all of this.
So I thought there were a few
things we should go over.
Right, right! Feel free to ask
us anything you want!
Sayaka... I think you've got it backwards...
How pretty!
This is a Soul Gem.
When Kyubey makes a contract
with a girl, a Soul Gem is born.
It is the source of our magic, and also
the proof that we are magical girls.
What about that "contract" business?
I will grant you one wish
- any wish you desire!
Huh? Really?!
A wish...?
Yes, anything at all.
I can grant you even the most
impossible of miracles!
So we could wish for riches and treasures?
Or eternal youth?
Or even the fabled 108-dish
banquet of the emperors?!
Uh, maybe not that last one...
Yes, but in exchange for that wish,
your Soul Gem is created.
Those who possess a Soul Gem are
duty-bound to do battle with witches.
Witches?
Hey... Mom?
Hm?
Say that - just hypothetically...
Say that someone offered to magically
grant you any wish in the world.
What would you do?
I'd have those two trustees driven
straight out of the company.
Ahh...
And also...
The CEO really is getting too
old to keep pushing himself,
so maybe I'd have him retire?
Oh, but he hasn't named a successor yet...
Then what if you became the new CEO?
I hadn't considered that...
If I could gather enough support
in the Sales Department...
I've already got the Planning Committee
and General Affairs in my corner...
Then my only hurdle would be old Baldy
from the Accounting Department...
Maybe... Interesting...
Mom... You've got a scary
look in your eyes...
So what exactly is a witch?
Are they different from magical girls?
If magical girls can be said
to be born from wishes,
then witches are creatures
born from curses.
Just as magical girls spread hope to
the world, witches spread despair.
And since they're invisible
to regular humans,
it makes their evil all the more insidious.
Anxiety and mistrust...
Irrational rage and hatred...
They sow the seeds of disaster
throughout the world.
Many of the inexplicable suicides
and murders that occur...
...are caused by a witch's curse.
Its formless darkness grows
within the cursed human...
...until it consumes him
from the inside out.
If these witches are so dangerous, why
don't people know about them yet?
Because witches hide themselves deep
within the labyrinths they create...
and take care never to appear
before human eyes.
That maze-like place you wandered
into today was a labyrinth.
Actually, they're very dangerous.
Humans who stray into them usually
don't make it out alive.
And you fight such scary creatures?
Yes, often at the risk of my life.
That's why you two...
should think very carefully before
deciding to become magical girls.
Having been chosen by Kyubey,
you have the rare chance
to have any wish granted.
But remember that that wish
lies side-by-side with death.
Oh, man... This is gonna be a tough choice.
To help you make up your minds,
why don't you come along with
me on a few witch hunts?
Huh?!
You should see for yourself what
it's like to do battle with witches.
Also... you should think long and hard...
about whether there's something
you want badly enough...
...to make it worth putting
yourself in danger.
Good morning!
Good morning.
Good-- waaughh!
Good morning, Sayaka!
Uh...
Is something the matter, Sayaka?
So other people really can't see him?
Seems that way.
Um...
O-oh! No, it's nothing at all!
L-let's get going!
It seems like we can communicate...
...just by thinking to each other like this.
Wah!
What?! You mean we already
have magical powers?!
No, no.
I'm just acting as an intermediary
between your thoughts right now.
But it's handy being able to
talk telepathically, isn't it?
It... feels a little weird...
Hey, you two. What's going on?
You've been staring so intently
into one another's eyes...
Huh? Oh, n-no, there's nothing... going on...
No, don't tell me--
You're already close enough to
communicate through your eyes alone?!
Ohh!! But for two people to suddenly
get that much closer overnight--
What on earth did you do
after I left yesterday?!
No, seriously. It totally isn't
what you're thinking--
Well, a lot of things did happen
last night, but...
But you can't!! You're both girls, after all!
Don't you see that it's a love
that can never beeeee?!
You left your bag!
Hitomi's acting so much
like you today, Sayaka.
Hey! What's that supposed to mean?!
But seriously, is it really okay for you
to tag along to school with us?
Why not?
Like I said, that girl from yesterday
just transferred into our class.
Isn't she trying to kill you?
Actually, I think the school
is the safest place for me.
After all, Mami's here too.
But Mami is a third-year student, so her
class is pretty far from ours.
Don't worry, I can hear you all perfectly.
At this distance, I can still reach
her with my telepathy.
Oh! U-uh, um, good morning!
I promise I'll keep close watch
over you all, so don't worry.
Anyway, she doesn't strike me as the
type who would attack you in public.
I sure hope you're right...
Ugh! Speak of the devil...
So is that transfer student also a...
A magical girl?
Just like you, Mami?
Yes, there's no doubt about it.
She seems to be a fairly powerful one, too.
But doesn't that mean she's a good guy
who also fights against the witches?
So why would she suddenly
start attacking Madoka?
It was me that she was after.
It seemed like she was trying to prevent
me from contracting a new magical girl.
But why?
If we're all fighting the same enemy,
wouldn't it be better if there
were more of us?
Not necessarily.
It's actually more common for magical
girls to contend against one another.
What? But why?
There are certain rewards one can
gain from defeating a witch.
That's why sometimes, depending
on the time and situation,
Magical girls may actually battle one
another for the right to those rewards.
So basically,
the reason that girl was staring
at Madoka all day yesterday...
...was because she knew Kyubey
was trying to get to her?
Most likely, yes.
Don't worry, Madoka.
If she tries anything on you,
I'll punch her lights out!
Plus, we have Mami here
to protect you too!
That's right.
Leaving aside Miki and her punches,
I am here, so you will be just fine.
What do you mean "leaving aside?!"
And so...
...the form we've been studying
up to this point...
...in which the person or thing performing
an action is the subject of the sentence...
...is called the "active voice."
On the flip side, we have
the "passive voice"...
...which is what we call a sentence
in which "B is et cetera'd by A."
In other words, the subject of the sentence
is the recipient of the verb...
...instead of the one performing it.
So the form is "be" + the verb
in the past participle.
Now let's take the sample
sentence, "he likes me."
Here you go.
Hey, Madoka...
Have you come up with a wish yet?
Not really...
Have you?
Nope, not a clue.
Seriously...
I've gone through and considered
so many different things too.
I mean, there are plenty of things
I want to have or do, but...
...I guess the whole "risking your life
for it" part is what's getting me.
None of the stuff I want
is worth that much.
Yeah...
How odd.
Most of the girls I make my
offer to accept right away.
Well... Maybe the pair of us are just fools?
Huh? You think so?
Yep. A pair of blissfully ignorant fools...
I'm sure it's not all that unusual.
Wishing for something so strongly
you'd gladly trade your life for it...
There must be countless
people in this world...
...who have such wishes in their hearts.
Most likely...
It means the two of us who can't even
figure out what to wish for...
...haven't experienced even a fraction
of those people's suffering.
We've been so blessed...
...that we've become ignorant fools.
...Why us, of all people?
Doesn't it seem unfair?
There are probably people who would
give anything for a chance like this...
Sayaka...
It's all right.
Picking up where you left off yesterday?
No. I have no such intention.
I had hoped to kill it before it made
contact with Madoka Kaname,
but it is too late for that now...
So what will you do?
Will you become a magical girl as well?
I...
Like you have any right to ask us anything!
...Do you remember what I said yesterday?
Yeah...
Good. Then I'll pray that my warning
will not have been in vain.
H-Homura!
Um...
What did you wish for when
you became a magical girl?
Hitomi!
Sorry, but the two of us have a few
small errands to run today, so...
Oh, my. Something private?
Um...
I'm so jealous!
I guess there's just no room anymore...
...for a third wheel like meeeee!!
Once again, you've got it totally wrong...
Miss Akemi...
You're finally going to come have
coffee with us after school, right?
...I have some urgent business
to attend to today as well.
My apologies.
Aww...
Now, then!
Shall we begin Lesson 1 of our little "A
Day in the Life of a Magical Girl" class?
Are you ready?
I don't know if it'll be any help, but...
...I brought this along!
I figured it was better than having
nothing to defend ourselves with.
Well, I'm glad you're going into
this with that kind of mindset.
How about you, Madoka? Bring anything?
Huh?!
Well... I...
Ooh!
I-I thought maybe I should at least start
thinking about costume ideas...
Huh?!
Well, you've certainly brought
enough enthusiasm!
Well, I can't top that! You totally beat me...!
These are remnants of the magic used
by that witch we faced yesterday.
The core of witch-hunting is
scouting the city on foot.
Once your Soul Gem picks
up a witch's trail,
you just follow it until it
leads you to the witch.
It's a lot less exciting than I was expecting.
The Gem doesn't seem to
be glowing any brighter.
It's because it's been a full night
since the witch escaped.
There are fewer footprints around
to catch hold of now.
What if you had gone after
it right away yesterday?
I may have been able to finish it off.
But it wasn't worth leaving the two of you
alone after what you'd been through.
...I'm sorry.
It's fine.
Yep! You truly are an ally of justice, Mami!
On the other hand, what is with
that transfer student?!
She really pisses me off!
Is she really a bad person...?
Say, Mami...
Do you at least have an idea
of where the witch might be?
You often find traces of witches' auras...
...around car crashes or deadly accidents.
That's why I usually check high-traffic streets
and spots in the Red Light District...
...where fights tend to break out first.
Also, out-of-the-way places where people
might try to commit suicide.
Then, there are hospitals--the most
awful places for a witch to take up.
It's unbearable to see them...
...draining the precious life force...
out of those who are already weakened
with pain and illness.
It's reacting to some very powerful magic.
It must be close.
There's no mistake!
It must be here!
Mami, look!
A Witch's Kiss...
Just as I expected.
I-is she...?
No, she's fine. She's only fainted.
Let's go!
I won't let you escape this time!
Wh-whoa!
Wow!
It's not much,
but it should serve to protect you from
any immediate dangers at least.
You must stay near me once
we're inside, all right?
Right!
Stay away!
Stay away!!
So?
Are you scared yet, you two?
A-As if!
I am scared...
But...
Keep it up!
We're almost at the deepest
point in the labyrinth!
Look.
That is a witch.
Eww... Disgusting...
Y-you're going to fight that thing?
I'll be fine.
As though I would lose to that!
Stay back!!
Mami!!
I'm fine.
As though I could let myself look so uncool
in front of my future magical girl juniors!
Close, but no cigar.
Tiro Finale!
S-she beat it...?
Amazing...!
This is a Grief Seed.
It's a witch's egg.
E-egg?!
Witches carry them sometimes. If you’re
lucky, you’ll find one after a battle.
It's all right. In this form,
they're perfectly safe.
In fact, they're incredibly valuable
because of what they can do.
The color of my Soul Gem looks a little
muddier now than it did last night, right?
Now that you mention it...
But if I use the Grief Seed...
See?
Oh! It cleared up again!
Right?
With this, the magic I expended during
the fight is restored as well.
When I said there were certain
rewards to defeating witches,
I meant this.
It should be good for one more use.
I'll let you have it...
...Miss Homura Akemi.
Her again?!
Or do you dislike sharing with others?
It was your kill.
You should keep the reward for yourself.
I see.
So that's your answer.
Ugh! She really does bug me!
We could have been friends...
It only works if both parties feel that way.
Where am I? Huh? I...
O-oh my god, what was I about to...?
Why would I...?
It's okay. You're safe now.
You were just having
a bad dream, that's all.
Well, that's one case closed.
Yeah...
It's too confusing, figuring out
what I would wish for...
But Mami looked so amazing when
she was fighting to save people...
If even someone like me...
...could go around truly helping
people like that...
...I think that would be...
...truly wonderful.
“Soreja matane” tte te wo futte
I say “See you later” and wave my hand
Murini waratte samishiku natte...
I force myself to smile but I feel sad
Kousaten, shingou, tookuno kurakushon
Crossroads, traffic signals, horns from far away...
Shiranai darekano waraiau koe
And laughter of people I don't know
Kyou wa hitoride aruku kayoi nareta machi
When walking alone in the town where I’ve walked many times
Demo itsumo yori mo nanndaka jibun ga chotto chiisaku omoeruyo
But I feel that I am smaller than usual
“Soreja matane” tte te wo futte
I say “See you later” and wave my hand
Egao tsukutte samishiku natte...
I fake a smile and I feel sad
Honto wa mada hanashi tarinai kedo
To be honest, I wanted to talk with you more
“Soreja matane” tte kotoba de
I would say “See you later”
Mata aerutte uso wo tsuite
I lied when I told you I'd see you again
Itsumo dourino egao de iuyo
I will tell you that with the usual smile on my face
“Mata ashita”
“See you tomorrow”
I only pretend to be cool.
I'm really pushing myself hard.
Even when I'm scared, or hurting,
there's no one I can talk to.
All I can do is cry on my own.
It isn't a good thing... to be a magical girl.
EPISODE 3: I'M NOT AFRAID OF ANYTHING ANYMORE
I'm not afraid of anything anymore.