Hi...
Here. For you.
Really, thank you so much for all of this.
You're really some kind genius
at finding rare CDs, aren't you?
Nah!
I just get lucky, that's all.
This soloist's interpretations
are really incredible.
Do you want to try listening
to it too, Sayaka?
I-if you don't mind...
I wish I could play this on a speaker for
you, but we are in a hospital, after all...
Kawashita yakusoku wasurenai yo
I won't forget our promise we made
Me wo toji tashikameru
I close my eyes to make sure
Oshiyoseta yami
I will move forward,
Furiharatte susumuyo
shaking off the surging darkness
Itsuni nattara nakushita mirai wo
When can I see the future that I lost
Watashi kokode mata mirukoto dekiruno?
Here in this place once again?
Afuredashita fuan no kage wo
Tearing up the shadow of anxiety
Nando demo saite
That floods into me many times
Kono sekai ayunde ikou
I will keep walking in this world
Tomedonaku kizamareta
Time that is endlessly ticking
Toki wa ima hajimari tsuge
now starts
Kawaranai omoi wo nose
With our everlasting passion,
Tozasareta tobira akeyou
And open the door that has been closed
Mezameta kokoro wa hashiridashita
Our awakened souls
Mirai wo egaku tame
Set out to paint our rising future
Muzukashii michi de tachi domattemo
Even if we get stuck on a troubled path
Sora wa kireina aosa de itsumo mattete kureru
The beautiful blue sky always waits for us
Dakara kowaku nai
So I won't be afraid of anything
Mou naniga attemo kujikenai
Whatever happens, I won't give up
EPISODE 3: I'M NOT AFRAID OF ANYTHING ANYMORE
Tiro Finale!!
Maaan, you are so cool, Mami!
This isn't a magic show, you know.
Don't forget that what we're doing
here is very dangerous.
Right on!
It didn't drop a Grief Seed this time.
It's because that was only a witch's
familiar - not a witch itself.
Familiars don't carry Grief Seeds.
So that wasn’t a witch...
It seems like we've only been
fighting duds lately.
Yes, but we can't leave familiars
to do as they please.
If allowed to develop,
familiars become the same kind
of witch they broke off from.
Well, shall we go?
So have you figured out what to wish for?
Nah... How about you, Madoka?
Uh-uh...
That's how it goes, once someone tells
you to think hard about something.
What did you wish for, Mami?
Oh! I don't mean to pry if you
don't want to answer--
In my case...
...I didn't have the luxury
of thinking about it first.
It's not that I have any regrets.
I think the life I currently live...
...is far better than dying in that
place would have been.
But...
I'd like those who do have the chance
to think carefully before deciding.
I want them to have the
choice I didn't have.
Hey, Mami...
If you make a wish, does it
have to be for yourself?
Huh?
For example - and this is really
just an example, okay?
Say there was someone who was having
a way tougher time than I am,
and I wanted to make my wish to help him.
Are you talking about Kamijo?
I said this was just an example!!
There's no requirement that the wish's
beneficiary be the contractee herself.
There's even precedent for it already.
But it may not be the best idea.
If you want to use your wish
to grant someone else's,
then you must make doubly sure you
know what you're wishing for.
Miki, do you truly wish for
his dream to come true?
Or do you actually wish to grant his dream
so that he will be grateful to you?
Mami...!
They sound similar, but they're completely
different at the core.
You know?
...That's a little harsh, isn't it?
I'm sorry.
But this really needs to be said
now, before it's too late.
Because if you go ahead with
it without making certain first,
you're sure to regret it later.
...You're right.
I guess my idea was a little naïve.
Sorry.
It really is a hard decision, isn't it?
There's no need to rush into it.
Though for me, the sooner
you decide, the better.
That's no good, Kyubey.
Nobody likes a boy who pressures
girls to do things.
It really isn't an easy decision, is it?
And considering my position, I can't
rush you into deciding either.
Suggesting wishes would
also be against the rules.
So I guess just wishing to become
a magical girl wouldn't work, huh?
Is power for its own sake what
you desire, Madoka?
It isn't that.
...Or... Maybe it IS that...
I mean, I'm not very smart, and
I don’t really have any talents.
So if I could become someone as
cool and wonderful as Mami...
...I'd be more than happy with just that.
If you became a magical girl, Madoka,
you'd be much more powerful than Mami.
Huh?
Though, of course, part of that depends
on what kind of wish you make.
Even I can't completely gauge how large
the Soul Gem you'd create would be.
I've never met another girl with such
enormous potential as you.
Oh, come on!
You're just teasing me, right?
No...
Madoka? Are you awake?
Yes. What's wrong?
Oh, not again.
Oh, Mom...
W-water...
...that balding old coot...!
If he wants a drink so badly, he can
damn well pour it himself...!
Thanks.
Shall I make us some hot chocolate?
Yes, please!
I wonder why she loves to work so much.
I mean, it wasn't always her dream
to work for that company, was it?
Hmm...
It isn't so much that Mom
enjoys her work...
What she really likes is trying
her best at something.
Even though she encounters lots
of trying and unpleasant things...
...the satisfaction she gets from
overcoming those challenges...
...is what she treasures most in this world.
So even though working at a company
wasn't necessarily her dream...
...the way she is living her life
is absolutely ideal to her.
It's possible to achieve your dreams
in that way as well, you know.
So the way she lives her
life was her dream?
Different people might have
different opinions of that...
But as for me, that's something
I really love about her.
I respect the way she leads her
life and am very proud of her.
She truly is amazing, isn't she?
Yeah.
You do understand, don’t you?
That you're leading innocent
bystanders into real danger?
They were chosen by Kyubey.
They're not innocent
bystanders anymore.
You're trying to lead them so that
they want to be magical girls.
And you don't like that, I take it?
No. It's a problem.
...Particularly in the case
of Madoka Kaname.
I see. So you've noticed
it as well, have you?
That she has incredible potential.
She is the one person I absolutely cannot
allow to make the contract.
Afraid that a magical girl stronger
than you will get in your way?
That's the way a bullied child thinks.
I have no wish to fight you, but...
Then take care to ensure that our
paths will never cross again.
Tonight will probably be the last time...
...that we will be able to speak
without coming to blows.
Hey. Sorry for the wait.
Huh? Weren't you able
to see Kamijo today?
Apparently, he couldn't be inconvenienced
to see me today or something.
Seriously, after I took all the trouble
to come here. How rude!
What's wrong?
There's... something over there.
A Grief Seed!
It's about to hatch!
No way! Why here of all places...?
This isn't good. We have to get out of here!
A Labyrinth is about to open up here!
You mean one of those crazy mazes?!
Madoka, do you have Mami's
phone number on you?
N-no...
This isn't good...
Madoka, find Mami and bring her here.
I'll stay here and keep an eye on that thing.
No!
That's too dangerous.
Though there's still time before
the witch emerges,
once the labyrinth pulls you inside,
you won't be able to leave it.
There's no guarantee that Mami
will get here in time to save you.
But once the labyrinth opens, we'll
lose track of the witch, won't we?
I can't afford to let that happen. Not here...
Madoka, you go on ahead.
I'll stay here with Sayaka.
Huh?
Once Mami gets here, she'll be able
to track my position using telepathy.
So if I stay and watch the
Grief Seed with Sayaka,
I'll be able to guide Mami...
...down the shortest path to us.
Thank you, Kyubey!
Then, I'll find Mami and bring
her here as fast as I can!
Are you frightened, Sayaka?
Well, yeah... that kind of
goes without saying.
If you were just to decide upon a wish...
...I could turn you into a magical
girl right here and now.
OPERATION IN PROGRESS
Right.
If things get bad enough,
I may ask you to do that.
But I'll hold off for now.
Because this is such an important
decision to me...
...I don't want to make it rashly if possible.
Here, right?
Kyubey, what's the situation?
We're still okay.
It looks like the witch isn't
going to hatch just yet.
Sayaka, are you okay?
Totally fine.
I'm so bored I'm about to doze off in here!
Right now,
it'd be better not to use any large amounts
of magic that might disturb the egg.
There's no need to hurry,
so come to us as quietly as you can.
Got it.
Thank goodness we made it in time.
Though Sayaka took such a huge
risk that I'm actually a bit angry...
But in this one case, it was a good,
clear-headed call on her part.
This way, we won't have to worry
about the witch getting a--
I thought I told you I didn't
want to see you again.
I shall hunt this prey.
The two of you should leave here.
I don't think so.
Miki and Kyubey are waiting
for us in there.
I shall guarantee their safety.
And you think we could trust you?
F-fool!
This isn't the time for--
I don't want to hurt you, of course.
But if you insist on struggling,
the cords will only tighten.
This witch is not like the others!
Behave and I will release you unharmed
after I finish up here.
Let's go, Kaname.
O-okay.
Wai--!
Um... Mami?
What is it?
I've been thinking really hard about
all sorts of different wishes, but...
Did you decide on one?
Yes.
But, I think it might be the naïve kind
of wish that would make you mad...
So what is this dream you want granted?
Well, I've never been good at school,
and I don’t have any kind of talent
that I could take pride in...
And I'm sure I'll continue on like this,
being no use to anyone and having
to bother others for help...
Thinking about that makes me
feel so awful, I can't stand it.
But then I met you, Mami.
And you showed me what it's like...
...to fight to save people.
And then...
...when I heard that even I might
be able to do the same thing...
...it was the happiest thing I'd
ever experienced in my life.
That's why, I think that just becoming
a magical girl would fulfill my dreams.
If someone like me can help people
and live my life with pride...
That would be my greatest dream.
It won't be easy, you know?
You'll get injured,
and you won't have time to go on
dates or have fun with friends.
Even so, after watching the way
you keep doing your very best...
...I really look up to you, Mami.
I'm really not worth looking up to.
Huh?
I only push myself and pretend to be cool.
Even when I'm scared, or hurting,
there's no one I can talk to.
All I can do is cry on my own.
It isn't a good thing...
to be a magical girl.
But you're not alone any more, Mami.
You're right...
I'm not alone anymore, am I?
Will you really stand and fight
with me from now on?
Will you really stay with me?
Yes. If someone like me will do.
Oh, goodness!
Some role model I'm supposed to be.
I'm really no good at this, am I?
Mami...
Still, it's not every day you
can have a wish granted.
So try to think of something you want.
Yeah, it is a special chance, isn't it?
You're still making a contract, after all,
so you may as well get something out of it.
You could wish to become a billionaire,
or maybe to have a perfect boyfriend.
Anything you want.
Um, but...
Okay, then how about this?
If you can't decide on a wish by
the time I finish off this witch...
...we'll ask Kyubey to give us a huge
feast with a fabulous cake!
C-cake?!
Yep!
The biggest and most
extravagant cake ever!
And with it, we'll have a
big party for everyone--
To celebrate the two of us becoming
a magical girl duo!
But I can't become a magical
girl for a cake!
No? Then decide on a wish
you really do want.
Mami!
The Grief Seed's moving!
It's going to hatch! Hurry!
Okay! I've got it.
Today's a special day,
so I'll finish it off fast!
Wah! B-but--
I feel so light today.
This is the first time I've felt
so happy during a fight.
I'm not afraid of anything anymore.
Because... I'm not alone anymore!
Sorry for the wait!
You're just in time!
Be careful. It's coming!
Sorry to rain on your parade.
But I'm going to finish you right here!
Got you!
You did it!
TIRO--
FINALE!!
It can't be...
You two! Make a contract
with me right now!!
Madoka! Sayaka!
Decide on a wish! Hurry!
That won't be necessary.
I shall be the one to slay it.
A moment later and you
would have been dead.
Burn this sight into your minds.
This is what it means to be a magical girl.
...Give it back.
Give it back! That--
That belongs to Mami...!
I said to give it back! Back to Mami!
That's right. This belongs
only to magical girls.
Neither of you has any right to touch it.
Itsuka kimi ga hitomi ni tomosu
The light of love
Ai no hikari ga
You will turn on in your eyes
Toki wo koete
Someday will go beyond time
Horobi isogu sekai no yume wo
And surely shatter a dream of the world
Tashika ni hitotsu kowasu darou
That is rushing towards destruction
Tamerai wo nomihoshite
What do you wish for
Kimi ga nozomu mono wa nani?
After swallowing up all of that hesitance?
Konna yokubukai akogare no yukue ni
Is there an ephemeral tomorrow
Hakanai ashita wa aruno?
At the end of this greedy admiration?
Kodomo no koro yume ni miteta
Using an ancient magic
Inishie no mahou no youni
That I used to dream of as a child
Yami sae kudaku chikara de
I want to break the darkness
Hohoemu kimi ni aitai
And see you smiling
Obieru kono te no naka niwa
The only thing left in my scared hand
Taorareta hana no yuuki
Is the courage of a broken flower
Omoi dake ga tayoru subete
All I can trust is my wish
Hikari wo yobisamasu negai
And my wish would awaken the light
Mami... was truly a kind-hearted person.
To make us really understand what kind
of resolve we'd need in order to fight...
...she...
EPISODE 4: MIRACLES AND MAGIC ARE REAL
Miracles and magic are real.