Oh, are you here to see Kamijo?
Y-yes.
I'm sorry.
His examination schedule got moved up,
so he's in Physical Therapy right now.
Oh, I see.
Thank you.
She comes to see him quite
often, doesn't she?
It's a big help.
He's a difficult case, that boy.
I really hope she'll become the
encouragement he needs to get better.
Before the accident, he was a child
prodigy, wasn't he? On the violin?
Even if he's able to walk
again, his fingers...
...will probably never recover
enough to play again...
Why did it have to be Kyosuke?
My fingers work perfectly,
but what good are they?
Why couldn't it have been
me instead of Kyosuke?
If I were to use my wish to heal his body...
...what would Kyosuke think about that?
Would he just say, "thank you" and
that would be the end of it?
Or am I hoping he'll say something more?
I'm...
...such a horrible person...
Now that I think about it, I really didn't
understand anything back then.
Neither what it meant
to pray for a miracle...
...nor the price of one.
Kawashita yakusoku wasurenai yo
I won't forget our promise we made
Me wo toji tashikameru
I close my eyes to make sure
Oshiyoseta yami
I will move forward,
Furiharatte susumuyo
shaking off the surging darkness
Itsuni nattara nakushita mirai wo
When can I see the future that I lost
Watashi kokode mata mirukoto dekiruno?
Here in this place once again?
Afuredashita fuan no kage wo
Tearing up the shadow of anxiety
Nando demo saite
That floods into me many times
Kono sekai ayunde ikou
I will keep walking in this world
Tomedonaku kizamareta
Time that is endlessly ticking
Toki wa ima hajimari tsuge
now starts
Kawaranai omoi wo nose
With our everlasting passion,
Tozasareta tobira akeyou
And open the door that has been closed
Mezameta kokoro wa hashiridashita
Our awakened souls
Mirai wo egaku tame
Set out to paint our rising future
Muzukashii michi de tachi domattemo
Even if we get stuck on a troubled path
Sora wa kireina aosa de itsumo mattete kureru
The beautiful blue sky always waits for us
Dakara kowaku nai
So I won't be afraid of anything
Mou naniga attemo kujikenai
Whatever happens, I won't give up
EPISODE 4: MIRACLES AND MAGIC ARE REAL
Madoka!
If you don't hurry and eat,
you'll be late for school.
Oh... right...
Sis, wat's wong?
D-does it taste bad, honey?
No... It tastes good.
Really, really good...
I'm alive... And your cooking...
tastes so good, Dad...
So I was like, "Jeez, Yuka!"
"You still don’t get it even after all that?!"
And she was like,
"Huh? Did I say something weird
again?" and got all weepy.
I wanted to laugh so bad!
Sayaka... About yesterday...
Sorry, but can we talk about it later?
While a woman's prime age for childbirth
is indeed based in medical fact...
...counting backwards from there...
...to determine whether she
is of a marriageable age...
...is an extremely grave mistake!
In other words...
...of course women over the age of 30...
...still have a chance of marrying
for love. Therefore...
...we would use the present progressive
tense here instead of the past perfect--
It... feels like we're in a foreign
country or something.
Even though nothing about school or
Hitomi has changed since yesterday...
Somehow, it feels like I'm surrounded
by strangers...
It's because no one knows.
No one knows about witches... or Mami...
It's because we know,
and no one else does.
It's like we're seeing and living in an
entirely different world from them.
Sayaka?
But our world had already
changed long before this.
We should have realized that sooner.
Madoka, do you still want to
be a magical girl, even now?
Yeah, I know.
Well, I can't blame you.
I know it's unfair...
I know it's way too selfish of
me to back out now, but...
But I just can't.
Just thinking about the way she died...
Even now, it gets so hard to breathe...
I'm scared... I don't want that...!
Mami was truly a kind-hearted person.
To make us really understand...
...what kind of resolve we'd
need in order to fight, she...
Hey, Kyubey... What's going
to happen to this town?
Who's going to fight to protect everyone
from the witches from now on?
This town has been Mami's
territory for a long time.
But once the other magical girls realize
she's gone, they won't stay back for long.
I'm sure one of them will arrive
here soon to hunt witches.
But all they care about are
finding Grief Seeds, right?
Just like that transfer student.
It's true that magical girls
like Mami are rare.
Most do approach witch-hunting
with their own benefit in mind.
But it's natural for people to want
to be rewarded for their work.
Then--
But I think the only ones who have
a right to judge their actions...
...are their fellow magical girls, who
bear the same destiny they do.
All right, I understand.
It really is an awful shame, but
I can't force you, after all.
I guess this is good-bye then.
I'd better go search for girls with greater
need to make a contract with me.
I'm sorry, Kyubey.
No, I should apologize for getting
you mixed up in all this.
Though we weren't together for long,
thank you, Madoka. It was fun.
I'm sorry...
MAMI TOMOE
I'm sorry.
For being so weak...
I'm sorry...
Homura...
You're blaming yourself too much
for this, Madoka Kaname.
Huh?
No one could criticize you
for anything you've done.
And even if they did, I wouldn't permit it.
It seems you've taken my warning to heart.
Yeah...
If I had only listened to you earlier...
It wouldn't have changed
Mami Tomoe's fate.
But I was able to change yours.
I'm glad I was able to save
at least one person.
S-say, Homura...
You seem like you're a veteran too. Though
in a different way from Mami...
Perhaps. I won't deny it, at least.
Have you seen a lot of people
die like yesterday?
Yes.
How many?
Too many to try keeping count of anymore.
I wonder if Mami's apartment
will just stay like that.
Mami Tomoe had no close relations.
It will be a long time before a missing
person's report will even be filed for her.
Then, no one will even know
that Mami is dead?
It can't be helped.
If someone dies on the other side,
there won't be a body left behind.
In this world, she will simply remain
a missing person forever.
That is the end that all magical girls meet.
That's horrible!
She fought to protect everyone
for so long on her own!
To think that no one will even
realize she's dead...
...that's just too sad!
That is the nature of the contract
that grants us the power we hold.
And we don't fight to protect people.
We fight for the sake of our own wishes.
If our deaths go unnoticed by others...
and we are ultimately forgotten
by this world...
I suppose that cannot be helped.
I won't forget...
I'll never forget about Mami!
Never!
I see.
I'm sure with that alone, Mami
Tomoe must truly be happy.
I envy her.
You too, Homura!
You too--
I swear I'll never forget you either!
I'll never forget...
...the way you saved us yesterday!
Homura...?
You're too kind for your own good.
Huh?
Remember this...
That kindness may bring about
an even greater tragedy.
What are you listening to?
"The Girl With the Flaxen Hair."
Ah, by Debussy, right?
It's such a beautiful song!
I-I guess I don't strike people as the type
who would listen to classical music.
Sometimes, people get so surprised
when I can name a piece like that.
I guess it's so unexpected, people
sometimes get impressed with me.
It's only because you taught
me about all this.
If not for you, I may never have given
classical music a real chance.
Maybe not for my whole life, even.
Hey, Sayaka...
What is it?
Are you torturing me?
Why are you still making
me listen to music?
Are you trying to cause me more pain?
But I thought you loved music, Kyosuke...
I don't want to hear it anymore!
I don't want to hear these songs
that I can't ever play again--
That I can only ever listen to anymore!
I just... I just...
I can't move it...
I can't even feel the pain anymore!
What use is a hand like this...?
It's going to be okay.
I'm sure someday, somehow...
Just don't give up hope,
and I'm sure someday--
But they've already told me to give up.
They said I had no chance
of ever performing again.
The doctor came and told me himself.
He said that with current medicine,
it just wasn't possible.
My hand will never move again.
Not until the day miracles or magic
start existing in this world.
They do exist.
Miracles... and magic... are real!
Homura...
When I actually tried talking with her, it
seemed like we could really be friends.
So why did she end up fighting with Mami?
Huh?
Hitomi?
Hitomi!
Don't you have your lessons to--
Huh? It's the same as that woman's--
Hitomi!
Hey! Hitomi, come on!
Ah, Kaname! Good evening.
What's happened to you?
Where are you going?
Where am I going, you ask?
I'm going somewhere
far better than here...
Hitomi...
Oh, yes. You simply must come along!
Yes, indeed. It would be so wonderful!
What should I do?
This couldn't be...?
If only I could contact Homura...
Oh, but I don't have her cell phone number!
It's true... I'm completely... worthless...
I couldn't even keep such
a tiny factory running...
In an era like this one...
...there's just no place
for someone like me...
Listen closely, Madoka.
Don't ever mistake this one for the
other, or the results could be fatal.
Our entire family could end up dead.
Make sure you never mix up these bottles.
Stop!
You can't use those!
You mustn't interfere.
This is a sacred ceremony.
But those chemicals! They're dangerous!
Everyone here will die!
That's right.
All of us are going to journey to a
magnificent new world together.
Don't you see how wonderful that will be?
These physical bodies would
simply get in our way.
Kaname, I'm sure you'll
understand very soon...
Let go of me!
W-what should I do?! What should I do?!
No!! No...
This can't...
No! Someone help me!
I wonder if this...
...is my punishment.
For being...
...a coward...
...and a liar.
I guess this...
...is a fitting punishment.
Sayaka?!
This is the end for you!!
Hey, sorry about that!
I cut it pretty darn close, didn't I?
Sayaka...
Those clothes...
Huh? Oh...
Uh, well. Guess I had a change of heart.
Oh, I'll be fine!
After all, I did pretty well for
my first time out, didn't I?
But...
You...
Aren't you pretty late, Transfer Student?
I didn’t think you would come...
I heard ol' Mami had bought it.
So I came all this way.
But what's the deal?!
Sure looks like the story's changed
from what you told me.
Sorry, but this territory has already been
taken over by another magical girl.
Though she only just made the
contract a short while ago.
What?!
That really pisses me off!
But y'know...
I find the idea...
...of handing such prime territory
over to some rookie hatchling...
...to be pretty annoying.
What do you intend to do, Kyoko?
There's only one thing to do.
I'll put the new girl out of commission.
Permanently.
Itsuka kimi ga hitomi ni tomosu
The light of love
Ai no hikari ga
You will turn on in your eyes
Toki wo koete
Someday will go beyond time
Horobi isogu sekai no yume wo
And surely shatter a dream of the world
Tashika ni hitotsu kowasu darou
That is rushing towards destruction
Tamerai wo nomihoshite
What do you wish for
Kimi ga nozomu mono wa nani?
After swallowing up all of that hesitance?
Konna yokubukai akogare no yukue ni
Is there an ephemeral tomorrow
Hakanai ashita wa aruno?
At the end of this greedy admiration?
Kodomo no koro yume ni miteta
Using an ancient magic
Inishie no mahou no youni
That I used to dream of as a child
Yami sae kudaku chikara de
I want to break the darkness
Hohoemu kimi ni aitai
And see you smiling
Obieru kono te no naka niwa
The only thing left in my scared hand
Taorareta hana no yuuki
Is the courage of a broken flower
Omoi dake ga tayoru subete
All I can trust is my wish
Hikari wo yobisamasu negai
And my wish would awaken the light
I'm really getting fired up for this now.
From here on, I - Magical Girl Sayaka -
will keep Mitakihara City super-duper
safe and sound!
EPISODE 5: THERE'S NO WAY I'LL EVER REGRET IT
There's no way I'll ever regret it.