You can really grant any wish, right?
Don't worry.
Your wish is absolutely grantable.
So... Ready?
Yes. Do it.
Now...
Open yourself and accept it.
This is your destiny.
Kawashita yakusoku wasurenai yo
I won't forget our promise we made
Me wo toji tashikameru
I close my eyes to make sure
Oshiyoseta yami
I will move forward,
Furiharatte susumuyo
shaking off the surging darkness
Itsuni nattara nakushita mirai wo
When can I see the future that I lost
Watashi kokode mata mirukoto dekiruno?
Here in this place once again?
Afuredashita fuan no kage wo
Tearing up the shadow of anxiety
Nando demo saite
That floods into me many times
Kono sekai ayunde ikou
I will keep walking in this world
Tomedonaku kizamareta
Time that is endlessly ticking
Toki wa ima hajimari tsuge
now starts
Kawaranai omoi wo nose
With our everlasting passion,
Tozasareta tobira akeyou
And open the door that has been closed
Mezameta kokoro wa hashiridashita
Our awakened souls
Mirai wo egaku tame
Set out to paint our rising future
Muzukashii michi de tachi domattemo
Even if we get stuck on a troubled path
Sora wa kireina aosa de itsumo mattete kureru
The beautiful blue sky always waits for us
Dakara kowaku nai
So I won't be afraid of anything
Mou naniga attemo kujikenai
Whatever happens, I won't give up
EPISODE 5: THERE'S NO WAY I'LL EVER REGRET IT
Oh, how crass of me.
Please excuse me.
What's the matter, Hitomi?
Didn't get enough sleep?
Yes, I was kept up so late dealing with
the police and the hospital last night.
Huh? Did something happen?
Apparently, I went sleepwalking
or some such thing...
Oddly enough, there were many other
people who did the same thing.
When we woke up, we were all collapsed
in the same place together.
Huh? What was that about?
The doctor said we'd had a mass
hallucination or something of the sort.
In fact, I have to go back in for
more tests after school today.
Ohh, what a bother.
After all that, you should've
just stayed home today.
Oh, I couldn't do that.
If I had stayed home, it would
really seem like I was sick.
And my family would just get
more and more worried.
That's our little overachiever! Good for you.
It's been a while since I've felt this good.
I'm totally refreshed!
Sayaka... Aren't you scared at all?
Huh?
Well, I am a little.
But I was able to beat that witch
yesterday pretty easily.
And when I think of how I might've
lost both of my best friends...
...that scares me a lot more.
Which is why...
I don’t really know what to call
it. Self-confidence, maybe?
Or relief?
I guess I'm a little bit proud
of myself right now, too.
Anyway!
I'm really getting fired up for this now.
From here on, I - Magical Girl Sayaka -
will keep Mitakihara City super-duper
safe and sound!
You really don't have any regrets at all?
Well... If I have any regret...
...it's probably that I hesitated for so long.
Since I ended up doing it anyway,
I feel like I should have made
up my mind sooner.
If I had been there to fight
that witch with Mami,
then maybe she wouldn't have had to die.
I...
Come on, you're not thinking
something silly, are you?
I... I should've...
It's easy for me to say so only because
I have become one already.
The important thing is that
I've made my decision.
Honestly, I really do think I was
meant to be a magical girl.
Sayaka...
After all, I found something
I truly wished for.
Something that I wouldn't mind having
to risk my life fighting for.
Having a wish that strong
gives me reason enough.
I guess the one frustrating thing...
...is how long it took me to realize
how much it meant to me.
Which is to say, you have
no reason to feel guilty.
This just means there's no problem if you
don't want to become a magical girl.
Anyhow! It's about time I got going.
Do you have something
to do this afternoon?
Yeah, sort of.
I see. So they're not discharging you yet?
I've still got to finish my leg rehabilitation.
After all, I can't do much anything
until I can walk again.
Plus, we still have no idea why my
hand suddenly healed like that.
So the doctors want me to stay
to run a few more tests on it.
And how do you feel, Kyosuke?
Does any part of your body
feel strange at all?
No. In fact, I feel so fine
that it's a little scary.
The accident almost feels
like a bad dream now.
So much so that I sometimes wonder
what I'm doing in this bed.
It's just like you said, Sayaka...
It's a miracle.
What's the matter?
I... said some really awful
things to you, Sayaka.
Just because I was depressed,
it doesn't excuse--
Oh, forget about stuff like that!
Right now, you should be completely
over-the-moon happy about your hand.
So don't make a face like that.
Right...
Though it still hasn't really sunk in.
Well, that's no surprise.
Ah, it's about time.
Kyosuke, why don't we
go out for some air?
What are we going to the roof for?
You'll see.
Why are all of you...?
We'll have the real party after you get
released from the hospital, but...
Since your hand healed already...
Is that...?
You told me to get rid of it, but...
I just couldn't bear to throw it away.
I...
Go on, give it a try.
Don't be afraid.
Mami...
My wish has been granted.
There's no way I'll ever regret it.
This is the happiest moment of my life.
So that's the city's new magical girl, huh?
Are you really going to
pick a fight with her?
Sure, seems like an easy win to me.
She won't even know what hit her.
Or, what?
You got a problem with that?
It may not all work out
the way you imagine.
There is another magical girl in this city.
Huh? Who is it?
I'm not really sure myself.
Huh? What's that supposed to mean?
If she's a magical girl, she must've
made a contract with you, right?
You could say yes. You could also say no.
She's quite the "irregularity."
Even I can't guess when
or where she'll strike.
Hmm... Sounds good to me!
Gettin’ kinda boring around here, anyway.
Gotta shake things up once
in a while after all!
You said you wanted to talk?
Um, well... It's about Sayaka...
S-she gets offended easily,
and she's stubborn, and she's quick
to start arguments sometimes, but...
But she's really a wonderful person!
She's kind-hearted and brave,
and if she thinks someone needs help,
she'll try really hard for them...
All fatal flaws for a magical girl.
R-really?
Unchecked kindness grows into naïveté,
and brash courage often leads
one to be caught off guard.
Further, no matter how hard you try,
there is no thanks or recompense.
Those who cannot comprehend that
are not fit to be magical girls.
That is why Mami Tomoe lost her life.
Don't talk about Mami that way!
Anyway... Sayaka says she'll
be all right by herself.
But...
When I think about how what happened
to Mami might happen to her...
I just don't know what to do.
You're worried about Sayaka Miki, then?
I can't do anything to help
her myself, so I...
I was hoping that I could
ask you, Homura...
Please become friends with Sayaka.
And please don't fight with
her like you did with Mami.
Because if all of us work together
when we go to fight witches...
...it's sure to be a lot safer for everyone.
I don't like to tell lies.
And I don't make promises
I can't keep, either.
Which is why I'm telling you to
give up on Sayaka Miki now.
But why...?
She should not have made the contract.
I admit it was an oversight on my part.
I should have kept a close watch
on her, as I did on you.
Then -
But as I acknowledge my responsibility,
you must understand as well.
This is a mistake from which
she can never be recovered.
Just as the dead don't return to
life, consider her fate sealed.
Once you become a magical girl,
you have no hope of salvation.
When we make our contracts,
we give up everything in exchange
for a single wish.
Does that mean you've
given up too, Homura?
Both on yourself and on all the other girls?
Yes.
I won't make excuses for myself.
No matter what sins I bear,
I must continue my fight.
It seems I've wasted your time.
I apologize.
Are you nervous?
Yeah, kind of.
After all, one mistake and I'm done for.
Madoka?
Sayaka... Are you going to...?
Yep! Time to patrol for wicked witches!
After all, that's a duty of any ally of justice!
Will you really be all right on your own?
I'll be just fine.
Mami always did this on her own too.
As her successor, I can
do that much, at least!
Um... I know I can't do anything to help,
and I'll probably just get in your way...
But -
As long as I'm not being a bother -
For as far as you can take me...
Please let me come with you?
Aren't you trying a little too hard?
I-I'm sorry...
I'm asking too much. I
knew I'd be a bother...
No - I'm really happy you asked!
You could tell, couldn't you?
That my hands were shaking?
They haven't stopped this whole time.
Pathetic, aren't I?
Even though I've become a
full-fledged magical girl,
I get so scared when I'm alone...
Sayaka...
You wouldn't be a bother.
I'd really like you to come.
Just knowing I'll have someone with
me makes me feel incredibly brave!
I feel like I could beat up 100 bad guys!
I...
I swear I'll keep you safe.
So come with me, and don't
worry about a thing.
Let's go hunt witches together,
just like we used to.
Okay.
You understand how dangerous
this is, right?
I'm kind of an idiot,
so if I went alone, I'd probably do all sorts
of reckless things and get killed.
But with Madoka there, I'll think harder
about my actions and focus better.
I see.
Well, as long as you've thought
it through, it's fine with me.
Kyubey...
After all, you've thought up your own
plan too, haven't you, Madoka?
I understand your desire
to protect Sayaka.
Actually, just by coming with us,
you'll give us a trump card that we
can play if things really get bad.
I...
You don't have to say anything
about it now.
Sayaka is sure to be against it, after all.
But if ever the time comes when
you decide upon a wish...
...I will always be ready for you.
Okay.
This is it.
This labyrinth was probably made
by a familiar, not a witch.
It'd be nice if I can beat it easily.
I'm still new at this, after all.
Getting caught off guard could be fatal.
I know.
Is that it?!
It's getting away!
Leave it to me!
Hey, hold on now.
What do you think you're doing?
Wha...?
It's getting away!
Can't you tell just by looking at it?
That was a familiar, not a witch.
You weren't gonna get any Grief
Seeds off of that one.
But -
If we just leave it alone, it might
go off and kill someone!
I'm telling you.
You should wait for it to eat 4 or 5
people and become a real witch.
That way, you'll be sure to get
a Grief Seed when you kill it.
Seriously, what were you thinking killing
the goose before it laid its golden eggs?
What...?
What about the people it'll attack?
Are you just going to sit back
and let them get killed?
Listen, kid - you've got this whole
thing all wrong from the get-go.
Ever heard of the food chain?
They taught you about it in school, right?
Witches eat weak humans.
And in turn, we eat those witches.
It's the basic rule of this world.
The weak have to give way to the strong.
Oh no...
You...
Don't tell me...
...you actually believe in all that "saving
people" and "justice" crap?
You didn't actually make the contract
over that load of bull, did you?
And what if I did?
Come on. Give it up already.
The way you're butting into this
and acting like it's a game...
It kinda ticks me off.
Sayaka!
Hmph! What an amateur...
Go cool your head for a while.
Strange...
That should've put you out of commission
for at least 3 months.
Is Sayaka really okay?
It's because she made her contract
wishing for someone to be healed.
She heals twice as fast as a regular
human being does now.
Who... would lose to you?
It's because of magical girls
like you that Mami...
That pisses me off.
That REALLY pisses me off.
But seriously - you sure
have a mouth on you.
That's not how you're supposed
to speak to your elders.
Shut up!
This ain't the time to be jumping
around, dummy!
Sayaka...!
Madoka, it's dangerous for
you to get any closer!
You don't get it when I try to explain.
You don't get it when I beat it into you.
Guess there's no choice but
to kill an idiot like you!
I won't lose...
I won't lose to you!
Why...?
Why is this happening? She's not a witch.
Why are the two of them fighting
when they should be allies?
It can't be helped.
Neither of them is willing to back
down from the other now.
Please, Kyubey... Make them stop!
This can't be right!
I don't have the ability to stop them.
But...
If you're determined to stop them, even
if it means using force, there IS a way...
Only another magical girl could
get between them now.
But you have the qualifications
to become one, after all.
If you truly wish it, that is.
That's right...
I can make the contract...
It's over!
I...
There's no need for that.
Itsuka kimi ga hitomi ni tomosu
The light of love
Ai no hikari ga
You will turn on in your eyes
Toki wo koete
Someday will go beyond time
Horobi isogu sekai no yume wo
And surely shatter a dream of the world
Tashika ni hitotsu kowasu darou
That is rushing towards destruction
Tamerai wo nomihoshite
What do you wish for
Kimi ga nozomu mono wa nani?
After swallowing up all of that hesitance?
Konna yokubukai akogare no yukue ni
Is there an ephemeral tomorrow
Hakanai ashita wa aruno?
At the end of this greedy admiration?
Kodomo no koro yume ni miteta
Using an ancient magic
Inishie no mahou no youni
That I used to dream of as a child
Yami sae kudaku chikara de
I want to break the darkness
Hohoemu kimi ni aitai
And see you smiling
Obieru kono te no naka niwa
The only thing left in my scared hand
Taorareta hana no yuuki
Is the courage of a broken flower
Omoi dake ga tayoru subete
All I can trust is my wish
Hikari wo yobisamasu negai
And my wish would awaken the light
Sayaka, you became a magical girl in
order to fight witches, didn't you?
That girl isn't a witch. She's
a magical girl just like you.
EPISODE 6: THIS JUST CAN'T BE RIGHT
This just can't be right!