It's over!
Homura...?
You!
Wha--
What the hell did you do?
Oh, I see. You're that "irregularity",
aren't you?
What the heck kind of
magic are you using?
Stay out of our way!
Sayaka!
She's all right. She's only unconscious.
Who the hell are you?
Whose side are you on, anyway?
I am on the side of those
who think rationally,
and an enemy to those who
engage in needless conflict.
Which are you...
...Kyoko Sakura?
Have we met somewhere before?
Perhaps. Who knows?
Since I don't know anything about you...
Well, I'll be taking my leave for today.
That's wise of you.
You... saved us?
How many times must I warn you?
How foolish can you possibly be?
You should not become involved in this.
I've told you many times already.
But I...
If reasoning with a fool won't work, I
will turn to more drastic measures.
Homura... Why...?
In any case, it's certain that
she's planning something.
We'll have to be more careful than ever.
Homura Akemi... Could it be that you're...?
Kawashita yakusoku wasurenai yo
I won't forget our promise we made
Me wo toji tashikameru
I close my eyes to make sure
Oshiyoseta yami
I will move forward,
Furiharatte susumuyo
shaking off the surging darkness
Itsuni nattara nakushita mirai wo
When can I see the future that I lost
Watashi kokode mata mirukoto dekiruno?
Here in this place once again?
Afuredashita fuan no kage wo
Tearing up the shadow of anxiety
Nando demo saite
That floods into me many times
Kono sekai ayunde ikou
I will keep walking in this world
Tomedonaku kizamareta
Time that is endlessly ticking
Toki wa ima hajimari tsuge
now starts
Kawaranai omoi wo nose
With our everlasting passion,
Tozasareta tobira akeyou
And open the door that has been closed
Mezameta kokoro wa hashiridashita
Our awakened souls
Mirai wo egaku tame
Set out to paint our rising future
Muzukashii michi de tachi domattemo
Even if we get stuck on a troubled path
Sora wa kireina aosa de itsumo mattete kureru
The beautiful blue sky always waits for us
Dakara kowaku nai
So I won't be afraid of anything
Mou naniga attemo kujikenai
Whatever happens, I won't give up
EPISODE 6: THIS JUST CAN'T BE RIGHT
MIKI
There, you should be all right for a while.
Ugh, it's pitch black!
And it's dangerous now.
If it absorbs any more impurity,
a witch could hatch from it.
Huh?!
Don't worry. Give it to me.
Now it's safe again.
You ate it?
That's another one of my duties.
But before it comes time to
purify your Soul Gem again,
we'd better hurry and find
another Grief Seed.
Is it that important to keep
my Soul Gem clean?
Kyoko Sakura was powerful, wasn't she?
If you have extra Grief Seeds
to clean your Soul Gem with,
you could let loose and waste as much
magic as you want in any fight.
That's what makes Kyoko so strong.
But I can't let innocent people get hurt
just so I can find more Grief Seeds!
The more you use your magic, the more
polluted your Soul Gem will become.
Sakyaka, you'll never stand a
chance of defeating Kyoko...
unless you can gather more Grief Seeds.
Hmm... You really think so?
But Mami never had enough Grief Seeds
to keep her Soul Gem clean either.
But she was still able to fight just fine.
Was she just more talented than me?
Well, there's certainly that.
Aw, come on!
That's totally not fair!
That's one thing that really can't be helped.
Kyoko has great inborn talent,
plus plenty of experience.
That said, there's someone with
absolutely no experience...
...whose natural talent would
far exceed Kyoko's...
And who's that?
Madoka Kaname.
Madoka? Are you serious?
Yes.
Meaning, if you ultimately can't get
strong enough to defeat Kyoko,
you also have the option of
asking Madoka to do it.
That is, if she makes a contract with me!
No, that's no good.
This... is my fight, after all.
I won't let her get dragged into it.
CAUTION: NO FOOD OR DRINK ALLOWED.
NO SOLICITATIONS OR LOITERING.
Yo! So what do you want now?
I want to put this city in your charge.
And why the sudden change of heart?
Girls like you are most suited
to be magical girls.
Sayaka Miki is not qualified.
Hmph!
Well, that's what I was planning
from the start anyway.
So what about that Sayaka girl?
If I leave her alone, she'll probably
come bug me again.
I want that settled as peaceably
as possible.
You keep out of it.
I will handle her myself.
You haven't told me the most
important thing, though.
Who the heck are you?
What's in all of this for you?
Two weeks from now, "Walpurgisnacht"
will descend upon this city.
How do you know that?
That is a secret.
In any case, if we are able to defeat it,
I will leave this city, and you will be
free to do with it what you please.
"Walpurgisnacht," huh?
Guess it would be pretty tough
to beat it by yourself.
But if we double-teamed it,
we could probably win.
Want some?
It's no use. Too much time has passed.
It looks like we've got no way to trace
the familiar from last night.
I see...
Hey... Sayaka?
If we keep hunting witches like this,
won't we eventually run into that
girl from yesterday again?
Yeah... it seems pretty likely.
In that case,
maybe you should look for her ahead
of time and try talking with her first.
Otherwise you might end up
fighting again like yesterday.
"Fighting", you say?
Is that what last night looked
like to you? "Fighting"?
That was an honest-to-goodness
fight to the death.
It was only the first few blows
that weren't lethal.
After that,
both she and I were sincerely trying to kill
each other with every blow we struck.
But that's...!
That's even worse, then!
And you are telling me to talk with
her? That is completely insane!
She's willing to let people
become witch food...
...just so she can collect more Grief Seeds!
How could I ever be civil
with someone like that?!
Sayaka, you became a magical girl in
order to fight witches, didn't you?
That girl isn't a witch. She's
a magical girl just like you.
If you give her a chance, I’m sure you'll
find a way to become friends.
Even if your methods are different,
you both feel the same way about wanting
to hunt witches, don’t you?
I'm sure she does...
...and Homura, too.
I'm sure if Mami hadn't gotten into
a fight with her, she and Homura--
There's absolutely no way!
You saw her, didn't you, Madoka?!
She just waited...
...until that witch had murdered
Mami before she came to help.
Just because she wanted a Grief Seed,
she sat back and let Mami get killed!
No... that's not--
That transfer student and that Kyoko
girl... they're both the same.
They don't think about anything
but their own benefit!
I understand it now...
Mami was the one exception.
All the rest of the magical girls
are just like those two!
N-no...
That familiar from last night
might've been small,
but it could still kill someone.
And who knows, maybe its next
target will be your dad or mom.
It might even be little Tatsuya.
Would you be okay with it then, Madoka?
Could you forgive those who stood
by and let them get killed?
I didn't wish for this power just
so I could fight witches.
I wanted the strength to
protect those I love.
Which is why...
If there are humans who are worse than
witches out there, I'll fight them too.
Even if they happen to be magical girls!
Sayaka...
Kyubey, say something...
The only thing I could say to that
is that she's being too reckless.
As she is now,
Sayaka has no hope of defeating either
Homura Akemi or Kyoko Sakura.
But...
I'm sure Sayaka won't listen to me...
WELCOME HOME.
THERE'S SOME POTATO
SALAD IN THE FRIDGE.
-TOMO
Can't sleep?
No... Can we talk?
One of my friends... is in a lot of trouble.
I don't think anything she's doing
or saying is wrong, but...
Even though she keeps trying so hard to
do the right thing, the more she tries,
the worse things get for her...
That happens quite a bit.
It's sad to say,
but just because you keep
trying to do what's right...
doesn't mean you're guaranteed
a happy ending.
In fact, sometimes people are so sure...
that their way is right that
they become obstinate.
The more they get like that, the
further from happiness they go.
But not ending up happy despite
not doing anything wrong...
That's awful.
It is.
What do you think I should do?
In a case like this,
no one else can bring about
a neat and tidy end to it.
But would you still want to help resolve it,
even if it wasn't a neat and tidy resolution?
Yes.
Then you should make a mistake for her.
Your friend is trying so hard to do right...
...that someone's got to make
some mistakes for her.
Make mistakes...?
Sometimes you tell an awful lie, or
run away from something scary...
...and then later look back...
...and realize that that was actually
precisely the right thing to do, right?
If you can see there's no way for your
friend's problem to end but in disaster...
...it'd be better for her to crash and
burn sooner rather than later.
But do you think she'll understand
that I'm doing it for her own good?
Sometimes they do, sometimes
they don't - especially at first.
But I warned you it wouldn't
be a pretty ending.
So what seems better to you?
To give up on your friend, or to
be misunderstood by her?
Madoka... you've grown up
to be a very good girl.
You don't tell lies or do bad things.
You always try your best
to do the right thing.
You've already passed your
childhood with flying colors.
Which is why it may be good for you...
...before you become an adult
- to learn how to mess up, too.
Learn how to mess up?
After all, wounds heal faster
when you're young.
If you learn how to fall well now,
I'm sure it'll help you later in life.
When you grow up, you see,
the consequences for messing
up get bigger and bigger.
The more responsibilities
you start shouldering,
the more important it gets not
to make a wrong move.
But isn't that... really painful?
Oh, us adults are always in pain.
That's why we're allowed to drink alcohol!
I wish I could hurry up and drink
alcohol with you too, Mom.
Then grow up super-fast, my dear.
For adults, it's only as fun as it hurts!
Oh!
If you're looking for Mr. Kamijo,
he was discharged yesterday.
He was doing so well with
his physical therapy...
...that they moved up his discharge date.
O-oh, I see.
Going home without even seeing him?
After you spent the whole day
running around chasing him?
You...
I know who you're after.
The little rich boy who lives here, right?
The one you made the contract
with Kyubey for...?
Jeez!
You wasted your once-in-a-lifetime
miracle on something that stupid?
What would you know?!
Apparently, a lot more than you, dummy!
Magic is only supposed to be used
to grant wishes for yourself.
If you use it for somebody else,
it always ends up going bad.
Didn't Mami Tomoe even
teach you that much?
If all you wanted was to possess
the boy you love,
aren't there a lot of better ways to do it?
After all, you've got all that magic now...
What?
You should bust in there right now...
...and break his arms and legs so bad
he'll never be able to use them again.
Make him so helpless he won't be
able to do anything without you.
Do that, and this time, he really
will be yours and yours alone.
Both his body and heart will be all yours...
If you don't have the guts to do it, I
wouldn't mind busting him up for you.
You know, as a favor to
my fellow magical girl?
It'd be so easy to do, too...
No way...
You are the one person I'll never forgive!
This time, it ends!
Let's take this some place else.
We're bound to attract attention here.
Your friend is trying so hard to do right...
...that someone's got to make
some mistakes for her.
But how could I ever...?
Madoka...
Madoka!
Hurry! Sayaka's in trouble!
Come with me!
We won't have to hold back up here.
So gimme your best shot!
Wait! Sayaka!
Madoka...!
Don't get in my way! You
don't even belong here!
You can't do this! This just can't be right!
Hmph! Annoying jerks sure
attract annoying friends.
Then what kind of friends would
you have, I wonder?
This isn't what we agreed on.
I thought I told you to leave
Sayaka Miki alone.
Well your way would've been too soft!
Besides, it's not like she's backing down...
I'll take her on, then. Stay out of it.
You got until I finish eating this then.
That's all I'll need.
Don't underestimate me!
Sayaka!
I'm sorry!
Madoka! How could you...?!
Because if I hadn't--
Sayaka?
That wasn't good, Madoka...
No matter how mad you are,
you shouldn't throw your own
friend away like that.
What?
What did you say?
No, stop!
What the heck is this?!
She's dead!
Sayaka?
Hey, Sayaka...?
Wake up! Hey!
Come on... What's wrong?
I don't want this... Sayaka...!
What the hell is going on here?
Hey!
It's because the furthest you magical
girls can control your bodies...
...would be within about
a 100 meter radius.
100 meters? What are you talking about?
What do you mean?!
You rarely have this sort of accident...
...because you usually carry
it with you all the time...
What are you saying, Kyubey?!
You have to help her!
Don't let Sayaka die...!
Madoka, that isn't Sayaka.
It's just an empty shell.
Huh?
Sayaka is what you just threw
away a moment ago.
What... did you say?
Did you really think you
could fight witches...
...with the same fragile bodies
that humans possess?
It's unthinkable.
For magical girls,
those so-called "bodies" that you possess
are really just exterior hardware.
Your real bodies are your souls,
and in order to make them able
to use magic more efficiently,
we put them in these compact,
easy-to-protect forms instead.
To complete the contract to
become a magical girl...
...what I do is rip your souls out of your
bodies and turn them into Soul Gems.
Bastard... What have you done...?!
You've gotta be kidding me!
So now you've made us into
zombies or something?!
But isn't it handy this way?
Even if your body's heart gets crushed,
or you bleed out your very
last drop of blood...
...you can just heal your bodies with
magic and get right back up!
So long as your Soul Gem
remains unharmed...
...you're basically invincible!
Isn't that a lot better for battle than
those breakable human bodies?
That's horrible...
Too horrible for words...
You humans always react this way.
Whenever I try to tell you the simple facts,
you inevitably have this same reaction...
I just don't get it.
Why are humans so touchy about
the placement of their souls?
What?
What is it?
Itsuka kimi ga hitomi ni tomosu
The light of love
Ai no hikari ga
You will turn on in your eyes
Toki wo koete
Someday will go beyond time
Horobi isogu sekai no yume wo
And surely shatter a dream of the world
Tashika ni hitotsu kowasu darou
That is rushing towards destruction
Tamerai wo nomihoshite
What do you wish for
Kimi ga nozomu mono wa nani?
After swallowing up all of that hesitance?
Konna yokubukai akogare no yukue ni
Is there an ephemeral tomorrow
Hakanai ashita wa aruno?
At the end of this greedy admiration?
Kodomo no koro yume ni miteta
Using an ancient magic
Inishie no mahou no youni
That I used to dream of as a child
Yami sae kudaku chikara de
I want to break the darkness
Hohoemu kimi ni aitai
And see you smiling
Obieru kono te no naka niwa
The only thing left in my scared hand
Taorareta hana no yuuki
Is the courage of a broken flower
Omoi dake ga tayoru subete
All I can trust is my wish
Hikari wo yobisamasu negai
And my wish would awaken the light
Before you took on this destiny
of battling witches,
wasn't there a wish you wanted granted?
That wish has really has
come true, hasn't it?
EPISODE 7: CAN YOU FACE YOUR TRUE FEELINGS?
That wish has really has
come true, hasn't it?