You tricked us, didn't you?
I told you precisely what
I wanted from the start:
For you to become magical girls.
I just didn't explain exactly what
form you'd be taking to do that.
Why didn't you ever tell us?!
Because you never asked.
Even though you didn't know, there
wouldn't have been any inconvenience.
In fact, even Mami never
noticed to the very end.
After all, you humans don't physically
sense your souls to begin with.
Actually, all they really are is
a little cluster of neurons.
Just a nerve center with functions
similar to a circulatory organ.
For all that, if they stop functioning,
even your conscious minds seem
to crumble along with them.
So to help prevent that,
I put your souls in a form that's easier
to keep track of and protect.
That makes it as safe as possible
for you to battle witches. Right?
Well, no one asked for your "help"
with something so ridiculous!
You still don't fully understand
what it is to do battle, do you?
For instance, say that you've
been impaled with a spear.
How much pain do you think you could
take before you simply went into shock?
This is what real "pain" feels like.
See? You could be totally incapacitated
with just one hit.
You only managed to finish
the fight with Kyoko...
...because you were spared the
full extent of your body's pain.
It was only possible because your mind
and body weren't directly connected.
And as a result, you were able
to live through that fight.
Once you get better at it,
you can even detach yourself enough
to block out all sense of pain.
That said...
It causes your body to respond slower
when you command it to move,
so I don't recommend it.
Why...? Why would you do
such a thing to us...?!
Before you took on this destiny
of battling witches,
wasn't there a wish you wanted granted?
That wish has really has
come true, hasn't it?
Kawashita yakusoku wasurenai yo
I won't forget our promise we made
Me wo toji tashikameru
I close my eyes to make sure
Oshiyoseta yami
I will move forward,
Furiharatte susumuyo
shaking off the surging darkness
Itsuni nattara nakushita mirai wo
When can I see the future that I lost
Watashi kokode mata mirukoto dekiruno?
Here in this place once again?
Afuredashita fuan no kage wo
Tearing up the shadow of anxiety
Nando demo saite
That floods into me many times
Kono sekai ayunde ikou
I will keep walking in this world
Tomedonaku kizamareta
Time that is endlessly ticking
Toki wa ima hajimari tsuge
now starts
Kawaranai omoi wo nose
With our everlasting passion,
Tozasareta tobira akeyou
And open the door that has been closed
Mezameta kokoro wa hashiridashita
Our awakened souls
Mirai wo egaku tame
Set out to paint our rising future
Muzukashii michi de tachi domattemo
Even if we get stuck on a troubled path
Sora wa kireina aosa de itsumo mattete kureru
The beautiful blue sky always waits for us
Dakara kowaku nai
So I won't be afraid of anything
Mou naniga attemo kujikenai
Whatever happens, I won't give up
EPISODE 7: CAN YOU FACE YOUR TRUE FEELINGS?
Stand.
Bow.
Homura... Did you know?
Then why didn’t you tell us?
I've tried telling others in the past.
Not a single one has ever believed me.
Why would Kyubey do something
so cruel to us?
Because it doesn't think of it as cruel.
It is a life form that cannot comprehend
human values.
It would probably insist that it is simply
fair payment for the miracles it grants.
But it's not a fair exchange at all!
To have that done to her body...
when all Sayaka wanted was to heal
the wounds of the boy she loved!
That doesn't change the fact
that it was a miracle.
Because it made something
impossible possible.
Even if Sayaka Miki had spent
her entire life caring for him,
that boy never would have regained
the ability to perform.
In truth, the value of a miracle is far
greater than that of an entire human life.
And it is that which that creature sells.
So Sayaka will never be able
to go back to her old life?
I told you once before, didn't I?
You should give up on Sayaka Miki.
But Sayaka saved my life!
If she hadn't become a magical girl then,
both Hitomi and I would have died!
Don't confuse gratitude with responsibility.
You have no ability to save Sayaka Miki.
If you hope to repay her in order to
alleviate your own sense of guilt, don't.
There is no need for such presumption.
Homura, why are you always so cold?
Perhaps...
...it is because I, too, am
no longer human...
Now that I've got a body like this...
...how can I possibly face Kyosuke again?
How long are you planning to sit
up there moping, blockhead?
Can you come out for a sec?
I wanna talk.
Guess you're really regretting it, huh?
This whole zombie thing...
As for me, I guess I'm okay with it.
I mean, whatever the details,
it was only after I got this power that
I was able to live like I wanted.
So I guess it's not so bad that I'd regret it.
It's all just "you get what you
pay for" to you, isn't it?
Exactly! "You get what you
pay for" - that's how I live.
And if you live only to benefit yourself,
you've got to pay for your
own mistakes too.
So I don't hold this against anyone,
and I don't regret anything.
If you think like that, you can take most
anything without getting down.
What did you bring me all
the way out here for?
It's gonna be kind of a long talk.
Want one?
Don't ever waste food. I'll kill you if you do.
See... this was my dad's church.
He was an overly kind and earnest man.
Like, the type who cries reading the
morning paper every morning...
and seriously thinks about
how to make things better.
He thought that in order to
save a new generation,
we needed to have a new religion.
That's what he always said.
That's why, one day,
he started preaching stuff that wasn't
in the Bible to his parishioners.
Naturally, people stopped
coming to his sermons.
Then he got excommunicated
by the church...
...and no one would listen
to his words anymore.
I guess it was only natural, huh?
From the outside, he probably looked
like some raving cultist.
No matter how right he was,
no matter how logical the
things he said were,
the world only saw him
as some crazy outcast.
It got to the point where our entire family
didn't even have food to eat.
I just couldn't understand it.
My dad wasn't saying anything
that was wrong.
It was just different from what
people were used to hearing.
If they would've given him just 5 minutes
to hear what he had to say,
anyone would've agreed that he was right.
But no one would listen.
I got angry.
I couldn't accept it.
I couldn't stand that nobody would
give my dad a chance...
...and understand what he was saying.
So I asked Kyubey...
...to make everyone listen seriously
to what my dad said.
The next morning, the church was
packed full of people again.
Every day, they came in bigger and bigger
crowds to hear my dad speak.
And as for me, I happily began
my work as a magical girl.
After all, even if my dad was
preaching truth to the world,
someone still had to take
care of the witches.
And so...
...like an idiot, I thought of it as my role,
and threw myself into witch-hunting.
I thought that my dad and me--
one from the front, one from the shadows--
were going to save this world together.
But one day, my dad found out about me.
When he heard that all the
people were there...
because I'd used magic
to make them come,
and not because they really
believed, he flipped out.
He called me - his own daughter - a
witch who tainted people's hearts.
Isn't that hilarious?
After I'd been out hunting
real witches every night!
After that, my dad had a breakdown.
He was miserable in the end.
He wasted away with drink, got
messed up in the head...
...then finally killed my whole family
and committed suicide.
Leaving only me behind...
My wish destroyed my whole family.
Because I went and made
a wish for someone else...
...without really knowing what he wanted,
I ended up bringing everyone misfortune.
Right then, I vowed in my heart never to
use magic to help anyone else again.
I would use this power up...
...for my sake and mine alone.
Miracles aren't free, you know.
If you wish for hope,
an equal amount of despair will
be rained down upon you, too.
That's how everything
stays in equilibrium...
...and the world's balance
doesn't get disturbed.
Why are you telling me all of this?
'Cause you should just quit caring
and do whatever you want, too.
"You get what you pay for," right?
Now, that's odd.
Since you only live for your own benefit,
why are you worrying about
me, all of sudden?
'Cause you started off with
the same mistake as me.
You shouldn't keep living the kind of life
that's gonna bring you more regrets.
I mean, you've already paid your dues
- and paid way too high a price.
So now, you should just think about
how to get your money's worth.
Like you do?
Yep.
I've already figured out how
things really stand,
but you're continuing on
with the wrong idea.
I couldn't watch you go on like that.
I was really wrong about you.
I apologize for that, really.
But even then, I don't regret making
my wish for someone else's sake.
To make sure the feelings I made that
wish with never become a lie,
I've decided I'll never regret anything. Ever.
Why are you--
Actually,
I don't think I paid too high a price.
Because, depending on how we use it, this
magic can be used for wonderful things.
Which reminds me...
Those apples...
How did you get them?
Where did you get the money
to pay for them?
You can't answer me, can you?
In that case, I can't eat those apples.
And I can't be happy about
receiving them either.
You jerk!
We're magical girls!
There's no one else who
can do what we do!
I'll do things my own way...
...and continue my own fight.
If that interferes with your life,
you're welcome to come
and try to kill me again.
I won't lose to you.
Nor will I resent you or anyone else.
Sayaka! Good morning!
Good morning, Sayaka.
H-hey!
Good morning!
Where were you yesterday?
Oh, I was just feeling a little sick...
Sayaka...
It's okay. I feel all right now.
You don't have to worry.
Well, then! Let's do our best today--
Oh!
Has Kamijo already been released
from the hospital?
Kamijo, are you really okay
to come to school already?
Yeah.
If I just sat bundled up at home,
it wouldn't help my leg
rehab much anyway.
I'm aiming to walk without crutches
again by next week.
I'm so glad for Kamijo.
Yeah...
You should go say hi to him, Sayaka.
You haven't talked to him yet, right?
I'm... fine here.
So...
What did you want to talk about?
About love.
I have a secret that I've been keeping
from both you and Madoka.
Huh? Um, okay...
For a long time now, I...
...have been in love with Kyosuke Kamijo.
O-oh, really?
I never would've guessed, Hitomi!
Kyosuke, the lucky guy--
Sayaka, you were a childhood friend
of Kamijo's, weren't you?
Y-yeah, or, um, maybe more of
a tag-along or something...
Was it really only that?
I've decided not to lie to myself any longer.
How about you?
Sayaka, can you face your true feelings?
W-what are you talking about?
You are a precious friend to me.
That's why I don't want to cut in
or steal him out of your hands.
The amount of time you spend looking
at him surpasses even mine.
So I think you have the right
to try for him before me.
Hitomi...
I will confess my love to Kamijo
after school tomorrow.
I will wait one full day for you.
So please decide what to do so
you won't have regrets, Sayaka.
Decide whether you want to confess
your feelings to Kamijo, or not...
I-I...
Madoka...
Is it okay if I come along?
I don't want you to be all alone,
Sayaka. So please...
You... Why...?
Why are you so nice?
I don't deserve such kindness...
What?
I had a moment today, where
I almost regretted something.
For just a split-second, I thought,
"If only I hadn't saved Hitomi that time..."
I completely fail at being an ally of justice.
How will I ever face Mami?
I'm going to lose Kyosuke to Hitomi...!
And there's nothing I can do...
Because I'm already dead...
Because I'm a zombie...!
I can't ask him to hold me when
I have a body like this!
I can't ever ask him to kiss me!
Thank you...
I'm sorry.
Sayaka...
I'm okay now.
I got it all out.
Now, let's go.
We've got some more witches
to beat up today!
Okay.
It's not like you to just
sit quietly and watch.
She's battling a witch today, not a familiar.
It's sure to drop a Grief Seed.
So it isn't a waste this time.
But I'm surprised that you're handing
over your prey for such a reason.
That idiot! How long does
it take her to finish it!?
Sayaka!
For Pete's sake! I just can't watch this!
Just get back for now.
I'll show you how it's done!
Hey!
Stay out of my way. I can do this alone!
Sayaka!
You... you're not...?
It's really true!
If I just detach myself...
...I really don’t feel any pain!
Stop...
Please, just stop...
Itsuka kimi ga hitomi ni tomosu
The light of love
Ai no hikari ga
You will turn on in your eyes
Toki wo koete
Someday will go beyond time
Horobi isogu sekai no yume wo
And surely shatter a dream of the world
Tashika ni hitotsu kowasu darou
That is rushing towards destruction
Tamerai wo nomihoshite
What do you wish for
Kimi ga nozomu mono wa nani?
After swallowing up all of that hesitance?
Konna yokubukai akogare no yukue ni
Is there an ephemeral tomorrow
Hakanai ashita wa aruno?
At the end of this greedy admiration?
Kodomo no koro yume ni miteta
Using an ancient magic
Inishie no mahou no youni
That I used to dream of as a child
Yami sae kudaku chikara de
I want to break the darkness
Hohoemu kimi ni aitai
And see you smiling
Obieru kono te no naka niwa
The only thing left in my scared hand
Taorareta hana no yuuki
Is the courage of a broken flower
Omoi dake ga tayoru subete
All I can trust is my wish
Hikari wo yobisamasu negai
And my wish would awaken the light
I'm going to be a different kind
of magical girl from all of you...
That's what I've decided...
I don't need thanks or recompense.
I'll be the one magical girl who won't
use her magic for herself.
EPISODE 8: I WAS STUPID... SO STUPID
I was stupid... so stupid.