It's easy once you know how to do it.
I’m sure I'll never lose this way.
It's yours.
That's what you're after, isn't it?
Hey...
I don't want to be in your debt.
Now we're even, got it?
Come on, let's go, Madoka.
Sayaka...
Ah... Sorry...
I'm just... a little tired...
Don't push yourself. Lean on me.
That idiot...
Kawashita yakusoku wasurenai yo
I won't forget our promise we made
Me wo toji tashikameru
I close my eyes to make sure
Oshiyoseta yami
I will move forward,
Furiharatte susumuyo
shaking off the surging darkness
Itsuni nattara nakushita mirai wo
When can I see the future that I lost
Watashi kokode mata mirukoto dekiruno?
Here in this place once again?
Afuredashita fuan no kage wo
Tearing up the shadow of anxiety
Nando demo saite
That floods into me many times
Kono sekai ayunde ikou
I will keep walking in this world
Tomedonaku kizamareta
Time that is endlessly ticking
Toki wa ima hajimari tsuge
now starts
Kawaranai omoi wo nose
With our everlasting passion,
Tozasareta tobira akeyou
And open the door that has been closed
Mezameta kokoro wa hashiridashita
Our awakened souls
Mirai wo egaku tame
Set out to paint our rising future
Muzukashii michi de tachi domattemo
Even if we get stuck on a troubled path
Sora wa kireina aosa de itsumo mattete kureru
The beautiful blue sky always waits for us
Dakara kowaku nai
So I won't be afraid of anything
Mou naniga attemo kujikenai
Whatever happens, I won't give up
EPISODE 8: I WAS STUPID... SO STUPID
Sayaka...
That way of fighting... it's no good...
You say it doesn't hurt, but you're lying.
I can tell just by looking at you.
Just because you don't feel it, it doesn't
mean it's okay to get hurt.
If I don't fight like that, I can't win.
Because I don’t have any natural talent.
Even if you can use that method to win,
it doesn't mean it's good for you, Sayaka.
What's "good for me?"
With my body this way, what could
ever be "good for me?"
Sayaka...
All I can do now is kill witches...
That's the only worth I
have left in this world.
I'm just a walking, talking corpse,
pretending it's still alive.
What kind of "good" could anyone
possibly do for me now?
It's stupid to even think about it.
But I just want to make you
happy again, Sayaka...
Then you fight them.
I heard from Kyubey that you've got
more natural talent than anyone.
Without even suffering the way I do,
you could finish off any witch easily.
I...
I just...
If you really want to do something for me,
you should experience what
I've experienced first.
You can't, can you? Of course not.
You can't give up being human just
out of a little pity, can you?!
Pity...?! That's not...
In place of you, who could accomplish
anything but won't--
I am suffering in your stead!
So don't talk like you care, when you've
conveniently overlooked that!
Sayaka...
Don't follow me!
I'm so stupid...!
Why did I say all that to her?
I'm beyond saving...
HOMURA
Walpurgisnacht's descent will
occur within this area...
How do you know?
Statistics.
Statistics?
I've never heard that Walpurgisnacht
appeared in this town before.
So what "statistics" are
you estimating with?
Look, I'm not saying we should
trust each other or anything,
but can't you show me your
hand just a little bit more?
I'd certainly like to ask the same...
...Homura Akemi.
You've got some nerve showing
your face here!
My, my. I take it I'm an
uninvited guest here?
And here I came all this way just to give
you some important information...
Sayaka Miki's deterioration is happening
far quicker than I expected.
It isn't just all the magic she's using...
She, herself, has begun to curse the world.
And who's fault do you think that is, huh?
At this rate,
she'll be causing you some trouble...
...before Walpurgisnacht descends.
You'd best be on your guard.
What? What's that supposed to mean?
Perhaps you should ask her instead of me.
I'm sure you already know what I'm
talking about, Homura Akemi.
I thought so.
Just where did you learn
such interesting things?
I'm very, very curious to know...
Are you by chance...
I've heard all I care to hear from you.
Begone.
You're just letting him go?
There's no point in killing that creature.
More importantly, what's
up with Sayaka Miki?
What's this "trouble" that fuzz
ball was talking about?
Her Soul Gem has become too tainted.
If it is not purified soon, there will
be no coming back for her...
HOMURA
The auxiliary verb, "must," basically means
that et cetera has to be done...
ABSENT
I should have gone after her then...
But Shizuki...
I never realized that your house
was in this direction.
I feel like I've never seen you walking
home this way before...
You're right.
To be honest, I live in exactly
the opposite direction.
Huh? Then why did you
walk this way today?
Because, Kamijo...
I have something I need to tell you.
What?
She hasn't been home?
Not since yesterday? That's...
Yes, um...
I understand.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Sayaka...
I've got to find her!
Why can't you understand?
You don't have the luxury
of killing familiars.
You should target only witches.
Shut up...! I don't need your advice...
Your Soul Gem must be at its limit.
You need to purify it now.
Use this.
What are you planning this time?
Don't be a fool.
You're in no position to be questioning
anyone's help right now.
Or do you simply hate being
rescued that much?
I'm going to be a different kind
of magical girl from all of you...
That's what I've decided.
I won't forsake anyone, or use anyone...
And I won't associate with
those who do, either.
I don't need thanks or recompense.
I'll be the one magical girl who won't
use her magic for own gain.
You...
...are going to die.
So what if I die?
It just means I won't be able
to kill witches anymore.
It'll mean I won't be of use anymore.
That's fine with me.
Someone like me who can't even defeat
witches... the world doesn't need me.
Why?
All I want is to save you.
Why can't you trust me?
Why can't I trust you...?
I'm not sure. I just know somehow...
...that you're a liar.
By looking at your eyes, I can tell
you've given up on everything.
You always recite hollow words.
You're even doing it now.
You say you want to help me, but I know
that's not what you're really thinking.
You're not fooling me.
You do realize that you're just making
Madoka suffer more and more?
Madoka...?
This has nothing to do with her.
You're wrong.
Everything has to do with her.
You're very perceptive.
You're absolutely right.
I have no desire at all to save you.
I just don't want Madoka to have
to watch you destroy yourself.
If you refuse my help here, there
is no recourse for you but to die.
If you will make Madoka grieve
more than she has...
...then I...
...will kill you...
...here and now.
Sayaka Miki...
Hey!
Hurry up and run!
Are you insane?!
Weren't you coming here to save her?
Let go of me...
Oh, I see.
If I keep a grip on you like this,
you can't use that weird technique
of yours, can you?
What?!
Crap!
No way, man, you can't let the
dumb slut make any excuses.
Gotta get her to fork over all the
money she makes, no shit.
Cuz women are complete morons.
They get money in their hands and
they blow it all on stupid crap.
Yeah, seriously, man...
You just can't treat women
like rational human beings.
You gotta treat'em like they're
stupid dogs or something.
But you know, my stupid hoe would
probably be happy with that!
All I gotta say is, "I'm gonna bust up
your face!" and she shuts right up!
You give'em an inch and they're all over
you, whining to get married and shit.
You just can't let up on them.
I'm like,
"You think a shit-for-brains hostess like
you will still be around in 10 years?"
That hoe body ain't gonna
last forever, y'know!
God, they're so annoying when
it comes time to dump them.
You are really good at dumpin'
hoes, though, Sho. I envy you!
Dude, I gotta learn from you.
Hey, tell me more about her.
Um, what?
The woman you were talking
about just now.
Tell me more about her.
Are you a middle schooler, kid?
You shouldn't be out this late.
That woman... she probably loves you
and tries hard to make you happy.
I bet you know that too, don't you?
And yet you call her a dog? Have
you never told her, "thank you?"
Are you really going to dump her
once she stops being useful?
What the... Do you know this kid?
No...
Hey... is this world even worth protecting?
What have I been fighting for all this time?
Tell me.
You, right now. Tell me.
Or else, I'll...
Sayaka... Where are you?
Are you upset with me, too?
If I was, would you turn Sayaka back?
I can't. It's beyond my power to do that.
Hey...
You once told me that I could become
an incredibly powerful magical girl.
Was that true?
"Incredible" doesn't even
begin to describe it.
Your power would be almost
incomprehensible!
You'd probably be the strongest
being in this world!
If I had made the contract with you...
...would Sayaka not have had
to become a magical girl?
Sayaka had her own wish as well.
You really had nothing to
do with her decision.
Why me, though?
I have no idea, either.
Truth be told,
your latent potential is on a scale that
theoretically shouldn't even be possible.
I want someone to come explain
it as much as you do.
Really?
If you were to release your power,
the miracle you could unleash might
twist the very fabric of the universe.
Why you alone should carry
such unthinkable power...
I can't guess the reason right now.
I...
I always thought there was
nothing special about me.
That I would just kind of
stumble through life,
never being able to help anyone
or be of any use at all.
It was really frustrating and kind
of lonesome to think about.
But I figured there was no helping it.
Though the reality is quite different.
Madoka, if you wished it...
...you could even become
the god of this world.
Then...
Would I be able to do things that
even you can't do, Kyubey?
What do you mean?
If I made a contract with you, would I be
able to turn Sayaka human again?
That would be child's play for you.
Would that be worth trading
your soul for, then?
For Sayaka, yes.
I'll do it.
Make me into a mag--
Th-that's horrible...
You didn't have to kill him--
You--
Why must you always try to
sacrifice yourself like that?
Huh?
Calling yourself useless,
and meaningless...
Don't treat yourself like you don't matter!
Think about all the people who
consider you precious!
Stop being such a fool!
There are so many people who
would grieve if you died.
Why can't you understand that?!
What about the people who are
trying so hard to protect you?!
Homura...!
Have the two of us...
met somewhere before...?
That's...
I'm sorry.
I've got to go find Sayaka.
Wait!
Sayaka Miki is already...
I'm sorry.
Wait!
Madoka!
You knew there was no point in doing that.
You just don't learn, do you?
I have countless spares, of course,
but making me use them up
for no reason like this...
It's a waste.
That's the second time you've killed me.
But thanks to that, I was finally able to
see what your magical specialty is.
That was Time Magic, wasn't it?
That's what I thought.
I had suspected as much already, but...
You're not from this timeline, are you?
I know what you really are
and what you're planning.
I see.
So that's why you've been trying so
hard to keep interfering with me.
Do you want to change Madoka
Kaname's fate that badly?
Yes.
I won't let things go according
to your plans, Kyubey.
Or should I say...
..."Incubator?"
Found you at last!
How long were you planning to
go on being stubborn like this?
I'm sorry for making you look for me.
What?
That doesn't sound like you.
It's because I just can't care
about anything anymore.
I can't even remember what I thought was
so important, so worth protecting...
None of it makes sense anymore.
Hey...
Hope and despair balance
back out to zero...
You told me that once, didn't you?
Now I get what you meant.
It's true that I've saved a few people.
But in equal measure, my heart became
filled with resentment and hatred.
So much so that I even
hurt my dearest friend.
Sayaka! You didn't--?
For as much happiness as
we wish on one person,
we can't help but curse someone else.
That's how it works for us magical girls.
I was stupid... so stupid.
Sayakaaaa!!
In this country, half-grown women
are called "girls," right?
In that case,
it's appropriate that you, who will
one day grow into witches,
should be called "magical girls."
Itsuka kimi ga hitomi ni tomosu
The light of love
Ai no hikari ga
You will turn on in your eyes
Toki wo koete
Someday will go beyond time
Horobi isogu sekai no yume wo
And surely shatter a dream of the world
Tashika ni hitotsu kowasu darou
That is rushing towards destruction
Tamerai wo nomihoshite
What do you wish for
Kimi ga nozomu mono wa nani?
After swallowing up all of that hesitance?
Konna yokubukai akogare no yukue ni
Is there an ephemeral tomorrow
Hakanai ashita wa aruno?
At the end of this greedy admiration?
Kodomo no koro yume ni miteta
Using an ancient magic
Inishie no mahou no youni
That I used to dream of as a child
Yami sae kudaku chikara de
I want to break the darkness
Hohoemu kimi ni aitai
And see you smiling
Obieru kono te no naka niwa
The only thing left in my scared hand
Taorareta hana no yuuki
Is the courage of a broken flower
Omoi dake ga tayoru subete
All I can trust is my wish
Hikari wo yobisamasu negai
And my wish would awaken the light
Maybe I'm being a fool...
But until I know for sure whether
she can or can't be saved,
I don't want to give up.
EPISODE 9: I'D NEVER ALLOW THAT TO HAPPEN
I'd never allow that to happen.