For as much happiness as
you wish on one person,
you cannot help cursing someone else.
That's how it works for us magical girls.
I was so stupid... so stupid.
Sayaka!
What is this?!
What the heck are you?!
What have you done to Sayaka?
Get back.
Take my hand.
What are you--
Just do it!
That's...
If you let go of my hand, time
will stop for you as well.
Be careful.
What the heck is going on here?!
Where did that witch come from?
That is what used to be Sayaka Miki.
You saw it happen yourself, didn't you?
Are we just gonna run away?
If you want to fight it, drop
that needless baggage...
...and we'll turn around to kill it right now.
Can you do that?
Like hell!
You're only dragging us down like this.
We need to withdraw for now.
Kawashita yakusoku wasurenai yo
I won't forget our promise we made
Me wo toji tashikameru
I close my eyes to make sure
Oshiyoseta yami
I will move forward,
Furiharatte susumuyo
shaking off the surging darkness
Itsuni nattara nakushita mirai wo
When can I see the future that I lost
Watashi kokode mata mirukoto dekiruno?
Here in this place once again?
Afuredashita fuan no kage wo
Tearing up the shadow of anxiety
Nando demo saite
That floods into me many times
Kono sekai ayunde ikou
I will keep walking in this world
Tomedonaku kizamareta
Time that is endlessly ticking
Toki wa ima hajimari tsuge
now starts
Kawaranai omoi wo nose
With our everlasting passion,
Tozasareta tobira akeyou
And open the door that has been closed
Mezameta kokoro wa hashiridashita
Our awakened souls
Mirai wo egaku tame
Set out to paint our rising future
Muzukashii michi de tachi domattemo
Even if we get stuck on a troubled path
Sora wa kireina aosa de itsumo mattete kureru
The beautiful blue sky always waits for us
Dakara kowaku nai
So I won't be afraid of anything
Mou naniga attemo kujikenai
Whatever happens, I won't give up
EPISODE 09: I'D NEVER ALLOW THAT TO HAPPEN
Sayaka?
Sayaka! What happened?
Where's her Soul Gem?
What happened to Sayaka?
Her Soul Gem transformed
into a Grief Seed...
...and was obliterated after
it hatched a new witch.
You're... joking, right?
It's the truth.
That is the final secret of the Soul Gems.
When these gems grow tainted
and turn completely black,
they change into Grief Seeds...
...and we are reborn as witches.
That is the inescapable fate of
all who become magical girls.
That's not true.
It can't be true.
Right?
But... how can that be?
Sayaka said she wanted to protect
people from witches.
She wanted to fight for justice.
That's why she became a magical girl.
So why...?
It could only last until she had suffered...
an amount equal to the good
she had wished for.
From here on, for every person she
has saved, she will curse another.
You... What is your problem?
Are we supposed to be impressed
that you know so much?
How can you stand there and talk
like you're so smart right now?!
She was Sayaka's...
...Sayaka's best friend...!
You understand now, don't you?
What this thing you so wanted to become...
...is truly like.
This corpse you've brought along--try
not to be seen with it.
Take care how you dispose of it,
or you'll run into trouble later.
How do you even call yourself human?!
I don't, of course.
And neither should you.
Can I come in? I'd like to talk with you.
So you're alive after all.
Was what Homura said true?
True enough that I can't protest it.
So you've been turning us into magical
girls just so we'll become witches?
Please don't misunderstand.
We don't do this out of ill will
toward the human race.
Everything we've done is for the sake
of prolonging the life of the universe.
Madoka, do you know what
the word "entropy" means?
To give a simple example...
the amount of heat energy
a bonfire gives off...
is not equal to the energy it took
to grow the wood it's made of.
In short, when energy changes
form, some of it gets lost.
As a result, the amount of usable energy
in the universe is decreasing.
So we began searching...
for a form of energy that wasn't bound
by the laws of thermodynamics.
And what we found...
...was the power of the magical girls.
What... are you?
Our civilization created technology...
that could convert the emotions of
a sentient lifeform into raw energy.
Unfortunately...
Our species do not possess the
capacity to experience emotion.
So we studied various species
throughout the universe...
until, finally, we found you humans.
With the size of your population
and the rate of reproduction...
the amount of emotional energy
produced by a single human...
is greater than the amount used
between its birth and growth.
Human souls truly are the energy source
that could counter entropy!
And the most effective of all are girls in
the second stage of development...
...who experience the greatest fluctuations
between hope and despair.
In the moment when your Soul Gems
flare out and turn into Grief Seeds,
enormous energy is created.
It is the job of us Incubators
to collect that energy.
Are we just disposable energy
supplies for you, then?
Are you saying we should die for you?
Do you know how many
civilizations fill this universe,
and how much energy they
use in a single moment?
And someday,
even you humans will be able to leave
your planet and come join all of us.
When that day comes,
you wouldn’t want to find the universe
empty and desolate, would you?
If you look at it in the long run,
this should be a good deal
for your benefit as well.
Don't be ridiculous...
How can you say it was okay for Mami
to die and Sayaka to suffer like that...
...just because of some
crazy reason like that?
That isn't right. It's too cruel!
But we always ask and receive your
consent before making the contract.
Doesn't that alone show our good will?
But you do it by tricking all of us!
We aren't able to comprehend
what you mean by "tricking."
Why is it that when humans regret a
decision based on a misunderstanding...
...they feel resentment toward
the other party?
I can't follow what you're saying.
I don't understand you at all.
It's we who've had such a hard time...
understanding humans and
your values system.
With a current population of 6.9 billion...
that is increasing by a rate of
10 per every 4 seconds...
...why should you care so much about
the loss of a tiny handful?
If that's how you think, then
you really are our enemy.
Despite that, I did come here to
try to explain ourselves to you.
I was hoping you'd understand...
...what incredible good your sacrifices
have done for this universe.
But I guess not.
Of course not.
Madoka,
I still believe that one day,
you will become the greatest
of all magical girls,
and then the wickedest of all witches.
When that happens, we will surely obtain
an incomparable amount of energy.
So if you ever feel like dying for the sake
of the universe, please call me anytime.
I'll be waiting for you!
What do you hope to achieve,
expending so much energy...
to keep that body fresh?
Is there a way to get her Soul Gem back?
None, as far as I know anyway.
So there's stuff even you don't know, huh?
The existence of magical
girls defies logic as it is.
So I wouldn’t be surprised no matter
what kinds of impossible feats...
you manage to accomplish.
So it's possible?
There's no precedent for it.
That's why I don't know
how it might be done.
Unfortunately, I can't offer
any guidance this time.
Like I'd want it.
Who would listen to your advice now?
Madoka, you're looking a
bit unwell this morning.
Are you quite all right?
Yeah... I just didn't get enough sleep.
Speaking of which, it looks as if Sayaka
is staying home again today.
Perhaps we should go to see her later.
Though she may not welcome me...
Things are a bit awkward
between us right now...
Hitomi... There's something--
After yesterday...
Is now really the time to go to school?
Madoka?
We need to talk.
Will you come with me?
I'm sorry, Hitomi...
I think I'm going to stay home today too.
Huh?
But-- Madoka, wait!
Um... You wanted to talk?
Don't you want to save Sayaka Miki?
Is there a way to save her?
If there weren't, were you just
going to leave her like that?
Sorry, that came out wrong.
Maybe you'll think I'm an idiot, but...
Until we know for sure whether
she can be saved or not...
...I don't want to give up.
Even if she's a witch now,
she may at least remember
the voices of her friends.
So if you call out to her, maybe she'll get
back her memories of being human.
And probably, the only who could
do that... would be you.
Do you really think it'll work?
How am I supposed to know?
It's because I don't know
that I want to try it.
I mean,
maybe when I slice that witch in half,
instead of a Grief Seed, Sayaka's
Soul Gem will pop out.
Wouldn't that be something?
It'd be like one of those stories where
love and courage triumph over all.
Actually...
I probably became a magical
girl to begin with...
because I used to love stories like that.
I'd totally forgotten that.
It was Sayaka who reminded me again.
If you don't wanna come, I won't force you.
It's gonna be pretty dangerous, after all.
And I can't guarantee that
I'll be able to protect you.
I'll help.
I want to help.
I'm Madoka Kaname.
Aw, man...
You're so gonna cramp my style.
Huh?
Kyoko Sakura. Pleased to meet ya.
UNMAI BO
(TASTY BAR)
Excuse me.
I'm not feeling well. May I
go to the Nurse's Office?
Hm? Who's the Nurse's Aide in this class?
Kaname is, but she's not here today.
In that case, let's have the
Class President escort--
I wonder if Homura would help us...
Nah. She's not that kind of person.
Aren't you two friends?
Not really.
I guess you could say we've
got goals in common.
We kinda teamed up to beat enemies
we couldn't take on alone.
A few days from now, "Walpurgisnacht"
is coming to this town.
Walpurgis...?
It's this insanely huge and powerful witch.
Probably neither of us
could beat it alone.
That's why we decided to team up.
That's basically how it is.
This is it.
Are you sure it's really Sayaka?
And not some other witch?
The magic patterns are
the same as yesterday.
No doubt about it, it's her, all right.
Okay, let me ask you again.
You sure you're ready for this?
I've gotten kind of used to this, actually.
Although... all I ever do is
trail along behind others.
I've never been able to help at all...
But please, take me along.
You really are a strange one, aren't you?
Hey, Kyoko?
Hm?
Since I've always made others do the
fighting and never tried to do it myself...
I guess I'm a coward, huh?
Why would you ever become
a magical girl?
"Why"...?
Don't underestimate it--this isn't
a job just anyone can do.
But...
If you get to eat good food every day and
live a happy life with your family...
...why would you give it all up to become
a magical girl on some stupid whim?
I'd never allow that to happen.
I'd pound your face in first.
I mean, putting your life in danger...
Only people who've got no other
choice should do that.
Anyone else who sticks their nose
in it is just playing around.
It's beyond moronic.
I wonder...
But maybe a time will come...
...when you'll have no choice
but to risk your life and fight.
You should wait until then to think about it.
Okay.
So, Kyoko why did you--
She knows we're here!
She's coming!
Ready?
Do it just like we planned.
Right.
Sayaka, it's me. It's Madoka.
Can you hear me?
Do you recognize my voice?
Don't be scared.
Keep calling to her!
Sayaka, stop!
Please, remember!
I know you never wanted
to hurt anyone, Sayaka!
You always wanted to fight
for justice, didn't you?
Please, Sayaka, go back to your old self!
There's a limit to how stubborn
you should be...
...Sayaka!
Kyoko!
I'm fine.
I'm not even breaking a sweat yet.
You just keep calling out... to Sayaka.
Stop!
Please, just stop!
Sayaka!
Please recognize us!
Oh, I get it...
This is payback, isn't it?
How funny...
...we started off trying to kill
each other too, didn't we?
I thought you'd be a wuss.
But no matter how much I beat you
up, you kept standing back up.
You are mad, aren't you?
Is it just too hard to let go right now?
I get it.
But once you've had enough,
come back, okay?
Sayaka... P-please...
Sayaka!
Didn't you tell me you believed?
That you could use this power
to make people happy?
Please, God...
Look at the life I've lived.
Please, let me have a happy
dream, for once in my life.
Kyoko!
Hey...
You--
Take care of her for me...
I was an idiot for dragging her into this.
You said you wouldn't fight when weighed
down with a burden, right?
That's fine. And you're right.
You've gotta focus...
on the one thing that means most
to you, and protect it to the end.
It's funny... All this time...
...that's what I thought I was doing.
Go.
I'll take care of her.
Don't worry, Sayaka.
I know you don't want to be alone.
It's okay. I'll be here with you.
...Sayaka.
Kyoko...
HOMURA
Was there really any chance for Kyoko
Sakura to save Sayaka Miki?
Of course not. She should have
known that was impossible.
Then why didn't you stop her?
Naturally, I would have stopped her
if her death had been needless.
But getting her out of the picture
served a very important purpose.
Because now, there is no one left
but you to battle Walpurgisnacht.
And of course, you stand no chance
of beating her alone.
In order to protect this city,
there is no choice but for Madoka
to become a magical girl.
I won't let that happen. I swear it!
HOMURA
Sabitsuita kokoro
With rusted heart in this soundless world,
Oto mo nai sekai nani wo miteruno?
What is it you are looking at?
Matane wo ieru
I look for a face
Kao wo sagasuyo
I can say "see you again" to,
Sore wo kurikaesu dake
Over and over again
Kizukeba
I suddenly realized
Sokoni wa
someone was standing there,
Hitori kiri de naku ushiro sugata
Crying all alone with her back to me
Tsurai youna, sabishii youna, basho
Such a painful place, such a lonely place
Te wo tsunaide itainda
I want to keep holding your hand
Nando demo namae wo yobuyo
I call your name as many times as I must
Futashikana mirai demo
The future is uncertain,
Hanase nai mono
But my heart still aches
Omou dake kokoro ga itaiyo
When I think of the one I can't let go
Kokoni iruyo, kokoni iruyo
I am here. I am here.
Kaeru basho wa
And this is the place
Koko dayo?
you can come home to, you know?
Itsudatte kawaranai
I'll preserve these feelings
Omoi wo nokosuno
That will never change
No one believes me about the future.
No one can accept the truth about the future.
EPISODE 10: I WON'T RELY ON ANYONE ANYMORE
I won't rely on anyone anymore.