Now, then!
Why don't you tell your
classmates about yourself?
U-um...
M-m-my name is Homura Akemi.
P-p-pleased to meet you...
Miss Akemi has been in the hospital
for a while due to a heart condition.
HOMURA AKEMI
Since it's been some time since
she's been in school,
she may be a bit behind on a few things.
I want all of you to help her out, okay?
So, Miss Akemi...
What school did you come from?
Did you do any club activities
at your old school?
How about sports? Or cultural activities?
Your hair is so long!
That must take a lot of time
to braid every morning!
U-um...
I... I...
Miss Akemi?
You have to go to the Nurse's
Office, don't you?
Do you know where it is?
Huh? Um, no...
Then I'll take you there. I'm the
Nurse's Aide in our class.
Sorry, everyone,
but Miss Akemi is supposed
to take her medicine...
during break times at the Nurse's Office.
Oh, really?
Sorry for keeping you, then.
We'll talk again later, Miss Akemi!
Sorry about that.
They don't mean any harm.
They just got excited because we
don't get many transfer students.
No, it's...
Thank you very much.
You don't have to be so nervous.
We're classmates, after all!
I'm Madoka Kaname.
But just call me Madoka.
B-but...
It's fine, really. So, is it okay
if I call you Homura, too?
I-I don't really get called by
my first name very much...
I-I mean, it's such a weird name, so...
Huh? No, it's not!
It means "flame," so it's like you're
supposed to flare up passionately!
I think it sounds cool!
I guess I don't live up to my name...
But that's such a waste!
Since you were blessed with
such a great name,
you should become cool to match it!
All right, why don't you try solving this one?
Oh, you were out sick for
a while, weren't you?
Why don't you ask a friend
to let you copy their notes?
She got light-headed just
from doing warm-ups...
That's so lame!
Well, she's been bedridden for half a year.
Guess it can't be helped, huh?
You should become cool to match it!
That's impossible.
I... can't do anything right...
All I ever do is make trouble for others...
and embarrass myself...
Why?
Will I always...
...just be like this...forever?
Then maybe it'd be better
if you just died right now.
Maybe it would be better to just die...
That's right. You should just die now...
I should just... die...
Wh-what is this place?!
Wh-what?
What's going on here?
No... Ah!
That was a close one!
You're safe now...
...Homura.
Y-you're...!
They're magical girls.
They hunt witches.
I guess you've discovered our little secret.
Don't tell anyone else in class, okay?
MAMI TOMOE
Miss Kaname...
Do you always fight those things...?
Always? Hmm... Mami's
the real veteran but...
I actually just made my contract
with Kyubey last week.
But your performance today is a big
improvement from before, Kaname.
You're really okay with it?
You don't... get scared?
It's not that it doesn't bother me,
and of course, I get scared too.
But the more witches we slay,
the more people we can save.
So it's worth the effort, right?
I would like you to get fully-trained
and ready...
before Walpurgisnacht gets here.
...I'd better go now.
But...
But Miss Tomoe...
...just got killed.
That's why I have to go.
I'm the only one left who can
stop Walpurgisnacht.
But it's impossible! No one could
beat that thing alone!
You'll just be killed, too!
Even then, I'm a magical girl.
I have to protect everyone.
Listen...
Let's just run away...
There's nothing we can do, so...
No one will blame you.
Homura...
I'm really glad I became friends with you.
Even now, the fact that we were in
time to save you from that witch...
It's one of my proudest accomplishments.
That's why, I'm really glad in the end that
I chose to become a magical girl.
Miss Kaname...
Good-bye, Homura.
Take care.
No! Don't go! Miss Kaname!!
Why...?
You knew...
...you were going to get killed...
I'd rather you had lived...
than saved someone like me...!
Do you really mean that, Homura Akemi?
Would you put your soul
at stake for that wish?
If there is something you want badly
enough to accept a destiny of battle...
...then I can be of help to you.
If I make a contract with you,
can you really grant me any wish I want?
That's right.
It seems that you have
enough potential for it.
So tell me--
What is the wish that will make
your Soul Gem shine?
I...
I want to redo my meeting
with Miss Kaname.
But this time, instead of
her protecting me...
...I want to become strong
enough to protect her!
The contract has been made.
Your wish has prevailed over entropy.
So, go now... unleash your new power!
This is--
I...
NEW STUDENT GUIDE
I'm still in the hospital?
This isn't a dream?!
Now, then!
Why don't you tell your
classmates about yourself?
My name is Homura Akemi! I'm
very pleased to meet you!
Miss Akemi has been in
the hospital for a while--
Miss Kaname! I've become
a magical girl too!!
So let's do our best together from now on!
Uh... um...
Okay, here I go!
What do you think, Mami?
Hmm...
Time magic. I see...
It's incredible, but it's tricky
to learn how to fight with it.
Right...
HOW TO MAKE A BOMB
Mami! Now!
Okay!
Akemi! Go for it!
R-right!
I did it...
I did it...!
You did it!!
Well done!
You were amazing, Homura!
What's wrong?
Miss Kaname! Hold on!!
W-why...?
...What?
Why...?
How? How could that...?
I have to tell them!
Kyubey's tricking all of you!
Okay, look...
What could Kyubey possibly gain
by telling us such a huge lie?
Well, um...
I bet you're just saying that to get
us all to turn against each other!
In fact, you're probably working with
that Kyoko girl, aren't you?!
N-no, I'm not!
Sayaka, you're the one who's
turning against people here.
Whatever.
Personally, I'm against teaming
up with this girl.
You and Mami are fine since
you use long-range weapons.
But I fight right in the thick of things,
and having bombs go off in my face
is something I can live without.
I've almost been caught in the
blast multiple times now!
Are there any weapons you
can use besides bombs?
...I'll think of something.
What the heck are you?!
What have you done to Sayaka?
Sayaka, stop! Please, remember!
I know you never wanted
to hurt anyone, Sayaka!
I'm sorry... Miss Miki...
Sayaka...
Damn it...
How could this happen...?
It's too horrible...
This isn't right!
Miss Tomoe?!
If Soul Gems give birth to witches...
...then we have no choice
but to die, do we?!
Both you...
...and me!!
S-stop...!
I don't want this...
I can't take any more... of this...!
It's okay...
The two of us will keep going by ourselves.
We'll beat Walpurgisnacht,
just the two of us!
Okay...
I guess... this is the end for us too...
You don't have any more Grief Seeds...?
I see...
Listen...
How about the two of us
become monsters...
and really mess up this whole,
awful world, huh?
Until there's no more evil, no more
sadness, nothing left at all...
Let's just break, break,
break it all to dust...!
Don't you think... that would be great?
I lied earlier.
I had just this one left.
No! Why would you--? On me?!
Because I want to ask you to do
something that only you can do.
Homura... you can go back in time, right?
You can change history, so that
it won't end like this, right?
Yeah...
Then would you...
go back and save stupid me before
I get tricked by Kyubey?
I swear it!
I promise I'll save you!
No matter how many times
I have to go back and try!
I swear, I will protect you!!
Thank you...
Can I ask you... one more thing...?
I... I don't want to become a witch...
There are awful... sad things
in this world, but...
...there are lots... of things...
...worth protecting too...
Madoka!
Homura, you... finally called
me... by my first name...
I'm... happy...
No one will believe me about the future.
No one will accept the
truth about the future.
Then, I...
Wh-who's there?!
Madoka...
If someone comes to you offering a
miracle in exchange for something...
...you absolutely must not listen to him!
Huh? Um...
I won't rely on anyone anymore!
I don't need anyone to understand
me, either!
I won't let Madoka fight anymore.
I will finish every last witch myself...
And finally, this time...
...I shall defeat Walpurgisnacht...
with my own hands!
That's horrible...!
There's no helping it.
This was too much for her to handle alone.
But... that's too much! This can't be right!
Madoka! Don't listen to anything he says!!
If she gives up, it's over.
But you have the power
to change fate itself...
All this inevitable destruction
and tragedy...
You can change it, if you want.
The power to do so lies within you.
Can I really?
Don't let him trick you! You're
falling right into his trap!!
Can I really do something to help?
Could I really change this ending?
Of course you could.
So make a contract with me...
...and become a magical girl!
Nooooooo!!
She really was amazing when
she transformed, wasn't she?
That Madoka...
I estimated that she would become the
most powerful magical girl in the world...
...but to think she would take down
Walpurgisnacht with a single shot...!
And did you know what would
happen to her as a result?
Be it sooner or later, there is only
one ending for you magical girls.
As the strongest of all magical girls,
she took down her greatest enemy.
Naturally, after that,
all that was left for her was to turn
into the wickedest of all witches...
As she is now,
I imagine it will only take Madoka about
10 days to destroy this entire planet.
Oh, well. What happens next is
mankind's problem, not ours.
We've got all the energy we need
now. Our quota is almost met.
Aren't you going to fight her?
No.
My battlefield lies elsewhere.
Homura Akemi...
...you're--!!
I'll do it over...
As many times as it takes,
I'll keep going back...
I'll relive the same time over and over...
I'll find the one way out...
I'll find the one road that will save
you from a destiny of despair...
Madoka...
My only friend...
Homura...?
If it's...
If it's for you...
I don't care if I have to stay locked
in this endless maze...
...forever!
Kawashita yakusoku wasurenai yo
I won't forget our promise we made
Me wo toji tashikameru
I close my eyes to make sure
Oshiyoseta yami
I will move forward,
Furiharatte susumuyo
shaking off the surging darkness
Itsuni nattara nakushita mirai wo
When can I see the future that I lost
Watashi kokode mata mirukoto dekiruno?
Here in this place once again?
Afuredashita fuan no kage wo
Tearing up the shadow of anxiety
Nando demo saite
That floods into me many times
Kono sekai ayunde ikou
I will keep walking in this world
Tomedonaku kizamareta
Time that is endlessly ticking
Toki wa ima hajimari tsuge
now starts
Kawaranai omoi wo nose
With our everlasting passion,
Tozasareta tobira akeyou
And open the door that has been closed
Mezameta kokoro wa hashiridashita
Our awakened souls
Mirai wo egaku tame
Set out to paint our rising future
Muzukashii michi de tachi domattemo
Even if we get stuck on a troubled path
Sora wa kireina aosa de itsumo mattete kureru
The beautiful blue sky always waits for us
Dakara kowaku nai
So I won't be afraid of anything
Mou naniga attemo kujikenai
Whatever happens, I won't give up
EPISODE 10: I WON'T RELY ON ANYONE ANYMORE
After all the time you spent
watching over those girls...
Do you really feel nothing for them at all?
Did you never try to understand
how much they were suffering?
EPISODE 11: THE ONLY THING I HAVE LEFT TO GUIDE ME
The only thing I have left to guide me.