Time-traveler, Homura Akemi...
By turning back time and
changing past events,
you have traversed numerous
different timelines...
...and relived this past month over and
over, seeking the outcome you desire.
Your existence has answered
at least one great mystery:
Why is Madoka Kaname's potential as
a magical girl so abnormally vast?
Now, at last, I have a theory
that explains it.
You see, a magical girl's potential...
is based on the weight of the
karmic destiny she bears.
I could've understood if she had been
the queen or savior of a country.
But Madoka was only living an ordinary
life, so I couldn't understand why...
...so many threads of fate should all
be gathered so tightly around her.
But now I think... Say, Homura...
Couldn't it be...
that Madoka has been made into
such a powerful magical girl...
because you kept turning back time?
I thought so. You were the cause of it.
Or to be more precise, a side effect
of your magic was the cause of it.
What do you mean?
All this time reversal you did was
all for one purpose, wasn't it?
To save Madoka Kaname?
By turning back time over and over
for the same purpose and reason...
...you inadvertently caused multiple
timelines to converge together...
...and centered them all on the
existence of Madoka Kaname.
If Madoka's threads of fate from each
of those separate timelines...
...all ended up linking to the Madoka
in this current timeline...
...it would explain why her magical
potential appears so impossibly huge.
All that karmic destiny you set spinning
in all those different timelines...
...eventually attached to Madoka Kaname.
After all, she was the main
culprit of every event.
Excellent work, Homura.
You've made Madoka into the most
powerful witch we've ever seen.
Kawashita yakusoku wasurenai yo
I won't forget our promise we made
Me wo toji tashikameru
I close my eyes to make sure
Oshiyoseta yami
I will move forward,
Furiharatte susumuyo
shaking off the surging darkness
Itsuni nattara nakushita mirai wo
When can I see the future that I lost
Watashi kokode mata mirukoto dekiruno?
Here in this place once again?
Afuredashita fuan no kage wo
Tearing up the shadow of anxiety
Nando demo saite
That floods into me many times
Kono sekai ayunde ikou
I will keep walking in this world
Tomedonaku kizamareta
Time that is endlessly ticking
Toki wa ima hajimari tsuge
now starts
Kawaranai omoi wo nose
With our everlasting passion,
Tozasareta tobira akeyou
And open the door that has been closed
Mezameta kokoro wa hashiridashita
Our awakened souls
Mirai wo egaku tame
Set out to paint our rising future
Muzukashii michi de tachi domattemo
Even if we get stuck on a troubled path
Sora wa kireina aosa de itsumo mattete kureru
The beautiful blue sky always waits for us
Dakara kowaku nai
So I won't be afraid of anything
Mou naniga attemo kujikenai
Whatever happens, I won't give up
EPISODE 11: THE ONLY THING I HAVE LEFT TO GUIDE ME
SAYAKA MIKI FUNERAL SERVICE
The body of Mitakihara Public Middle
School 2nd-year student,
Sayaka Miki, who had been missing
since the 12th of this month,
was discovered today in a room
at a downtown hotel.
As there were no signs of violence
present at the scene of the crime,
both murder and accidental death are
being considered by the police.
Up next, the weather forecast.
Tonight, expect moderate winds
from the northwest and rain.
Welcome home.
Hey, Madoka...
About Sayaka's case...
Are you sure you don't know
anything about it?
Yeah.
Both Sayaka and Kyoko are dead...
It wasn't exactly an unexpected outcome.
The signs had been there
for quite some time.
So you're saying you don't care, then?
Even though you're somewhat
to blame for their deaths?
Then, for example, do you feel responsible
for the deaths of livestock?
Do you ever think about the process by
which they become foodstuffs for you?
Stop it!
That's not a rational reaction.
If you think these scenes are cruel,
then you're missing the
big picture completely.
Because they are slated to
become food for humans,
livestock are fed and provided
for all their lives...
...and given equal chance to reproduce
free from natural selection.
Cows, pigs and even chickens...
have an overwhelmingly higher rate of
survival in captivity than in the wild.
So isn't it actually...
a rather ideal, mutually beneficial
relationship for you both?
Are you saying it's the same
between you and us?
On the contrary,
our treatment of humankind...
is much more respectful than
your treatment of livestock.
Perhaps it isn't perfect,
but we do acknowledge your species as
sentient and try to deal fairly with you.
You can't believe that?
Then shall I show it to you?
Shall I show you the history spent together
by mankind and Incubators?
We have intervened in your civilization's
development since prehistoric times.
Countless girls throughout time have
made contracts with Incubators,
had their wishes granted...
...and then ultimately succumbed
to despair.
Beginning in hope and then
ending in a curse...
...that is the cycle that countless magical
girls have repeated to this day.
There are some who have wrought
revolutions that changed history...
...or elevated human society to
new stages of development.
Please, stop!!
They all trusted you.
They all trusted you, and
you betrayed them?
It wasn't we who betrayed them,
but their own prayers that did.
All hopes are wishes for something other
than the current reality, after all.
And anything that doesn't match reality
is bound to create a distortion.
So why is it surprising that these
things always end in disaster?
If they considered such a natural
outcome to be a "betrayal,"
they were wrong to have
made wishes at all.
Not that I am calling them foolish.
After all, it was thanks to their sacrifices...
that human society has
developed as far as it has.
All the tears shed throughout history...
have laid the foundations
of the life you have now.
If you understand now,
why are you still holding the fates of
a few individuals to be so precious?
After all the time you spent
watching over those girls...
do you really feel nothing for them at all?
Did you never try to understand
how much they were suffering?
If we had the capacity to
comprehend such things,
we wouldn't have had to come to
your planet in the first place.
In our society,
the phenomenon known as "emotion"
is only considered a mental disease.
That's why, when we discovered
humankind, we were quite surprised.
We never imagined a world could exist...
in which every individual had
its own set of emotions...
...and still somehow managed
to coexist with others!
If you... had never come to Earth, then...
Most likely, you would all still
be living naked in caves.
You know what...
...it really does hurt, losing one
of my own students this way...
Yeah...
We still don't even know what
really happened to her...
Now, I'm hearing that one of the third-year
students is missing as well...
Everyone was in an uproar
at the last staff meeting.
No one knew anything, I'm guessing?
It seems that Sayaka was quarreling
with a friend over a boy.
She's taking all of this pretty hard too.
This kind of thing...
should've just passed with some
heartache and bittersweet memories.
But since it ended this way...
The police are going to rule
it accidental death...
exacerbated by mental stress after
running away from home.
They don't have any leads to go on.
How is Madoka taking it?
I don't know.
My gut tells me she knows
something about all this.
But she doesn't seem like
she's lying to me either.
This is the first time...
that I haven't been able to
tell what she's thinking.
Pathetic, isn't it? She's my own daughter...
It's rare to see you so at
a loss over what to do...
Lately, something has seemed
a little off about her.
I can tell something's weighing
on her mind,
but she hasn't come to talk
to me about it like usual.
I thought she would always know
she could rely on me...
It's hard with kids that age...
You turn around one day, and
suddenly, they're all grown up.
It must be a pretty big shock to a parent.
I guess you're right...
At that point, we've got no
choice but to trust them.
What Madoka probably
needs most right now...
is a little time to get a handle
on her feelings.
Just give her some time.
It's so hard not being able to do anything.
You never were good at just sitting
by and waiting, were you, Junko?
HOMURA AKEMI
Can I come in?
Is that...
...Walpurgisnacht?
Kyoko told me about it.
She said it was a witch so strong that
one person couldn't beat it alone,
so the two of you were teaming up.
So you've been preparing for
that all this time here?
Will the city be in danger?
Unlike the other witches you've seen,
this one is powerful enough that it doesn't
need to hide in a Labyrinth.
If it manifests even once,
thousands will die.
Since ordinary humans can't see it,
they'll think the destruction was caused by
an earthquake, tornado, or other disaster.
Then it absolutely has
to be defeated, right?
Now that Kyoko's... dead too...
you're the only magical
girl left who can fight it.
So maybe I--
I can do it on my own.
While Kyoko Sakura couldn't have defeat
Walpurgisnacht on her own, I can.
I actually never needed her help.
I just agreed so that she
wouldn't lose face.
...Honestly?
I don't know why, but...
...I really want to believe in you, Homura.
I don't want to think that you'd lie to me.
And yet, I just can't believe you're
really going to be all right.
I just can't believe what
you're saying is true.
How can I tell you what I’m really feeling?
Homura...?
After all... I'm...
I'm not...
even living in the same time
that you are, Madoka!
You see, I... I come from the future.
I've met you over and over,
and each and every time,
I've had to watch you die.
What do I have to do to save you?
What do I have to do to change your fate?
Searching just for that answer,
I've kept redoing this month.
What do--
I'm sorry... I'm not making
any sense, right?
I must seem horribly creepy, right?
After all, to you...
I'm just some transfer student you've
barely known for a month.
But to me...
To me, you are...
The more times I redo all this, the further
in time we drift from one another.
Our feelings drift further apart, and my
words don't even reach you anymore.
The truth is, I think I've been
lost for a very long time now.
Homura...
I will save you.
That was the feeling that
I started all of this with.
And now, it is the only thing
I have left to guide me.
It's okay if you don't understand.
It's okay if my words don't reach you.
But, please...
Please... just let me protect you.
HOMURA AKEMI
These thunderclouds are spreading and
rotating at unbelievable speeds.
There's no doubt about it,
a supercell is forming!
Issue an evacuation order immediately!
Starting at 7AM this morning...
...an evacuation order is being issued
due to extreme weather conditions.
All residents must immediately
evacuate to the nearest shelter.
This is a public service announcement
for Mitakihara City.
It's here.
Are we going to camp tonight?
That's right!
Tonight, we're camping
here with everyone!
- Yay, camping! We barbeque?
- Homura...
This time...
...I'll put an end to you.
What's wrong, Madoka?
Oh, I'm just going to the bathroom.
Was Homura telling the truth about
being able to win by herself?
Even if I tell you no, would
you believe me anyway?
At this point, explanations are pointless.
You should go and see for yourself.
See how well Homura Akemi is
faring against Walpurgisnacht.
Why does she push herself
that hard to fight?
Because she still hasn't given up hope.
If things go badly, she'll probably just
negate this timeline and try again.
She'll stubbornly continue her battle,
restarting this meaningless chain
of events over and over.
Because at this point,
it is no longer possible for
her to stop or give up.
The moment she acknowledges that
everything she has done is pointless,
and your fate is impossible to change,
Homura Akemi will fall into despair
and turn into a Grief Seed.
She knows that as well.
And that's why she has no choice.
Whether she has any hope of winning or
not, Homura must continue to fight.
So you're saying that as long as she
continues to hope, she can't be saved?
That's right.
It's just as it was for all the other
magical girls in the past.
Madoka, you saw it all as well, didn't you?
But...
But...!
But...!!
Where do you think you're going?
Mom?
I have to go to save a friend.
Leave it to the firefighters.
Civilians need to stay here.
It has to be me!
You don't live your life just for
yourself, understand?!
Did you even think about how much
we would worry if you went off--
I know.
I understand very well how you feel.
Because I love you and dad that much too.
So I understand how much
you both care about me...
...and I know that I need to take care
of myself for your sakes too.
But this is different.
It's because I treasure all of
you that I must protect you.
To do that, there's someplace
I need to go right now!
And you can't tell me what this is about?
Then I'm going with you.
No.
You have to stay with dad and Tatsuya
and make sure they're safe.
Mom, you told me you had raised me well.
I don't tell lies. I don't do bad things.
Will you believe in me now?
Will you trust that I'll do what's right?
Are you sure you're not making a mistake?
That you're not being misled
by anyone's lies?
Yes.
Thank you, mom.
If I let it get any further...
...the shelter will be attacked.
Whatever happens, I have
to stop it right here!
No...!
Why...?
Why?! No matter how many times I try...
...why can't I win?
If I go back again...
I'll only make Madoka's destiny worse...
Then in the end...
Everything I've done...
That's enough.
You've done enough, Homura.
Madoka...
Madoka... You didn't...!
Homura... I'm sorry.
Itsuka kimi ga hitomi ni tomosu
The light of love
Ai no hikari ga
You will turn on in your eyes
Toki wo koete
Someday will go beyond time
Horobi isogu sekai no yume wo
And surely shatter a dream of the world
Tashika ni hitotsu kowasu darou
That is rushing towards destruction
Tamerai wo nomihoshite
What do you wish for
Kimi ga nozomu mono wa nani?
After swallowing up all of that hesitance?
Konna yokubukai akogare no yukue ni
Is there an ephemeral tomorrow
Hakanai ashita wa aruno?
At the end of this greedy admiration?
Kodomo no koro yume ni miteta
Using an ancient magic
Inishie no mahou no youni
That I used to dream of as a child
Yami sae kudaku chikara de
I want to break the darkness
Hohoemu kimi ni aitai
And see you smiling
Obieru kono te no naka niwa
The only thing left in my scared hand
Taorareta hana no yuuki
Is the courage of a broken flower
Omoi dake ga tayoru subete
All I can trust is my wish
Hikari wo yobisamasu negai
And my wish would awaken the light
If someone says it's wrong to have hope...
...then I'll tell them they're
wrong, every single time.
And I know I'll always tell them so.
FINAL EPISODE: MY VERY BEST FRIEND
My very best friend...