Homura... I'm sorry.
I'm going to become a magical girl.
Madoka...
No...
I finally figured it out.
I found a wish I truly want granted.
So I'm going to use my life for it, okay?
Don't!
Because then...
Because then, what have I...
...been fighting for...?
I'm sorry. I’m so sorry.
But I believe it's because you've
protected me for so, so long,
that I am the person I am now.
I really am sorry.
Won't you believe in the answer...
that the one you've protected
all this time has found?
I swear I won't waste everything that
you've done for me, Homura.
Madoka...
Since you're now the central
point of karmic destiny...
from numerous different timelines...
...no matter how enormous the wish, you
will likely be able to make it come true.
It's true, right?
Now, Madoka Kaname...
What is the wish that you will pay for...
...with your soul?
I wish...
I wish to erase all witches
before they are born...
All the witches in all the universes,
both past and future...
With my own hands!
That prayer...
If a prayer like that were granted, it could
unravel the fabric of time itself!
It would go against the very
force of karmic destiny!
Do you truly intend to become a god?!
I don't care what I become.
All those who have fought against witches,
who believed in hope as magical girls...
...I don't want to see them cry.
I want them to be smiling to the very end...
If any rule or law stands
in the way of that...
I will destroy it. I will rewrite it.
That is my prayer... That is my wish.
Now!
Grant my wish...
...Incubator!!
FINAL EPISODE: MY VERY BEST FRIEND
Kaname... do you truly understand
how fearsome a wish that was?
I think so.
It means that for all the past and future,
and throughout all of time,
you will have to continue fighting forever.
In doing so, you will certainly wind up
losing all traces of your individual self.
Simply dying would be a kinder fate.
For all eternity,
you would continue merely as a concept--
a principle that destroys witches.
That's fine. That's what I intend to do.
If someone says it's wrong to have hope,
then I'll tell them they're wrong,
every single time.
And I know I'll always tell them so.
Then it's fine, isn't it?
If you think you can do it, then
you've just gotta do it!
I mean, you've found your
reason to fight, right?
You've decided yourself
not to run away, right?
Then there's no problem! All that's
left is to run full steam ahead!
Right... Thank you, Kyoko.
Then there's something I
should give back to you.
Here you go.
You aren't just granting us hope.
You're becoming hope, itself.
...The hope of us all.
I won't let your prayers end in despair.
None of you have to hate anyone,
or curse anyone...
I will bear all of that cursed destiny
for you. So, please...
To the very end, keep believing
in yourselves!
It's okay. It's all right now.
You don't have to hate anyone anymore.
You don't have to curse anyone anymore.
I’ll go back, before you turned into
this, and take the burden of yours.
Where am I...?
The universe is in the process
of reordering itself...
based on Madoka's new laws.
That's right...
You are able to control
time-crossing magic.
Well, then, let us witness together...
what kind of end the existence called
Madoka Kaname will meet...
That is the Soul Gem her prayer created.
That...?!
Can you see all the cursed destinies
she took unto herself,
as the price for making such
an enormous wish?
She was able to bring forth enough hope
to give birth to an entire universe.
Which is to say,
it will also become enough despair
to end the entire universe as well.
It's only natural, right?
No, it's all right.
My wish was to erase all witches...
And if that prayer really comes true...
...then even I...
should have no reason to despair...
...ever!
Madoka...
With this, your life has ceased to
have either a beginning or end.
No trace of your life on Earth,
nor a single memory of you
will remain anywhere.
Your existence has shifted
onto a higher plane,
and all that will be left of
you here is a concept.
No one will ever be aware
of your presence again,
and you will never be able
to interact with anyone.
You have ceased to exist in this universe.
What are you saying?
That Madoka wished for such an ending?!
You think this is a fair reward
for everything she's done?!
Don't be ridiculous!
This... is even worse...
than death would have been...!
No, you're wrong, Homura.
As I am now, I can see everything
that ever has or will happen.
Both the universes that could have been...
...and the universes that might
one day be. All of them...
Madoka...
And that's why, I finally know...
...just how much you've done for me,
in all those different timelines.
All of it.
How many times you cried,
how often you ended up
covered in injuries...
...and yet, kept going for my sake...
I'm sorry I never knew until now...
I'm so sorry.
It wasn't until I became this way that
I could truly know who you are.
To think that I had such a precious
friend with me all this time...!
I'm so glad I know now.
Homura... thank you!
You really have been my very
best friend, haven't you?
But still, as you are now...
...you no longer have a
place to go home to,
and you'll be separated from
everyone you love...
...to live trapped all alone in
a place like this forever?!
But I'm not alone.
All of you will always be with me.
Because I will be everywhere at
every moment from now on.
So even if you can't see me or hear me,
know that I'll be by your side, Homura.
Are you... really all right
with that, Madoka?
Even though I'll forget you?
Even though I'll never even be
able to sense you again?
It's too soon to give up yet.
After all, you managed to follow me
all the way out here, didn't you?
So even when you go back to your world...
...maybe you'll still be able
to remember me.
It'll be all right. I know it'll be all right.
Let's believe.
Madoka...
After all, magical girls make hopes
and dreams come true!
And I'm sure that if it's just a little one,
real miracles really can happen.
Don't you think?
Madoka! Don't go!
I'm sorry... I've got to go
meet all the others.
I'll see you again one day, Homura.
So for just a little while until
then, I'll say good-bye.
Madoka!!!!
Number 25. Kyosuke Kamijo.
I will be performing "Ave Maria."
Looks like...
I ended up causing you a lot of trouble.
No. I'm the one who should apologize.
In order to save you, I had to leave
things as if nothing has happened.
As a result, this future would
have to disappear as well.
But, I thought it probably wasn't
exactly what you wanted...
I think your wish and all the hard work
you did for it were truly precious.
It absolutely wasn't meaningless.
So...
Yeah.
This is fine.
Really.
All I really wanted was to hear
him play one more time...
I wanted more and more people
to be able to hear him play.
Just remembering that again
is enough for me.
Now I really don't have any regrets.
Well, I guess there is one
thing that bothers me....
But it's Hitomi, after all.
Kyosuke doesn't deserve such a great girl.
I'm sure they'll be very happy...
...won't they?
Yeah.
Should we get going?
Yeah...
...Sayaka?
Where's Sayaka?
Hey! What happened to Sayaka?!
She's gone. Led away by the
indelible Law of the Cycle...
Miki used up all her remaining
power in that last attack.
That idiot!
She didn't have to let herself vanish
just for some boy she liked...!
Idiot... just when we were finally
getting to be friends...
That is the fate of all magical girls.
You've known that since you first
gained this power, surely.
Before the hope we wished for summons
an equivalent amount of misfortune,
we have no choice but to
vanish from this world.
Madoka...!
Akemi?
"Madoka"...?
Who's that?
Madoka! Madoka!
That's right. It looks just like her.
No, Tatsuya. That's not nice.
You don't pull a girl's hair, okay?
Madoka, Madoka!
I'm sorry. Are you all right?
I'm fine. Excuse me for intruding.
"Madoka"... right?
Yeah!
Here I come!
Okay, come on over!
So that's...
...some kind of imaginary friend my
son sees when he plays alone?
I guess that's not unusual
for small children.
Yes. I used to do that, too.
So who is "Madoka"? Do you know her?
Is she some kind of anime
character or something?
Maybe so...
It feels like a name I've both
heard and haven't heard...
I see... Yeah, maybe I've seen her
somewhere with Tatsuya, too...
Sometimes...
...it seems to have such
a nostalgic ring to it...
"Madoka"...
I see...
That is such a cute ribbon!
And exactly the sort of thing I would
like--almost shockingly so!
Allow me to give it to you.
It wouldn't suit an old lady like me.
Well, if I had a daughter, maybe
I would've made her wear it...
I see.
Theoretically, I suppose the system
you described could have worked.
It isn't theoretical. It was real.
Even so, we have no way of proving it.
If the laws of the universe really changed
the way you say they did,
there's no method we could
use to verify that.
And since you are the only one
who remembers that world...
there's no way to tell if your memories are
real or a fairytale you just imagined.
Well, it is true...
that we can't explain why Soul Gems
shatter when they become too sullied.
But that "witch" concept you mentioned
in your story is quite interesting.
As a means of collecting human
emotional energy,
it certainly has its appeal!
If such a lucrative means of harvesting
energy had been available to us...
...we Incubators might have employed a
very different strategy for all of this...
Of course. That's the sort of
creatures you are, after all...
But in that witch world
you were describing,
there weren't any wraiths like
the ones we fight here, right?
So collecting curses must have
been a much faster process!
It wasn't that simple.
And our relationship with you
was fairly rocky as well.
I guess it really is impossible to
understand human values.
Just because witches are no
longer born into this world...
...it doesn't mean the curses of
mankind have ceased to exist.
The distortions of this world
have merely changed form,
and now attack people from the
depths of the darkness...
The miasma is pretty thick tonight.
Honestly, these wraiths
just keep on coming!
No matter how many we beat,
there's no end to it.
Your complaining isn’t going to help.
Come on, let's go.
Though this irredeemable world...
continues repeating its
hatred and tragedies...
...this is still the place that
she once tried to protect...
I remember that.
And I will never forget it.
That is why...
I will keep fighting.
Kawashita yakusoku wasurenai yo
I won't forget our promise we made
Me wo toji tashikameru
I close my eyes to make sure
Oshiyoseta yami
I will move forward,
Furiharatte susumuyo
shaking off the surging darkness
Itsuni nattara nakushita mirai wo
When can I see the future that I lost
Watashi kokode mata mirukoto dekiruno?
Here in this place once again?
Afuredashita fuan no kage wo
Tearing up the shadow of anxiety
Nando demo saite
That floods into me many times
Kono sekai ayunde ikou
I will keep walking in this world
Tomedonaku kizamareta
Time that is endlessly ticking
Toki wa ima hajimari tsuge
now starts
Kawaranai omoi wo nose
With our everlasting passion,
Tozasareta tobira akeyou
And open the door that has been closed
Mezameta kokoro wa hashiridashita
Our awakened souls
Mirai wo egaku tame
Set out to paint our rising future
Muzukashii michi de tachi domattemo
Even if we get stuck on a troubled path
Sora wa kireina aosa de itsumo mattete kureru
The beautiful blue sky always waits for us
Dakara kowaku nai
So I won't be afraid of anything
Mou naniga attemo kujikenai
Whatever happens, I won't give up
Do your best...