Hello!
I'm Katsuki Yuri.
Now that the Russian Punk, Yurio,
has come in pursuit of my coach,
Victor, all hell's broken loose.
The Hot Springs on Ice event is now being
held so that Yurio and I can face off!
Hasetsu Exhibition
Hot Springs on Ice
Presented by Victor Nikiforov
If Yurio wins, Victor will go back
to Russia and be Yurio's coach.
If I win, Victor will stay in
Japan and be my coach.
So I'm gonna give it all the eros I've got!
Third Skate
I Am Eros, and Eros Is Me?!
Face-Off! Hot Springs on Ice
Face-off! Hot Springs on Ice.
First, Yurio's "On Love: Agape."
Agape... Unconditional love.
God's infinite love is
self-sacrificing and uncalculating.
Crap, this is hard.
Victor can pull it off,
but I wonder how Yurio will do it.
Kind of like that. What do you think?
Yeah, I pretty much got it.
Huh?!
Wow... That was amazing.
Hey, who's that chick?
Oh, she's one of the staff here, Yuko-san.
Sorry for interrupting your practice.
It was so wonderful, I couldn't help myself.
Okay, Yuri. You're next.
Let's go!
O-Okay.
Choreography that Victor did for me alone...
"On Love: Eros."
Spurt
Eros... Sexual love.
Pleasure followed by pleasure.
One just drowns in it.
D-Damn, he's so hot!
What the... Are you sick?
It's enough to make even me,
a man, pregnant! Such eros!
Huh?
Can I skate this?
Yuri!
How was that?
Oh, um...
It was very "eros"!
Right?
So, about the program composition...
Which quads can you land?
The toe loop, and...
I can land the Salchow in practice,
but never in competition.
Um, I think I can do it if I try!
So, um...
Okay, you can practice the basics.
I'll teach Yurio first.
I won't teach you anything
you can't do right now.
How many times have you messed
up during a competition?
You have the skill to win.
Why can't you make it happen?
Well, that's probably because...
I lack confidence.
Right. My job is to make you
feel confident in yourself.
No one in the whole wide world
knows your true eros, Yuri.
It may be an alluring side of you
that you yourself are unaware of.
Can you show me what it is soon?
Hey, Victor! Aren't you teaching me first?!
Right.
So, Yuri.
Think long and hard about
what eros is to you.
What eros is to me? What would that be?
Hot Springs on Ice
Yuri vs. Yurio
Hasetsu Exhibition!!
Who knew we'd get a lineup like this in Hasetsu?
Lots of people will come!
Well, either way...
Yuri's back! Cheers!
Cheers!
Huh?
You had to do basic training for half
a day because you didn't get "eros"?
Yeah.
You should have just made something up.
I bet Victor hasn't thought
much about it, either.
Victor's a genius, so he can get away with that.
I could see a story in the program, too.
A playboy comes to a certain town
and bewitches the women left and right.
He decides to pursue the most
beautiful woman in town,
but she isn't swayed.
Then, as they play the game of love,
she finds it difficult to make the right choices
and ends up falling for him.
Then he casts her aside,
as though he's tired of her,
and goes off to the next town.
"Wow! So hot! Take me!"
That doesn't really sound like you, Yuri.
Right?
I bet people will say they'd prefer
to see Victor skate the program.
But you looked pretty sexy in the video
when you copied his program.
Well, I can't copy him.
I'll never surpass him by doing that.
Wait, you seriously think you can
be better than him someday?
Huh?
Oh, um, no, not at all!
I mean, how can someone as
inexperienced in dating as you
beat the hottest bachelor in the world?
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Stop, stop!
Hmm, something isn't right here.
I'm doing it like you showed me, aren't I?
The way you currently are,
your greed is too obvious.
There's no sense of agape, unconditional
love, in your performance.
It's good to have confidence,
but this program isn't where
you should show it off.
Huh?
You're the one who's skated with
complete confidence this whole time!
Well, what's agape to you, then, Victor?!
It's a feeling, of course,
so I could never explain it in words.
Do you bother thinking about
that when you skate?
You're funny, Yurio.
Well, maybe we need a temple.
A temple?
Ow!
Damn it.
I'm an adult male of twenty-three.
I could totally show mature
sexiness if I wanted to.
Hey, hey!
Take a photo of me in the bath
so I can post it online.
Sorry, but we don't let people
take photos in the bath.
Really?
It's no good...
From a physical standpoint,
I'm not even close to eros.
Eros, eros...
It's what causes you to lose the
ability to make normal decisions.
For me, what causes me to
lose that ability is...
I get it now!
Pork cutlet bowls!
That's what eros is to me!
Silence...
Oh, sorry.
It's not...
Okay, let's go with that.
It's nice and unique.
Seriously?
Man, I'm so embarrassed!
They totally think my ideas
are way too immature!
Yuri!
Try to imagine entangling more of the egg.
Think of the pork cutlet bowl!
Got it!
Next, Yurio!
Maybe the temple.
Just tell me if I'm not up to par!
Your free leg's sloppy!
Keep it up!
Put your back into it!
All right...
Hmm...
Well, maybe a waterfall would help.
A waterfall?!
I'm gonna kill him.
Why me, too?
Who cares?
Damn it.
Who cares about agape?
Forget all of them.
Yuratchka...
You were the best of the bunch.
Grandpa, can you come to
practice again tomorrow?
I can skate even better!
I'm fine, even if Mom's not there!
Yurio?
Hey, Yurio!
Are you okay?
Let's call it a day.
Oh... Okay.
What's going on?
Why did he suddenly look so vulnerable?
Ugh... Where's Victor, anyway?
He went to eat at Nagahama Ramen, I guess.
What?
We're going there, too!
Huh?
Nagahama Ramen
Vkusno!
Hasetsu Exhibition
"Hot Springs On Ice" in 1 Day
Victor still isn't here, huh?
They said he was drinking until dawn.
Dumbass.
Oh, Yurio...
Huh?
What?
Please teach me how to land a quad Salchow.
Please!
You suck!
Hey, Pork Cutlet Bowl.
Watch me do it one more time.
Sorry I'm late!
Huh?
What were you practicing just now?
I'm gonna check my choreography.
Agape...
Unconditional love.
To me, that means Grandpa.
Looks like Yurio found his agape.
Maybe he's ready for the next stage.
Huh? Next stage?
Does that mean I have a next stage, once
I perform the eros of the pork cutlet bowl?
I still can't find it, though.
I still lack what would serve as
the backbone this program needs.
Hasetsu Hot Springs
Yu-topia Katsuki
So, what will you do for a costume tomorrow?
Oh! I totally forgot!
I didn't bring anything, either.
That's taken care of!
I had them send all the costumes I've ever
worn in competition from Russia!
Wow!
There are lots of stupid-looking ones.
Hey, you wore this one at the
Grand Prix Final last year!
Hey! Don't pick anything flashier than mine!
This is from the Junior World Championship!
Oh, yeah.
I had long hair at the time,
so my costume suggested both
male and female genders at once.
Oh, that's right...
I choose this one!
Oh, come on! Who is it?
Huh?
You want to practice in my
studio this late at night?
Minako-sensei, I need you
to teach me something.
We're here at Ice Castle Hasetsu, venue of
the Hasetsu Exhibition: Hot Springs on Ice.
Right off the bat,
Hasetsu Exhibition: Hot Springs on Ice
we have skaters Katsuki Yuri and Yuri Plisetsky.
Both your new short programs were
choreographed by Victor Nikiforov.
You'll be presenting them today in competition.
Tell us how you feel going into the event!
Um, it'd be great if you'd try
the hot springs afterward.
Hasetsu Exhibition: Hot Springs on Ice
Hey! We're not asking you to promote tourism!
Promote yourself!
We don't need two Yuris. I'll crush him.
Yes, that's it! Thanks for giving
us what we wanted to hear!
Spasibo, spasibo.
Last but not least, let's hear
from Victor Nikiforov,
who's switched to coaching out of the blue!
Hasetsu Tourism Ambassador
Hi!
Hasetsu is a great place.
Come and visit at least once!
What are you doing, Victor?
Huh?
Stop that! It makes today's
face-off look cheap!
You'd better be ready to evaluate our battle!
You'll grant the wish of whichever
one of us wins, right?
Oh...
Of course!
You forgot, didn't you?
Thank you for coming to the Hasetsu
Exhibition: Hot Springs on Ice,
Wow, this is amazing.
How many years has it been since
so many people were in this rink?
presented by Victor Nikiforov.
Yurio-kun!
It's almost time.
Okay.
It's the see-through costume of legend
from Victor's junior days!
I never thought I'd see it in
person! It's so beautiful...
You're gushing all kinds of fluids again.
You look really good in it! Good luck!
O-Okay.
Oh, you have to go.
Come on, get a move on!
Now, a champion with wins in the Junior Grand
Prix Final and Junior World Championship.
Hoping for a
brilliant senior division debut, with programs
choreographed by Victor Nikiforov,
Yuri Plisetsky!
Davai!
Yuri, davai!
He will be skating to "On Love: Agape."
His first jump is a triple axel.
Excellent.
Everyone's drawn into Yurio's agape performance.
I can tell it's completely different
from what I saw in practice.
That's when Yurio's performance changed.
No one can look away from this
beautiful, ever-evolving monster!
We're approaching the quadruples he was
prohibited from performing in competition.
Not to mention they're in the
second half of his program.
A quadruple Salchow,
followed by a triple toe loop!
He unveiled the quad with a flourish!
Here comes his final jump,
a quadruple toe loop!
He nailed it!
What an astonishing fifteen-year-old!
He nailed all of his jumps!
Sorry, Grandpa.
I'm too busy trying to skate the program
to really think about agape at all!
The last element is his signature move,
the combination spin.
Damn it...
Just end already!
Amazing! A masterful performance!
There's a lot to look forward
to this coming season!
I'm better than this!
Yurio!
That was the best performance
I've seen from you so far!
Go on, greet the audience!
Yuri Plisetsky, who's enthralled the audience!
That was amazing.
He'll definitely rank among the
top senior division skaters.
Right...
If I lose, Victor will go back to Russia.
I don't want that.
I have to win.
I want to win.
I want to win!
Yuri.
It's your turn.
U-Um, I'm...
I'm going to become a super
tasty pork cutlet bowl,
so please watch me!
Promise!
Of course.
I love pork cutlet bowls.
We're pleased to introduce a skater
who represents Japan,
a late bloomer who's become a rising star,
Katsuki Yuri!
Good luck, Yuri-kun!
He will skate to "On Love: Eros."
Yuri!
Good luck, Katsuki-kun!
He's been having difficulty expressing "eros,"
but he said he'll think of how he'd
love to eat his favorite dish,
the pork cutlet bowl.
I pulled an all-nighter to help him practice,
and he's no ordinary pork cutlet bowl.
Who am I dancing for?
I know who.
What a seductive step sequence!
It's hard to believe he's
imagining a pork cutlet bowl!
Good!
You're known for your step sequences and spins.
I want you to teach me how
to move in feminine ways.
Huh?
Trying to be the playboy isn't me.
I want to be the most beautiful woman
in town, who seduces the playboy!
I won't drastically change any moves,
but I think this is a lot closer to how I feel.
At first, I wasn't sure what he
was being all serious about,
but his performance has
integrated his emotions.
It's changed.
Now, we have a spread eagle into a triple axel.
Man, this program is tough.
Scheduling all the jumps in the second
half just because he has stamina
is pretty spartan.
Oops! He stepped out of
his quadruple Salchow!
He managed to stay on his feet
by putting his hand down.
About what you'd expect.
Don't panic!
A mistake like this isn't enough
to make me lose my charms.
I'm better than any other woman out there.
You ask why?
A quadruple toe loop,
followed by a triple toe loop!
He nailed it!
A quad-triple combination
at the very end? Is he insane?
He nailed it, too.
Welcome back, Yuri!
Welcome back!
Guys, it's not "welcome back."
That was a Yuri you've never seen before.
No one could look away.
I'm looking forward to this season now.
Yuri!
That was the tastiest pork
cutlet bowl I've ever seen!
Wonderful!
Th-Thank you.
But can I say something?
S-Sure.
What was with your triple axel
out of the spread eagle?
That was the worst attempt so far.
I know you had Yurio teach you the quad
Salchow in secret, but what was that?
Huh? Yuri?
Yurio-kun, hang on.
You're going back without even
hearing the results?
I already know the results.
That performance...
I'm going to keep going under Yakov.
Later.
Dasvidaniya.
I see.
Don't get me wrong!
I'm the one who'll win at
the Grand Prix Final!
Tell him that!
Katsuki Yuri has won the
Hot Springs on Ice event.
A word, please.
O-Oh, um...
I'm going to try and win the next
Grand Prix Final with Victor!
Thank you for your continued support!
The battle for my very last
figure skating season has begun.
To Be Continued!!!
Who'd even be happy to see me naked on ice?
At the very least, I would be.
Huh?
Fourth Skate:
Like Yourself...
Fourth Skate
And Complete the Free Program!!