Moscow
Sheremetyevo International Airport
Look!
Yakov's team is here!
Meow
Yuratchka!
Yuri!
Mila, watch my luggage.
Huh?
Oh.
Coach Yakov, Yuri's disappeared.
Oh, yeah.
His family in Moscow's coming to pick him up.
My name is Yuri Plisetsky.
In my senior debut, I'm aiming
for number one in the world.
I'm the Ice Tiger of Russia.
Oh, Yuri!
Grandpa!
Crack
S-Sorry, I forgot you had a bad back.
Yuri, I made my usual pirozhkis for you.
Grandpa, have you ever had a pork cutlet bowl?
Pork cutlet bowl?
I had them back in Japan.
They're really tasty!
Are the pirozhkis not very good?
No, that's not what I meant.
Our national hero, Victor Nikiforov,
has returned to Russia as a coach
in the Figure Skating Grand Prix Series.
Eighth Skate
Yuri vs. Yuri
The Horror!! Rostelecom Cup, Short Program
Yuri vs. Yuri.
The Horror!! Rostelecom Cup, Short Program.
How do you feel about returning to Russia?
When will you return to skating?
Until the Grand Prix Final is over,
I won't comment on any future plans.
Right now, I see a lot of potential
in Katsuki Yuri's skating.
I'd like you all to focus on Yuri
at the Rostelecom Cup.
I'm in it, too!
If the skater Yuri has that much charisma,
don't you want to face him
as a fellow competitor?
Hey, it's Yurio!
He's right.
It's Yuri Plisetsky!
Did you all see the short program
I put together for Yurio?
Quit acting like you're still
the top Russian figure skater.
I'm the star in this event!
Oh, it's Seung Gil Lee from Korea.
Unlike the Cup of China, there's
no one here I'm friendly with...
If you want to date my little sister,
you'll have to beat me first!
Sorry, sorry.
Mickey!
Stop, we're just going out for a bite.
Oh?
Sala's leagues above any other woman, idiot!
Hi, Yuri.
Hi, Seung Gil. Do you want to come with—
No.
Hey!
If you're turning a lady down,
can't you be more considerate?
Do I get any benefit out of
being friendly with you?
What?
Hey!
How dare you speak that way to Sala?!
Want a smackdown?!
Could you step aside?
Huh?!
Why are you sneaking around?
Yurio... Good to see you again.
Um, good luck to both of us
in the Rostelecom Cup.
Huh?
You'll suffer a miserable defeat here in Moscow.
I'm going to have Victor stay in Russia.
Right...
If I can't rank higher than fourth in this event,
I won't make it to the Grand Prix Final.
And if I don't, what will Victor do?
The Men's Singles Short Program event
is about to start here in Moscow.
Grand Prix Final
Figure Skating
Grand Prix Series
World Championships
Sixth Event: Rostelecom Cup
Katsuki Yuri & Victor Nikiforov
The Battle to Advance to the Final
After the series' fifth event,
the Trophée de France,
Moscow Small Sports Arena
Moscow, Russia
Sixth Event in GP Series, Rostelecom Cup
Men's Singles Short Program
the current rankings are as follows.
GP Series Men's Singles Point Ranking
Otabek Altin
Christophe Giacometti
Phichit Chulanont
Jean-Jacques Leroy
Yuri Plisetsky
Katsuki Yuri
Michele Crispino
Emil Nekola
Seung Gil Lee
Qualifier for Final
Only the top six skaters will
compete in the Grand Prix Final.
First Event: Skate America
Skate America 2nd Place, NHK Trophy 1st Place
Otabek Altin (Age 18)
Katsuki Yuri & Victor Nikiforov
The Battle to Advance to the Final
Currently, only two are confirmed qualifiers.
One is Otabek Altin of Kazakhstan,
who placed second in Skate America,
Fourth Event: NHK Trophy
and then won the NHK Trophy as a dark horse.
Third Event: Cup of China
Cup of China 3rd Place, Trophée de France 1st Place
Christophe Giacometti (Age 25)
The other is Christophe Giacometti,
who placed third in the Cup of China
Fifth Event: Trophée de France
and first at the Trophée de France.
Sixth Event
The last four spots in the Final will be
fought over by the following skaters.
GP Series Rostelecom Cup
Men's Singles Short Program
Canada's Jean-Jacques Leroy,
who's on a roll after winning
on his home turf at Skate Canada.
Skate Canada 1st Place
Jean-Jacques Leroy (Age 19)
Korea's Seung Gil Lee, a newcomer
to the Grand Prix Series who made
great strides by placing
second in the NHK Trophy.
NHK Trophy 2nd Place
Seung Gil Lee (Age 20)
Michele Crispino of Italy,
here today with his sister, Sala,
after placing third in the NHK Trophy.
NHK Trophy 3rd Place
Michele Crispino (Age 22)
Emil Nekola, a rising star
from the Czech Republic,
who took third at Skate Canada.
Skate Canada 3rd Place
Emil Nekola (Age 18)
Russia's own Yuri Plisetsky,
who made a brilliant senior debut
with a second-place finish at Skate Canada.
Skate Canada 2nd Place
Yuri Plisetsky (Age 15)
And finally, Japan's Katsuki Yuri,
who placed second in the Cup of China.
Cup of China 2nd Place
Katsuki Yuri (Age 23)
He'll be skating in the final group.
The Rostelecom Cup results will also determine
whether Thailand's Phichit Chulanont
will advance to the Grand Prix Final.
Ugh, I'm getting disconnected
from the livestream!
I should've gone to Russia.
You three, go to sleep already!
No!
I want to see it!
I want to see it live!
Group One's six-minute warm-up has ended.
Seung Gil, are you listening to me?
Everything you do is for Pyeongchang.
What you should be focused on right now is...
Seung Gil!
Seung Gil Lee of Korea, age 20.
In his first event, the NHK Trophy,
he drove the crowd wild by skating
to this music, "Almavivo."
The first jump will be a quad.
So far in the world,
only Seung Gil Lee has landed
this jump in competition.
A quadruple loop! Success!
The base value is 12.0.
Seung Gil Lee's theme this season is "greed."
He said he'd like to approach
this season with a different masculine
sex appeal than before.
His theme's similar to Yuri's.
Talk about sex appeal inflation.
Overflowing...
...masculine...
...sex appeal!
Even with the quadruple loop under his belt,
with the arsenal necessary to
compete on the world stage,
Seung Gil still wants to break new ground
and personally requested to skate a mambo.
A triple axel.
Oh, he fell!
I had enough rotation.
The jump was in the second half,
so I get a 1.1 multiplier,
which means a 9.35 with a deduction of 1.
A triple Lutz, triple toe loop.
No mistakes there!
With a 1.1 multiplier, that got me 11.11 points.
Now the final element, a step sequence...
What a passionate step sequence!
His polished execution should be
well-received by the judges.
His face is expressionless,
but his steps are out of this world.
He's evolved even further since the NHK Trophy!
Wow!
That's a hard act to follow...
Yeah, right.
That was hot!
I've never seen you nervous.
Mickey! Sala!
Let's all go to Barcelona!
Seung Gil Lee's score is 91.83, a personal best.
RK: 1
Seung Gil Lee     Total
He's currently in first place!
Next up is Emil Nekola of
the Czech Republic, age 18.
Cheers from the crowd never
affect my performance.
He sure can jump,
but if his performance is lackluster...
Is it?
Once Mickey's done,
it's almost time for Group Two.
Did you all hear that?
Emil landed a quadruple loop, too.
Applause!
Huh?
Oh, sorry. I didn't catch that.
Victor did the same jump
at last year's exhibition.
I want to see that again!
I don't recall.
Aww!
RK: 2
Emil Nekola     Total
Emil Nekola's score is 82.43.
He's currently in second place.
Mickey, you'll one-up me now, right?
Mickey, hey!
Next up is Michele Crispino of Italy.
Sala!
His sister, Sala, is also here for support.
He will skate to "L'Homme Armé" from
the movie Destiny of Knights.
See my chivalry, Sala!
A triple axel.
Mickey!
I've defeated every single man who's
tried to approach Sala so far.
I want to skate with Sala forever!
My love will take a back seat to no man!
A quadruple Salchow.
Ah, he fell.
Sala...
I don't want you feeling down because of me
when your short program is coming up!
As your older brother,
and as a man...
Only my love, the kind that doesn't
rely on physical love,
can protect Sala as a lady!
The next jump combination is
a triple Lutz, triple toe loop.
Oh, no way...
The combination turned into
a triple Lutz, triple loop!
That combination has a very high difficulty.
Among active skaters, only his sister,
Sala Crispino, attempts this combination.
Wow, what a surprise!
Sala...
I'm sure you'll be able to jump that
combination like I just did!
Don't worry.
We'll always be together.
Mickey has to reach a place where he
can win without my being around.
Sala!
Mickey!
If something doesn't change,
both of us will go down.
RK: 2
Michele Crispino     Total
Michele Crispino's score is 89.65.
All right! Sala!
He's currently in second place.
Grandpa, you're not coming?
Oh, jeez! I still can't connect!
Why won't they show the event live on TV?
Oh, finally!
It's already Yuri's turn!
Good luck, Yuri!
Enough already!
Victor! Victor! Victor!
Katsuki Yuri won second place in the
Cup of China with the power of love.
Victor! Victor! Victor!
What kind of performance will he give us here?
Victor! Victor!
The performance has already begun, Victor.
You're right.
Don't worry.
I'll show my love to the whole of Russia.
That was so embarrassing.
But before the crowd can
intimidate me in enemy territory,
I have to intimidate them!
Japan's Katsuki Yuri, age 23.
He's skating to "On Love: Eros."
He's been beating his short program personal
bests since the first event in the series.
He'll need to finish fourth or higher
to advance to the Grand Prix Final.
If I lose at the Rostelecom Cup,
this may become the last time
I can skate this program
with Victor at my side as my coach.
Maybe no one in Russia, or even the
entire world, wants me to win.
Thinking that runs chills up my spine.
I'm the only one who can change that world!
I guess Yuri is more motivated
when he's competing away,
where expectations are lower.
At any rate, he's in his best form so far.
His first planned jump is a triple
axel from a spread eagle.
A triple axel.
Very clean!
A quadruple Salchow.
Yuri!
Amazing!
A quadruple toe loop, triple toe loop.
He nailed the last combination, too!
He's refined the program this much since
the Hot Springs on Ice event, huh?
Another flawless performance, following his
last short program in the Cup of China!
The crowd's giving him a standing ovation!
Yuri!
My skating must've gotten my message across.
Crap.
And here I thought I'd be able to perfect
"agape" by having Grandpa watch.
Yuri...
That was perfect!
Out of my way, pig.
Th-This is Yurio's real agape!
Nice!
Good!
Yuratchka!
Yuri!
Yuri, no need to get tense just
because it's the Rostelecom Cup.
All the work you did in practice
won't betray you.
Listen, have confidence in yourself.
Huh?
I can't hear very well.
Calm down.
Calm down!
109.97!
You did it, Yuri!
He's surpassed his personal best again!
He's now in first place!
Oh, my!
Overcome with happiness,
Nikiforov kissed Katsuki's skate!
Yurio!
Davai!
Huh?
Good luck, Yurio!
Grrr!!!
Yuri?
The usurper skater of Russia,
Yuri Plisetsky, age 15.
His program was choreographed
by Victor Nikiforov.
Damn it, I'm not so down on my luck
that I need you guys cheering me on.
He's skating to "On Love: Agape,"
a different arrangement of the
music used in Katsuki's program,
with an opposing theme.
Crap!
I'm not feeling agape at all.
I'm angry!
Here comes the first jump, a triple axel.
Ah, he fell!
Crap!
Since last year, I haven't missed
that triple axel once until now!
A flying sit spin.
His position is quite beautiful.
I've been pouring blood, sweat,
and tears into this
since that humiliation, too.
I just lack overall experience, that's all.
The first quad comes in a combination.
A quadruple Salchow, triple toe loop.
A fantastic jump combination
with great height and flow!
With such polish,
it's hard to believe he only started
doing that this season.
And here comes the final jump.
A quadruple toe loop.
Beautiful!
Yuri Plisetsky of Russia has
truly remarkable talent!
Even when he wasn't at his best,
he always analyzed his performance
mid-program to make a strong comeback.
That's right.
Have pride in yourself as a work
of art until the very end, Yuri.
This is damn tough...
Yuri Plisetsky has delivered a beautiful
short program in response
to the local supporters' high
expectations here in Moscow!
So cute!
Oh, ladies first.
I forgot there was someone even
more annoying than those two.
JJ!
The score's up.
RK: 2
Yuri Plisetsky     Total
Yuri Plisetsky's score is 98.09,
putting him in second.
Katsuki Yuri remains in first place.
The last competitor is the skater with
the most momentum right now,
Jean-Jacques Leroy of Canada, age 19.
He's known as "JJ."
He will skate to an original
song composed for him,
"Theme of King JJ."
I'm the only one in the whole
wide world who can pull off
a dream collaboration with
a world-famous rock band!
A quadruple toe loop, triple toe loop.
He's doing mega-jumps right off the bat!
He placed third in last year's Grand Prix Final.
This season, he has won Skate Canada,
and currently has the greatest momentum.
Watch me do another big one!
A triple axel.
That was another mega-high jump
that almost cleared the fence!
You might expect a top skater
to plan a lot of jumps for the
second half of their program,
but I'm different.
Because I value the collaboration
between my skating and the music!
It's JJ style!
Let's go! Everyone sing along!
The lyrics express how JJ is at the top of the
world and invite everyone to follow him.
What an impressive step sequence.
Now, the last jump is a mega-jump that
not even Victor Nikiforov ever
attempted in the second half,
a quadruple Lutz.
He did it!
No one else takes such risks, right?
I get them done because...
Right, because I'm the king!
I never stand still.
Or rather, I can't stand still!
Huh?
JJ!
It's JJ Style!
Oh, Yuri?
Veterinary Hospital
Sorry to bother you during an event,
but Maccachin stole some buns,
and they got stuck in his throat.
We're at the vet right now,
but we're not sure he'll make it.
RK: 1
Jean-Jacques Leroy     Total
Jean-Jacques Leroy's score is 113.56!
It's JJ style!
He's surpassed his personal
best Skate Canada score!
Sorry, what do you want us to do?
Victor!
Go back to Japan right now.
I'll face the free skate tomorrow on my own!
Don't eat too many pirozhkis tomorrow, okay?
Yeah, yeah.
Huh?
But you have to go back!
Like I said, I can't.
What's going on with them?
Yakov!
Thank God!
You're the only coach for me.
What?
You want to come back?
Can you be Yuri's coach tomorrow,
for just one day?
Huh?
Huh?!
To Be Continued!!!
Whine...
My dear Yuratchka, eat some pirozhkis.
I'd like some, too.
I have no pirozhkis for you!
You don't seem to have changed.
Next time, Ninth Skate:
Yuri Versus...
...Yuri.
Ninth Skate
Yuri vs. Yuri
The Horror!! Rostelecom Cup, Free Skate
The Horror!!
Rostelecom Cup, Free Skate.