Motivation
What's wrong, Yukko?
I just don't have any motivation.
What are you talking about?
Come on, we're high school students,
and it's the start of the new semester.
If you just get started,
the motivation will come to you naturally.
But I don't have the
motivation to get started.
What do I do about that?
The motivation to get started, huh?
You just have get started anyway!
All right!
I wish I could be a simpleton.
Professor, please wake up already!
Shinonome Laboratory
Nichijou: Everyday Life, Part 1
Good morning.
What're you doing?
Making breakfast. We're having fried fish.
What? But, omelet rice...
Didn't you already eat that yesterday?
Besides, fish is good for you.
Don't be picky.
If you don't eat anything, you won't grow...
Ah, that's our breakfast!
What?
Oh, no!
This isn't a robot part,
it's a... uh...
It ran away.
Wait!
Bye.
Wait, what if that cat is down on his luck... ?
I'm going to crash!
Tatta ima hajimete kizuita
I only just noticed
that I fell in love
Koi ni ochita no da no
All I think of the whole day is you, you, you
Nijuuyo jikan kimi kimi kimi
and I can't do anything about it
Ishiki sezaru wo emasen
Somehow
Nanka
you're different when you're with me
Itsumo to chigau kimi to
Together
Futari
Are we doing this conversation wrong?
Doji na kaiwa masaka
Again, today
Kyou mo
Nah, the love is one-sided
Iya kataomoi
Rats, our glances met
Yabai shisen acchatta
What's up with this excitement?
Nani nani kono dokidoki
My train of thought slips into chaos
Shikoukairo guchagucha konran
This is the first time it has happened to me,
Konna koto hajimete da yo
maybe I have a fever?
Netsu demo aru no kana
My love awakened with a bang and my heart beat faster
Kyun to shougeki chatta koigokoro
There was no pride in it
Jimankan datte de nakatta
My s-s-stupid hands are trembling
Ba-ba-baka na te ga furueru zo
This'll bring my family together
Kore kazoku ni yuugoi na no
The conversation we h-h-had goes in circles
Ya-ya yacchatta kaiwa kami makuri
That's the role of an awkward silence
Kimazui chinmoku no ninmu na no
I want
Kimi no
to know your feelings
Kimochi shiritai yo
O-o-o-o-one-sided love
Ka-ka-ka-ka-kataomoi
My first love
Hatsukoi
on my normal way to school
Itsumo no tsuugakuro
glitters brightly
Pikapika hikaru
I will fall in love
and seems to fly
Sore mo tobesou sa
O-o-o-o-one-sided love
Ka-ka-ka-ka-kataomoi
Wooden Figurine
Red Cow
Salmon
Mio, selamat pagi.
Yukko, good morning.
What should I do?
I forgot to bring my student ID.
What? No response to selamat pagi?
You don't think an upperclassman
will call me out on it, do you?
If that happens,
why not just say you're a third year?
That won't solve anything.
What? Was that thunder?
But it's sunny.
We might have a sudden storm!
With showers and hail!
It's raining wooden figurines.
A-are you okay, Yukko?
I can't believe it's a figurine...
What a surprise.
I wonder where it came from.
I don't know...
But not many people ever get hit in the head by a wooden figurine!
That hardly ever happens to anyone, right?
Not that I've seen.
Maybe I'm lucky!
I'm not lucky...
Yukko, are you okay?
I can't believe it's a red cow...
A red cow...
No, I'm not unlucky.
Think of it this way, Mio.
I should be glad no
raw foods have hit me.
It could have been worse.
It's salmon!
Prefectural High School
Morning.
Good morning.
Mai, good morning.
Selamat pagi!
Good morning.
Mai, what are you reading?
A real estate magazine.
What? Mai, are you moving?
Undecided.
No response to selamat pagi?
Fine. I guess I'll have to put this phrase to sleep.
Yukko...
Selamat malam.
Oh, Mai! Don't you mean selamat pagi?
What language is that?
H-homeroom is starting...
When I arrived at school this morning,
I found this in my shoe locker.
Did someone put this in there?
U-um, if anyone knows
who did this, please tell me!
Mio, who'd do
something like that?
Maybe it was a prank?
Maybe it was a student
with a crush on her.
But a statue of the Maitreya Buddha?
But I guess I can understand what it's like
to have one-sided feelings
for someone, though.
You mean like your
feelings for Sasahara?
Y-you idiot!
Where am I?
I need to get home.
The professor must be worried,
and I left the grill on.
I can't get down!
I lost my chopsticks.
And my slipper!
What am I going to do?
I lost my arm!
Now everyone will know I'm a robot...
Here we go.
Wonderful
I'm finished.
Hey now, if you don't hurry up and eat,
we'll be late to fifth period.
Huh? I thought you liked wieners.
I save the tastiest part
of my lunch for last.
And I wrap it up by saying "delicious".
Now then, here I go!
Nichijou: Everyday Life, Part 2
It slipped through!
It's not over yet!
It's over!
Not yet!
One...
Two...
Three!
Safe!
You're definitely out!
Jeez, Mio. Don't you know the three second rule?
No, that was a total out!
Delicious!
She's kind of an idiot...
First comes rock! Then comes paper...
You can't throw all of them,
rock, paper, scissors!
Okay!
Good morning, everyone.
Spring is here,
and a new year has begun,
but it's still quite cold.
I'm twice as cold as
any of you, though.
Nichijou: Everyday Life, Part 3
In any case, be sure not to catch a cold.
All right?
Please, promise your
principal that you won't.
If you break that promise...
I'll become the principal of another school.
Hey, Mio.
What is it? We'll get in trouble for talking.
Do you think that the principal knows
how old all of his jokes are?
He must know better than anyone
that nobody thinks they're funny...
I don't know.
Wait, what if he knows they're not funny,
but he just wants to show today's corrupt youth the meaning of hard work?
If that's the case, this
principal is absolutely diabolical!
Mai?
Mai...
You don't think she
really thought his joke was...
I've never seen Mai
laugh so hard before...
All right, I'll try this!
Why do I feel
that if I say anything right
now, I'll lose everything?
Yukko...
Oh, sorry. Never mind.
I'll wait just a bit longer.
Before I remove it.
Squid Tentacle
Moving on, Ms. Sakurai has an important message for you all.
Ms. Sakurai, if you please.
Um, Ms. Sakurai...
Yes!
Excuse me, I'm the
student adviser, Ms. Sakurai.
Please excuse me...
Oh, being in front of this many people makes me nervous.
No, I can't act this way.
Otherwise, I'll never become
the teacher I want to be.
I have to swallow my fears!
I know!
Recently, I've seen a lot
of goats around school.
Please, do not bring
your goats to school!
Goats?
What do you have against goats?!
Arriving by goat...
doesn't violate school policy!
What? Uh...
Mio, isn't that Sasahara?
Oh? Is that so...
I will allow goats!
No you can't! Cannot! I forbid it!
Bringing a goat is definitely not okay!
Don't say that, Tachibana Misato.
Why must I walk on my own two legs?
As the Sasahara family's eldest son...
Who cares if you're the
Sasahara family's eldest son?
Aren't the Sasaharas just a farming family?
So what?
What's wrong with an eldest son calling himself the eldest son?
Sasahara comes from a farming family.
I feel deceived.
That goat by the bicycles was Sasahara's...
Lawsuit Victory
Sasahara came for me on a white goat!
Ah, happy new year.
Me, too...
Mio!
Talking on your phone while riding a bike is extremely dangerous.
Don't do it at all! Finally...
I found a Maitreya in my
shoe locker this morning.
I don't find this sort of action to be acceptable!
Excuse me! Coming through...
Maitreya...
Mai, don't just stop all of a sudden!
Is this...
déjà vu, or something?
Now, who did it?
I won't be mad, so please raise your hand.
We'll stay here all morning
until you turn yourself in!
Who did it?
Turn yourself in.
Well, I heard it was your birthday, Ms. Sakurai...
Oh my, so you really don't like Maitreya?
I thought you'd like it for your birthday,
but you didn't want a Maitreya statue.
Principal
This concludes the
morning announcements.
Thank you for your
work until now, Principal.
Vice Principal?
Button
Don't you feel tempted to
push the fire alarm button?
You're right, I do.
Why don't you push it?
The last time I pushed it,
the alarm didn't go off.
Really?
What? A fire?
No way!
What do we do? Should we run?
We have to get outside!
Stop pushing me!
You pushed me first!
What are you talking about?
I've always hated you!
Cut it out! Someone could die!
Just run! You can argue later!
Excuse me.
Excuse me, but do you know
What does "clueless" mean?
Excuse me, but could you
tell me what "clueless" means?
Help me!
Hey!
Captain, what's "clueless"?
You are.
Class 2-P, Sasahara Koujirou.
Requirements and Affairs
Please see Tomioka in the
faculty office immediately.
Requirements and Affairs
I know it doesn't violate school policy,
but why do you have to ride a goat?
Can't we work this out?
If you don't like walking,
you could always ride a bike.
So long as it's not a goat.
Sir.
It's Tomioka.
Tomioka.
Call me teacher.
Teacher, could you please call him
Sasahara Kojiro, rather than "goat"?
He's a goat for now.
Nichijou: Everyday Life, Part 4
My name is Shinonome Nano.
I'm a robot, made by
the professor I live with.
The professor seems to be doing research,
so she stays home all day.
I spend my days helping her.
Professor, I warmed up some milk for y—
I don't have any special
features, but I can still feel pain.
Nano, what's wrong?
Professor, my toe... My toe...
Y-y-your t-t-toe...
It should be all right now.
I don't have any special features,
but my toe can come off.
Professor, what is this key for?
I've never turned it?
No, but it spins every now and then.
If you turn it like this...
What's going on?
I'm sorry, I do have special features.
See? Fun, isn't it?
Is that the only reason this key is here?
Yup.
That's the only reason for this key?
Yup!
Please remove it!
Nope!
It's cute.
I'm serious. Please remove it!
What? But it's cute...
I want to be more normal.
I want to sit in chairs normally,
and roll over normally in my sleep.
I can't go to school like this.
I wish I wasn't a robot.
Nano...
I-I'm just kidding!
You're being silly, Professor.
Then take it...
What?
Take my Akutagawa Prize!
Why?
This is my everyday life.
Where am I?
I wake up in the morning, brush my
teeth, and before I know it it's 10 PM
Asa okite ha wo migaite atto yuuma gogo juuji
We laughed and had a lot of fun today
Kyou mo takusan waratta na takusan tokimeita na
and at times my friends and I chatted noisily like nitwits
Tomodachi to baka mitai ni sawaideru toki ni mo
When our eyes met, flutteringly, it was coincidence
Chirachira tte me ga au guuzen da yo ne
It's not in me to say this is my first love
Hatsukoi da tte ienai kyara ja nainda mon
Hey, we'll see each other tomorrow, right?
Nee ashita mo aeru yo ne
If I close my eyes, all I see is a sparkling you
Mabuta wo tojiru to kirakira kimi darake
I wonder why today was so much fun again
Kyou mo tanoshikatta ne aa doushite kana
I'm so happy, happy, that my love awakened
Ureshii na ureshii na hajimemashita koigokoro
I'll see you again tomorrow, so good night
Ashita mata aeru ne oyasuminasai
I'll see you in my dreams soon, so good night
Yume de sugu aeru ne oyasuminasai
Hello! I'm Nano's big toe.
I'm actually quite small.
I wish I were a little bigger...
The next episode of Nichijou is episode 2.
Narration: Katsura Reiko
Don't miss it.