Sakamoto Medicine
Tatta ima hajimete kizuita
I only just noticed
that I fell in love
Koi ni ochita no dano
You are on my mind all day, day, day
Nijuuyo jikan kimi kimi kimi
and I can't do anything about it
Ishiki sezaru wo emasen
Somehow
Nanka
while having an awkward conversation
Itsumo to chigau kimi to
with you
Futari
you seem different from usual, could it be...
Gikochinai kaiwa masaka
Mutual love?
Ryouomoi
Nah, it's is one-sided
Iya kataomoi
Oops, our glances met
Yabai shisen acchatta
What's up with this excitement?
Nani nani kono dokidoki
My train of thought slips into chaos
Shikoukairo guchagucha konsen
This is the first time it has happened to me,
Konna koto hajimete da yo
maybe I have a fever?
Netsu demo aru no kana
Suddenly my first love wavered
Kyuuten shogedashichatta koigokoro
And I instantly blushed a deep red
Atchuuma kao hakka de makka ka
My s-s-stupid hands are trembling
Ba-ba-baka na te ga furueru zo
Is this what's commonly referred to as love?
Kore ga zoku ni iu koi na no
The conversation we h-h-had goes in circles
Ya-ya yacchatta kaiwa kami makuri
Awkward silence, mmhmmhmhm
Kimazui chinmoku mamimumemo
I want
Kimi no
to know your feelings
Kimochi shiritai yo
O-o-o-o-one-sided love
Ka-ka-ka-ka-kataomoi
My first love
Hatsukoi
on my normal way to school
Itsumo no tsuugakuro
glitters brightly
Pikapika hikaru
I will fall in love
I feel like I can fly in the sky
Sore mo tobesou sa
O-o-o-o-one-sided love
Ka-ka-ka-ka-kataomoi
Hey, Mio.
What?
I've been wondering for a while now...
Why do you always
wear those pigtail holders?
Oh, these? Well...
I just do, I guess.
You just do?
I just do, so I do.
I forgot my math notebook...
Huh? We have math today?
We do. We even had
homework, remember?
I'll go get it. You go on ahead.
Well, I didn't do my homework,
so it doesn't matter
where my notebook is.
Mai!
Selamat pagi!
Nichijou: Everyday Life Part 9
Here it is! Ms. Mai's doing it!
Is this her dreaded silent treatment?
The scale is huge.
Like a mountain...
it's mountainous!
Maybe it actually is a mountain?
I guess not...
I know...
I know why you're mad, Mai.
I was watching TV in my room last night...
It's because I took a piece of broccoli from your lunch yesterday, isn't it?
That's why I bought some broccoli!
I didn't know you liked
broccoli until after I ate it.
I knew I'd done something terrible,
and so, I'm giving you this.
My dad just wouldn't shut up, so...
It's not the broccoli.
It isn't the cauliflower, either.
So much has happened lately,
so I can't tell exactly why she's mad.
But I've got a general idea.
I don't want things to
stay this way forever...
I'll just have to apologize!
Mai!
I'm sorry I ate your
main dish yesterday!
I'm sorry I ate your bunnies!
I'm sorry I ate your rice!
I'm sorry I didn't eat
your black beans!
What is it? Why are you so mad?
I don't get it...
You're not mad about
yesterday's lunch?
Is this about the time you
had that thing on your desk?
Is it because I broke your
Maitreya statue's neck?
Or because I borrowed
it without asking?
Or because I secretly buried it?
Is it because I changed my mind
and left an offering on your desk?
Is it because I changed my
mind again and burned it?!
Hey, Mai!
Oh, you were listening to music?
No wonder you didn't hear me.
I didn't notice, so I've just
been talking to myself.
That was close.
I almost spilled the beans...
The second half.
I didn't know about that.
Tanaka
Oh, Tanaka!
I'm sorry, but do you have a minute?
Uh, um, d-don't you think that hairstyle's...
just a little... inappropriate?
Teacher.
Yes?
Want a red bean pancake?
Nichijou: Everyday Life Part 10
Oh, no! I forgot we had a worksheet to do!
There are still five minutes until math...
Mio already showed me
her homework yesterday...
Just this once!
I can't ask her again!
I'll have to...
Mai...
This is really embarrassing.
I forgot to do my math homework.
I'd be really glad if, maybe, if you don't mind, you could show me yours for just a min–
Here.
Oh, thanks! Thank you!
Just wait a second. I'll copy
this at super-mach speed!
Oh, no! I'm really late!
Oh, no! Oh, no!
Shut up! It's still early, Masao!
Oh, no! I'm really late!
I've been laid off!
That's strange. Um, Mai...
This doesn't look like
the math worksheet...
I'll buy you some juice!
Here.
Thanks!
I'm late to school, and my
dad's been laid off! Oh, no!
I don't have time for this!
Look! Masao's in trouble!
What's Masao going to...
No... wait.
I don't have time for this, either!
I almost got distracted!
The worksheet, Mai!
I'll buy you that thing from the station!
Here.
Thanks!
This! This is it!
You had it, after all.
Why didn't you just
hand it over, you tease?
I'll knock it out in a second.
How long ago did I
get my worksheet?
I want to go to New Orleans.
Find the area of ABCD
A quadrilateral ABCD is inscribed in a circle
So, does anyone know the
answer to this problem?
No one?
Akagi's classes are tough...
He hits you if you forget your homework,
and he yells at you for
answering problems wrong.
Bear in mind that your lack of enthusiasm will be reflected on your evaluations.
So that's his game...
I won't crumble under such threats!
Nichijou: Everyday Life Part 11
Well, how should we do this...
Today is the 23rd,
so student number 23...
There it is!
Nakanojou...
is absent today.
What?
I... I'm cramping up!
Why did my arm
have to cramp up now?
This isn't good. I'll end
up in his field of vision.
Well, it's May, so student number five will...
No, I just called on him.
Must stay out of sight. Out of sight...
I'll call on someone new.
Out of...
The chair! I'll pretend it was the chair...
What's that sound? What is that?
Hey! Someone's phone is ringing.
Thanks for calling.
No one has a ring tone like that.
Everyone's smiling now, huh?
Now, about this problem...
Aioi.
First comes rock! Then comes paper...
You can't throw all of them,
rock, paper, scissors!
It's fading!
Um... I bought milk and sugar.
Nichijou: Everyday Life Part 12
I didn't forget anything, right?
Eggs were cheap today, weren't they?
I bought two cartons.
What a good deal.
Oh, no! Eggs were on sale today...
What should I do?
I can still make it.
I guess I'll go back to the store.
It's a black cat...
H-how cute...
There's no way I can keep it.
I already have the
professor to take care of...
I'm sorry.
I'm home...
Welcome back!
What? That cat!
I found him!
You can't just bring cats home.
What? But he's cute...
That's true...
I mean, no! That's not it!
You don't think he's cute?
No, he's cute. He's cute, but...
If we keep a pet, you'll
have to take care of him.
Can you do that?
I can!
I won't help at all.
You can't forget to
clean up his litterbox.
You won't do anything?
Then I won't let you
touch him, either!
B-but... no! That's not what I...
Professor, he fell asleep!
I want to pet him!
He's so fluffy!
No fair, Professor! Me, too! Me, too!
His stomach is fluffy, too!
His sides are fluffy, too!
His right foot is fluffy, too!
His left foot is fluffy, too!
His tail is even fluffier!
The back of his ears
are fluffier than his tail.
What? But when I touched
it, the tail seemed...
His tail isn't fluffy!
What's wrong?
Are you hurt somewhere?
Eureka!
Hold on.
Professor?
Nano! Nano! Nano!
I invented a scarf that
will allow him to speak!
Amazing, Professor! That was fast!
Let's put it on Sakamoto.
Sakamoto? That cat's
name is Sakamoto?
Yeah! That's what
was written on his box.
Doesn't that seem
a bit too simple?
Finished!
Will he talk?
He will.
I want to hear it...
That was too much
petting, don't you think?
When cats meow, they're
almost always hungry.
I'm sorry. I didn't know.
Also, my name!
Calling me Sakamoto just because the box said so is too simple.
I'm sorry...
Didn't I tell you?
But...
How old are you?
Eight years old.
One year old.
In human years, I'm twenty years old.
It's Mr. Sakamoto to you.
Osaka dialect...
I'm grateful that I'll be getting
my food for free from now on...
but don't forget to
respect your elders.
And while I have your attention,
you both should reflect on
how much you should pet a cat.
To be honest, I don't
dislike being petted,
but even cats have their limits...
I'm going to return him to
where we found him, okay?
Yeah.
W-wait, wait!
I'm sorry.
Straw
Here you are.
Are you sure?
I haven't paid my rent yet,
and now you're giving me food...
It's fine. Good neighbors
should help each other in need.
Let me know if there's
anything else you need.
Really? In that case...
I don't suppose I could
borrow some money?
Don't get cocky over a few favors.
I'm sorry.
Straw Part 2
V-Vice principal, is this...
What's all the confusion about, Principal?
Try opening its body...
If I win,
Nichijou: Everyday Life Part 13
I don't have to buy
that thing from the station.
Okay?
Nichijou: Everyday Life Part 13
Okay.
I've got this!
Battle for juice, ready...
Go!
Mai, that was a false start.
Right, Mio?
I guess it was a little early. Just a bit.
Right? Let's start over!
Let's start fresh. Ready...
Go!
Mai wins!
I underestimated my
opponent's strength.
I'm finally warmed up.
One more time!
Oh, my. My arm is pretty sore...
I was up all night!
My body and mind are heating up.
Are you ready for the real battle?
Oh, shoot! I looked away...
I let her win three times in a row.
What a surprise!
Yukko, why don't you...
Wait.
Just wait... I see, I see.
I understand now. I get it.
Your beginner's luck
runs out here, Mai!
Let's have a fair fight!
Ready...
Chest!
Pretty fun, isn't it?
What is this?
Yukko...
So, this is what they
call arm wrestling?
Mio, take this!
Could you hold on
to that for a while?
It's finally time to
break out the big guns.
Oh, come on!
I can't give it my
best if you don't!
All right? This time,
give it your best shot!
I'll give it my all, too!
Earth Dangerous!
Shooting Shake!
Death!
Dea...
What was that...
I just don't understand.
Why did I get so worked up over a simple arm wrestling match?
I forgot I had to use the bathroom.
I'll be right back.
I knew something was wrong...
Yukko.
That thing from the
station. And 23 juices.
I wake up in the morning, brush my
teeth, and before I know it it's 10 PM
Asa okite ha wo migaite atto yuuma gogo juuji
We laughed and had a lot of fun today
Kyou mo takusan waratta na takusan tokimeita na
and at times I and my friends chatted noisily like nitwits
Tomodachi to baka mitai ni sawaideru toki ni mo
When our eyes met, flutteringly, it was coincidence
Chirachira tte me ga au guuzen da yo ne
It's not in me to say this is my first love
Hatsukoi da tte ienai kyara ja nainda mon
Hey, we'll see each other tomorrow, right?
Nee ashita mo aeru yo ne
If I close my eyes, all I see is a sparkling you
Mabuta wo tojiru to kirakira kimi darake
I wonder why today was so much fun again
Kyou mo tanoshikatta ne aa doushite kana
I'm so happy, happy, that my love awakened
Ureshii na ureshii na hajimemashita koigokoro
I'll see you again tomorrow, so good night
Ashita mata aeru ne oyasuminasai
I'll see you in my dreams soon, so good night
Yume de sugu aeru ne oyasuminasai
My arm cramped up, and I got
yelled at for not doing my homework.
Today sucks...
But!
Mai! What's going
to happen to Masao?
Hey, Mai!
Fine. I'll buy you another juice.
Okay.
All right!
I don't get it...
Don't you want to
make some kind of joke?
Kinase? What is that,
some kind of serenade?
The next episode of Nichijou is episode 4.
Narration: Masaoka Hiroshi
Don't miss it.