Principal's Office
Lately, our school's
morality has been in decline.
Nichijou: Everyday Life Part 14
Principal's Office
Lately, our school's
morality has been in decline.
I'd like to ask you, as a student adviser,
to crack down on this behavior.
Yes, sir!
I-I'll do my best!
Tattaima hajimete kizuita
I only just noticed
that I fell in love
Koi ni ochita no da naa
You are on my mind all day, day, day
24h kimi☆ kimi☆ kimi☆
and I can't do anything about it
Ishiki sezaru wo emasen!
Somehow
Nanka
while having an awkward conversation
Itsumo to chigau kimi to
with you
Futari
you seem different from usual, could it be...
Gikochinai kaiwa masaka
Mutual love?
Ryouomoi
Nah, it's one-sided
Iya kataomoi
Oops, our glances met
Yabai! Shisen acchatta!!!
What's up with this excitement?
Nani nani!? kono dokidoki!?
My train of thought slips into chaos
Shikoukairo gucchagucha konsen...
This is the first time it has happened to me,
Konna koto hajimete da yo
maybe I have a fever?
Netsu demo aru no kanaa
My love took a sudden turn
Kyuutenchokka irasshatta koigokoro
And I instantly blushed a deep red
Acchuuma kao hakka de makkakka
N-n-no way! My hands are trembling
Ba.ba...baka na!? Te ga furueru zo
Is this what's commonly referred to as "love"?
Kore ga zoku ni iu "koi" na no!?
I st-st-stuttered through our conversation
Yayayacchatta kaiwa kami makuri
Awkward silence, mmhmmhmhm
Kimazui chinmoku mamimumemo
I want
Kimi no
to know your feelings
Kimochi shiritai yo
O-o-one-one-sided love
Kakakata☆kataomoi
My first love
Hatsukoi!!
on my normal way to school
Itsumo no tsuugakuro
glitters brightly
Pikapika hikaru
I DO fall in love!
I feel like I can fly in the sky
Sora mo tobesou sa
O-o-one-one-sided love
Kakakata☆kataomoi
That's right. I became a student
adviser to change myself.
I have to correct their behavior.
Unbelievable! I don't believe it!
No. I must not back down!
E-excuse me...
What is it, madam?
Well, you see...
I-I just think... that it's poor
manners to eat while walking...
Please excuse me.
Since I skipped breakfast,
my stomach has been growling.
I'll put this away immediately.
Please excuse me.
I-I'm sorry. It's no big deal.
As long as you understand...
Good.
If I just talk to them,
the students will understand.
Tell the chef...
it was delicious!
What was delicious?
Why are you shouting in the hallway?
Why don't you think about
common decency for once?
U-uh, y-you shouldn't...
bring that to school...
Misato, come on.
Okay.
Sasahara!
I need to talk to you at lunch,
so you'd better be in the classroom!
School morality might
just be in decline...
Excuse me.
Tachibana Misato means no harm.
Please forgive her.
All right. Excuse me.
U-um...
What is that frilly
thing around your neck?
Oh, this?
Yes. It's sort of cute...
Our everyday lives may, in fact,
be a series of miracles.
They just may be...
So what is that frilly thing?
Well said.
I shall see you in class, madam.
Thank you.
Student Adviser
Excuse me, Nakanojo.
Yes. What is it?
Yes, well, you see...
Don't you think that hairstyle's just... a little too much for school?
No, just a little.
Just a little, I think...
It doesn't...
I'm sorry, I didn't hear you.
Could you repeat that?
It doesn't grow...
It doesn't grow on the sides!
Go-Soccer Club Part 1
Greeeeeeeen liiiiiiiight...
Red light!
Everyone went home.
Nichijou: Everyday Life Part 15
Nano, what's this?
It's a green plum.
I'm thinking of pickling
some plums myself this year.
Pickled plums are sour.
Plums are good for you.
If you put them in rice balls,
they'll keep the rice from going bad.
Nano!
No.
I haven't said anything yet!
We just bought a lot of snacks recently.
Eat those first. Once
we run out, we'll buy more...
Professor...
I said no. Today, that cat... uh...
Sakamoto.
Yes. I need to buy Mr. Sakamoto's dinner, so your snacks...
It's huge.
Excuse me...
May I help you?
Wh-what is this?
Oh, the snowman.
We just got it today.
You're welcome to buy it.
Snack?
Maybe it's for shaved ice?
It's cold.
It's cheap...
You're buying it?
What? N-no, I'm just looking.
It's a snowman.
I want it.
Hey, you.
Yes?
If you're not buying
that, hand it over.
I-I'm buying it.
You get to buy what you want,
but you won't let
me buy what I want...
No, this is...
You get to buy what you want,
so I should get to
buy what I want!
I want it! I want it! I want it!
Fine, fine. But just one.
Really?
I love you, Nano.
Which is why you bought that thing.
Yes. It's cute and refreshing.
Professor, it's ready.
Okay.
Nano, more!
I can't believe you two...
So, where's my dinner?
Shaved ice...
I refuse to eat shaved ice for dinner.
First comes rock! Then comes paper.
You can't throw all of them...
rock, paper, scissors!
It's flying.
The screw!
Nichijou: Everyday Life Part 16
Midterm Exam
Nono...
Okay! The test is over.
Oh my god!
It was a bald cap.
Short Thoughts
When you try to consider
the wishes of others,
there are so many other people that it's easy to get confused.
However, when you
focus on your own wishes,
they seem much easier to grasp.
All that's left is to pray to a god.
So, I pray to that god,
please grant my wishes.
Greeeeeeeen liiiiiiiight...
Go-Soccer Club Part 2
Red light!
Why don't we stop?
Parakeet
I've been sent out
to the hall again...
I'm finally getting
used to this body.
Nichijou: Everyday Life Part 17
Just looking at them
makes me hungry.
What's this?
Oh, Mr. Sakamoto.
They're pickled plums.
Don't eat them.
They're not ready yet.
I'll use this to
play with Sakamoto.
It's a green foxtail.
I'll use this to
play with Sakamoto.
It's a green foxtail.
Sakamoto! Sakamoto...
Child, I told you to say "Mr."!
Oh, right. Sorry, Sakamoto.
Are you making fun of me?
Whoops. I forgot...
Sorry, Sakamoto.
You're doing this
on purpose, aren't you?
I'm going shopping.
See you later.
You girls haven't
been raised properly.
Sorry, Sakamoto.
It's not on purpose.
Don't just call me Sakamoto!
Here, Sakamoto. Have some gum.
How many times do
I have to tell you?
And who would give
gum to a cat, you fool?
Cut it out!
Sorry...
Listen! Like I said,
I'm older than you.
Using "Mr." when referring
to your elders is... um...
It's... you know...
It's... um... You
What?
Can I go pee?
Fine! Go!
Pee!
You're taking it with you...
As far as I can tell, only
those two kids live here...
I can see why they're
so poorly educated.
Which makes me
the oldest in this house.
I suppose I have no choice.
It won't be easy, but I'll
have to act as their parent.
Geez, I've been taken in
by such a ridiculous family.
I can't believe how fun this is!
Sakamoto, what're you doing?
Oh, no!
If she finds out I was
playing with an eraser,
she'll lose respect for me...
Respect...
I was just taking a nap.
Cats sure do sleep a lot.
That's how it is.
Yeah, that's how it is.
I can't teach you too much at once,
but you can start by learning to...
respect... your elders!
Oh, man! This is so fun!
Sakamoto! Again! Again!
Sakamoto! Sakamoto, over here!
No, this is wrong! That was just...
Didn't I tell you to say "Mr."?
Sakamoto!
I'm home.
Home run!
Nakanojo
Mom!
Nichijou: Everyday Life Part 18
Green light...
Red light!
Mai made a confusing joke again.
I guess I should play along.
Mai! Isn't that on the book?
Yukko, don't ever make
a joke like that again.
If you do...
you'll make my jokes look bad.
It's like, you know,
I'm at that age when English
just pops out of my mouth.
But that on the book,
I just didn't know if you
were making a joke or not.
And, you know,
I just couldn't resist...
You couldn't understand?
Are you serious?
Of all people...
I thought you would understand.
Oh, wow. I didn't realize
you thought of me that way.
I'm glad you trust me, though...
Trust you?
Yeah...
We're not friends,
so let's not talk about trust, okay?
Sisters don't need words
to understand each other.
Mai...
Oh, Mai! Sisters can use words, too!
Could you stop touching me?
Huh? Oh, sorry...
Stop it.
If you do that, I...
I might like you even more...
What?
Who cares if you
like me more? Right?
We're sisters! Sisters!
That's not what I meant.
I know we're the same gender,
but I still see you as
someone of the opposite sex.
Sorry,
I don't know how to say it...
W-w-w-w-w-w-w-w-w-what?
What the heck?
I knew something was up today!
Sh-she's talking a
lot more than normal,
and she even suggested
that we go somewhere alone!
Was that all so she could say this?
How long has she...
How long has she been...
U-u-um, M-Mai?
W-well, um... I'm not sure
I really understand, but...
Don't you think we're a little young?
I mean, we're still in high school...
I was joking.
Super-ultra, great,
delicious, wonderful...
incomprehensible!
Don't do stuff like that!
I almost believed you!
I see...
You're quick to catch on,
so I thought you'd get it.
Oh? I guess I got it a little.
You're lying, aren't you?
I'm not lying, it's just...
I was thinking.
The gears were turning...
I mean, there was clearly something wrong with what you were saying.
Didn't you say you believed it?
I hate being lied to
more than anything.
Sorry...
I was joking again.
How am I supposed to tell?!
You didn't notice?
There was one more joke.
I didn't notice! What was it?
When I said you were
quick to catch on.
You were supposed
to say you weren't.
That was iiiiiiiiiit?!
That one's pretty easy to understand.
I wake up in the morning, brush my
teeth, and before I know it it's 10 PM
Asa okite ha wo migaite atto yuuma gogo juuji
We laughed and had a lot of fun today
Kyou mo takusan waratta na takusan tokimeita na
and at times I and my friends chatted noisily like nitwits
Tomodachi to baka mitai ni sawaideru toki ni mo
When our eyes met, flutteringly, it was coincidence
Chirachira tte me ga au guuzen da yo ne
It's not in me to say this is my first love
Hatsukoi da tte ienai kyara ja nainda mon
Hey, we'll see each other tomorrow, right?
Nee ashita mo aeru yo ne
If I close my eyes, all I see is a sparkling you
Mabuta wo tojiru to kirakira kimi darake
I wonder why today was so much fun again
Kyou mo tanoshikatta ne aa doushite kana
I'm so happy, happy, that my love awakened
Ureshii na ureshii na hajimemashita koigokoro
I'll see you again tomorrow, so good night
Ashita mata aeru ne oyasuminasai
I'll see you in my dreams soon, so good night
Yume de sugu aeru ne oyasuminasai
It's been forty years.
This is the apartment building.
Try writing the word "housewife".
I think you'll find an unbelievable amount of sexiness to it.
The next episode of Nichijou is episode 5.
Narration:    Ohara Noriko
Don't miss it.