Nano!
Nano.
Nano...
Nano!
Yes!
Nano, Nano!
Nano.
Yes, yes.
It's me-ow!
Nano!
Look, look!
It's me-ow.
Sakamoto, look. It's me-ow.
Professor.
I think that's cute!
It's me-ow!
It's cute.
It's cute!
It's me-ow!
It's me-ow me-ow!
It's cute!
It's me-ow!
It's me-ow me-ow!
The Shinonome household passed
another peaceful day.
Tattaima hajimete kizuita
I only just noticed
that I fell in love
Koi ni ochita no da naa
You are on my mind all day, day, day
24h kimi☆ kimi☆ kimi☆
and I can't do anything about it
Ishiki sezaru wo emasen!
Somehow
Nanka
while having an awkward conversation
Itsumo to chigau kimi to
with you
Futari
you seem different from usual, could it be...
Gikochinai kaiwa masaka
Mutual love?
Ryouomoi
Nah, it's one-sided
Iya kataomoi
Oops, our glances met
Yabai! Shisen acchatta!!!
What's up with this excitement?
Nani nani!? kono dokidoki!?
My train of thought slips into chaos
Shikoukairo gucchagucha konsen...
This is the first time it has happened to me,
Konna koto hajimete da yo
maybe I have a fever?
Netsu demo aru no kanaa
My love took a sudden turn
Kyuutenchokka irasshatta koigokoro
And I instantly blushed a deep red
Acchuuma kao hakka de makkakka
N-n-no way! My hands are trembling
Ba.ba...baka na!? Te ga furueru zo
Is this what's commonly referred to as "love"?
Kore ga zoku ni iu "koi" na no!?
I st-st-stuttered through our conversation
Yayayacchatta kaiwa kami makuri
Awkward silence, mmhmmhmhm
Kimazui chinmoku mamimumemo
I want
Kimi no
to know your feelings
Kimochi shiritai yo
O-o-one-one-sided love
Kakakata☆kataomoi
My first love
Hatsukoi!!
on my normal way to school
Itsumo no tsuugakuro
glitters brightly
Pikapika hikaru
I DO fall in love!
I feel like I can fly in the sky
Sora mo tobesou sa
O-o-one-one-sided love
Kakakata☆kataomoi
Why is the Earth round?
Why do rockets fly?
Why do magnets attract each other?
All of the world's truths can
be found through science!
RIP
The underworld,
ghosts, and paranormal activity...
Such things cannot possibly exist!
They mustn't exist...
Osorezan
Which is why...
I don't believe in psychic mediums!
Nichijou: Everyday Part 19
I used my day off
to make the eight-hour
journey to Osorezan.
The closer I get to the summit,
the faster my heart begins to beat.
Are there really mediums there?
If they do exist,
where would they be?
Do they live here by themselves?
Or perhaps...
There!
Medium
A-all right! I'll have her
summon something.
Excuse me.
Yes.
Um...
Please summon soap!
Okay.
Hello, I'm soap.
Soap, soap.
What is this helpless feeling?
Could there seriously
be a person named Soap?
Soap, soap, soap.
So-so-soap, I'm so-soap, yes.
I mustn't back down.
If I keep questioning her,
I'm sure she'll contradict herself.
I have a question.
What is your blood type, Soap?
Who knows?
Perhaps I should choose
someone more well-known.
Excuse me.
Nobunaga...
Please contact Oda Nobunaga.
Give me a break.
She refused before
attempting contact!
No... she's old.
It must be a health issue.
Attacking her now would be...
Please excuse me.
I'm going home.
I cannot attack people.
Even if that's all I learned,
I still took something from this.
Sir.
That will be 5,000 yen.
Dharma Drop
100 points
Sneeze
No Way!
Boys are...
Nichijou: Everyday Life Part 20
Study Hall
Ready?
Rock, paper, scissors!
You're doing it wrong, Mai!
I just explained this to you!
When you win, you're
supposed to hit me!
That was amazing!
Amazingly cruel, that is!
You could say it
was worse than a hit!
Ready? Like I explained before,
if you lose, you protect yourself.
And if you win, you hit.
Not yet! Why did you hit me?!
Because I won.
Not now! That was before!
It's in the moment!
We're living in the moment!
That's the kind of
creatures we are!
First comes rock
Then comes paper...
You can't throw all of them,
rock, paper, scissors!
It's me-ow!
Okay, let's try again.
Rock, paper, scissors!
Do you even want to do this?
You're a mime!
You really are a mime!
This is driving me crazy...
Mai?
I found it.
Mai...
Wh-where did that come from?
I carved it.
Oh, good. I thought it
had been reincarnated...
I'll leave this here.
She seems really happy.
Who cares about that? Come on.
Rock, paper, scissors!
M-Mai, that...
That's all of them!
I don't believe it.
How heartless...
Geez, Mai!
You can't do that. You
can't throw all of them.
And don't hit me with the Buddha!
Let's go.
First comes rock,
Study Hall
rock, paper scissors...
Mai.
That's it! That's it! That's it, Mai.
See? You can do it!
Okay, let's go again.
Rock, paper, scissors...
High School Literature
God is dead!
Why did you hit me?
You did it right earlier!
Maybe...
it's because I
don't want to do this.
Can I see your Maitreya statue?
Okay.
I'm going to return
the books to the library.
Look after the
house while I'm gone.
Okay!
Nichijou: Everyday Life Part 21
Why does Nano's dharma
only have one eye?
I know!
If I make an eye for it,
maybe she'll praise me.
Maybe she'll say I
can eat lots of snacks.
I might have made a mistake...
What am I going to do?
Maybe she'll get mad at me.
You can't have any
snacks until I say so!
Um, like this... and this...
What are you doing?
Oh, Sakamoto.
What should I do?
What is this?
What are you doing?
Doesn't this belong to that girl?
But it was missing an eye...
You're hopeless.
Do as I tell you.
I'm home!
Good luck.
Sakamoto!
Are you going out, Mr. Sakamoto?
Professor, I'm home.
Sorry I'm late. I was choosing
a new book to borrow.
What are you doing?
Professor! What's wrong
with your stomach?
Don't laugh!
I'm giving birth.
No, no, no. That's not possible!
I'm giving birth!
The baby's coming!
The baby is coming!
Uh, is this some kind of game?
The baby's coming!
The baby is coming!
No! I'm giving birth to
your younger brother!
It's your brother.
She's done for!
Table
Turning
Mio, Mio.
What?
Let's do some table-turning.
What's that?
You mean you don't know?
I don't.
I'll try to explain it to you.
You start by drawing a shrine gate in the middle of a piece of paper.
Then you write "yes", "no", and the Japanese alphabet all around it.
Okay.
In some places, you're supposed to draw a fried bean curd...
But for now,
let's keep it simple.
Okay.
Then you open the north
window, so spirits can come in.
Okay.
Then you put a 10 yen
coin on the shrine gate...
We both put our fingers on top of
it together, and we ask questions...
about secrets, about love,
or about our worries.
Okay.
Even though we don't do
anything, the coin will move.
And the spirits will
answer our questions.
Pretty amazing, right?
But some things are taboo.
You can't do it alone, and
you have to take it seriously.
Or else you'll be haunted by spirits...
And if you stop in the middle,
you'll be haunted too, so be careful.
I see...
It's kind of a dangerous game.
Let's give it a try.
I'll pass.
What?
Nichijou: Everyday Life Part 22
And with that, we'll stop here.
We'll have a small quiz
tomorrow, so be sure to study.
What? Push it back.
No matter how far
we push it back,
your grade'll still be the same.
Maybe.
Ms. Sakurai!
Aioi, what is it?
There's something
I wanted to ask you.
Yes?
It's about our last quiz.
What is this?
That would be "fly".
Oh no, I wasn't
asking for the answer.
Did you draw this thing that looks
like it'd be killed by a Poof spell?
Oh, yes. I thought drawings
might make the quiz easier...
You draw some cool pictures!
I'm sorry.
Since I'm not very good at drawing,
it must have been hard
to tell what they were...
I see.
Oh, right!
Will you put my
drawing on the next quiz?
I'll draw something really cool.
Okay.
Mio!
Listen to this...
My drawing's going
to be on the next quiz.
What? Why?
The teacher's going to put it on.
If you start drawing now,
you'll definitely get
your drawing in there, too.
I'm not so sure about that...
You're not going to draw?
No, I'm fine. I'll pass.
Besides, I have to return this.
Really?
I'm going to draw a cool guy!
Not bad.
He's so cool!
Aioi, you're great at drawing,
aren't you? I'm impressed.
I'm not great... I'm awesome.
Just kidding.
By the way, his name
is Samidare George.
Oh, that's even cooler!
Cool?
Hold on, you two.
Cool is usually more...
... like this, right?
Amazing! This looks
just like a manga!
Naganohara, do you draw manga?
Well, just a little...
Amazing. You'll have
to show me sometime.
I don't know about that...
You won't? I'd really like to see it.
Please show me.
What? Ah, well...
Give me that!
My drawing's way cooler!
You copied me!
No, I didn't.
It's a type of copying
known as an homage!
You admitted it!
It's so cool...
Anything goes?!
What about this?
Glasses!
Intelligence and a cool look
appeal to women of all ages!
Oh... glasses...
Does he have poor eyesight?
He should wear contacts.
They don't understand!
Mine looks something like this.
They're under his ears!
You copied me again!
They're sunglasses.
He's so cool!
You're okay with that?!
Then, how about this?
The butler!
From picking you up
to serving you tea,
he makes you feel like a young lady!
Taste the magic of Darjeeling!
Glasses again?
I'm sorry, but I don't understand...
You didn't hear what
I said about the contacts.
Mio, you don't understand.
I'll show you the
true meaning of cool...
It's this.
It's floating!
Wait! Is this thing moving?
He looks so fast and cool.
You're joking!
Cool is...
Coolness is...
coolness is something...
True coolness is...
This is cool!
Oh, shooooooooooot...
Just kidding!
1-Q in front of the podium
Naganohara Mio sunk
15:40
A
Short Thoughts
I drew this while listening to jazz.
The Next Day
Morning!
Master, good morning.
Who are you calling master?!
I'm handing out
this morning's quiz,
so please pass them down.
I'm done for...
I wanted to keep
my drawings a secret.
I can't believe
I drew that picture.
But even though I lost control,
it could have been worse.
I should count myself lucky.
But I'm sure Yukko will
tease me for two or three days...
No, no! I must let
go and look forward.
Master Mio, hurry.
Umm...
Begin.
Master Mio...
I wake up in the morning, brush my
teeth, and before I know it it's 10 PM
Asa okite ha wo migaite atto yuuma gogo juuji
We laughed and had a lot of fun today
Kyou mo takusan waratta na takusan tokimeita na
and at times I and my friends chatted noisily like nitwits
Tomodachi to baka mitai ni sawaideru toki ni mo
When our eyes met, flutteringly, it was coincidence
Chirachira tte me ga au guuzen da yo ne
It's not in me to say this is my first love
Hatsukoi da tte ienai kyara ja nainda mon
Hey, we'll see each other tomorrow, right?
Nee ashita mo aeru yo ne
If I close my eyes, all I see is a sparkling you
Mabuta wo tojiru to kirakira kimi darake
I wonder why today was so much fun again
Kyou mo tanoshikatta ne aa doushite kana
I'm so happy, happy, that my love awakened
Ureshii na ureshii na hajimemashita koigokoro
I'll see you again tomorrow, so good night
Ashita mata aeru ne oyasuminasai
I'll see you in my dreams soon, so good night
Yume de sugu aeru ne oyasuminasai
Zing! Boom! Bang!
Nice to meet you.
I'm onomatopoeia.
You can't help but say "cock-a-doodle-doo", even though that isn't Japanese.
Narration:    Koyama Rikiya
The next episode of Nichijou is episode 6.
Don't miss it.