I've brought him here.
Enter.
Well, if it isn't King Albert.
Dolph...
What is the meaning of this?
I thought we could enjoy
a delicious meal together.
Unfortunately, it appears
there's no food for you.
Restrain him.
Yes, sir.
Is that what you're after?
Let's end this game
of hide-and-seek
with the princess, King Albert.
Or should I say Albert?
Did you find her?
No, I haven't!
I'll check over there!
Listen up!
Get the wooden cube.
Don't kill the princess yet.
Do you think your actions
can be forgiven, Dolph?
Forgiven?
Just who do you
think will punish me?
You no longer have
any allies here, Albert.
This trip around the
world that you planned...
was the greatest chance
you could have given me.
I was able to trap the young
princess with my subordinates.
Why? Why did you betray me, Dolph?
Don't say things like that, Albert.
I am grateful to you.
When I was an orphan,
you took me in and raised me,
and you even made me
your kingdom's commander!
Then why?
Do you think I supported you until
now with no ambition of my own?
This is simply the punishment
of our just God, Albert.
Commander Dolph!
We've found the princess!
Okay! I'll be right there!
There you have it.
I look forward to hearing
your last words, King Albert.
Traitor.
What are you doing?
Don't you know your place?
Well, if it isn't Princess Starla.
How do you do?
Dolph.
Do you have any idea
what you're doing?
Your speech is always so vulgar, despite your appearance.
Of course I know what I'm doing.
I will take King Albert's wooden cube and your wooden cube,
and resurrect the ancient weapon.
So that I may become the
Fey Kingdom's new king!
You have no friends here.
You cannot escape!
Now, be a good girl
and hand it over!
He... he's dead...
Princess! Princess!
Hey, you!
This is going to cost you!
Now, take me to my father!
The wooden cube?
I thought the princess had it.
No, it's probably...
What?
Wait, what?!
Does this mean I'll become king?
No... no, hold on. Calm down.
I need a cigarette.
For twelve years, I've been a soldier.
I always expected to die a soldier.
I never thought I'd
have a chance like this...
I can't do it.
I don't have a plan
for after I become king.
Even with both of these,
I don't know how to
summon the ancient weapon.
Ow!
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 27
Good morning.
Japanese
National Lottery
Super
Jumbo
Lottery
Japanese
National Lottery
Super
Jumbo
Lottery
Hooray! Hooray! Hooray!
Mio! I won 100,000 yen in the lottery!
You're kidding!
Buy me something.
What should I do?
What should I buy?
Maybe I'll buy a house!
Yukko...
This is last year's...
There, there. No one
ever wins the lottery.
Present
I'm fine. You don't
have to comfort me.
Isn't today your birthday?
Here.
Really? A present!
Thank you!
Can I open it?
Yeah!
It's nothing special.
It was just lying around the house.
It's okay. It's the
thought that counts.
Octopus Wasabi
Faculty Office
Ms. Sakurai.
Oh, Mr. Takasaki.
Good morning.
Ms. Sakurai, is there anything
we can do about that Aioi girl?
That Aioi girl
Ms. Sakurai, is there anything
She never does her homework.
That Aioi girl
Oh, I'm sorry.
It would help if her homeroom teacher talked to her about it.
Sorry. I'll let Aioi know...
I need to get to my first period class.
Please take care of it!
Excuse me.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Are you all right?
Did you get any tea on yourself?
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 28
I want to protect her!
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 28
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 28
I'm really sorry.
I'm twenty-six years old.
It's all right. Don't worry about it.
For a man who has had no luck with women,
Ms. Sakurai is like a bamboo shoot
that suddenly began
to grow in my yard.
No, I mustn't.
As a teacher, bringing romantic
feelings to the workplace
would be an egregious offense!
Keep it together, Takasaki Manabu!
She forgot something...
Ms. Sakurai!
You forgot your black folder.
Ah, sorry for the trouble, Mr. Takasaki.
But this is my black folder.
What?
Mr. Takasaki!
Where are you taking
my black folder?
What?
I'm sorry!
Well, please excuse me.
I want to take her mushroom hunting!
I wonder if Ms. Sakurai has a boyfriend.
She doesn't wear a ring,
so she can't be married...
Do I have a chance?
What kind of music does she like? What's her favorite animal?
What's her favorite sport?
What's her favorite vegetable?
What am I thinking?!
It's impure... impure, Takasaki Manabu!
A proper role model for the
students shouldn't be doing this!
Mr. Takasaki, are you
worried about your students?
But, isn't asking her what her
favorite food is innocent enough?
Ms. Sakurai, what's
your favorite food?
Um, I'll eat anything.
Ha, I see. How do you feel
about shiitake mushrooms?
They're good grilled or boiled.
You're right. What about fried?
Of course you can fry them.
They're good fried, aren't they?
I can do it!
Act naturally! Naturally,
Takasaki Manabu!
Talk to her naturally, like
you're talking to eggplants!
Ms. Sakurai.
Yes, what is it?
Sorry for stopping
you again and again...
Are you dating anyone right now?
What am I saying?!
Stupid! Am I stupid? Am I an idiot?
No, I'm not.
I'm not... I'm not... I'm not...
Awesome!
Um, Mr. Takasaki?
Sorry for asking such
a personal question.
That turned out well.
Ms. Sakurai, work
hard in your first class.
You, too, Mr. Takasaki.
I will!
Well, please excuse me.
You, too, Mr. Takasaki...
That's the spirit.
P-please give me back my scythe!
If I don't pawn off this scythe
and buy some food, I'll die!
Oh, no, a river!
I did it.
Give it back!
First comes rock,
then comes paper...
You can't throw all of them,
Rock, paper, scissors!
I won!
Thanks.
That's not all.
...with nata de coco.
Tomorrow's weather is...
Miracle Pinch! But,
I'm just getting started!
Imagination
Do you want me to guess what
you aren't thinking
about at all, right now?
What is it?
Carefree Office Lady Travel Diary.
Just a little.
Running onto trains is dangerous.
Mio, Mai, the train's here! Hurry!
Wa... wait...
All right! I made it! Safe!
You got on by yourself.
Selamat tinggal...
What will you have?
Give me your orders.
One albacore.
Yellowtail and salmon roe.
Give me your orders.
Tuna and flounder fin, please.
One urchin.
Um, one albacore and, uh...
I forgot.
He forgot...
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 29
Oh, hello.
H-hello. Um, can I help you?
Well...
W-wait! What are you doing?
Well, I just thought
you seemed unusual.
There's nothing unusual
about me. I'm perfectly normal.
This key is an accessory.
Hey, how did you do
this? Come on, tell me.
Please give that back! Give it back!
Okay, let's do this.
See ya.
Why?
Sorry, sorry. I'm just kidding.
I'm serious. Give it back.
Which hand?
It's in your bag!
Wow, correct!
Second question!
What?
Kenta's mom bought ten apples.
His mom ate three of them.
She gave four of the remaining
apples to their neighbor, Yumiko.
Where is your arm?
In your bag!
Amazing! Correct again!
Now give it back.
Last question!
If you get this question
right, you'll receive an arm!
What? It was mine to begin with!
You don't want an arm?
I want it!
Here's the challenge.
Say the word "bag" ten times.
Bag... bag... bag...
Bag... bag... bag... bag.
What do you usually draw on?
A drawing ba... I mean, board.
Wrong!
What?
The answer we were
looking for was "paper".
That's not fair.
I'm kidding.
Please stop following me.
Fine, fine. Sorry.
It came off.
It came off!
Mio.
Let's go home.
Huh? Are you on your
way home from school?
I just ran into someone interesting.
What sort of person?
Her arm came off.
What?
She had a key on her back.
What are you talking about?
I met someone like that.
That's weird...
Short Thoughts
I want to use some quotation marks
that have a pretty rad vibe to them.
Nano, let's go.
Nichijou:
Everday Life
Part 30
Nano, let's go.
Okay.
Nichijou:
Everday Life
Part 30
Okay.
Well, they're just kids, after all.
I won!
I lost.
What are they doing?
They're doing it all wrong.
Sakamoto, how many
points was that?
What?
Ready, Professor?
Ready.
She didn't throw the ball yet!
Is she trying to kill me?
Mr. Sakamoto, how
many points was that?
You, too?
She swung again!
You're next, Sakamoto.
Why me?
How do you expect me to
hold a bat with these paws?
What?
Geez, what do you think
my paws are, anyway?
You're always poking
the pads on my feet.
This is why you kids are...
Well, you know,
it's not safe for you
to play on your own...
So I'm keeping an eye on you.
I have no intention
of participating.
Why don't you start
with some catch?
Okay.
Okay, coach!
Coach?
Coach! We only have one glove.
You'll be fine without one.
Coach, the glove doesn't fit.
Weren't you just wearing
it on your left hand?
Coach!
You girls are hopeless.
Professor, ready?
Ready.
Where did it go?
So the teacher got mad at me.
No surprise there.
I agree.
You too, Mai?
But she didn't need to go that far.
That's true, but you should
be careful from now on.
That's right. You never
know what will happen.
Ah, excuse me.
Oh! Gentleman!
Listen to this.
Mai, let me borrow it again.
Okay.
Oh, great! Everyone should
have such good friends.
Maybe she's the girl my sister mentioned.
Oh, great! Everyone should
have such good friends.
Birthday Present
I wake up in the morning, brush my
teeth, and before I know it it's 10 PM
Asa okite ha wo migaite atto yuuma gogo juuji
We laughed and had a lot of fun today
Kyou mo takusan waratta na takusan tokimeita na
and at times I and my friends chatted noisily like nitwits
Tomodachi to baka mitai ni sawaideru toki ni mo
When our eyes met, flutteringly, it was coincidence
Chirachira tte me ga au guuzen da yo ne
It's not in me to say this is my first love
Hatsukoi da tte ienai kyara ja nainda mon
Hey, we'll see each other tomorrow, right?
Nee ashita mo aeru yo ne
If I close my eyes, all I see is a sparkling you
Mabuta wo tojiru to kirakira kimi darake
I wonder why today was so much fun again
Kyou mo tanoshikatta ne aa doushite kana
I'm so happy, happy, that my love awakened
Ureshii na ureshii na hajimemashita koigokoro
I'll see you again tomorrow, so good night
Ashita mata aeru ne oyasuminasai
I'll see you in my dreams soon, so good night
Yume de sugu aeru ne oyasuminasai
I am a wooden cube.
Become my owner, and you
shall inherit an ancient weapon.
The next episode of Nichijou is episode 8.
Narration:  Wakamoto Norio
Don't miss it.