Green light... Red light.
Red Light,
Green Light
Tattaima hajimete kizuita
I only just noticed
that I fell in love
Koi ni ochita no da naa
You are on my mind all day, day, day
24h kimiOkimiOkimiO
and I can't do anything about it
Ishiki sezaru wo emasen!
Somehow
Nanka
while having an awkward conversation
Itsumo to chigau kimi to
with you
Futari
you seem different from usual, could it be...
Gikochinai kaiwa masaka
Mutual love?
Ryouomoi
Nah, it's one-sided
Iya kataomoi
Oops, our glances met
Yabai! Shisen acchatta!!!
What's up with this excitement?
Nani nani!? kono dokidoki!?
My train of thought slips into chaos
Shikoukairo gucchagucha konsen...
This is the first time it has happened to me,
Konna koto hajimete da yo
maybe I have a fever?
Netsu demo aru no kanaa
My love took a sudden turn
Kyuutenchokka irasshatta koigokoro
And I instantly blushed a deep red
Acchuuma kao hakka de makkakka
N-n-no way! My hands are trembling
Ba.ba...baka na!? Te ga furueru zo
Is this what's commonly referred to as "love"?
Kore ga zoku ni iu "koi" na no!?
I st-st-stuttered through our conversation
Yayayacchatta kaiwa kami makuri
Awkward silence, mmhmmhmhm
Kimazui chinmoku mamimumemo
I want
Kimi no
to know your feelings
Kimochi shiritai yo
O-o-one-one-sided love
KakakataOkataomoi
My first love
Hatsukoi!!
on my normal way to school
Itsumo no tsuugakuro
glitters brightly
Pikapika hikaru
I DO fall in love!
I feel like I can fly in the sky
Sora mo tobesou sa
O-o-one-one-sided love
KakakataOkataomoi
Shoot! Shoot, shoot!
Homeroom is about to start!
I used "I was helping my
grandmother" the other day.
"My mother wasn't home"
isn't much of an excuse.
What should I do? How
can I get out of this?
Couldn't one car drive by?
How did I get stopped
by four red lights?
It'll be first period
when I enter...
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 40
What's with this obvious trap?
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 40
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 40
There's no way I'd
fall for a classic trap like...
Double!
What? Why am I being
punished for being late?
What did I do
to deserve this?
Besides being late...
Well, I can just sneak
in through the back.
There's no reason I
have to get yelled at.
I knew it! It's locked!
I know! Why don't I sneak
in through the lower door?
I'll enter silently,
like the wind,
and smoothly join the class...
Why is this happening?
I had a feeling
this would happen!
She's the only one who'd
do something like this!
If I quietly try to
enter from below,
I'll get in even more
trouble if I'm caught.
If I'm going to be discovered,
I might as well enter from above!
They put stained glass in!
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
Why am I running?
Running from the classroom
won't solve anything.
I have to go back...
That's right.
I need to figure out
the best entrance to use.
If I'm getting in trouble
no matter what I do,
I may as well make a grand frontal
assault, and fight to my last breath.
Wouldn't that be cool?
My best option...
is the chalkboard
eraser in the front!
I'll take an eraser to the face
while grinning ear to ear.
Good morning!
And the entire class
will burst into laughter.
What time do you think it is?
You're hopeless...
Hurry and take your seat.
It'll work!
That's right, Yukko.
You must be a bright
and cheerful clown!
Let's go!
And a very good morning to you!
Just kidding!
Soap
Invincible
Alien
I'm an invincible alien!
Invincible
Alien
I'm an invincible alien!
Why are you acting stupid?
You're not a grade schooler.
Invincible aliens are immune
to any and all attacks!
Sorry! Are you all right?
Blue
Note
Shut up!
Miles would turn in his grave!
Oh, sorry. We just got so into it.
You were listening, Sakamoto?
Was I listening?
What kind of torture is this?
It's ruining my ears!
I'm gonna play again. So listen, okay?
You listen to me!
Flowing noodles
in the park at noon.
I heard they were having
flowing noodles in the park,
so I decided to check it out.
I've only seen flowing
noodles on TV before,
so I'm really excited.
Do I have to stand near
the front to get any noodles?
I haven't eaten today,
so I'll stand near the
front and eat my fill!
Flowing
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 41
Here it comes!
What are you doing?
I've never seen such a lousy customer!
Next round, coming up.
Uh, e-excuse me, um...
What do you want?
Are you quitting before
you've had a bite?
Even if the law may
forgive you, I shall not!
Well, um... I don't
have any chopsticks.
Who do you think you are, kid?
Come on, let's go!
Um, sure.
I-I'm sorry, but these
have been used...
We're recycling.
Next round!
Time waits for no one!
I have no choice.
I'll use the back ends.
It's transient humor.
The next one will be different!
I'll show you true hell!
Don't expect us to
have infinite water!
So you'd better eat it all.
Excuse me...
Don't be such a wallflower!
Why not try to savor the flavor?
Stop dawdling!
It won't stay fresh forever!
You haven't changed a bit.
Flowing Noodle
Researcher
Egi Masaharu (51)
Masaharu...
Masaharu!
The moment I heard there were
flowing noodles in the park,
I knew it was you.
I've been doing this...
because I believed you
would return someday.
It's been thirty years since you left in
search of the perfect flowing noodles.
Did you find them?
I've eaten so many kinds of noodles,
I just don't know anymore...
I raided our savings to take this trip,
but the money's run out.
I'm sorry.
Please let the flowing noodles slide.
I will.
What are you looking at?!
This isn't a show!
I'm sorry,
but could you make like a
flowing noodle and flow away?
Short Thoughts
The first-years are all here?
Listen up.
Some people respond to praise,
and others respond to criticism.
I'll use my intuition to tell you apart.
Got it?
I respond to praise,
but I never receive any.
NASA
If I say it like that!
What!?
Whaaat!!?
Nano!
Look, look. I tried
tying up my hair.
Does it look good?
Professor! You look
a bit more mature.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 42
Hey, how much more
mature do I look?
What? You look pretty mature.
What about you?
How mature are you?
Oh, well... I don't
think I'm that mature.
Whoops! Yeah, I guess you aren't.
I'll have to clean this up for you.
And this.
Oh, Nano...
I'm still reading that...
Oh, Nano.
You, too, Sakamoto.
What are you doing?
You'll catch a cold.
What's gotten into you?
What are you planning?
Sakamoto...
What?
You'll catch a cold.
No, I won't!
If you're going to put
something on me, use a blanket.
Why would you use a book?
Sakamoto, you're always complaining.
What do you think you're doing?
I'll go do the laundry.
I'll do it.
It's okay, Professor.
I just have to turn the dial.
You're hopeless.
I'll turn it for you.
No, really. I just have to turn it...
I said I'd turn it, so I'm turning it!
U-um...
Thanks, I guess.
If you need anything
else, let me know.
O-okay.
Hooray!
Oh, dear.
Nano, you're
hopeless. Let me cook.
Oh, it's okay. I'm making
something right now...
I'll make something better.
No, wait! That's dangerous!
Come on. I'll do it.
It's okay.
No, it's not okay. Really!
Come on, come on.
Really, Professor. No!
Ow!
Hot, hot, hot, hot, hot!
Are you okay, Mr. Sakamoto?
What are you doing?!
I-I'm sorry!
Sakamoto, you're hopeless,
walking there like that.
I'm not the hopeless one!
You two are the ones messing around!
Now now, Sakamoto, getting
angry won't help anything.
That doesn't make any sense!
Let's just make it again.
I'll do it.
No, the rest of the food will get cold,
so I'll make it quickly.
Oh, Nano... I'll do it.
Professor! That's dangerous!
You'll drop an egg!
It's okay.
Hey, watch out!
It's fine...
You're hopeless.
You're the hopeless one!
What's with this kid today?
I think she's trying to act mature.
I am mature.
Hey, kid.
What?
Did you know that mature
people don't eat snacks?
Ta-dah! It's actually just me!
Liar.
River Fishing
I hooked a big one!
A boot!
This is it!
A kettle!
This stuff's crazier than
fish would be, right?
If I knew I'd have this much fun,
I'd have invited someone else.
I'll come back.
Chic things.
Eating sushi with your bare hands.
Damn it...
I don't want to do my homework...
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 43
I don't want to do my homework...
Why do I have to do
homework, anyway?
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 43
Well, my grades suck,
so I have to do it.
But I know I can fix them.
So I should be able to pass.
I think...
Then I'll graduate.
But I don't want to go all
the way to college, so I guess...
I'll get a job?
But I heard on TV the other day that it's tough to find a job.
Maybe it's harder to find
work without a degree...
High school.
College.
Employment.
And I can't get through it without taking a college entrance exam.
But...
I really don't want to study!
How will the stuff I'm studying now
help me in the future, anyway?
No, hold on.
What do I...
want to do?
"What I Want to Do" by Aioi Yuuko.
When I grow up,
I wanna be a frill-necked lizard.
Frill-necked... Frill-necked...
I don't want to study!
I don't want to study,
and I don't want to
be a frill-necked lizard!
Hold on.
If I became a lizard,
I wouldn't have to
worry about this stuff.
But if I'm becoming something else,
I should just become
a living national treasure
Clay-
like
subs-
tance
I should just become
a living national treasure
and be the center of attention.
Clay-
like
subs-
tance
Clay-
like
subs-
tance
and be the center of attention.
Clay-
like
subs-
tance
How much does a living
national treasure make per month?
Clay-
like
subs-
tance
Clay-
like
subs-
tance
Clay-
like
subs-
tance
How much does a living
national treasure make per month?
Paycheck
Clay-
like
subs-
tance
How much does a living
national treasure make per month?
How do I become a
living national treasure?
Clay-
like
subs-
tance
Paycheck
How do I become a
living national treasure?
And...
what is a living national treasure?
No, no, no.
I need to think realistically.
What do I want to be?
I can't think of anything.
Well, I'm still a high school freshman.
I've got three years to think about it.
If I still haven't found
anything by then, I'll...
go to college!
Exams!
Which leads back to...
I don't want to study!
No, no, no.
Being depressed won't
get me anywhere.
I can't think of anything because I'm thinking of what to be.
I should think of what I want to do!
What do I want to do?
Mom!
Quit your banging!
Do you know how late it is?
Well, I'm not good
at thinking too hard.
I'll just work on my homework!
I wake up in the morning, brush my
teeth, and before I know it it's 10 PM
Asa okite ha wo migaite atto yuuma gogo juuji
We laughed and had a lot of fun today
Kyou mo takusan waratta na takusan tokimeita na
and at times I and my friends chatted noisily like nitwits
Tomodachi to baka mitai ni sawaideru toki ni mo
When our eyes met, flutteringly... it must be coincidence
Chirachira tte me ga au... guuzen da yo ne
It's not in me to say this is my first love!
Hatsukoi nante ienai kyara ja nainda mon!
Hey, we'll see each other tomorrow, right?
Nee ashita mo aeru yo ne
If I close my eyes, all I see is a sparkling you
Mabuta wo tojiru to kirakira kimi darake
Today was fun again, it must be love
Kyou mo tanoshikatta ne aa koi shite da naa
I'm so happy, so happy. Nice to meet you, awakening love.
Ureshii na ureshii na hajimemashite koigokoro
I'll see you again tomorrow, so good night
Ashita mata aeru ne oyasuminasai
I'll see you in my dreams soon, so good night
Yume de sugu aeru ne oyasuminasai
Damn it.
I don't want to do my homework...
I'm a frill-necked lizard.
I'm really hard to
make with origami.
It might take a
couple of extra sheets
before you figure
out how to make me.
The next episode of Nichijou is episode 11.
Narration:     Nozawa Masako
Don't miss it!