Summer Heat
Sold Out
Man, it's hot... It's so hot!
Tanaka, you've been
saying "hot" this whole time.
It's already hot,
and pointing out how hot
it is just makes it feel hotter.
So, I forbid you from saying "hot".
Okay, okay.
It's blistering!
It's blistering, isn't it?
Just kidding!
But it's really
blistering, huh?
It's blistering!
Blistering!
Super blistering!
I guess I'll have to hit him.
Man, it's blistering. So blistering!
Blistering!
Tattaima hajimete kizuita
I only just noticed
that I fell in love
Koi ni ochita no da naa
You are on my mind all day, day, day
24h kimiOkimiOkimiO
and I can't do anything about it
Ishiki sezaru wo emasen!
Somehow
Nanka
while having an awkward conversation
Itsumo to chigau kimi to
with you
Futari
you seem different from usual, could it be...
Gikochinai kaiwa masaka
Mutual love?
Ryouomoi
Nah, it's one-sided
Iya kataomoi
Oops, our glances met
Yabai! Shisen acchatta!!!
What's up with this excitement?
Nani nani!? kono dokidoki!?
My train of thought slips into chaos
Shikoukairo gucchagucha konsen...
This is the first time it has happened to me,
Konna koto hajimete da yo
maybe I have a fever?
Netsu demo aru no kanaa
My love took a sudden turn
Kyuutenchokka irasshatta koigokoro
And I instantly blushed a deep red
Acchuuma kao hakka de makkakka
N-n-no way! My hands are trembling
Ba.ba...baka na!? Te ga furueru zo
Is this what's commonly referred to as "love"?
Kore ga zoku ni iu "koi" na no!?
I st-st-stuttered through our conversation
Yayayacchatta kaiwa kami makuri
Awkward silence, mmhmmhmhm
Kimazui chinmoku mamimumemo
I want
Kimi no
to know your feelings
Kimochi shiritai yo
O-o-one-one-sided love
KakakataOkataomoi
My first love
Hatsukoi!!
on my normal way to school
Itsumo no tsuugakuro
glitters brightly
Pikapika hikaru
I DO fall in love!
I feel like I can fly in the sky
Sora mo tobesou sa
O-o-one-one-sided love
KakakataOkataomoi
Shiny!
Today, everything's
shining brightly!
The air, the people,
and even this classroom...
Because today...
I actually did my homework!
I'll show it to Mio.
What?
Wha-wha-wha-wha-wha-WHAT?
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 48
It's gone!
No, no, no! That's impossible!
I finally did my homework, for once!
Why? Why, why, why?
Why is it gone?!
Well, I'll just copy hers.
Mio?
Wait.
Hold on.
Just hold on.
Today's homework...
was a worksheet!
What's wrong,
Yukko? It's early.
I forgot my homework...
I'm just hoping that
aliens invade our class...
You forgot to do it again?
Don't insult me!
I did my homework,
but I forgot to bring it!
I wasn't insulting you.
You mean the literature
worksheet, right?
Maybe it got stuck between
something in your bag.
Why not double check?
I already looked
a bunch of times.
There's no way it's...
Oh?
Oh!
Oh...
my god!
What's a rice cake fair?!
What is that?
Th-there, there.
Look, maybe there's
a worksheet in the podium.
No way! You found one?
Damn it!
Damn it! Damn it!
You're going back for it?
You'll never make it in time!
I know... but I'm still going!
Class is starting.
Take your seats.
Idiom
Twist... twist... twist... twist...
Turn, turn, turn, turn...
Slow and steady wins the race.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 49
Go-Soccer
Club
I was sent to stand
in the hall again.
Why do I always
forget my homework?
I even did my homework
today, but I still forgot it.
You're a blockhead, God...
Business Card
Sakamoto...
Here's my business card.
Professor
What's this?
What do I do with this?
Professor
What is this?
What do I do with it?
Vending Machine
I'm sorry...
What's wrong,
Tachibana Misato?
Wh-what?
Some new drinks came out,
so I was thinking
about which one to buy!
I see.
Perhaps this one—
Why would I listen to you?
If it doesn't suit your taste,
perhaps you should
purchase the other one.
Please excuse me.
It's not like I bought this one just because you recommended it!
I heard some stalls
were setting up nearby,
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 50
so I decided to check them out.
I was looking for
a shooting gallery.
I've only seen one on TV before,
so I'm very excited.
But I only have 500 yen.
I wonder if it's enough.
Just 5,000,000 yen per shot.
Lucky me, I have
exactly 500 yen.
I wanted to get
some yakisoba, too,
but I came here today for this.
They only have
caramel and eggplant.
Um, is this everything?
What do you mean by that?
We only carry brand-name goods.
I've already spent
what little money I had.
I have to take
home something.
Miss, you shouldn't start
off with the expensive ones!
They won't fall over easily.
Expensive ones?
Start with something
within your reach!
Within my reach?
The only other choice is caramel!
Close!
The caramel must
be glued down, too.
A few more millimeters,
and you would've had it.
Miss, you're pretty good at this.
I don't suppose you're
a professional gunner?
Just kidding!
This eggplant
won't budge an inch...
C'mon what's
with the long face?
You don't think I've
rigged the game, do you?
We might be stingy,
but lively and honest service
is our stall's hallmark!
No, you've definitely
done something to this!
What is that?!
Hey, hey, look at that!
There's a nail...
I can see the nail!
Wouldn't that
make this rigged?
Why don't you say anything?
And how could you do this?
You were so lively
until just a minute ago!
You must have rigged
the caramel, too!
Why are you pretending to be asleep?
I only have one shot left.
What am I supposed to aim for?
Don't come back again.
What the hell?
Things we think are cool!
Aioi
Mio! Ready?
Nice catch!
Aioi
Oh! SuperBall!
Things we think are cool!
Shoot, so close!
Wow!
Oh! Slipstream!
Thanks.
This old amusement park
is a lot of fun, isn't it?
I'm glad we came.
I'm getting some juice,
so can I have my wallet?
Oh, right.
I'm holding it for you.
Yeah, thanks.
If I had it, I'd lose it.
Yeah, you're right.
Huh?
Wh-what? What?
I thought it was in here...
It appears that I've
dropped your wallet.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 51
Hey, it might be at
the lost and found!
How much was in it?
4,016 yen.
That's specific...
Lost and Found
It's a brown wallet,
with a snake skin inside.
Here it is.
I'm glad they had it.
I know, right? For a while
there, I was worried.
The following person is lost.
A girl wearing a denim shirt
tucked into denim shorts
with a denim hat is
looking for her mother.
If you have any information,
please contact the
lost persons center.
I really don't like haunted houses.
There it is!
Say "cheese".
Coffee Shop
Daiku-ya
Three lattes for
takeout. Is that all?
Oh, um...
Could I also get this,
this, and this, please?
Izumi
Uh, excuse me.
Could you give me a name, please?
It's Sakurai.
That's not the name I meant...
Oh, right. Sorry.
It's Izumi. I'm Sakurai Izumi.
Uh, I wasn't asking because
you gave me your surname.
People always tell me that both
of my names sound like surnames...
Actually, I was asking
about the product name.
The product name?
What do you mean?
I'm sorry. I don't understand.
Oh, um... I'm sorry...
Family Restaurant
Ah, that was delicious...
Chopstick Stand
I ate a ton.
Now we just wait for dessert
to make its appearance.
Right.
Oh! Me too.
I did it!
Me, too.
As amazing as always, Mai!
What about you, Yukko?
Are you finished?
Huh?
A crane?
Nano, look!
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 52
Ta-dah.
I stuck one on myself, too.
Now we match.
You're right.
I'm you for a day,
so whatever you do,
don't call me Professor.
Got it, Nano.
That was quick!
Done already, Professor?
Nano, you just
called me Professor.
Huh? But didn't you just
take off your key?
I'm just taking a break!
Today, I'm Nano.
Okay.
Professor... I mean,
Nano, would you
like to play a game?
Okay! What are we doing?
You'll be me, and I'll be you.
We'll trade roles.
I'll play!
Okay, Professor... I mean,
Nano, put on your key.
Okay!
And since I'm the professor,
let's remove my key.
Not gonna happen.
What do you want to play?
How about cards?
This snack is delicious.
I was saving that!
Right now...
I'm...
the professor.
I don't understand!
I'll be you, but if you're
me, you'll eat my snacks,
so just be you!
Well, now that I'm Nano again,
I'll go grocery
shopping for dinner.
I'll go, too!
I'm not buying any snacks.
I want shark chocolate
and strawberry juice.
I'm not buying those.
Buy them.
No.
Hey, don't forget my food.
The Shinonome household passed
another peaceful day.
Killing Time
If you use English
from here on, you lose.
Okay.
Mio, you just used English.
You didn't say
start, so I'm safe.
I guess I should use
a bunch of English
before I say to start.
You know a bunch of English?
Okay.
Short Thoughts
Bubbly, carbonated drinks
make you feel awake.
Unintentional
I fell asleep.
It looks like Sleeping Beauty
woke up without a kiss.
How?
What do you mean?
I wake up in the morning, brush my
teeth, and before I know it it's 10 PM
Asa okite ha wo migaite atto yuuma gogo juuji
We laughed and had a lot of fun today
Kyou mo takusan waratta na takusan tokimeita na
and at times I and my friends chatted noisily like nitwits
Tomodachi to baka mitai ni sawaideru toki ni mo
When our eyes met, flutteringly... it must be coincidence
Chirachira tte me ga au... guuzen da yo ne
It's not in me to say this is my first love!
Hatsukoi nante ienai kyara ja nainda mon!
Hey, we'll see each other tomorrow, right?
Nee ashita mo aeru yo ne
If I close my eyes, all I see is a sparkling you
Mabuta wo tojiru to kirakira kimi darake
Today was fun again, it must be love
Kyou mo tanoshikatta ne aa koi shite da naa
I'm so happy, so happy. Nice to meet you, awakening love.
Ureshii na ureshii na hajimemashite koigokoro
I'll see you again tomorrow, so good night
Ashita mata aeru ne oyasuminasai
I'll see you in my dreams soon, so good night
Yume de sugu aeru ne oyasuminasai
Welcome home,
master. I'm cider.
I'll enchant these bubbles
with a spell to make me delicious...
The next episode of Nichijou is episode 13.
Narration:     Korogi Satomi
Don't miss it.