I'm hungry...
That kid is up to
something ridiculous again.
Well, I guess I wouldn't mind
falling for a trap like this.
The bait's worth it.
You fell for it! You fell for it!
Damn it... she really got me!
This was going to be for lunch.
Now we don't have anything.
Sakamoto...
You're guilty, too!
No, you said you
wanted to eat it.
I didn't say that!
Good morning.
What are you talking about?
But you ate it.
It's hot again today.
After school, let's get
ice cream near the station.
Good idea.
Hey, kid.
Don't you think the girl
wants to go to school?
Don't go!
What's gotten into you?
He said you'd leave me.
What? Who told you that?
Sakamoto.
That's not what I said!
Nano, are you going somewhere?
I was thinking of
going shopping soon.
We don't have
anything for lunch now.
I'll go with you!
I'm not buying you anything.
I want shark chocolate!
No.
Buy some shark chocolate!
I told you, I'm not
buying you anything.
Come on, buy some!
No.
Sakamoto said to buy some.
I never said that.
Tattaima hajimete kizuita
I only just noticed
that I fell in love
Koi ni ochita no da naa
You are on my mind all day, day, day
24h kimiOkimiOkimiO
and I can't do anything about it
Ishiki sezaru wo emasen!
Somehow
Nanka
while having an awkward conversation
Itsumo to chigau kimi to
with you
Futari
you seem different from usual, could it be...
Gikochinai kaiwa masaka
Mutual love?
Ryouomoi
Nah, it's one-sided
Iya kataomoi
Oops, our glances met
Yabai! Shisen acchatta!!!
What's up with this excitement?
Nani nani!? kono dokidoki!?
My train of thought slips into chaos
Shikoukairo gucchagucha konsen...
This is the first time it has happened to me,
Konna koto hajimete da yo
maybe I have a fever?
Netsu demo aru no kanaa
My love took a sudden turn
Kyuutenchokka irasshatta koigokoro
And I instantly blushed a deep red
Acchuuma kao hakka de makkakka
N-n-no way! My hands are trembling
Ba.ba...baka na!? Te ga furueru zo
Is this what's commonly referred to as "love"?
Kore ga zoku ni iu "koi" na no!?
I st-st-stuttered through our conversation
Yayayacchatta kaiwa kami makuri
Awkward silence, mmhmmhmhm
Kimazui chinmoku mamimumemo
I want
Kimi no
to know your feelings
Kimochi shiritai yo
O-o-one-one-sided love
KakakataOkataomoi
My first love
Hatsukoi!!
on my normal way to school
Itsumo no tsuugakuro
glitters brightly
Pikapika hikaru
I DO fall in love!
I feel like I can fly in the sky
Sora mo tobesou sa
O-o-one-one-sided love
KakakataOkataomoi
Mio, good morning...
What's wrong, Yukko?
You can barely stand!
Since I woke up,
now that ya mention it...
Your speech is broken.
You look feverish.
Why did you come
to school like this?
Well,
you know...
I thought I'd perform that
magic trick I told you about...
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 53
What are you talking about?
This is the first I've heard of it.
This isn't the time for magic.
But I practiced.
When you see my magic,
you won't believe your eyes...
It'll be great—
I already can't believe my eyes.
Why don't you sit d—
Yukko...
I...
already see the trick!
I'll just pretend
I didn't see anything.
She came all the way
here in her condition.
But why is Yukko
trying to show off a...
I-it's out in the open!
Your trick is out in the open!
It flew away!
Tissues...
All right, here we go...
O-okay.
Geez, what am I doing?
I just grabbed that on instinct...
So... okay... first...
She hasn't noticed that the
dove and the stick are missing.
How sick are you?
I'll pass a cigarette
through a hundred yen coin.
The hole... is already open.
They're all... aces of hearts.
Right now,
something flew out of her mouth...
What sort of trick
are you trying to...
Yukko!
Yukko...
Rest in peace.
I'm off to the supermarket.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 54
I'll go with you!
You didn't behave,
so I'm not buying
you anything today.
Poor Sakamoto.
She's talking to you.
Let's go.
What are you buying?
Fish, I suppose.
I wonder what I should get...
What? Not today, Professor.
What? But it's not a snack.
Even if it's not a snack,
I'm not buying it.
Then I don't know what to buy.
You're set on buying
something, aren't you?
Shark Sponge Cake
Nano! It's shark sponge cake.
It's a food stand.
They look pretty
good. Let's try some.
Did you forget
already? Not today.
Shark Sponge Cake
But I'm buying it for Sakamoto.
Mr. Sakamoto also misbehaved,
so he doesn't get anything, either.
But I meant it's really for you...
I made a mistake.
I said no!
If I give in now,
she'll just do this again.
All right, Professor. Let's go.
Buy it! Buy it! Buy it!
I must steel my heart!
But...
Buy it! Buy it! Buy it! Buy it!
But I have to...
But...
Buy it! Buy it! Buy it!
No, no. I mustn't.
Maybe a little...
Buy it! Buy it! Buy it!
No! No!
But...
Buy it! Buy it! Buy it!
No, no...
But...
Delicious!
You bought her something.
I'm sorry. I lost.
This kid is always throwing
tantrums to get her way.
Maybe I should scold her.
Hey, kid. Why don't you
learn some self-control?
I have!
No, you haven't!
The Shinonome household
passed another peaceful day.
80 Point Mongolian
80 points is great!
If you really try, you can do it.
Well...
What is it?
What's the secret
behind your high score?
Oh, there's no secret!
What? Come on,
tell me your secret...
80 points, 80 points.
Hey, Yukko. Ow...
Stop it!
Secret
Ow...
Do you want me to tell
you how I got 80 points?
I don't really care. I got a 96.
80 points...
It takes tremendous effort...
...and heart.
Shut up.
A Little Miracle
Aioi.
Uh...
What...?
Hooray!!
Contemporary Japanese Quiz
Reality
Dad, I'm here to make dinner.
Mom's still traveling, isn't she?
Thank you.
Hello.
Hello, Mi.
I'll play with my
grandson all day,
and forget the troubles of reality.
Mi, what do you want to do today?
Hey, hey, where's our official seal?
What?
Hey, where's the official seal?
Where are you
hiding it? Tell me!
Is it in this bookshelf?
Hey, where's the seal?
Hey, where is it? Where is it?
This is... worse than reality...
Come out, come out,
wherever you are...
You're late!
What time did you think
you were supposed to get here?
Sorry, sorry.
I wanted to go on the bus,
but instead I went with the flow.
Let's keep going all
the way to Okachimachi.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 55
Nano...
Hey, Nano, Nano.
What is it, Professor?
I need to use the
bathroom a little bit.
Come with me.
Come on, let's go. Come on, let's go.
Hey, Nano. Hey, hey...
Professor, that's not right.
What?
Borscht is a food!
Not that...
I need to use the bathroom.
Hey, Nano. Nano, hey...
Just go!
D-did you just...
It's okay. It was just a little.
Hurry up and go
to the bathroom.
I'm going to sleep.
Go!
Kindly, Sakamoto
did not say anything.
Geez, kids are so hopeless.
Going to the bathroom alone
at night during a storm...
is just too much for her.
Because she's just a kid.
I'll go with her,
and remind her...
just how grateful
she should be to me.
Hey, kid.
I'll go with you.
Sakamoto, you're small and
weak, so you don't have to.
Don't you think the girl
wants to go to school?
Huh? Professor,
you came over here?
Nano, let's go to the
bathroom together.
But I don't need to go...
I'm just a little scared,
so let's go together.
Why didn't you wake me up?
I tried.
I hear banging.
Maybe someone's here.
It's probably just the chimney.
The rain's coming
down really hard.
Nano, what's wrong?
Hey, Nano. Hey.
Hey?
Professor... Professor...
There's thunder.
I'm here. It's okay.
Hurry up, so we
can go back to bed.
Okay.
It's scary to go alone,
but it's okay if we're together.
You're right.
Nano, do you want
to go to school?
What?
No, I'll stay at home.
But Sakamoto said
you wanted to go!
Well...
Things we think are cool!
80!
Ugh.
Short Thoughts
A month passes quickly,
but Sunday seems so far away.
Elated
Next stop, 80 points, 80 points.
The exit is on the right.
Shut up.
I'll sing you an 80s
number for 80 points.
Shut up.
80 points, huzzah!
Go to hell!
Eden
Quiet down!
I'm announcing the
average test score.
The average score
was 92 points!
Yukko.
Don't!
Just don't...
Excellent Luck
What are you doing, kid?!
What are you doing?
Stop playing around,
and help me fold the laundry.
Starting tomorrow,
you can go to school.
What?
Really?
Why? What's gotten into you?
It's the right thing to do.
Hooray!
Now I won't get scolded for
eating lots of snacks at lunch.
But, Professor,
I can't wear an elementary
school bag with this.
You're going to high school.
But, Professor,
if you don't remove
my key, I can't go to...
Here's your uniform.
Professor, I love you!
Nano! Nano! Nano!
Professor! Professor! Professor!
Nano! Nano! Nano! Nano! Nano! Nano!
Nano!
Professor!
Nano! Nano!
Professor! Professor!
Professor!
I wake up in the morning, brush my
teeth, and before I know it it's 10 PM
Asa okite ha wo migaite atto yuuma gogo juuji
We laughed and had a lot of fun today
Kyou mo takusan waratta na takusan tokimeita na
and at times I and my friends chatted noisily like nitwits
Tomodachi to baka mitai ni sawaideru toki ni mo
When our eyes met, flutteringly... it must be coincidence
Chirachira tte me ga au... guuzen da yo ne
It's not in me to say this is my first love!
Hatsukoi nante ienai kyara ja nainda mon!
Hey, we'll see each other tomorrow, right?
Nee ashita mo aeru yo ne
If I close my eyes, all I see is a sparkling you
Mabuta wo tojiru to kirakira kimi darake
Today was fun again, it must be love
Kyou mo tanoshikatta ne aa koi shite da naa
I'm so happy, so happy. Nice to meet you, awakening love.
Ureshii na ureshii na hajimemashite koigokoro
I'll see you again tomorrow, so good night
Ashita mata aeru ne oyasuminasai
I'll see you in my dreams soon, so good night
Yume de sugu aeru ne oyasuminasai
I'm a string of international flags.
People often ask if I'm a string of
international flags, or the flags of all nations,
but both are correct.
"Don't worry about
the small things"
was the last thing my father said.
Narration:     Ogata Megumi
The next episode of Nichijou is episode 14.
Don't miss it.
Narration:     Ogata Megumi