It's glittering...
What are you doing?
Oh, Mr. Sakamoto.
Ah! Don't go over there.
You've been shedding
a lot lately, haven't you?
Your fur will get on it.
What's this?
You're treating me
like a nuisance?
I'm going to get changed,
so please step out for a minute.
The best, friendship, perfect harmony!
jou-jou-yuujou magi magi kaichou
Yes, let's go, you're my best friend!
hai icchai mashou kimi wa best, best friend!
hai
If you try being annoying
chotto fuza kete mitara
shai
Then I'll be annoying in return
motto fuza ke kaeshite kuru
Ran ran ran!
ran ran ran
If I speak of comfort, it goes away
iigokochiitta aryashinai!
wai
I had things I hated
iiyana koto attatte
hai
But I forgot them in one swift stroke
sokko wasurechaunda
Ran ran ran!
ran ran ran
Let's go do something non-stop!
itsudatte janjan yarimashou!
We can be together 24/7!
nijyuuyon jikan isshodemo mondainai
marude futago ka oyako ka kuroom saibou
Almost like twins, a parent and a child or cloned cells!
Don't you cry when you fall in love?
kore ja renai suru hitsuyou to ka nakunakunai?
sore to kore to wa mattaku mattaku betsumondai
Those are totally different things!
Even when we fought
kenka shichatta toki mo
Even when we felt really blue
kanari e konda toki mo
Even when we want to be alone
hitori de itai you na toki mo
futo kizukeba chikaku ni iru
We are next to each other
shi na ba morotomo
Until death do us part
nande daro
Why, I wonder?
I want to be by your side
soba ni itainda
kimi to isshonara
When I'm with you
Time flies a hundred times as fast
tokei hyaku baisoku
It's so much fun
tanoshii na
It's too much fun
tanoshi sugirunda
Always the same, with my best friend!
sasuga saikyou furendo
What is it?
nan nano yo
Man, we're even synchronized
yabai shinkuro mo
Always such a rage
itsumo oosawagi
yabai shinkuro mo
Always such a rage
Annoying everyone around us
kanari go kinj omeiwaku
itsumo oosawagi
Always such a rage
kanari go kinj omeiwaku
Annoying everyone around us
What time is it?
ima nanji?
Time to yodel!
tatoe yororeihi
What time is it?
ima nanji?
tatoe yororeihi
Time to yodel!
What are you talking about?
wakewakan nai nai!
tatoe yororeihi
Time to yodel!
wakewakan nai nai!
What are you talking about?
What am I going to do?
soure-da-shi-ra-
More than imagination!
so-zo-i-jo-
What should I say, awesome!
nante iu ka saikou
a-dako-da itte temo tomodachi
Whatever you say, we're friends!
wasshoi!
The best, friendship!
jou-jou-yuujou
Perfect harmony!
magi magi kaichou
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 56
Mr. Sakamoto!
Look, it fits perfectly.
O-of course it is.
We had it made
especially for you.
How do I look?
Well... it looks good, I guess.
That isn't what I mean!
D-do I look like...
an ordinary girl?
You look just like
any other girl.
Mr. Sakamoto!
I love you, Mr. Sakamoto.
I really love you!
Your fur will stick to me!
What's wrong with you?
It's school! School!
I might even
make some friends.
You aren't listening to me!
"Hey, Nano."
"Why don't we get some
ice cream after school?"
Oh, yes. I'd love to go.
"Want to go to
karaoke afterwards?"
What? Yes, but
I've never been...
"I'll show you! Come with us!"
Ah, o-okay...
Just like that!
Good morning, Nano.
Professor!
Good morning.
Look, Professor!
What do you think?
How do I look?
Well...
Yeah, looks good.
Professor!
Professor, those pajamas
look good on you, too.
Yay! They look good?
Professor! They look good!
Aren't you just acting
like you always do?
Sakamoto! You look good, too!
You, too?
Handkerchief, check.
Student ID, check.
Textbooks, check.
Notebooks, check.
Pencil case, check.
Mechanical pencils, check.
Mechanical pencil lead, check.
Okay! Got everything!
Professor?
You forgot something.
Huh? What is it?
Feeling hungry?
Have a Snickers!
Professor!
I left breakfast and lunch in the
kitchen for you. Make sure to eat, okay?
Also, I'll bring in the
laundry after I come home.
So you don't have
to do anything.
Hey, when will school be over?
At around three thirty.
On my way home,
I'll go shopping for dinner,
so I'll probably be
home at around five.
Five...
Huh? Didn't I tell you?
Five is at night...
Yes, but that's how school is.
I'll see you...
Uh, Professor?
Don't go!
What? But you said I could go...
But I'm going to be late!
No! Don't go!
Please, give me back my bag.
My left hand!
Hey, kid! Don't be unreasonable.
Professor...
Well, how about this?
For dinner tonight, we'll have
your favorite, omelette rice.
Um, and I'll buy some shark
sponge cake on the way home.
Uh... and... and I'll throw
in some strawberry juice.
Then...
Then?
Will you get me
an Akutagawa prize, too?
I... I can't do that!
I was worried about
what would happen,
but I'm glad the
professor finally gave in...
Now, I can take my first
step as an ordinary person.
Oh, no. I forgot...
What am I going to do
about the key on my back?
Things we think are cool!
All right, let's do this!
Oh! Upperclassmen
with motivation!
What am I going to do?
I can't think of any solutions.
I came all this way...
Allow me to introduce
our transfer student.
Ms. Shinonome.
Yes!
E-everyone's noticed my key...
Here.
Ms. Shinonome,
please write your name.
My key really stands out.
I have to fool them somehow...
M-m-my name is
Shinonome Nano!
Uh, um... and, um...
This key... uh, well...
It got stuck in my
back on my way here!
Oh, no! I freaked them out...
I mean, uh... Well, actually...
That was a lie!
Oh, no... why am
I changing my story?
What do I do?
Um, uh...
Well, it's not like
turning it will make my big toe into
a USB port, like a robot, or anything...
It's hopeless!
Divination
I hope the weather's
good tomorrow!
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 57
Hey, Sekiguchi.
Go-Soccer Club
Put down your
book and play.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 57
Go-Soccer Club
Put down your
book and play.
I bought the game of Life...
Second-Year
Daiku
Kensaburo
Go-Soccer Club President
I bought the game of Life...
First-Year
Sekiguchi
Yuria
Go-Soccer Club Member
There's nothing to do...
Guess we should do some life-or-death
Go problems since we're the Go-Soccer Club.
I can't play real Go, though.
Excuse me!
Um, is this the Go-Soccer Club?
Yes...
I'd like to join.
We're happy to have you!
What's your name?
I-I'm Sakurai Makoto, a first-year.
I see.
I'm a second-year student
and club president, Daiku Kensaburo.
This is Sekiguchi, a first-year.
Take a seat.
Okay.
Well? What do
you want to do?
Do you want to play
the game of Life?
Uh, aren't we going to practice?
What?
For Go-Soccer...
The truth is, Go-Soccer
is a sport I made up.
There's no actual
game like that.
We're just a club for having fun.
A recreational club, if you will.
I see...
But in middle school,
I was in a Go-Soccer club.
I hadn't realized this
school had a Go-Soccer club.
But the other day, there was
a sign out in front of the school.
That's how I heard about you.
I was the middle school MVP.
What?
Curiosity
M-Ms. Shinonome...
Y-yes?
Uh, there's something
I wanted to ask you.
Well, on your back...
What? Uh, um... This...
What? Uh, um...
Um, well... Uh...
Well, uh...
Um...
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 57.5
Um...
What does a Go-Soccer club do?
It's difficult to explain...
I'll act it out myself.
You start with lifting...
From lifting, Go stones...
And then...
From Go stones...
One-man German Suplex!
That's the avalanche
pattern, Tertiary Star!
What is this?
I started this club without
much thought, but this...
Go-Soccer Club
This is getting interesting!
Shoe
Wait up!
What are you doing?
Where are you going, Buddy?
Short Thoughts
Sakamoto!
Sakamoto, Sakamoto, Sakamoto!
Hey! Don't! Stop!
When asked,
"What are you doing?",
she replied, "Spinning".
Buddy
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 58
I can't believe I made such a
huge mistake on my first day.
Everyone must think I'm weird...
Oh, Nano, you
brought a lunch.
Huh? Oh, y-yes.
It looks good.
Do you always
pack a lunch?
Yes! I'm normal, after all.
You can look at it.
That's pretty cool...
Mio, thanks for waiting.
You're late, Yukko.
Lunch is almost over.
Sorry, sorry.
On my way to buy lunch,
a car and a dog stole my shoes.
Chasing them down was a lot of work...
I'm not sure I understand,
but it sounds pretty incredible.
I'm just glad you
made it back with lunch.
Huh? Yukko, where's your lunch?
I ate it on the way here.
What did you have?
Twice-cooked pork.
Wow! Twice-cooked...
well, whatever.
Uh, why don't you
eat with us, Nano?
What?
Tell us about yourself.
O-oh...
I wonder if they think
I'm an ordinary girl.
Maybe we can be friends!
Hey, what's that thing on your...
Uh, um... This isn't
anything weird! It's, um...
You wouldn't happen to
be a robot, would you?
What are you talking about?
Sorry. Yukko's an idiot.
We're almost out of time.
Nano, sorry.
Let's have a quick lunch today.
Let's see...
Hey, Yukko. Is this...
It's fried mackerel.
What did I ask for?
Huh? Didn't you
say fried mackerel?
I asked for fried noodles!
Whoops... you mean
I misheard you?
Sorry, sorry.
This isn't some minor problem!
It's a serious issue!
Really? They're so similar.
It's just a difference
of a few letters.
But...
This is fine...
So, where's my rice?
What do you mean?
My white rice!
What? That's all I brought.
How am I supposed
to eat this by itself?
Huh? But you said you
wanted fried mackerel...
I said fried noodles!
Fried! Freaking! Noodles!
I... I see.
But this will be good
material for your blog and...
I don't have a computer!
You don't have to get so mad...
Fine, I'll go buy
you another lunch.
Give me some money—
Why do I have to pay again?!
Because I don't
have any money.
Forget it...
Just go get it.
Lunch is almost over.
Okay, okay.
It's just...
What?
It's just a peso!
All I have is the Argentinian
peso I kept as a souvenir...
What?
Argentinian!
All I have is a peso!
Argentinian peso!
You were the one who
bought the wrong thing!
You should pay for it!
I bought my own lunch,
so I don't have any money...
Well, what about my lunch?
Uh, um... you can have...
mackerel!
You've been getting on
my nerves for a while now!
Mackerel?
You've been getting on
my nerves for a while now!
You're always copying
my homework!
Why don't you do it
yourself for once, you idiot?!
My stupidity has nothing
to do with your lunch.
It's got everything
to do with my lunch!
What? How?
You misheard me
because you're stupid!
Everyone makes mistakes like this...
You must be really petty,
going on and on like this!
I didn't have breakfast,
so it's a matter of life or death!
Not that an idiot
would understand!
I'm not stupid!
Didn't you just call
yourself stupid?
Just so you know,
I'm never letting you
copy my homework again!
Fine, who cares?
If you forget your homework,
I won't let you copy mine!
Who would want to copy
your terrible homework?
I can't believe you
bought the wrong lunch
and didn't even apologize!
Get on the ground! Kneel!
Fine, fine, fine, fine!
You want me on
the ground, do you?
Will that make you happy?
I'm so sorry for displeasing you!
There! I apologized!
Is that good enough for you? Huh?!
What? You didn't even kneel.
That's right, I didn't...
I was just bending! Bending...
Why won't you kneel?
Because I'm pissed!
Are you sure you're
not the stupid one, Mio?
What was that weird drawing
you did the other day?
That... that weird drawing...
Are you stupid? That's...
What was that weird drawing?
What were you thinking?
Really pissed off!
Are you stupid?
Are you stupid? Are you
stupid? Are you stupid?
What's wrong with you?
You're stupid for drawing
that stupid picture!
Come on! Eat up!
Here's the fried frickin'
mackerel you asked for!
I asked for fried noodles!
Kneel and apologize!
Kiss the ground!
I already bought it!
As a human being,
you should apologize!
You piece of trash!
Fine! I'll show you the
true meaning of kneeling!
This is the true
meaning of kneeling!
Where's the apology for
buying me fried mackerel?
You should apologize
when you kneel!
Say it...
Say you're sorry for
buying me fried mackerel!
Say you're sorry
for being stupid!
Apologize from the
bottom of your heart!
You human trash!
Come on, hurry!
Say it, stupid!
Apologize, you moron!
Trash! Stupid! Idiot!
Stop calling me an idiot, Mio!
You think you know me
after just six months?!
You think you understand my art?!
I do! If you're so good at drawing,
why don't you
become a comic artist?!
Wh-what are you talking
about? You're so dumb!
What? Takes one to
know one, you idiot!
You just called
yourself an idiot.
No, I didn't!
You did!
But... I don't dislike
that about you...
What? What are
you talking about?
You're smart!
Sh-shut up, you comedic genius.
Wh-what are you talking about?
You're a fantastic artist!
Shut up! You're a fast runner!
You're smart!
You're positive!
No, you're smart!
Amazing!
Youth
Captain! I hate it!
Don't cry. You've still got next year.
I promise I'll work hard for you!
All right!
That was so long ago...
Hey, Nano. Did you
have fun at school?
Well, you know,
a lot happened.
But it was...
How was it? How was it?
Friends are amazing!
That's amazing!
I don't understand.
Huh? What?
Professor!
What?
Please remove the
key on my back!
No.
Why not? It interferes
with my school life...
Today, people suspected
me of being a robot!
I can't make friends with this...
Sure you can. It's cute.
It's not cute!
It is so cute.
Let's just eat, already.
Professor!
If my wish can come true today,
Ima watashi no negaigoto ga
then I’ll wish for wings!
Kanau naraba tsubasa ga hoshii
Please add white wings to my back
Kono senaka ni tori no youni
so I can be like a bird!
Shiroi tsubasa tsukete kudasai
I want to spread my wings
Kono oozora ni tsubasa wo hiroge
and fly into this wide sky!
Tonde yukitai yo
I want to flap my wings and fly to this
Kanashimi no nai jiyuu na sora he
free sky filled with happiness!
Tsubasa hatamekase yukitai
I'm a soccer ball.
Kicked, kicked,
kicked, and kicked.
Kicked, kicked, and
kicked until I collapse.
Kicked until the day I
die, and then I'll sleep.
The next episode of Nichijou is episode 15.
Narration:     Chiba Shigeru
Don't miss it!