Okay, that's all for today.
The days have gotten shorter,
so be sure to head home
before it gets dark, okay?
All right! Time to play!
Nano!
Yes?
Let's walk home together.
Want to get something
to eat at the station?
What?
Well?
Uh, um...
Mio, do you want to... huh?
She already left?
So, Nano...
Huh?
I left without saying anything...
I hope I didn't offend Aioi.
If only I had introduced
myself more normally...
M-m-my name is Shinonome Nano!
Uh, um... and, um...
This key... uh, well...
The best, friendship, perfect harmony!
jou-jou-yuujou magi magi kaichou
Yes, let's go, you're my best friend!
hai icchai mashou kimi wa best, best friend!
If you try being annoying
chotto fuza kete mitara
Then I'll be annoying in return
motto fuza ke kaeshite kuru
iigokochiitta aryashinai!
If I speak of comfort, it goes away
I had things I hated
iiyana koto attatte
But I forgot them in one swift stroke
sokko wasurechaunda
Let's go do something non-stop!
itsudatte janjan yarimashou!
We can be together 24/7!
nijyuuyon jikan isshodemo mondainai
marude futago ka oyako ka kuroom saibou
Almost like twins, a parent and a child or cloned cells!
Don't you cry when you fall in love?
kore ja renai suru hitsuyou to ka nakunakunai?
sore to kore to wa mattaku mattaku betsumondai
Those are totally different things!
Even when we fought
kenka shichatta toki mo
Even when we felt really blue
kanari e konda toki mo
Even when we want to be alone
hitori de itai you na toki mo
futo kizukeba chikaku ni iru
We are next to each other
shi na ba morotomo
Until death do us part
nande daro
Why, I wonder?
I want to be by your side
soba ni itainda
kimi to isshonara
When I'm with you
Time flies a hundred times as fast
tokei hyaku baisoku
It's so much fun
tanoshii na
It's too much fun
tanoshi sugirunda
Always the same, with my best friend!
sasuga saikyou furendo
What is it?
nan nano yo
Man, we're even synchronized
yabai shinkuro mo
What is it?
nan nano yo
yabai shinkuro mo
Man, we're even synchronized
Always such a rage
itsumo oosawagi
yabai shinkuro mo
Man, we're even synchronized
itsumo oosawagi
Always such a rage
Annoying everyone around us
kanari go kinj omeiwaku
itsumo oosawagi
Always such a rage
kanari go kinj omeiwaku
Annoying everyone around us
What time is it?
ima nanji?
Time to yodel!
tatoe yororeihi
What time is it?
ima nanji?
tatoe yororeihi
Time to yodel!
What are you talking about?
wakewakan nai nai!
tatoe yororeihi
Time to yodel!
wakewakan nai nai!
What are you talking about?
What am I going to do?
soure-do-shi-ra-
More than imagination!
so-zo-i-jo-
What should I say, awesome!
nante iu ka saikou
a-dako-da itte temo tomodachi
Whatever you say, we're friends!
Hooray!
wasshoi!
The best, friendship!
jou-jou-yuujou
Perfect harmony!
magi magi kaichou
The local coffee shop reopened,
so I thought I'd check it out.
Uh...
What would you like?
An espresso T.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 64
U-uh...
One tall espresso.
Will that be all?
T-tall?
Tall?
Does "T"  mean "tall"?
Well, I was thinking
it was a T-style espresso...
Uh, then...
Could I get a small espresso T?
One short espresso. Will that be all?
Uh, I'll... I'll just have a short small!
A-all right. So, one espresso...
Um...
Would you like it hot or iced?
Hot, please!
Um...
The hot comes in sizes...
solo...
and doppio.
D-d-d-d-doppio?!
Doppio?
What's doppio?
Wh-what the heck is doppio?
Doppio? Doppio?
What is doppio? What is it?
Coffee
of the Day
A
Oh, that's right!
I forgot I wanted to get
the coffee of the day...
Um...
Today we have an espresso...
I'll have that...
Okay. Would you like...
a solo...
...or a doppio?
Doppio...
Or a doppio?
Right...
Then... then...
please just do whatever.
Very well.
Thank you for waiting.
Here's your espresso.
It's tiny...
It's so bitter.
Thank you very much.
From now on,
I'll just buy my coffee
from a vending machine.
I gave my grandson, Mi,
Catch
a catcher's mitt for his birthday.
Grandpa, I'm gonna throw it.
Hey now, Mi,
it won't reach me from
all the way over there.
I didn't think he'd get this happy.
What a cute grandson.
Ready?
Oh, well...
Throw it as hard as you can.
I'll show him what
his grandpa can do.
A sinker...
50 yen
Chef's Choice Chicken Bar:
Unbearably
Super-Hot,
Tico Mart
E-excuse me...
Yes?
Could I get an Unbearably Super-Hot Chef's Choice Chicken Bar?
Miss, give me a break.
What is it, Kojirou?
Right! I need to hurry...
It closes soon—
Mio!
Y-Yukko... what's wrong?
What's wrong?
You left the second
that homeroom ended.
Oh, r-right.
But it's not too late.
Let's walk home together.
Actually, I've got something to do.
Really? What?
Uh, well, it's nothing...
What's with the attitude?
It's, you know...
Just tell me! Just tell me!
Do you have a minute?
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 65
So...
Sorry!
What? Yukko, what are you doing?
That just slipped out!
You surprised me, too.
I wasn't expecting an apology.
Sorry.
Did you need something?
Lately, we've found a lot of counterfeit bills in vending machines.
I was wondering if you'd
seen anyone suspicious.
Mio, have you?
I don't come this way too often.
According to witnesses,
the culprit had a beige
tote bag with a red line...
You can't really...
What?!
What is this strange reaction?
Do you have counterfeit bills? Do you?
No, no. That's impossible...
Give me a break, Mio...
What?!
Why is she turning herself in?
Hey, are you carrying
counterfeit bills?
O-of course not...
She's just preparing in case a
stray volleyball comes her way.
Right, Mio?
All right.
Just to be sure,
let me check your bags.
Here you go!
Come on, Mio—
No!
She pulled one out!
She pulled out a counterfeit bill!
She's done for.
I didn't think she
actually had any...
Please forgive me.
Please forgive me!
Is this the only counterfeit bill you have?
It isn't counterfeit!
It's real, and it's a bribe!
I don't understand.
Just let me see your...
Hey! Why are you resisting?
Because it belongs to a relative!
It's my relative's bag!
You're such an idiot.
One! Two!
Three!
Four!
Five!
Six?
Passion...
A fever, you idiot.
Idiot. Idiot. Idiot... Idiot...
What? What is this?
Some kind of accident?
Oh, Kojirou. There you are.
You're just like a newborn.
Mio!
Aren't you coming out to eat?
Your food will get cold.
Hey, Mio... hey!
This is Kojirou!
What are you...
Okay! That's all for today.
I've handed out all the material
the midterm exam will cover,
so be sure you get a copy.
Goodbye!
Nano always goes home right away.
Goodbye.
Bye.
Short Thoughts
Goodbye.
When I can, I like to
pretend I know everyone.
Goodbye.
Yukko, can I borrow your eraser?
Sure.
Guess which one.
Mai, can I borrow your eraser?
Wow!
Okay.
Here.
A character eraser!
This won't erase anything.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 66
It's just going to smudge.
Yukko, can I borrow your eraser?
Mai, you don't have one, either?
You girls are hopeless.
Guess which one.
This one.
Whoa!
No, no, no, no, no!
The rule is only one at a time,
so that didn't count.
When did you make that rule?
You first, Mai.
Come, come... look all you want.
No, no! No offensive attacks!
Mai, you've got one pena.
One pena?
One penalty.
What happens if you have one penalty?
You have to buy me twenty-three juices!
She's holding onto that grudge.
Here, Yukko. Baby Star.
It's opening...
That was close! It almost opened!
It's not "vyavalokayanti",
it's "vyavalokayati".
I thought that would work...
That's two pena!
Rock, paper, scissors, shoot...
Not so fast!
I'd never use the hand
holding my eraser.
That one.
Oh, no! She tricked me!
Come on, Yukko. Hand it over.
Yes, yes, yes, yes. You got it.
A character eraser!
Thank you very much!
You can't erase anything
with a character eraser.
Yeah, really.
It's Nano.
You're right.
Maybe Nano really is a robot.
Just let it go.
It hurts Nano's feelings.
Huh? Why?
Robots are cool!
What?
Love-like
Hey.
You want to run?
The Truth of
15 Years
Dad... hey, Dad!
The Truth of
15 Years
Do I really have to wear this outside?
It's embarrassing!
Embarrassing, you say?
You cowardly grass dumpling!
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 67
Shinonome... Shinonome...
Here it is!
Shinonome Laboratory...
A laboratory, huh? That's pretty cool!
Excuse me! Anyone home?
Huh? Maybe no one's here.
Yes! I'm coming.
Sorry to keep you...
Huh?!
Wh-wh-wh-what
am I going to do?
Why is Aioi here?
If she meets the professor,
Coming!
she'll find out I'm a robot.
Ah. Hello.
Huh? Where's Nano?
What should I do?
Nano's right there. Are you her friend?
Maybe she's just here
to deliver a worksheet.
Nano's right there. Are you her friend?
Yeah.
Maybe she's just here
to deliver a worksheet.
Yay! Come on in!
Maybe she's just here
to deliver a worksheet.
Yay! Come on in!
If that's all, I can...
Pardon me.
Come this way.
Don't mind me.
Idiot!
Well, she's already inside.
I'll just ask her what she wants
before the professor does anything.
I'm hungr...
What was that voice?
That's Sakamoto, our cat. He can talk.
Professor!
Really?
O-of course he can't.
M-Mr. Sakamoto,
please meow! Meow!
Huh? Why do I have to...
Meow, Mr. Sakamoto!
M-meow...
See? He's just a cat.
Ah, okay.
Mr. Sakamoto, we have a guest today, so please play outside, okay?
What?
Meow...
I haven't introduced myself yet.
I'm Aioi Yukko.
Are you Nano's little sister?
No, I'm the professor. I made Nano.
Made her?
Amazing! You're little,
but you're amazing!
I'm just a professor...
No, Aioi!
She's my relative's daughter.
Both of her parents work and don't get home until late at night,
so I'm looking after her...
Right? Isn't that right?
What are you talking about?
You... idiot!
Really?
Excuse me! I'll fetch more tea.
Nano, wait a second.
If you want tea...
What?
Here you go.
Amazing! Amazing!
This one's a gun.
Cool! Super cool!
I can't take any more.
Next, let's have a
cool phrase contest!
Yeah!
Then, I'll start...
Hey... you can't be serious. Get up...
Get up!
So cool!
You're next!
Okay!
Rhinoceros beetle.
So cool!
Why did Aioi come here?
They're on each other!
Uncle, uncle.
So small, so small.
So big...
Okay, I'm going home!
She didn't have a reason!
Thanks for today.
Sorry for staying so late.
Not at all...
Uh, Aioi?
I've actually been
studying magic tricks,
so I'm not a robot or anything...
Yeah, I already know
you're not a robot.
There we go.
Nano, you're just Nano.
Isn't that enough?
I just came here to tell you that.
But I forgot all about it.
See you later.
Okay...
Aioi!
Uh...
If you'd like to come over again...
Sure! I will!
Really? Hooray!
Next time, let's draw.
Okay! I'll draw a shark!
A shark? That's pretty cool!
Yeah, so cool...
Professor! Me, too!
Let's all sing together, and merge our hearts
minna de utaou kokoro wo hitotsu ni shite
Even during the sad times and the painful times
kanashii toki mo tsurai toki mo
Let's all sing together with a deafening voice
minna de utaou ookina koe wo dashite
Let's sing and ignore our uneasiness
hazukashigarazu utaou yo
A song that sets your heart on fire is sure to reach you
kokoro moeru uta ga uta ga kitto kimi no moto he
Sparkle, and spread my song throughout the world
kirameke sekaijuu ni boku no uta wo nosete
Sparkle, and deliver my message of love throughout the world
kirameke sekaijuu ni todoke ai no messeeji
Hey, Sakamoto.
See you later.
Later.
Well, whatever.
Plus-screw sounds good, doesn't it?
It sounds so positive.
You always have to live positively.
The next episode of Nichijou is episode 17.
Narration:      TARAKO
Don't miss it.