Glasses, glasses, glasses, glasses.
Glasses, glasses, glasses.
Glasses, glasses...
Glasses!
Glasses, glasses, glasses, glasses!
Glasses, glasses, glasses...
glasses, glasses, glasses,
The best, friendship, perfect harmony!
jou-jou-yuujou magi magi kaichou
Yes, let's go, you're my best friend!
hai icchai mashou kimi wa best, best friend!
If you try being annoying
chotto fuza kete mitara
Then I'll be annoying in return
motto fuza ke kaeshite kuru
iigokochiitta aryashinai!
If I speak of comfort, it goes away
I had things I hated
iiyana koto attatte
But I forgot them in one swift stroke
sokko wasurechaunda
Let's go do something non-stop!
itsudatte janjan yarimashou!
We can be together 24/7!
nijyuuyon jikan isshodemo mondainai
marude futago ka oyako ka kuroom saibou
Almost like twins, a parent and a child or cloned cells!
Don't you cry when you fall in love?
kore ja renai suru hitsuyou to ka nakunakunai?
sore to kore to wa mattaku mattaku betsumondai
Those are totally different things!
Even when we fought
kenka shichatta toki mo
Even when we felt really blue
kanari e konda toki mo
Even when we want to be alone
hitori de itai you na toki mo
futo kizukeba chikaku ni iru
We are next to each other
shi na ba morotomo
Until death do us part
nande daro
Why, I wonder?
I want to be by your side
soba ni itainda
kimi to isshonara
When I'm with you
Time flies a hundred times as fast
tokei hyaku baisoku
It's so much fun
tanoshii na
It's too much fun
tanoshi sugirunda
Always the same, with my best friend!
sasuga saikyou furendo
What is it?
nan nano yo
Man, we're even synchronized
yabai shinkuro mo
Always such a rage
itsumo oosawagi
Annoying everyone around us
kanari go kinj omeiwaku
What time is it?
ima nanji?
Time to yodel!
tatoe yororeihi
What time is it?
ima nanji?
tatoe yororeihi
Time to yodel!
What are you talking about?
wakewakan nai nai!
What am I going to do?
soure-do-shi-ra-
More than imagination!
so-zo-i-jo-
What should I say, awesome!
nante iu ka saikou
a-dako-da itte temo tomodachi
Whatever you say, we're friends!
Hooray!
wasshoi!
The best, friendship!
jou-jou-yuujou
Perfect harmony!
magi magi kaichou
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 78
I'd like to do something that has never been witnessed before,
and shall never be witnessed again!
Domestic violence.
How was it?
What am I supposed
to say to that?
It was just like you.
It really was.
Yes, just like you.
Then next, I'll do something
completely unlike me.
I tripped!
That was just like her...
Just like her.
Newbie,
Part 1
We've got rice cakes!
Come get some!
I'm sorry,
but do you think you
could wear this?
We've got rice cakes!
Come get some!
Sorry, but could
you stop talking?
Newbie,
Part 2
Can't you wear
some clothes?
Are you sulking?!
Newbie,
Part 3
You're not sulking?
So, what is it?
Hey... you can talk now!
Love-like
to Tokisada
High School.
I hope
I get accepted
I hope the person above gets accepted.
I hope the person to the right gets accepted...
You can do it!
I hope the person below gets accepted!!
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 79
Here I go!
Yes!
You didn't jump!
Huh? But the bar...
Yeah, but you didn't
jump over  it!
How many times do
I have to teach you?
The sun's going to set!
Sorry. I'll try harder next time.
This time, I'll lower the bar.
Take your time.
Just be sure you do it
how I taught you, okay?
Okay.
I have to be able to jump
before the next test...
or everyone's going
to laugh at me!
How was that?
You stupid cow!
Why won't you jump
the way I taught you?
Are you messing around?
In my head, it was a
perfect Fosbury Flop.
A perfect Fosbury Flop?
Your form's closer to...
a torpedo!
A human torpedo...
I didn't say that!
No, I...
I guess I did say that...
No, no, you're just kidding, right?
You don't see it?
Sorry.
Well, I'll stay until you're satisfied.
You always let me copy your homework.
It's my turn to help you!
Let's keep going until you can do it.
Just take it easy.
First, try to jump as if
you're just stepping over it!
Mio, you can do this!
It's no problem!
It's not like I've suddenly
become nonathletic.
Go! You can do it!
Hey, Mio! We're playing soccer!
I'm as fit as the average person.
But when rules get
involved, I lose control.
Backwards fall...
Go!
Mio, the other way!
You're doing it in reverse!
But if I do nothing,
nothing will change.
I'll just stay as I am!
Ready, and...
Mio, not the propeller!
It's a back hip circle!
I don't care if it's pointless...
I don't care if I don't get results.
There's only one thing I can do...
One, two, three!
Let's give it another try.
For Yukko...
I'm going to take a break.
Okay.
For myself, too!
I won't give up!
If I have to give up...
I'll make sure I've done
everything I could first!
Hard work will always open doors.
This came to be known
as the "Torpedo Jump".
This is a white tiger.
All they do is sleep...
That one's pointing its butt at us.
Yeah.
They're really far away,
too. It's hard to see.
We came all this way to
see them, and it's boring!
We should be glad
we got to see them.
I guess...
Hooray!
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 80
It's raining! We should
bring in the laundry.
Hey, where are you going?
Yay!
Looks like it's too late.
Just get it inside!
It's raining!
Professor, Mr. Sakamoto, I'm home...
It's raining hard, isn't it?
Did you bring in the laundry?
Sakamoto told me to bring it in!
It's true.
Sakamoto really did
tell me to bring it in...
So, you dropped the laundry because Mr. Sakamoto told you to bring it in?
That's not it! Sakamoto
told me to bring it in...
and drop it.
I did not!
That scared me...
What were you talking about, kid?
You told me to do it!
I never told you to drop it.
Did, too!
Did not!
Give me a break...
What?!
Nano... let's sacrifice Sakamoto.
Then everything'll be okay, right?
What's going on?
Forget it. We can just
wash the laundry again.
Oh! Right.
That's right.
But we can never get this day back.
Neither of you gets dinner tonight.
What?
How did I get dragged into this?
But Sakamoto did it!
And I said I'd sacrifice Sakamoto,
so it's okay, right?
Fine. Then I'll take Mr. Sakamoto.
And you won't get any dinner, Professor.
What?
No! Then I'll sacrifice myself!
I dropped it! I'm the
one who got it wet...
What?
Ta-dah! Today's dinner
is omelette rice!
Wow...
The eggs were on sale.
Huh? Do I get to eat today?
Oh! That's right. I completely forgot...
Um, well...
Well, let's just eat today!
Hooray!
No dinner tomorrow.
Lame.
Swim, swim.
Shark, shark, chomp.
What is this?
Mio! Mai! Selamat pagi!
Didn't that self-portrait
sculpture assignment suck?
What? That's due today?
What's this? Master Mio,
did you forget your homework?
I thought it was due tomorrow.
Mai, did you do it?
Crap.
Mai didn't do hers, either?
What's next, a shower?
It won't just be a shower.
It'll be a natural disaster!
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 81
It really did...
...start raining.
What have you done to my temple?
You thieves...
Th-that was close!
It's a curse...
It's an evil spirit.
B-begone...
Leave this temple!
"Let us go."
Is what they thought,
as the autumn rain fell.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 82
Please, President...
I'm about to have a match
against Mr. Takasaki.
Can you be our referee?
Referee? You mean for Go-Soccer?
Yes!
If I win, he has to
become our advisor.
I know I can do it!
What do I have to do?
It's okay.
The Go-Soccer rulebook I lent you
has everything you need to know.
I know it's my fault for
not reading the guide,
but I have no idea what
these two are doing...
This is Go-Soccer?
You wouldn't understand even if you'd read the rulebook.
Ogi?
Neither is observing the rules.
Their high-level play has
no regard for theory.
If that outstretched hand
is the leg of a Go board,
that stance is the stone.
It may appear normal at first glance,
but that ball between
his feet is an anomaly.
It's just speculation,
but I believe these two...
are trying to achieve brilliance!
I have no idea what
he's talking about.
There they go!
Oh, no!
Birabudo!
Ogi, what does that...
Quiet!
Can't you see how the
air flows between them?
One of them...
might even die.
What's going on?
I haven't seen such
high-level play in a long time.
No wonder the wind screams...
No! That stance!
Could it be?
Would he really use that move
in an unofficial match?
Is he out of his mind?
I cannot allow this to happen...
Father, I must do it!
All in the name of justice...
I must become a shining star!
Ogi Forbidden Technique...
Ogi Star!
This is a final rabudo!
Not bad...
You, too, teacher.
Unbelievable...
When I founded this club,
I didn't give it much thought.
Man...
this is unbelievable.
Why does the untamed horse
yasei no uma wa yasei no uma wa
run?
naze kaketeiku kaketeiku
It holds its head high, with tail fluttering
kubi motage o wo nabikasete
and the muscles flex in its heart
kinniku no yakudou mune ni
as it runs
dokomademo dokomademo
in perfect freedom
kaketeiku kaketeiku
Into a summer storm
natsu no arashi no naka wo
slashed by lightning it runs now
inaduma ni mukatte inaduma ni mukatte
The wild horse
yasei no uma wa yasei no uma wa
runs in perfect freedom
dokomademo kaketeiku
Runs in perfect freedom
kaketeiku
Short Thoughts
I break when no one sees me.
No matter how many times
you step on me, you won't kill me!
I'm clay.
Show some respect!
Today, I'll change into
various forms again,
to battle the children!
The next episode of Nichijou is episode 20.
Narration:     Mitsuya Yuji
Now, go challenge those children!