Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 87
It's lunchtime!
I wasn't expecting that to happen.
It's a miracle!
I forgot my homework, but I didn't
have to stand in the hallway!
Luck's on my side today!
You really should do it.
So, Mio, why not buy me some juice to honor my miracle?
Aioi,
I'd like to talk to you
about today's assignment.
Come to the faculty office.
Okay.
Someday, I'll buy her something.
The best friendship, everything is perfect!
joujou yuujou! banji maji kaichou!
Yes, I'll say it, you're my best friend!
hai icchaimashou kimi wa Best Best Friend!
If you try being annoying
chotto fuzakete mitara
chotto fuza kete mitara
Then I'll be more annoying in return
motto fuzakekaeshitekuru
If I speak of comfort, it goes away
igokochi ii ttara aryashinai!
I had things I hated
iyana koto attatte
But I forgot them in one swift stroke
sokkoo wasurechaunda
Let's go do something non-stop!
itsudatte janjan yarimashou!
We can be together 24/7!
nijyuuyo jikan isshodemo mondainai
marude futago ka oyako ka kuroon saibou
Almost like twins, a parent and a child or cloned cells!
Isn't it not unnecessary to love, then?
kore ja ren'ai suru hitsuyou toka nakunakunai?
sore to kore to wa mattaku mattaku betsumondai!!
Those are totally different things!
Even when we fought
kenka shichatta toki mo
Even when we felt really blue
kanari hekonda toki mo
Even when we want to be alone
hitori de itai yo na toki mo
futo kizukeba chikaku ni iru
We are next to each other
shinaba morotomo
Until death do us part
nande daro
Why, I wonder?
I want to be by your side
soba ni itainda
kimi to isshonara
When I'm with you
Time flies a hundred times as fast
tokei hyakubaisoku
It's so much fun
tanoshii na
It's too much fun
tanoshisugirunda
Always the same, with my best friend!
sasuga saikyou Friend! Hey!
What is it?
nan nanoyo
Man, I feel we're synchronized!
yabbai shinkurokan!
Always such a rage
itsumo oosawagi
Annoying everyone around us
kanari gokinjo meiwaku
What time is it?
ima nanji?
Let's see, yodelayheehoo!
tatoe yororeihi
What time is it?
ima nanji?
tatoe yororeihi
Let's see, yodelayheehoo!
What are you talking about?
wake wakannainai!
What am I going to do?
so-re-do-shi-ra-
More than imagination!
souzou ijou!
What should I say, awesome!
nante iu ka saikou!
a-dako-da ittetemo tomodachi
Whatever you say, we're friends!
Hooray!
wasshoi!
The best friendship!
joujou yuujou!
Everything is perfect!
banji maji kaichou!
Over here.
Oh, sorry. You must have
been waiting a while.
No. I just got here, too.
I see. That's good.
Are her friends over again?
There's somewhere I want to go today.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 88
So, how's it coming along?
What do you mean?
What do I mean? Sheesh...
You and Sasahara
are totally in love!
Why do I have to marry him?
I didn't say that...
Why do I have to have a
daughter and then a son?
Okay, okay! I'm glad you've got your adult life all planned out!
Adult...
What about you, Weboshi?
Who, me?
I've got nothing...
What? Come on, tell us.
There's someone you like, right?
Come on. Tell us... tell us...
Fet, sto—
I give, I give... Christian give...
Nope, I won't stop until you tell me...
Fine, fine! I'll tell,
I'll tell, I'll tell you...
I can't take any more...
If you don't tell me,
I'll tickle you to death!
I said I'd tell you!
Oh, sorry... I was
having too much fun...
Who is it? Who do
you like, Weboshi?
I don't know if I really like him.
I'm just sort of interested.
But I'm not sure what his name is.
It's the guy with the mohawk.
Oh...
That guy.
Oh, you two know him?
Of course we do.
He's pretty famous
around our school.
With his hairstyle and all.
Weboshi, why'd you
have to like him?
I'm not sure...
But he's sort of punk, you know?
I prefer kinda wild guys
to good students.
He's a total bad guy.
I mean, he's got a mohawk!
But the other day,
I heard that punk speaking politely.
There you go again!
That's ridiculous!
He's got a mohawk!
But on top of that,
he was watering flowers.
That's surprising.
Oh, and he planted that
thing that looks like Yakult.
What a cute contrast!
And his head looks
like a cut pineapple.
He's so handsome,
he oozes pineapple juice.
That kindness of his is
one of his strong points!
I'd like a kind man, too...
What about you, Fet?
Anyone you like?
Who, me? I—
Sasahara...
Kojirou.
Sasahara fed his
goat on a rainy day.
I get it. Yeah, I get it! That kindness!
What? I didn't say I liked it!
So how about you, Fet?
What now?
I'm asking if you like anyone.
I'm not interested in
anyone right now, but...
I don't think I'd be interested
in two weirdos like you.
Begin!
One point!
Love-like
Ow! Ow, ow...
Hold on.
Here.
Oh, thank you.
Let me see your hand.
And so, I spent my
precious day off
sleeping, eating, and
gardening, just like I always do.
Well, I suppose peaceful
days aren't too bad.
I don't suppose anything
interesting will come my way...
Hello.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 89
Casual clothes.
Ms. Sakurai's wearing... casual clothes.
Mr. Takasaki,
are you shopping too?
Her hair's tied up!
I've run into her on my day off.
I feel like I've gotten closer to her.
I'm so grateful...
Oh, I'm sorry! Are you in pain?
S-sorry! I was just feeling grateful.
Ms. Sakurai, are you shopping, too?
Yes! The onions were cheap,
so I bought a whole bunch.
Onions, eh?
I would have brought you
bamboo shoots if you'd asked.
Did you say bamboo shoots?
I have a vegetable garden at home.
It's, you know...
You do? That's amazing.
Running into her on a weekend
makes me feel this must be fate.
Like we're bound by
fate, or something.
Is the coincidence
causing these emotions?
I'm honestly surprised...
I've never felt this way before.
I want to be an onion.
Are you all right?
You seem to be in pain...
Shall we rest somewhere?
I-I'm sorry! I'm totally fine!
I wasn't thinking about...
Shall we rest somewhere?
Thinking about...
Think...
Shall we rest somewhere?
That would be more than enough...
Come! Come along!
Ms. Sakurai, there's a park
over there we can go to!
Okay.
I never thought
this would happen.
This isn't a date, isn't it?!
Aioi?
M-M-Ms. Sakurai! Let's try
that field over there...
What is Aioi doing here?
If people find out about this...
What are you two doing?
You idiot! This is,
you know, that...
That thing!
Hello.
I didn't know you
two were dating.
You idiot! Don't
mock your teachers!
What? But you seem
happy together...
You little brat.
A
The Next Day
Ms. Sakurai, good morning.
A
Mr.
Takasaki
Hey, you lovebirds!
It's getting hot in here!
Idiots! Don't make fun of us!
Jeez! Those brats...
I'm sorry.
I seem to have caused
you some trouble.
Oh, but...
I am a little happy.
Good enough!
Am I stupid?
There's no way that would happen!
I have to get out of here!
That came out of nowhere.
Oh, no!
What are you doing, Mr. Takasaki?
What's this? Why, if it isn't Ms. Sakurai!
And Aioi! Why, if it isn't Aioi!
You have to keep an eyes peeled,
or you don't even notice these things.
Aioi? You're Aioi, right?
I'm Aioi! Just kidding.
Well, there you have it.
I've got something to do,
so I'll see you later.
I guess...
I'll go buy some
onions, and go home.
Sorry for calling you out here.
Cry of
Youth
Did you sleep well last night?
Cry of
Youth
Yes, but I had a strange dream.
A strange dream?
Well, I dreamed we kissed here.
I'll make that dream a reality.
What? Are you serious?
P-Professor, would you like some snacks?
Do you really love me?
Don't be silly.
After a month-long investigation,
I've learned that she visits this
supermarket at this time every Saturday.
It's almost time for her to arrive.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 90
Once she's finished
shopping, I'll follow her.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 90
Once she's finished
shopping, I'll follow her.
When we reach an isolated location,
I'll use the still-untested
Mr. Short Circuit on her,
and take her home with me!
It's perfect...
Today's the day I'll examine
you, Shinonome Nano!
A
Later
Hours
What.
Why haven't you
come, Shinonome?
Does this mean you don't
always go to the supermarket?
I've already waited this long.
If I leave now, I might miss her.
Huh?
Ah, it's you, Ms. Nakamura.
Hello.
It's the Japanese teacher
with the sideburns!
H-hello.
I almost didn't recognize
you without your lab coat.
Why did I have to
run into him now?
If you don't need anything, just go.
If Shinonome arrives now...
Your casual clothes are
rather boyish, aren't they?
It's kind of cute.
No, I wouldn't say that...
No, the contrast between those
clothes and your normal lab coat
is sort of innocent and cute.
I'll have to retreat for today!
Huh? Ms. Nakamura?
Um, Minakami, have you thought about
what you'd like to do in the future?
Yes.
Are you planning to work?
Uh, do you plan on further schooling?
Um...
I understand.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 91
Did you find it?
Where is it?
I can't find the wood cube...
How does something
disappear from a locked safe?
We get paid if we find it,
so I'm happy about that.
I heard the officer just found one.
There's only one left?
I'll have to look harder.
I wonder if finding it would earn me any points with the throne.
H-hey, look there.
Give me back the wood cube.
What are you talking about, miss?
How'd you get in here?
Are you a stowaway?
The punishment for
that's quite severe.
You'll either be thrown in
prison for at least ten years...
Or you'll have tea
with me. Just kidding.
Twenty-two!
What are you doing...
Wait.
Hold your horses!
It's all right. I just
let down my guard.
Leave this to me.
You think you're a tough
little girl, don't you?
Don't you think this
game's gone too far...
Are you okay?!
He's dead...
That bitch!
The stowaway's
after the wood cube?
Surround her! We'll trap her!
Quiet, everyone.
There is no reason to panic.
Officer!
Fey Kingdom Military Staff Officer
AKA The Resilient Negotiator
Leave this to me.
I'm sure the officer will
do something about this.
She entered alone,
in pursuit of the wood cube.
She must be a spy.
However, if we could
harness her strength,
it might prove to be a great
weapon for our country.
Fortunately, I have
one wood cube here.
If this is what she wants,
I'm sure the right offer
will buy her allegiance.
This is the wood cube you desire.
Why don't we make a deal?
Ow!
Officer!
He's dead...
This isn't good.
That bitch...
She killed the officer!
You monster! We'll
never let you go alive!
This isn't good! This isn't good...
This is very bad...
Fey Kingdom Number 71
AKA Scholar
This is very bad...
Fey Kingdom Number 71
AKA Scholar
What's wrong, Scholar?
What's so bad?!
This is a serious matter.
She already had one wood cube,
and now she has the one
she just put in her hair.
That's the other wood cube!
She has both wood cubes!
What? Even with both,
if she doesn't know how to
summon the ancient weapon...
That's right! We can still do something—
Shut up!
According to this magic encyclopedia,
one possessing both wood cubes
gains the ancient weapon's power...
In other words,
she has the wood cubes.
So, she has the ancient weapon's power...
What did you say?
Explain it again!
Yeah, explain it again!
In other words...
There's nothing else to say!
It's foolish to approach her!
She'll destroy the world!
We're done for...
Don't panic!
Nothing comes of panic!
Fey Kingdom Captain
AKA Nothing Special
Nothing comes of panic!
Captain...
Captain!
If we attack from the
front, we're done for.
We cannot win.
However! There's only one of her!
In contrast, we are many!
We need only to attack together!
I'll lead the charge!
Follow me!
Captain!
Don't worry about me. Go!
B-but...
You fool,
I didn't teach you to be pansies!
We're finished.
The officer's dead,
and the captain can't move.
There's nothing we can do!
One...
One for all...
And all...
for one!
Captain!
It's been twelve years
since I joined this troop.
I won't let twelve years' worth
of memories end like this.
Not with this monster.
Not here...
I won't...
let it end here!
We're finished.
I don't want to die!
I'll go wash my face.
Short Thoughts
So obvious!
Don't be surprised, okay?
Jack-in-the-Box
So obvious!
Good grief...
Well, I don't have
anything else to do.
I might as well
play with the kid...
Even when wasting time,
talent is still talent.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 92
Your hair's sticking up. How cute.
It's kind of cute.
What am I doing?!
Sunday Night
I'm finished.
The water felt great...
Sunday Night
I'm finished.
The water felt great...
The colors of the flowers, the shadows of the clouds
hana no iro kumo no kage
are memories that take me back to my childhood
natsukashii ano omoide
Today I leave you all behind windows of yesteryear
sugi shi hi no mado ni nokoshite
to spread my wings and walk the world
sudachiyuku kyou no wakare
Goodbye, goodbye, my teachers
izasaraba saraba sensei
Goodbye, goodbye, my friends
izasaraba saraba tomo yo
May we see a bright tomorrow
utsukushii asu no hi no tame
I'm the lovers' umbrella.
Why don't you try
drawing me again?
Write your own name
on the right, and...
You don't have a name
to write on the left?
For all you lonely
viewers out there...
Narration:      Shimamoto Sumi
The next episode of Nichijou is episode 22.
Don't miss it.