Science can prove
everything in this world.
There are many reports of supernatural phenomena from across the globe,
but there's no way anything
that lame could exist.
They just can't exist.
In other words...
I don't believe in ghosts!
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 93
The best, friendship, perfect harmony!
jou-jou-yuujou magi magi kaichou
Yes, let's go, you're my best friend!
hai icchai mashou kimi wa best, best friend!
If you try being annoying
chotto fuza kete mitara
Then I'll be annoying in return
motto fuza ke kaeshite kuru
iigokochiitta aryashinai!
If I speak of comfort, it goes away
I had things I hated
iiyana koto attatte
But I forgot them in one swift stroke
sokko wasurechaunda
Let's go do something non-stop!
itsudatte janjan yarimashou!
We can be together 24/7!
nijyuuyon jikan isshodemo mondainai
marude futago ka oyako ka kuroom saibou
Almost like twins, a parent and a child or cloned cells!
Don't you cry when you fall in love?
kore ja renai suru hitsuyou to ka nakunakunai?
sore to kore to wa mattaku mattaku betsumondai
Those are totally different things!
Even when we fought
kenka shichatta toki mo
Even when we felt really blue
kanari e konda toki mo
Even when we want to be alone
hitori de itai you na toki mo
futo kizukeba chikaku ni iru
We are next to each other
shi na ba morotomo
Until death do us part
nande daro
Why, I wonder?
I want to be by your side
soba ni itainda
kimi to isshonara
When I'm with you
Time flies a hundred times as fast
tokei hyaku baisoku
It's so much fun
tanoshii na
It's too much fun
tanoshi sugirunda
Always the same, with my best friend!
sasuga saikyou furendo
What is it?
nan nano yo
Man, we're even synchronized
yabai shinkuro mo
What is it?
nan nano yo
yabai shinkuro mo
Man, we're even synchronized
Always such a rage
itsumo oosawagi
Annoying everyone around us
kanari go kinj omeiwaku
What time is it?
ima nanji?
Time to yodel!
tatoe yororeihi
What time is it?
ima nanji?
tatoe yororeihi
Time to yodel!
What are you talking about?
wakewakan nai nai!
What am I going to do?
soure-do-shi-ra-
More than imagination!
so-zo-i-jo-
What should I say, awesome!
nante iu ka saikou
a-dako-da itte temo tomodachi
Whatever you say, we're friends!
Hooray!
wasshoi!
The best, friendship!
jou-jou-yuujou
Perfect harmony!
magi magi kaichou
I came here because I heard that this temple performs exorcisms.
How may I help you?
I'll pretend an evil spirit is possessing me while I look for contradictions.
Lately, I've felt like
something's strangling me.
Oh, my...
Here. Use this.
This is it!
What kind of baseless ritualistic talisman is he giving me?
It's good for the throat.
H-how remarkably logical.
Was my story too unrealistic?
I must make him believe me!
Aren't you listening?
My throat doesn't just hurt. It...
feels like I'm being strangled.
And sometimes,
I hear strange voices,
like I'm being possessed!
You know, I think...
you've just been reading
too many strange books.
Stay away from me...
I never thought I'd hear
a professional say that!
Does this priest even
believe in ghosts?
But I came all the
way to this temple.
I can't just leave now!
Something terrifying
is strangling me!
Excuse me...
He saw right through me!
Of course he did.
I was an idiot to think my bad
acting could fool a professional!
I have to take this seriously.
To convince him,
I must take it to the limit!
What?
Hey! What are you doing?
What is this?
What are you doing?
Y-you brat!
You brat. My temple...
What are you
doing to my temple?
I want to become a scientist.
O-oh, no... I've gone too far.
I will explain the
world with science,
and make everyone understand.
And when the time comes,
I will have but one thing to say...
Are you all right?
Be...
Begone, evil spirit!
..."the true evil
spirits are just people".
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 94
You're open!
Who's there?
Mihoshi, long time no see.
It's you, Naganohara!
I haven't seen you since before you entered middle school.
That's because you
never come to the dojo.
I haven't been going to
practice at college, either.
I'm playing hooky.
But you still managed to win at that national tournament!
You damned genius!
Are you going to the dojo?
Yeah, my club just ended.
Are you coming too, Naganohara?
Eh, the more I practice,
the weaker I get.
What are you saying,
you damned genius?
I have to admit she's strong.
But I can't accept her strength
when she hardly even practices!
I heard that when Naganohara
was in seventh grade,
she scored a point against
the assistant instructor.
Against the assistant instructor!
I'm a middle school student too,
but I don't even stand a chance.
I go to the dojo after my club,
and I practice on weekends, too!
The assistant instructor said,
"Hard work will always open doors."
A black cat.
Here, kitty.
Seeing her makes
me question myself.
Ah, so cute...
I want to try to hit her.
Just one blow.
Maybe now, I could...
For now, this is all I can do.
But maybe someday, in a match...
And someday, against
the assistant instructor, too!
You damned genius!
S-sorry!
Assistant Instructor!
Love-like
So cold.
Rice Cake Fair
Do a good job, got it?
Reign
Father wants me to
follow in his footsteps.
Reign
Give this balloon to
any kids who come by.
Reign
Give this balloon to
any kids who come by.
But I won't fall for it.
I'll look for a chance to escape!
This balloon...
doesn't float!
Short Thoughts
In the end, everyone
hopes for a happy ending.
A Certain Christmas Short
Professor, what are
you asking Santa for?
I want chocolate
and colored pencils,
and cake erasers and... and...
You're asking for all that? No fair.
Then, I want two cartons of eggs,
five hundred grams of beef,
an Ivan Bilibin book, and—
I already asked for lots of stuff,
so you only get one thing!
What?
Nano, um...
You can still ask for a little...
I'll even let you borrow this...
Hello!
Hooray! It's Santa!
Merry Christmas!
Trap
I don't have time for this farce!
I'll take off this mask and...
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
Trying to run, Tsuyoshi?
Dad!
This time, I made some
modifications to the mask.
Modifications?
Underneath that mask, there's...
...wet paint!
Ow, hot!
Crap! I dropped my meat bun!
I didn't even get a single bite...
There, there, Weboshi.
If that bun were
poisoned, you'd be dead.
See? You're lucky.
I'm not lucky.
This is supposed to be the
best part about walking home.
If you're always positive,
good luck will eventually find you.
You should be grateful
your meat bun fell.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 95
What's with the optimism?
I've decided to be positive,
no matter what happens.
If you remove the dirty
parts, you can still eat it.
The poison scenario
sure disappeared fast...
If you remove the dirty parts...
Ow!
Ice save!
See? Fortune favors the upbeat.
It's merry magic!
But my meat bun's finished.
Now's the time to look
on the bright side.
If that bun were
poisoned, you'd be dead.
You don't have many
variations, do you?
Even if I cut off the dirty parts,
I don't want the part
with ice cream on it...
Come on. Positive thoughts,
positive thoughts!
Oh no!
The bun's heat must
have weakened it.
If I pretend the ice cream
was poisoned, it's no big deal...
You were just eating it!
What's wrong?
Loser
You used up all your
positive attitude's mojo!
No, God must be warning me not
to eat two and get a stomachache.
Oh? You're pretty
determined today.
And this ice cream...
If it had been soft serve,
it'd definitely be gone.
But I can wash off the
dirt from this frozen treat.
I'm grateful for that.
You're still going to eat it?
Wait!
How is it?
It looks wet.
Come on, Fet! Positive
thinking, positive thinking!
I give up!
Dash to
Freedom
If you refuse to
take over my job,
I'll set a second trap,
and then a third.
Dad...
this...
You...
is my...
Impossible!
answer!
Guidance Counselor's Office
Tachibana, what will
you do after graduation?
I'm deciding between
college and culinary school.
Culinary school, huh?
Wha... wh-wh-wh-what?
Marry him?
Calm down, Tachibana.
You tie it like this, and...
All done.
I'm home!
Oh, Nano, I'm going for
a walk with Sakamoto.
My friends are
coming over to study.
Is that okay?
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 96
Is that okay?
Okay. I wanna hang out
too, so I'll be back soon.
See you later!
Okay!
Hey, what are you doing, kid?
You're killing me!
You're killing me...
Okay! I'll listen!
What do you want? What?
A shark.
Don't be ridiculous!
Crying by myself...
I'm the one who wants to cry!
Okay, a shark?
No problem!
I'll get it right away...
so get this off me!
Dogs...
They're dogs,
so they might bite me.
Sakamoto, dogs.
They might bite us...
Wh-wh-what, y-y-you're scared of dogs?
They're on a leash,
so they can't bite us.
We have to run!
Got it! Let's run!
Sakamoto! We can't run!
Don't give up! If you give up, it's over!
Get the owner to put
them on their leash!
We're done for!
No, no, no... think harder!
What can we do? What can we do?
What to do... what to do...
What to do, what to do...
I had a gummy in my pocket.
That's it! We'll run
while they eat it!
I know! Invent something
that can help us escape!
Oh, right! I forgot!
Sakamoto...
What?
I don't have the equipment
to make anything!
Damn it!
Boil me or fry me!
Do whatever you want with me!
Boil me...
Fry me...
Do whatever you want...
Dinner.
They're gonna eat us,
they're gonna eat us...
If they get us,
we might be eaten...
Professor?
Why are you crying?
Are you lost?
Yukko!
So this is the professor
you were talking about?
Sakamoto's with you?
Let me pet him...
No, Yukko, you have
to defeat the dogs!
He's unbelievably fluffy!
I'm next!
Don't be ridiculous!
Stop the dogs...
I understand. He bit you,
so you want revenge.
No, he's about to bite us!
What? I bet you're afraid
of dogs, you scaredy cat!
No! He's a dog,
so he'll bite us!
Look at him. This docile
dog wouldn't bite anyone.
He will!
No, he won't.
Think he'll chew
gum? Just kidding.
He will!
Then watch this.
Shake.
Yukko, are you okay?
If you don't go near him,
he won't bite you.
Yukko... Yukko...
It's okay. Yukko's just stupid, okay?
Okay...
Let's get Yukko and
go to Nano's, okay?
You know Nano?
Of course I—
Where have you been?! You have to keep your dogs on leashes!
Did they play with you?
What are you talking about?!
They almost bit me!
Here.
Shark chocolate!
Thank you very much.
I got some chocolate,
and the dogs are gone.
Isn't that great, Sakamoto?
Only little kids are afraid of dogs.
Hurry up and get this leash off me!
I got some chocolate, so I will.
Huh?
What's wrong?
Sakamoto, take it off. It's too tight.
I would if I could!
Let's get Yukko to do it.
Yukko, untie this.
Hey, Yukko. Hey, Yukko.
Hey.
Is that...
We're home.
There were lots of dogs...
You're so sweaty!
Oh, right! I have some chocolate!
Chocolate, chocolate, chocolate,
chocolate, chocolate.
Aioi and Naganohara sure are late...
Shark chocolate, chocolate, chocolate,
shark, shark, shark chocolate.
They should be over here.
What is this?
There's Buddy...
and another Buddy.
What are they doing?
Gramps!
Humans help each
other out, Takashi.
Animals are the same, Takashi.
Don't underestimate the bond
between animals
and humans, Takashi.
Gramps...
I'm Kiyoshi.
O revered master, what debt I owe you
aogeba toutoshi, waga shi no on
How fast the years of learning have passed, here in the garden
oshie no niwa ni mo, haya ikutose
When I pondered, the months and years flew by
omoeba ito toshi, kono toshitsuki
Now we must part, so fare thee well
ima koso wakareme, izasaraba
I'm melon bread.
Humans, you spend
an eternity debating
whether melon-flavored
is better or not.
The next episode of Nichijou is episode 23.
Narration:   Shibata Hidekatsu
Don't miss it.