Morning!
First!
Solid
First
Stag beetle.
What are you doing, Aioi?
Wh-what are you
doing here this early?
I'm on duty today.
Oh, why don't you help me
take out the garbage?
Teacher, please don't tell anyone...
We'll see...
You're killing me!
That was close...
The best friendship, everything is perfect!
joujou yuujou! banji maji kaichou!
Yes, I'll say it, you're my best friend!
hai icchaimashou kimi wa Best Best Friend!
If you try being annoying
chotto fuzakete mitara
Then I'll be more annoying in return
motto fuzakekaeshitekuru
igokochi ii ttara aryashinai!
If I speak of comfort, it goes away
I had things I hated
iyana koto attatte
But I forgot them in one swift stroke
sokkoo wasurechaunda
Let's go do something non-stop!
itsudatte janjan yarimashou!
We can be together 24/7!
nijyuuyo jikan isshodemo mondainai
marude futago ka oyako ka kuroon saibou
Almost like twins, a parent and a child or cloned cells!
Isn't it not unnecessary to love, then?
kore ja ren'ai suru hitsuyou toka nakunakunai?
sore to kore to wa mattaku mattaku betsumondai!!
Those are totally different things!
Even when we fought
kenka shichatta toki mo
Even when we felt really blue
kanari hekonda toki mo
Even when we want to be alone
hitori de itai yo na toki mo
futo kizukeba chikaku ni iru
We are next to each other
shinaba morotomo
Until death do us part
nande daro
Why, I wonder?
I want to be by your side
soba ni itainda
kimi to isshonara
When I'm with you
Time flies a hundred times as fast
tokei hyakubaisoku
It's so much fun
tanoshii na
It's too much fun
tanoshisugirunda
Always the same, with my best friend!
sasuga saikyou Friend! Hey!
What is it?
nan nanoyo
Man, I feel we're synchronized!
yabbai shinkurokan!
What is it?
nan nanoyo
yabbai shinkurokan!
Man, I feel we're synchronized!
Always such a rage
itsumo oosawagi
Annoying everyone around us
kanari gokinjo meiwaku
What time is it?
ima nanji?
Let's see, yodelayheehoo!
tatoe yororeihi
What time is it?
ima nanji?
tatoe yororeihi
Let's see, yodelayheehoo!
What are you talking about?
wake wakannainai!
What am I going to do?
so-re-do-shi-ra-
More than imagination!
souzou ijou!
What should I say, awesome!
nante iu ka saikou!
a-dako-da ittetemo tomodachi
Whatever you say, we're friends!
Hooray!
wasshoi!
The best friendship!
joujou yuujou!
Everything is perfect!
banji maji kaichou!
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 97
Mio.
I made some jam yesterday.
Want to try some?
What's gotten into you?
Well, the other day, I finished
off your marmalade.
Oh! Oh, that...
You must be getting a bit more feminine if you're making jam.
Don't make fun of me!
Try guessing what
kind of jam I made.
Okay, okay.
Let's try a little.
Gross!
Gross! Gross! Gross! Gross! Gross!
It's so gross, I don't
know what I'm tasting!
Here, Mio!
Have some Russian tea!
Hot!
Hot! Hot! It's hot, it's hot,
and it's gross!
Gross! Gross! Gross! Gross! Gross!
Here, Mio! Cool your
tongue with some jam!
Gross!
Gross! Gross! Gross! Gross! Gross!
Water!
Water, water, water! Water, water, water!
Water Outage
Milk!
Milk! Milk!
Milk, milk, milk!
Mio, I put the
leftover jam in there.
What flavor could possibly cause such unmatched revulsion?
It's so gross! Gross, gross, gross, gross...
Gross, gross, gross, gross, gross, gross!
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle School Graduation Ceremony
Hair Ties (Wood)
300 yen
Mio, are you okay?
Okay? Am I okay?
Of course I'm not okay!
Your jam was so disgusting,
my life flashed before my eyes!
I thought it tasted bad, but I didn't think it would be that strong.
Why would you make something you knew would be disgusting?!
I thought it might be fun.
You idiot...
Well, whatever.
So, what flavor do
you think it is?
Who cares?
I bet you put shit-covered
fish or something in it!
Close!
The secret ingredient is...
salt-cured fish!
It stinks!
That day was the first and
last time I had salt-cured fish.
Accident
Mako!
Dad will be late tonight,
so I'm getting takeout.
Is there anything you'd like?
This place is a mess...
Honestly...
he never cleans, no matter
how many times I ask.
Maybe I should scold him...
A
Helvetica Standard
The Movie
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 98
Packed with doubt right
from the opening!
I-I-I-I-Is this wh-wh-wh-what I think it is?
Hey! What are you doing?
You startled me...
I told you to stay out!
If you come in here again,
I'll do... you know! You know!
A
President's Office
If you come in here again,
I'll do... you know! You know!
I'm sorry.
Right... I need to
scold him today.
Hey!
I told you not to barge in!
Uh, I'm sorry.
And why are you
cleaning my room?
Because you never
clean it yourself!
The layout's perfect the way it is!
Just stay out of my room!
Mako?
Why do you keep coming in?
I think you're a little
young for these!
Y-y-you...
I think you're a little young for these!!!
Is that...
I-i-i-is that...
I think you're a little young for these!!!
That's...
Y-you... What?
What?
What is that? What
are you talking about?
That totally isn't mine.
I found it in your room!
What? I've never seen
that before in my life!
Besides, since when
was this my room?
It might not even be my room!
Either way, I think you're
too young for these!
You shouldn't have this!
What? I have no idea
what you're talking about!
I don't understand a
thing you're saying!
Then I'll throw this away!
That belongs to my club president!
What?
You aren't seriously thinking about
throwing away someone else's stuff, right?
I'm sorry!
I just peeked inside,
and it's sort of amazing...
But you shouldn't be
looking at these yet.
You'll become a delinquent...
Got it! I won't look at them!
I won't look at them,
so stay out of my room!
This sucks...
What does Mr. Takasaki see in her?
Mako, are you mad?
Can't you at least knock?
But I thought you might be mad...
I'm not mad!
See? You are mad.
I'm not mad, so get out!
If you don't knock
next time, I'll... you know!
I totally will!
I want to live alone...
I messed up today...
He says his room is clean, even
though it looks like a typhoon hit it.
And that book
wasn't Mako's, either.
But the morals at school
have gotten pretty lax.
I have to keep it together,
at school and at home.
I'm the student adviser!
I completely forgot...
Mako, I'm ordering some takeout.
How many times do
I have to tell you?!
1 capsule
40 grams
Um, about this
"Hopes for the Future" section...
do you have any
dreams or goals?
Oh, yes.
Um...
Oh! I'd like to be on
TV once, before I die!
Um, that's not what I mean.
I'm sorry. I guess I didn't
ask the right question.
Is there a job or career
you'd like to pursue?
Oh, um, let's see... yes, um...
I'd like to be a teacher
like you, Ms. Sakurai!
Like... me?
Oh, um... uh... well...
This is our sash!
It's up to you, Nakamura!
This is our last college run!
He's dropping out!
Tokisadame University
has withdrawn.
Hey, Nano.
Yes, what is it?
On our way to your house,
we ran into the professor.
But some dogs attacked us.
Sounds like you had some trouble.
Tell the professor we'll
come by another time.
Okay.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 99
Teacher! Please be our adviser!
No way! Never!
What the heck? You said
you'd do it just the other day!
When did I say that?
I can't believe it...
You promised you'd be our
adviser if I could defeat you.
That one time?
No! We called that match
a draw due to injury!
What?
Well, I guess I'll tell everyone
about your feelings for my sister.
Where's your club room?
This way!
Yes! Today, the Go-Soccer
club will finally get started!
Yeah!
President!
S-sorry for barging in!
Uh, I brought our new adviser—
H-hold on!
Why are you running?
Mr. Takasaki!
Looks like he's gone.
I was just about to go
recruit members, too.
I can't really explain
this club without Sakurai...
Whatever. It's my club.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 100
I'm so nervous...
Why are you nervous?
Because you're on your way to confess
your feelings to this Nakanojo guy, right?
Yeah. He's the punk spirit
of this peaceful school!
That mohawk is just irresistible.
Maybe not irresistible,
but it's certainly unique.
Teacher!
Wait!
Hey, Mr. Takasaki... why did you run?
I haven't played such a passionate Go-Soccer game in a long time.
I can't imagine anyone
else as our adviser!
I'm sorry, but I've got...
you know, things...
I have things... and stuff... well, so...
You came with me all
the way to the room.
I have no choice.
Teacher...
After seeing this,
can you still refuse?
You... this is...!
That's right.
It's a photograph of my
sister in high school.
Well, teacher?
What will you do?
In exchange for this photo,
will you be our adviser?
I-I want it!
I want it so much...
But I feel like if I agree,
I'll lose something important.
Sakurai...
Yes?
Sorry, but...
it sounds like a good deal to me!
What am I doing?!
Great! Then you'll
become our adviser?
I'm terrible...
Such inappropriate
behavior for a teacher.
However, while I may be
a teacher, I'm also a man.
Necessity knows no law!
Listen, Sakurai!
If I'm doing this, we're aiming
for the national championship!
Got it?
Yes!
Great! The Go-Soccer
club begins today!
We'll get started first
thing tomorrow!
Yes!
This is it.
Oh, really?
Hey.
Yes?
Is Nakanojo here?
Oh, yes.
Nakanojo!
Nakanojo, someone's
here to see you.
Yes. Can I help you?
So unappealing...
Love-like
Dad, would you
go look for me?
Okay.
Well?
Which is it?
Wet Paint
The train will make
a brief stop here.
Someone
Help Me
Minakami, what are
you doing here?
I came to play.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 101
Thank you for
all these snacks.
She's the one who
let her dogs bite me!
What?
It's definitely her.
I'll go make some tea.
What are you doing here?
Here.
What is that?
Yamantaka.
I don't want it.
But it's cool.
It's not cool at all.
This is interesting.
What is it?
A 36-mat apartment with
living, dining, and kitchen.
That's not interesting at all.
No bath, no toilet, no windows.
Not interesting.
What are you drawing?
I'm not telling you.
Here.
A blue shark.
It's so cool!
You can have it.
Yay!
Hey, draw another shark!
Okay.
Draw a smiling shark!
Will you trade with me?
Okay.
Thanks for waiting...
Huh?
A
I'm going home.
Minakami
Professor, did Minakami leave?
Yeah, but I told her to
come back and draw more.
I see.
I wonder why she came over.
I didn't know
shiranakatta yo
that the sky was so blue
sora konna ni aoi to wa
We all linked hands and walked out
te wo tsunaide aruite itte
to look up at the sky together
minna de aoida sora
This perfectly blue sky
honto ni aoi sora
The sky taught us
sora wa oshiete kureta
how to be kind
ookii kokoro wo motsu you ni
and how to never let go of our friends
tomodachi no te wo hanasanu you ni
I didn't know
shiranakatta yo
that the sky was so blue
sora ga konna ni aoi to wa
Why, I wonder, did I grow sad
naze kashira kanashiku natte
when once I looked up at the sky alone
hitori de miageta sora
This deeply blue sky
tottemo aoi sora
The sky let us listen
sora wa kikasete kureta
to the song of clouds undefeated by the wind
kaze ni mo makenai kumo no uta
so that we would no longer weep when alone
hitori demo mou nakanai you ni
Short Thoughts
It is a big deal.
I'm a graduation photo.
When someone sees a photo
and says you were cute,
doesn't it make you think,
"So I'm not cute now?"
The next episode of
Nichijou is episode 24.
Narration:     Horie Yui
Don't miss it.