Hey, wasn't Sasahara sleeping?
Yeah, he was.
His arms were still
perfectly crossed.
Misato, why don't
you go wake him?
What?
Sasahara forgot we're
changing classrooms.
Wh-what are you
trying to say?
Why can't we just leave him?
I'd feel sorry for him...
Aren't you childhood friends?
Go on, already.
Besides, Sasahara's probably
alone in the classroom right now.
Huh? Wh-what...
We'll catch you later.
Good luck!
Hey, wait!
Why do I  have do this for him?
So what if we're childhood...
Why don't you confess
your love to Sasahara?
The best friendship, everything is perfect!
joujou yuujou! banji maji kaichou!
Yes, I'll say it, you're my best friend!
hai icchaimashou kimi wa Best Best Friend!
If you try being annoying
chotto fuzakete mitara
Then I'll be more annoying in return
motto fuzakekaeshitekuru
igokochi ii ttara aryashinai!
If I speak of comfort, it goes away
I had things I hated
iyana koto attatte
But I forgot them in one swift stroke
sokkoo wasurechaunda
Let's go do something non-stop!
itsudatte janjan yarimashou!
We can be together 24/7!
nijyuuyo jikan isshodemo mondainai
marude futago ka oyako ka kuroon saibou
Almost like twins, a parent and a child or cloned cells!
Isn't it not unnecessary to love, then?
kore ja ren'ai suru hitsuyou toka nakunakunai?
sore to kore to wa mattaku mattaku betsumondai!!
Those are totally different things!
Even when we fought
kenka shichatta toki mo
Even when we felt really blue
kanari hekonda toki mo
Even when we want to be alone
hitori de itai yo na toki mo
futo kizukeba chikaku ni iru
We are next to each other
shinaba morotomo
Until death do us part
nande daro
Why, I wonder?
I want to be by your side
soba ni itainda
kimi to isshonara
When I'm with you
Time flies a hundred times as fast
tokei hyakubaisoku
It's so much fun
tanoshii na
It's too much fun
tanoshisugirunda
Always the same, with my best friend!
sasuga saikyou Friend! Hey!
What is it?
nan nanoyo
Man, I feel we're synchronized!
yabbai shinkurokan!
What is it?
nan nanoyo
yabbai shinkurokan!
Man, I feel we're synchronized!
Always such a rage
itsumo oosawagi
Annoying everyone around us
kanari gokinjo meiwaku
What time is it?
ima nanji?
Let's see, yodelayheehoo!
tatoe yororeihi
What are you talking about?
wake wakannainai!
What am I going to do?
so-re-do-shi-ra-
More than imagination!
souzou ijou!
What should I say, awesome!
nante iu ka saikou!
a-dako-da ittetemo tomodachi
Whatever you say, we're friends!
Hooray!
wasshoi!
The best friendship!
joujou yuujou!
Everything is perfect!
banji maji kaichou!
Sasahara!
Why are you sleeping when we have to change classrooms?
Ah, Tachibana Misato.
G-gather up
your textbooks!
I see...
I had merely intended to
rest my eyes for a moment,
but I fell into a deep slumber.
Just hurry up...
If we show up late together,
people will get the wrong idea.
The wrong idea? About what?
Sh-shut up!
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 106
N-no! I mean, those just
happened to be there...
It's your fault for taking so long.
Tachibana Misato.
Your hand is bleeding.
Wh-why are you acting so nice?
Shouldn't you be more worried
about your glasses than my hand?
Why? Glasses feel no pain
when they're broken,
but hands feel pain
when they're cut.
Wh-what are you talking
about? That's obvious!
You think you're clever?
Fortunately, one of the
lenses is still intact.
These glasses are just
like an old veteran.
What a frail veteran...
So frail.
Let's go.
Tachibana Misato...
I know!
I know it was my fault.
Give Walking
a Chance
I still don't think it's cool, so...
Exactly. Then...
They're staring at us!
I'm dying... I'm dying!
I'm so embarrassed, I could die!
But I broke his glasses,
so I have to be
Sasahara's eyes.
It's okay... It's okay.
If I explain that I broke his glasses,
everyone will understand
that I'm just helping him.
That's all.
It's just my volunteer spirit that's
making me act as your eyes for the day.
Tachibana Misato.
Yes?
Before we arrive at the classroom, I'd like to visit the restroom.
What? The r-restroom...
You can't mean the men's room!
Indeed.
There's an obstacle already...
But it is my fault.
Overcoming this will
deepen our relationship.
Fine! I'll go with you!
Why?
Because your glasses are broken!
So?
Jeez, you're so slow!
You can't see,
so I'm acting as your
eyes for the day!
These are just for show.
Don't get the wrong idea!
I just tried to squish a bug that
happened to be on your right arm!
It's beautiful out today.
Nap
U-uh, there's a place with
spicy curry in Kamakura!
Curry
U-uh, there's a place with
spicy curry in Kamakura!
Ah, yes.
Curry
Ms. Sakurai, how spicy
do you like your curry?
Um, uh...
With zero spice.
M-me, too!
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 107
Um, Naganohara,
class starts soon...
Class starts soon.
Mio! Room LL isn't that way!
Room LL.
It's like, uh, you know!
In baseball, you never
know what's gonna happen!
That's why it's fun!
In baseball, you never
know what's gonna happen...
Anyway, she might not
even be his girlfriend.
Right, Nano?
Huh? Yes, that's true!
Sasahara is...
Sasahara...
Anyway, let's go back, Mio.
Mio!
Naganohara!
Nano, go to Room LL
and distract the teacher!
Right!
Mio, wait!
Mio! Watch out!
Mio!
Mio...
M-Mio!
Mio!
Mio...
Ready?
Mio!
I'm getting off.
M-Mio!
Mio!
Mio! Mio! Mio!
Mio! Mio!
M-Mio, Mio, Mio, Mio...
Mio, Mio, Mio, Mio!
Damn it!
O-Mio!
O-Mio...
Thanks...
Mio! Mio, are you okay?
Somehow.
I'm tired.
Mio.
Where is he?
Over here! Lil' Ma!
Osamu...
Oh, good. He's all right...
Are you okay?
Yeah, I think.
This person rescued me.
Y-you girls!
From that one time!
You girls should know that you
were interfering with police duties,
and it's a serious offense!
You girls? You mean me, too?
Normally, I'd contact
your school, but...
well, considering what
you did, I'll let it slide.
Really?
There you are...
I've finally found
you, pig-tailed girl.
When I saw your shadow
boxing, I realized something...
Well?
Would you like to...
take on the world with boxing?
Thief! Thief!
I've got to go!
Stop by the station later.
I'll give you a schedule
for the commendation!
You can have this.
Okay...
Osamu, it's okay, right?
Of course!
Why not come by my gym,
once things settle down?
We'll talk then.
Mio! Your English
textbook disappeared!
Mio?
I got rejected before
I even confessed...
saved a kid while running...
received a commendation and a kite...
and got scouted by a boxer.
I guess you never know
what's gonna happen.
It's just like you said, Yukko.
You never know
what's gonna happen...
that's why it's fun.
That's baseball, right?
Huh? What do you mean?
See?
Short Thoughts
Red bean soup is...
I realized that daydreaming is free.
Shoot, I lost sight of her.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 108
Shoot, I lost sight of her.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 108
I was watching
closely from school,
but I looked away for a
second, and she disappeared.
How unbelievably exceptional...
I must know your
secrets, Shinonome Nano.
I've come this far.
Should I look for something
that could be her home?
I guess tracking her too
far might be dangerous.
I'll give up for the day,
and follow her again tomorrow.
It's in plain sight!
I've already found her.
This has been my first stroke of luck since I began pursuing Shinonome.
No, "luck" doesn't
begin to describe it.
It's, um, what do you call it?
Well, whatever!
Why am I getting so worked up?
I wish to enter immediately
and see the laboratory.
I wish to see
Shinonome's creator.
I wish to steal their blueprints!
All this anticipation is making
my heart pound like a stampede!
Be still, my inner
cowboy, Bill Watts!
The home of Shinonome's
creator may contain traps.
I must approach cautiously.
I know... I'll just take a peek today.
May I help you?
Guinea!
Oh, no! A surveillance bot found me.
It looks rather cheap,
but it was made with the same
advanced technology as Shinonome.
I have to be careful.
I need to show it
I won't resist...
Oh, Ms. Nakamura.
Guinea!
Guidance Counselor's Office
I heard last week that you
carried an injured old lady
to the hospital with your goat.
I did.
Did you predict that an old lady would be
injured and decide to ride to school on a goat?
Say what you will.
For now it's as you say.
Here you are.
I was petrified.
I'm thrilled to have
accessed her home,
but I mustn't forget my situation.
She must be devising
a way to trick me.
For example, this tea...
It probably contains an
amnesia-inducing drug.
And eyes are watching me
from somewhere in this room.
Wh-wh-wh-what is that?
Its form is obviously bizarre!
It looks haphazardly placed, but it doesn't seem entirely harmless...
If I'm not careful, it'll get me!
What's wrong?
Sorry! It's nothing!
I drank it.
Oh, no! I can't believe I...
Was it too hot?
If she's going to
catch me anyway...
Allow me to be direct...
Huh? Uh, all right.
I've come to learn more
about you, Shinonome!
What?
I'd like to see the
real you! Is that okay?
Um, well... I think that's
an individual decision!
It's not normal
for girls to date,
and I think it's best to
stick with what's normal.
Don't be foolish!
That's not what I meant!
What are you thinking?
You're rather embarrassing, aren't you?
Sorry! I'm sorry!
I want to know more about...
Nano.
Professor!
What?
Nano, I finished my snacks.
Did she just say professor?
No... No, no, no.
You can't have any
more until tomorrow.
I must have misheard her.
You can't have any
more until tomorrow.
I must have misheard her.
What?
There's no way this
child created Shinonome.
What?
There's no way this
child created Shinonome.
Who's this?
There's no way this
child created Shinonome.
Who's this?
Perhaps she's
Shinonome's relative?
Who's this?
Perhaps she's
Shinonome's relative?
Ms. Nakamura, from school.
Perhaps she's
Shinonome's relative?
Ms. Nakamura, from school.
A younger sister?
Does that mean this
child is also a robot?
Hello, I'm the professor. I made Nano.
Shoulder Block!
Professor! Why did you say that?
Made her? This child
made Shinonome?
Professor! Why did you say that?
Made her? This child
made Shinonome?
I had to introduce myself...
Made her? This child
made Shinonome?
Hey!
Do something about this!
The kid did something again!
H-ho...
Homunculus!
The surveillance bot,
the strange Dharma,
the child professor, Shinonome Nano, and a homunculus...
Entering unarmed and
unprepared was foolish...
This place is extremely dangerous!
Professor, what kind of knot is this?
I must find an opportunity to
escape and form a new plan,
It's a tight, tight one.
I must find an opportunity to
escape and form a new plan,
Hey, are you done yet?
I must find an opportunity to
escape and form a new plan,
Hey, are you done yet?
but...
I'm worried about being attacked, so I must tread carefully.
If I simply tell
them I'm leaving...
I have no choice.
May I use your restroom?
Oh, yes. Let me show you...
No!
If you tell me where
it is, I'll find it myself!
You fell for it, Shinonome Nano.
I will escape.
I knew you'd believe what
I said without question.
Kindness is your weakness.
Next time I come, the winds
will blow against you.
Just you wait. As long as
you have that weakness,
I shall rise again!
Are you leaving?
Oh, no...
Uh, no... it's just, they
asked me to cut the grass...
Hold on!
Wh-what...
Oh, no! I've been discovered!
They knew I would try to escape...
Damn it! What is this?
My body... I can't move!
This way!
Huh? I thought she had
to use the restroom.
What is this?
Professor, this glue
dissolves in water, right?
If I'm captured now, it's all over.
What?
Water! Water!
My hopes! My reason to live!
What? I can't hear you.
Damn. I must do something...
Damn you, Shinonome Laboratory!
Take this off first!
Nano, snacks.
Damn you, Shinonome Laboratory!
Water! Water!
Someone... someone help me!
What should I do?
No Impermanence of Living Things
No Killing of Living Things
Oh, I have that.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 109
Oh, I have that.
Nichijou:
Everyday Life
Part 109
Really? Could I borrow it?
Sure. I'll bring it next time.
Thanks. I'm excited.
"You never know what's
gonna happen. That's baseball."
Annaka, I didn't know you
were such a maniac.
Is that all?
Annaka, I didn't know you
were such a maniac.
Yeah. Suddenly, she started
laughing, and she cheered up.
Maybe she's just
pretending to be happy.
The one she's always
loved broke her heart...
I guess I can see that.
No, my interests are
still pretty shallow.
Which?
No, my interests are
still pretty shallow.
Which?
Yukko, did you forget
your homework again?
No!
Oh, but I really did
forget my homework.
Which is it?
The answer...
after this commercial break!
What?
How funny, Aioi!
Right, Minakami?
Fleming?
Rap?
Naganohara, I wanted to
ask you something else...
S-sure.
What is it?
Doesn't that series
have a few spin-offs?
Aioi, do you have any ideas
for cheering up Naganohara?
If you have any, could
I borrow them, too?
Why did they leave?
I wanted to get something
to eat with them...
What are you doing?
Congratulations!
Have a lottery ticket.
What are you doing?
You're Yukko, aren't you?
Yukko? Who's that?
It's obviously you.
And Nano, I can see your key.
I-it's not robot-like in any way!
In any case, those who pass
here must enter the lottery!
Come on, hurry up! Hurry!
I don't understand you...
Do I just turn this?
Congratulations.
Why are you being so loud?
Here's your prize!
What is it?
Just take it!
What?
I'm always saying that your
ideas aren't very funny...
Once you've received your
prize, be on your way.
Thank you very much.
An extra prize...
I just carved it.
Thanks...
I once overheard Sasahara
talking to someone...
Our everyday lives may, in fact,
be a series of miracles.
They just may be...
No, I believe they must be...
Voucher for a Life-long Friendship
Aioi     Shinonome     Minakami
Okay! Let's go home
and draw some comics!
Let's search for tomorrow in this big, wide world
ashita wo sagasou kono hiroi sekai de
Now is the time! Come, everyone, let's set out together!
ima koso sono toki saa minna de tabidatou
We have limitless hope for tomorrow
ashita he no kagiri nai kitai fukuramasete
and for our hopes and dreams
bokutachi no subarashii kibou to yume wo
Let's search for tomorrow
search for tomorrow
in this big, wide world
kono hiroi sekai de
Love-like
I don't believe it...
It's your fault we're lost!
I apologize.
Shall I look up our location
on my mobile phone?
You sound like a foreigner.
Call it a cell phone!
Why are you watching that?
Tachibana Misato,
why not watch it with me?
I'm not into that!
I'm Nano's key.
Sometimes, I spin.
Sometimes, I don't.
Sometimes, I come off.
That's my life.
The next episode of
Nichijou is the final one.
Narration:      Yokozawa Keiko
Don't miss it.