Birthday
Hey, listen.
We should have a
birthday party for Nano!
Good idea. When?
Today.
Today?!
Don't tell me these
things at the last minute.
Sorry.
What are we going to do?
I don't have anything prepared.
Well, it's not like it's really
Nano's birthday today.
You didn't ask her?
That's right.
What's right?
It's a surprise!
What do you mean?
The professor...
Let's celebrate the professor's
birthday, as well.
Good idea! We'll kill
two birds with one stone!
Let's do it!
Well, good surprises are
fun to give and receive...
All right, I've got it!
Let's buy a cake
on the way home!
All right!
Mai, are you okay with that?
I forgot my coin purse.
Oh, well. I guess Yukko and I will...
I forgot my wallet, too.
Mio, please!
I still haven't returned the money I lost at the amusement park...
I guess I'll give it back today.
I'll go tell Nano we're
celebrating her birthday!
What happened to the surprise?
You're such an idiot...
But Sasahara rejected you...
He didn't reject me!
But you ran away in tears...
Oh, that was...
I mean, just because
their arms were linked
doesn't mean they're dating!
I haven't asked him about it yet!
So it's not like he
rejected me at all!
So I haven't given
up on him at all!
I still totally like him!
Forget I said that!
Got it?
Okay!
I haven't forgotten anything.
Nichijou:
My Ordinary
Life, Part 110
Professor, I'll see you later.
Nano!
Wh-wh-what's wrong, Professor?
I just made a little
one, so I'll go get it.
Professor, what do you
mean by "a little one"?
The little one's, um...
Will my back be smooth?
It will...
But the little one is...
Nano.
Yes!
It's gone.
Nano, it'll be okay! Nano!
What are you shouting about
so early in the morning?
Kid! Why did you
set a trap here?
Sakamoto broke the little one!
Huh? Uh... no!
No, um...
Sakamoto, you made Nano cry!
No, no, no! It's your fault
for leaving it on the floor!
I'm going to school...
Nano, you forgot something...
Nano.
I can make a new one in no time.
Can you make it by
the time I get home?
I can make a new one
in no time, so...
Professor!
I'm going to school!
Okay!
See you later!
See you later...
Principal
Oh? How strange...
The Principal and
the Vice-Principal
Vice-Principal!
This statue was here
when I was principal...
How strange. Principal
Shinonome's statue should be here.
The pranks kids play these days
are so humorous and mischievous...
Or perhaps...
Could it be that I have advocates?
Vice-Principal, I brought the delivery.
Is this where you wanted the statue?
Oh, um... I didn't...
Vice-Principal, is this...
Kids play such elaborate
jokes these days...
I-I'm sorry, but could you
take this statue away?
What?
You want me to cart
this cheap one away?
Cheap?!
Got it! I'll remove this
dull-looking one, too!
Dull!
Hey! He wants us to
take this lame one, too!
There, there, Vice-Principal...
don't let it get to you.
I'll take this and the gross one
away on the double!
What?
Go Soccer Club,
Part 8
Huh? It's unlocked...
You're here, Sekiguchi?
I wanted to get here first,
so I had the Blackbird rush me here.
What? Do you practice
in the mornings, too?
Um...
Uh... Um...
Yes...
Seriously?
Nichijou:
My Ordinary
Life, Part 111
I can't believe I have to
buy lunch for both of you...
Sorry.
Well, there's no way around it
if you don't have your wallet...
That's Mio for you!
So generous!
Are you okay?
Yukko, you hit too hard!
Sorry, sorry.
Sorry, Mai!
I'm fine...
By the way, Yukko, did you ask
Nano if we could visit her today?
I completely forgot!
Okay! I'll go tell her we're
celebrating her birthday!
Don't do that!
Just ask if we can
come over today!
I know.
No, you don't!
I'll do it!
I said I'd go.
No, I'll go!
I'll go.
No, me!
Hey! Mai, Mai!
A moment, please!
Just a moment, please!
Okay, I'll go talk to Nano.
Better late than never!
Ow!
Sorry!
Don't worry about it.
Go.
I'm really sorry! Sorry!
I accidentally picked black coffee...
Sorry!
It's okay. Sorry.
I'm really sorry!
A
Winner
Free
Another
Get
If 'Winner' Appears,
Aioi! Quiet in the hallway!
Rainbow.
I found it!
Ouch...
Aioi, are you okay?
Nano, I've been looking for you.
What? Really?
Yeah, actually...
Uh, this is just...
Are you okay? Did that hurt?
Uh, no. I'm fine...
Oh, good...
So, this isn't what you think. It's just...
Hey, forget that. Can we come
over to your house today?
Huh? Uh, yes.
Oh, right...
It's a surprise, so I can't explain.
Uh, um...
See you later.
Okay.
Maybe I'll buy some
for Aioi and the others.
First comes rock!
Then comes paper.
You can't throw all of them,
Rock, paper, scissors!
What's going on?
Nichijou:
My Ordinary
Life, Part 112
This pumpkin...
is really hard!
That brat...
why does she always...
Boss!
Is that you, Boss?
Na-Nakamura!
I've been looking
for you, Boss!
I'm glad you're...
Why are you running away?
Have you forgotten me?
I'm running because
I haven't forgotten!
Boss, it's dinner time.
Here.
What's wrong, Boss?
You're not going to eat?
It's bath time.
There you go...
Boss!
Cats
with
Living
Shoot. If I don't
hurry, I'll be late.
Boss, I'll see you later.
Shoot.
Boss!
Come here, Boss!
Just leave, already!
Ms. Nakamura?
Hello.
Shinonome!
Girl, do something!
What's wrong?
You seem to be
looking for something.
This robot really does
throw herself into danger.
You seem to be
looking for something.
This robot really does
throw herself into danger.
But I can see Shinonome
at school any time.
Right now, Boss comes first!
Excuse me, Shinonome.
Have you seen a black cat?
Ms. Nakamura,
you have a black cat?
Yeah. But he ran away...
I have a black cat, too!
Really...
May I help you look?
Oh, thanks, Shinonome.
It's no problem.
Are you stupid?
Oh, Ms. Nakamura.
What's your cat's name?
It's Boss.
What an interesting name.
Our cat is called
Mr. Sakamoto.
What an unusual name.
It really is, isn't it?
Is he cute?
Is Boss cute?
What are you saying?
Well, it's not like
Nakamura meant any harm...
but I'd never
survive in her care.
Memories of Nakamura's
Poor Care
but I'd never
survive in her care.
No, hold on...
Memories of Nakamura's
Poor Care
No, hold on...
That's not any different
from how things are now, is it?
Memories of the Kid's Pranks
That's not any different
from how things are now, is it?
The scale won't budge.
It's already this late?
I'm sorry, Ms. Nakamura.
I've got to get going,
or the groceries...
Oh, I see...
If you find him,
can I come see Boss?
Yes, please do!
You can come any time!
Come tomorrow!
Please excuse me.
Sure!
Damn it! My life sucks,
no matter where I go!
Nichijou:
My Ordinary
Life, Part 113
Professor! Mr. Sakamoto! I'm home.
Nano,
it's the little one!
You made it, professor?
Sakamoto stepped on it again!
Mr. Sakamoto...
Huh?
Are you sure you
want to remove it?
I'll make a new one right away!
Professor!
I never knew it
came off so easily.
I could never get it off myself...
That's because you
can't remove it yourself,
but other people can.
I see.
But even you can
put it back on!
What an unbelievable design...
By the way, Professor, what
functions does that little one have?
If I remove this, your big toe
won't come off any more.
I have a function
like that, don't I?
Could that be Aioi
and the others?
Yukko?
Hooray, it's Yukko!
Oh, right. I should
put this key away...
Now I finally look
like a normal person.
I wonder if I'll become
even closer with everyone.
Maybe I'll get to go out
with everyone more,
and live a more fun
and ordinary life!
Hey, forget that. Can we come
over to your house today?
Because it's cute.
Nano, you're just Nano.
Isn't that enough?
I just came here
to tell you that.
But I forgot all about it.
Nano.
Girl.
Shh! Quiet!
This is important!
I know, I know!
Ready, and...
Nano.
Ta-dah! Happy birthday!
We bought you a cake!
Aioi...
Happy birthday... huh? Why?
It's a surprise, a surprise.
Cake! I want cake!
Cake, cake, cake, cake!
Wait, Professor!
You're pulling too much!
Cake, cake, cake, cake!
Wait, Professor...
Now, now, Professor...
Cake, cake, cake, cake!
Unbelievable!
The cake...
What are we going
to do? Uh, um, uh...
I have another...
Mai...
What is that?
Hooray!
What? One more time!
But how did everyone
know it was my birthday?
Nano's
Birthday
Nano!
I made the little one!
Professor...
This key has certainly
been inconvenient,
and I really did want
to remove it, but...
I prefer things the way they are!
What?
This little one spins
when you're really happy!
What kind of key is that?
Oh, right.
Professor, could you
take this cake out?
More cake!
I'm going to bring out some tea.
Okay!
Cake, cake, cake, cake!
Professor?
Cake!
What are you two doing?
Cake, cake!
Aioi, are you okay?
Nano, get something to wipe this!
Okay!
Put a candle here...
No fair! I want to do it, too!
Mai, we have to clean it up first!
Something to wipe it,
something to wipe it...
Mai!
Uh, um, uh...
One more...
Stop it! We have to clean this!
Mai, stop, stop!
Uh, um, uh...
What is this? What is this?
Thank you...
The mountain ranges burn under the glaring light
shiroi hikari no naka ni yamanami wa moete
You fly to the farthest reaches of the sky
haruka na sora no hate made mo kimi wa tobidatsu
The endless blue of the sky shakes you
kagirinaku aoi sora ni kokoro furuwase
Fly, bird! You fly through freedom! Do not look back!
jiyuu wo kakeru tori yo furikaeru koto mo sezu
Put courage into your wings, ride the winds of hope
yuuki wo tsubasa ni komete kibou no kaze ni nori
and entrust your dreams to this vast sky
kono hiroi oozora ni yume wo takushite
Motivation
What's wrong, Mio?
I can't stop sneezing.
What are you talking about?
Will those sneezes away.
And what do I do until
they're willed away?
Just stop them!
That's impossible.
What a simple moron.