What?!
Sanae Mizuno, was it?
She and Kouchi often talked
about books together.
She was so young...
I worry about her brothers.
Oh, she had brothers?
One is named Takeru.
He's in my class.
Dear me, this is so awful.
Didn't a girl in your class
recently die in an accident, too?
After a death, there always follows a funeral.
How very tired I am of funerals...
So very tired of funerals...
June 4 (Thurs.)
The news about Mizuno's
sister comes as a terrible shock,
but it will be all right.
If we all try hard together,
we can overcome this.
So...
She died.
Mizuno's sister died in
an accident yesterday.
Oh...
Self-Study - Sketching
I wonder what's wrong
with Ms. Mikami.
Maybe she's really sick.
She didn't look too well.
I hope she doesn't...
Hey, Sakakibara?
Yeah?
You don't think Ms. Mikami
has some serious,
life-threatening illness, do you?
I'm sure she's fine.
You're probably right.
Are you that worried?
Well, after what happened
to Sakuragi...
And now Mizuno's sister...
So I just...
Are they related?
Is there a connection
between these accidents?
Um, I don't...
Where are you going?
To do some research.
Yomiyama Prefectural Junior High School
Class of 1972
Who am I kidding?
Of course I wouldn't find Misaki's name here.
Mom...
You found your mother?
Yes.
Interesting... So she graduated in '72.
Which class was she in?
Class 3, like me.
Oh? Which one is she?
This one.
Ritsuko?
You knew her?
Yes.
Ritsuko was...
But...
I heard that she died. When was that?
15 years ago, right after she had me.
15 years ago?
I see...
So that's what happened.
Kouichi.
Mr. Kubodera asked me to send
you to the faculty room.
Okay, thanks.
Let me apologize in advance.
I'm sorry.
But this is for all of us.
Forgive us.
You are aware that Sanae Mizuno
passed away in an accident at
the hospital yesterday, yes?
Yes.
Um, am I suspected of something?
Oh, no. We know it was an accident.
A very unfortunate accident.
It's just, Ms. Mizuno's cell phone was
found in the elevator in question.
Did you speak with her on the phone
around 1 p.m. yesterday?
Yes, I did.
She was on the roof at the time, correct?
And she entered the
elevator from there...
What caused the accident?
That's under investigation.
All we know for certain is that the
sheaves holding the cables
in place came loose, causing it to fall.
That building is several decades old,
and it's been through numerous
structural modifications.
Let's both be careful.
Especially where unusual
accidents are concerned.
Aya Ayano | Izumi Akazawa
Sakakibara.
Are the police finished questioning you?
Yes.
All right.
Then you're dismissed for the day.
Um, where is everyone?
The new female class officer
was selected during homeroom.
It's Akazawa.
But, where'd everybody go?
Please be sure to uphold
the class rules at all times.
Are we clear?
Who is dead?
Okay, sure.
Hey.
Walk home with me?
Where did everyone go
during sixth period?
To the meeting room,
to take care of some stuff.
What stuff?
You've had a lot of strange experiences
since you came here, haven't you?
If you know, can you tell me
what's going on?
Sorry, I can't.
Only, that something very unpleasant
might happen to you soon.
What do you mean?
At the meeting,
Akazawa said we needed
to discuss something,
without you there.
But even if you don't
like what happens,
try to deal with it.
Remember that you're doing it for all of us.
Please.
"All of us"?
This is for all of us.
Forgive us.
Is this one of those class rules?
Yeah.
I just don't get it...
Can I ask one favor?
What?
I want a copy of the class roster.
You didn't get one?
It's just not fair.
I can't agree with Akazawa's
way of handling things.
It's not fair of her to force her own ideas
on the rest of us.
There must be so many
things you want to know.
There are.
Then you can ask me.
I'll tell you everything I know.
Takabayashi, wait! Are you serious?
Okay.
Does Mei Misaki exist?
Mei Misaki is...
Takabayashi! Takabayashi!
Good morning. You're early today.
June 5 (Fri.)
That's it. Any other...
No, forget it.
Did something happen this morning?
Let us pray that the soul of
our classmate, Takabayashi,
may rest in peace.
Many sad events have transpired,
but do not lose heart,
and do not give up.
We'll get through this together.
Remember to uphold the
class rules at all times.
Ms. Mikami is in a difficult position,
but she has agreed to cooperate
to the best of her ability.
Does everyone understand?
Hey.
What's with him?
Hey, Wakui?
What's going on?
The customer you are trying
to reach currently
has their phone off or is
out of the service area.
Hey.
Listen...
Sorry.
Figures of Speech
Simile, Metaphor, Personification
"A rumor walks alone."
Here, we see something
that is not human
being expressed as
displaying human behavior.
This is known as personification.
The important thing to
understand is that
human attributes are given
to something non-human.
Pascal once said, "Man is but a
reed, but he is a thinking reed."
This is not personification.
So that's what they meant.
It is a metaphor.
Does that make sense?
Hi.
What's wrong?
Your call was unexpected.
Sorry. Ask Misaki to explain. -Mochizuki
24 Mei Misaki
So, you got a copy of the class roster.
And?
Let me start from the beginning.
Did you hear that Takabayashi died?
He had a heart attack.
I know he had heart problems, but...
I see.
The second June death
was caused by illness.
Then, when I got to school today,
the whole class was acting weird.
Like they'd all conspired to
treat me like I wasn't there.
So that's what they decided to do...
Does this mean I'm just like you now?
How does it feel to not exist?
Not so great.
But, in a way, it's a load off my mind.
It is?
Because now I know that you exist.
This is where you live, isn't it?
Yes.
I thought you figured
that out long ago.
You did say you lived around here.
And you're not a customer.
Was that your mother who
answered the phone?
She was surprised.
I very rarely get calls
from schoolmates.
Is Kirika your mom?
Yes. I guess you'd call it a pseudonym.
She goes by Kirika.
A strange woman,
who keeps herself cloistered
in the studio upstairs.
Does the "M" in "Studio M"
stand for Misaki?
It all makes sense now, doesn't it?
Let's go upstairs.
Did you know this was here?
Here you go.
Why don't you ask the questions?
It might be easier to explain
everything that way.
I thought you hated being questioned.
I do.
But today,
I'll make a special exception.
First of all, Mei Misaki,
you exist, right?
Did you think I was a ghost?
Sort of.
I guess you couldn't help it.
But your doubts are gone now, right?
Now that you know I exist,
as a living human.
I'm only nonexistent to
the others in class 3.
Since when?
It started on May 1.
That's pretty recent.
Lots of things seemed strange
to you from the start, right?
And nobody would tell me why.
Not explaining the situation
to you beforehand
was a costly mistake.
Mistake?
You were supposed to treat me
as someone who didn't exist,
just like everyone else in class.
But now you've ended up the same as me.
How awful for you.
It's not exactly bullying...
I don't think anybody thinks of it that way.
I understand that I
no longer exist to them.
But why are they doing this?
It's a natural question.
Remember the story about the
Misaki who died 26 years ago?
Yeah.
That was the trigger.
After that, class 3 drew closer to death.
Death?
It first happened to class 3
the year after Misaki's
classmates graduated.
And once it happens, once it begins,
somebody dies each month.
Either a student, or
someone from their family.
What is "it"?
It's when...
...the number of students in
the class increases by one.
Increases? Who?
Nobody knows.
They can never figure out
who the extra one is.
Extra one?
25 years ago, shortly
after the new term began,
they realized that the classroom
was short one desk and chair,
even though they had prepared enough
for all of the students.
Couldn't they just check
the school records?
They did, but there was no point.
The roster and records had been
altered to be inconsistent.
They were just one
desk and chair short.
So, someone rewrote the numbers?
I used the word "altered" figuratively.
They say that everyone's
memories had changed as well.
Huh?
Sounds impossible, doesn't it?
But it's supposedly true.
I was told this type of
phenomenon could happen.
Phenomenon?
At first, everyone thought
it was just an error
and thought nothing of it.
But starting in April,
people connected to the class
started to die each month.
Each month?
For the whole year?
That year, I think it was six students
and ten family members.
Clearly abnormal, right?
This phenomenon has continued
in class 3 ever since.
So, a 9th grade class 3 student
named Misaki died 26 years ago.
And starting the next year,
there was somehow an extra
student in the class.
Then, people connected to the
class started to die each month.
But why do people die when
there's an extra student?
Nobody knows the reason.
That's just what happens.
Plus, that extra student is...
...someone dead.
You mean the Misaki who
died 26 years ago?
Who is dead?
Is it a ghost or something?
I think it's different from
what we'd call a ghost.
It seems to have a physical body.
There's no way to tell it apart
from the rest of us.
No way to tell?
The dead person has
a soul and memories,
and they don't realize they're dead.
Who are they?
The people connected to the class
who have died over the years.
This is how I see it.
Class 3's actions 26 years ago
made the class a place
that invites the dead in.
After that, the dead
began to join the class,
and class 3 drew closer to death.
In response,
the class 3 students
came up with several
countermeasures to try
to escape this calamity.
Like exorcisms?
Possibly.
They tried moving to a
different classroom,
and changing the name of
class 3 to class C.
But that didn't stop it.
So the problem is with the students
in the 9th grade's third class?
Seems to be.
Then, about ten years ago,
they found a way to
deal with the problem.
A method that prevented
people from dying each month.
Don't tell me...
Treat one student like they don't exist,
to make up for the extra person.
That way, they return the
class to its correct number,
and they can avoid the
calamity for that year.
It's a sort of charm.
Face to face.