This is my village.
It's a quiet, peaceful place.
But... sometimes I think...
Do I actually...
Ren-chon!
...live in the country?
Episode 1
A New Transfer Student Came
Mornin'!
Say again?
Meowning.
I still don't get it. What's that mean?
Meow... ning!
Meowning...
Is Koma-chan coming?
She left earlier.
Such a nice day, and we
have to go to school...
I'm still a bright, shiny first
grader, so I think it's fun.
That won't last long.
School life is tough, you know.
What with homework, tests, homework...
We had miso soup with horsetail
shoots this morning.
We had egg soup with horsetail
shoots and onions.
Run, Ren-chon!
Renge! Natsumi!
Nee-chan!
Nattsun, did you see the news today?
No, I was in a hurry.
I didn't, either.
Too bad. Today's news was exciting.
Did something happen?
There was an old guy doing radio calisthenics
outside the window behind the host.
It was really cool.
Why did that make you excited?
Asahigaoka Branch School
It's still kinda chilly.
The classroom feels different than yesterday.
How so?
Mornin'.
Take your seats.
Um...
Can you introduce yourself?
Ichijou...
Ichijou Hotaru
U-Um... I'm Ichijou Hotaru.
I moved here from Tokyo.
Wow! From Tokyo?!
That says "Hotaru"?
I never saw that character before.
What grade?
Fifth.
Younger? She's younger than me?!
She doesn't look like a fifth grader.
Did you get into trouble at your old school?
No, it's because of my dad's work.
Oh, well, that sounds normal.
Meowning!
M-Meow...
Have a seat.
Okay.
Oh, that's it. There's an extra seat.
You just noticed?
Nice to meet you, Hotarun.
Hotarun...
What's first period again?
Japanese.
Complete Training Guide
Grade 7 Japanese Review Drills
Grade 8 Japanese Review Drills
Japanese Drills by Repetition
Oh, everyone's in a different year?
I'm in first grade.
I'm in eighth.
I'm in seventh.
And Nii-chan here is in ninth.
But you're all in the same classroom?
Yeah.
All different classes, too?
What do you mean, different classes?
This is the only class.
There are only four students
in the whole school?
Five, now that you're here.
Since we're all in different grades,
we mostly just study on our own.
On your own?
Didn't you get a workbook?
Oh, I did...
Grade 8 Class 1
+ Grade 1
+ Grade 7
+ Grade 9
Well, what should we do?
I think...
Dodge ball! I'm good at dodge ball!
Dodge ball, huh?
Um...
I wondered when I was on my
way to the classroom, too...
What are those buckets for?
Oh, they're just to catch leaks.
So try not to get too close to them.
I see.
It'd be a pain if a bucket got moved and
we couldn't tell where the leak was.
No, that's not why.
The floor around them is
rotten from the moisture.
If you get too close, you'll fall through.
What?!
I'm just kidding.
No idiot has ever fallen
through the floor before.
We're just supposed to be careful.
I see...
Here it comes!
Take that!
Darn it!
Huh?
Hotarun!
Hotarun's out.
I shouldn't have tried to catch it...
There's a key on the ground.
Oh, that's mine.
A key? To what?
What's up?
No one in my family will
be home until tonight,
so I brought a house key.
Ren-chon, do you lock your house door?
No.
Nee-chan, ours don't lock either, do they?
I've never even seen a lock.
Me, either...
You're unusual.
Then, what should I use my key for?
Filleting mackerel?
Finally done!
Let's head home.
Hotarun!
Want to come to my house?
You don't want to?
Oh, sure.
Just for a little while.
Those are tangerine trees.
The new blossoms are just coming out.
You grow tangerines here?
Also rice and vegetables, mainly.
Oh, and leaves.
Leaves?
The kind you garnish food with.
Um, do you have any stores?
There's a co-op and a candy store.
Um, any others?
The police box?
That's not a store.
Is there a bookstore?
The candy store sells magazines.
They come in two days late, though.
So... no convenience stores, either?
I've seen commercials about them!
Cattle Crossing
Cattle?
And sometimes deer.
And boars.
What's wrong?
I was just thinking it's nothing like Tokyo...
Guess it's still too early
to put the kotatsu away.
You noticed the door wasn't locked, right?
Yes.
My mom and dad are out in the fields today.
Nee-chan, grab that for me.
Can't you get it yourself?
Here.
Thanks.
What's this about, Ren-chon?
I'm gonna show Hotarun
my special talent!
No sound's coming out.
Still no sound coming out...
Whoa, something came out!
A tanuki!
You have a pet tanuki?
And the tanuki actually heard that?
I gave it a name, too.
What kind of name?
Gu!
Gu's Dish
Oh! A psychedelic name!
And if I whistle again, Gu will do a trick!
Seriously?!
It made a sound this time!
What's Gu gonna do?!
Ren-chon!
Morning!
Ren-chon?
Nattsun...
Do we live in the country?
Where's this coming from?
Hotarun was really surprised.
Having all different grades in
one classroom, and the tanuki...
Nee-nee told me that if you drive
a car at fifty kilometers per hour,
you'll get to a place fifty
kilometers away in one hour,
and that's really amazing.
I see.
Just so you know, if you drive
fifty kilometers per hour,
you can't get to a place fifty kilometers
away in one hour because of traffic lights.
Yeah... I knew that.
But even in Tokyo,
I'm sure there are places with combined elementary and middle schools,
even if they're not in the same room.
And there are no traffic
lights on the highway.
It doesn't mean we live in the country.
Hotarun, hello!
Morning!
Meowning.
Good morning.
Ren-chon?
But a tanuki lives at my house,
so I think we're in the country...
You're still talking about that?
What were you talking about?
Whether we live in the country or not.
Is this really the country?
If you think about it logically...
Nah, just because we live here,
that doesn't mean it's the country.
You already sound like a country girl.
But even in Tokyo,
monkeys randomly show up.
So just because a tanuki shows up,
it doesn't mean this is the country, right?
Right?
Ah...
You really don't want this
to be the country, do you?
If living in the country means it's so
inconvenient you can't do anything,
just having cattle and tanuki doesn't
make anything inconvenient, right?
So this isn't the country.
I get it!
So, this isn't the country...
I think I feel better.
Glad to hear it!
What a good girl you are.
Let's eat!
This was made with the wild
plants we picked today.
Horsetail shoots, wild udo, and tara sprouts.
It's good!
It sort of tastes like spring!
Hotarun, save your
sakura mochi dessert.
How far are we going?
We're almost there.
Hotarun!
Good, isn't it?
Yes, delicious!
We'll bring you here again.
Grade 8 Class 1
+ Grade 1
+ Grade 7
+ Grade 9
+ Grade 5
Wait!
We took it too slow...
By the way, when does the next bus come?
In two hours.
What?!
Man, buses in the country
are so inconvenient.
I knew it!
That's all for today
Anyone want to go play ball?
I do!
Besides, that flan was mine!
One bite of flan is the same
size as a piece of candy!
A candy store with Senpai...
10,000 yen?!
Episode 2
We Went to the Candy Store
Restaurant Non Non
Please Watch Again
Photo by:
Wanpasu
Come see us again!