My name is Ichijou Hotaru.
I'm in fifth grade.
Grade 8 Class 1
+Grade 1
+Grade 7
+Grade 9
+Grade 5
I used to go to school in Tokyo,
but my parents had to move,
so I transferred to this school.
And it seems,
when I begin life in a new place,
my school environment changes, too.
The first change is:
These are the only students
in the whole school.
Just five of us.
The second is:
There are elementary and middle school
students mixed into one class.
The third is:
Since we're in different grades,
we mostly study on our own in class.
That's probably why our teacher is...
...sleeping.
Why is this cat square?
Episode 2
We Went to the Candy Store
Now, I'll introduce the other
students at this school.
I finished my worksheet!
This is the first grader, Renge-chan.
I can't figure this one out at all...
This is the seventh grader, Natsumi-senpai.
And this is Natsumi-senpai's older sister,
the eighth grader, Komari-senpai.
Nee-chan, do you understand this question?
If you do, can you do it for me?
Why should I?
And this is the ninth grader, Suguru-senpai.
He's Natsumi-senpai and
Komari-senpai's brother.
Do I take this to the
teacher when I'm done?
Yeah. After you turn it in,
you can start lunch break.
Okay, I'll take it!
The teacher, Miyauchi-sensei,
is Renge-chan's sister.
Nee-nee, I'm done!
Oh, you're done, huh?
There! Break time!
It's no use. I just don't get it.
I'm gonna miss lunch break at this rate.
I'm done for...
As long as I'm done, I should take my break.
So can I start my break now?
What are you talking about?
Well, if you admit that you're
finished as a human being,
I can't stop you.
But you should think long and
hard about that before you act.
"Think long and hard," she says...
Anyone want to go play ball?
I do!
You haven't thought about anything.
Hey! No running in the hall!
Okay.
Honestly...
Komari-senpai's nickname is Koma-chan.
That nickname was taken...
...not from her name,
but from her size.
Komai means small.
At first, I just thought of
her as a small senpai.
Oh, Hotaru, what's our next class?
I think it's art.
But now I think she's so cute, I can't stand it!
Senpai's looking at me!
I just want to pet that little head.
I bet it's so soft...
She has her hand on her cheek...
Does she have a toothache?
Aww, what are you doing, Koma-chan?
We set that trap to drop
the eraser on Sensei.
The eraser's sitting right
on top of her head.
Your hair's white now, Koma-chan.
Don't call me Koma-chan!
Why are you more mad about
that than about the eraser?
I'm your older sister!
I'm the oldest one here!
Call me Onee-san!
Okay, I get it. Relax. Chop.
Why are you hitting me?!
I'm not the one who did something dumb!
Apologize to your big sister!
For the eraser, too! On your knees!
'Cause even if you are my older
sister, you don't look it.
Apologizing for the eraser comes second?
Come on, both of you, calm down.
Natsumi-senpai, you shouldn't pick
on Koma-chan-senpai so much.
I wasn't trying to pick on Koma-chan...
Koma-chan, fight!
Don't call me Koma-chan!
Koma-ch—
I mean, Senpai... I'll get
the chalk out of your hair.
Huh? Would this be petting her head?
Don't rub chalk into my Koma-chan!
Y-You're mistaken!
On Duty:
Koshigaya
(younger)
Man, that was terrible.
Candy...
Stare.
Lucky. You have candy.
You sniffed it out fast...
Huh? What's up?
I found candy. The new milk cola flavor.
You hyenas...
You shouldn't bring candy
to school, Koma-chan.
I told you, don't call me Koma-chan!
I bought it at the candy store yesterday
and forgot to take it out of my bag.
I'm in eighth grade now, you know.
I've gotta keep up with the
trends, as a grown woman.
What good does it do to keep
up with candy store trends?
Who cares about that? I want candy!
Oh! Me, too! Me, too!
What?!
No way! Not after what you said before!
Huh? I didn't do it on purpose.
Yeah! Yeah! That's right!
Before I'd give this to you guys...
Hotaru, I'll give it to you.
What? But...
Are you sure?
Yeah!
Here!
Hey! Give me some!
Give me some!
Shut up!
Gimme! Gimme!
Candy! I want candy!
Senpai gave me something
for the first time!
It's just candy...
But I'm so happy!
Why does this make me so happy?
I won't eat this.
I'll keep it in my desk drawer.
Ren-chon, Ren-chon...
Let's nail Koma-chan by
turning on the waterworks.
Then maybe she'll give us candy.
What?!
Koma-chan, Koma-chan.
Don't call me Koma-ch—
We've known each other for
a long time, haven't we?
What's all this?!
It was so much fun...
...when we wrote those cool words on
your forehead while you were asleep.
It wasn't fun for me!
And I gave you a bite of my flan yesterday.
Just one bite!
Besides, that flan was mine!
One bite of flan is the same
size as a piece of candy!
I guess that's true.
I love simple-minded girls.
Yay! Candy! Yay! Candy!
Hotaru, they're being a pain,
so could I have the candy ba—
B-But...
I... I was so happy to get candy from you...
Er, well, it's not like we wanted it that bad...
U-Um... Hotaru-sama?
We can't beat those waterworks.
Go ahead and keep it.
Yay! Yay!
I don't really get how, but I just got candy!
I never thought something
so wonderful could happen!
Hooray for candy!
I hope this feeling will reach Senpai someday!
Was it a good idea to give her
candy if she has a toothache?
Hotarun has a toothache?
I don't know.
Hotaru.
Yes?
Phone call from your friend.
My friend?
Who's "my friend"?
Hello?
Hello, Hotaru?
It's me, Komari.
S-Sorry!
It's the first time you've called me,
and I was so surprised I dropped the phone.
Did you need something?
No, it's nothing important,
but I'm close to your house,
and thought I'd call to see if
you wanted to hang out. Yeah.
I do! I do! Yes!
Okay, I'll be around the
phone booth near your place.
Got it!
See you soon, then.
Okay!
Uh, you can hang up first.
I'm going to hang out with Senpai...
What am I gonna do?!
I have to fix my hair!
And I should at least wear lipstick...
Mom! Do you have any nice clothes?
What about the ones you just bought?
I want something more grown-up!
Jeez...
I bought this grown-up dress,
and Natsumi and Renge don't even care.
They're both useless.
S-Sorry!
Sorry to keep you waiting!
So, where should we...?
I-Is something wrong?
Wh-Who is this lady?!
Um, I still don't know this town very well,
so I'd appreciate it if you
could show me around...
W-Wait, you mean you're from out of town?
Yes... From Tokyo.
I get it. She's here from Tokyo, and she's lost?
Um, where would you like to go?
W-Well, I...
I'd like to visit the candy store.
You came all the way from Tokyo
and you pick a candy store?!
W-We can't?
Uh, no, I didn't mean that!
Th-Then let's hurry!
U-Um...
I have to wait for Hotaru
so I can show her around...
I'll have to handle this like a grown-up.
Uh, I'm sorry, but I'm actually...
Is something wrong?
Uh...
Like a grown-up... Like a grown-up...
Um...
My mom and sister told me not
to go anywhere with strangers!
D-Darn it!
That wasn't grown-up at all!
I agree with that...
But can we just go to
the candy store now?
Huh?
U-Um...
I...
I'm supposed to be waiting for someone...
W-Wait a second...
I ended up coming with her.
This is weird. I thought I told her no.
What the heck went wrong?
Um...
Where is the candy store, again?
Um, well...
If you go straight down this
road, there's a tunnel.
Once you go through that,
it'll be right in front of you.
A tunnel?
Is it safe for people to walk through it?
Oh, it's a small one that only locals use.
Oh...
I-Is this it?
Yes.
But it's pitch dark, even during the day.
If you're scared, there's a longer way around.
Of course, you want to go back, right?
If a ghost were to show up—
What?!
How can she have such a relaxed
smile in a scary tunnel like this?
Is this...
...what they call a grown-up's composure?
A candy store with Senpai...
Is that it over there?
The candy store!
I've never been to a real candy store before!
Really?
What should we buy?
Uh, I don't have very much money...
Let me buy you something.
To thank you for showing me the way.
O-Okay...
There's so much...
...candy!
Welcome.
H-Hello.
Hi.
Hey.
Let's see... What should I get?
Shaved Ice
Shaved ice already?
Hey, is shaved ice all right?
Uh, sure.
Then, two shaved ices, please.
What flavor would you like?
Condensed Milk - Green Tea & Red Bean - Strawberry - Lemon
Green tea and red bean.
Green tea and red bean?!
Got it.
Green Tea & Red Bean
700 yen
That's expensive!
I'll be paying with...
...a 10,000 yen bill.
10,000 yen?!
Is this...?
Is this what they call...
...grown-up shopping?!
I'm glad I saved my New Year's money!
Maybe it's a little too early in
the season for shaved ice?
Oh, no. It's warm today, anyway.
The green tea is bitter...
Do grown-ups always eat stuff like this?
I got carried away and bought the
bitter kind to show off to Senpai...
But even the bitter kind is
good if I'm with Senpai!
It looks delicious, but it's bitter.
It's bitter, but it looks delicious.
I guess you can't be a grown-up
if you can't eat bitter stuff?
It's so nice and peaceful.
I never lived anywhere
but in Tokyo before,
so I was really worried
about coming here.
But it's a nice place.
I see...
I guess grown-ups have a lot on their minds.
Thank you for everything today.
Oh, no, I should thank you.
Well, goodbye.
So that's... a grown woman...
Sh-Sh-Sh-
She's so cool!
So that's what happened.
I think that's the kind of
grown-up I'll try to become.
Yeah?
So, who was she, anyway?
I forgot to ask her name.
King General
Oh... Hotaru!
Hotaru, phone for you.
Okay!
Hello, Hotaru?
I'm sorry about today! I'm really sorry!
Huh?
That's all for today
Time for a fun, fun class outing!
Yeah. I'm laughing, all right.
Rice balls made by Senpai...
Of course I'm not scared!
Because your behavior is always so poor!
We're running away!
Episode 3
I Ran Away from Home with My Sister
Non Non Biyori
Photo by: Suginami Kenji
Please Watch Again