Today's our class outing!
Nee-chan, I came to help.
What do you want me to do?
Just make rice balls.
You don't need to come
up with any weird ideas.
All right, leave this to me.
Looks yummy.
Thanks.
My sister is a year older than me.
But she's short and clumsy,
so she can't get by without me.
I told you, don't come up with weird ideas!
All right! Russian rice balls!
Huh?
We put mustard in just one of them.
If you get lucky, you lose!
You're contradicting yourself now...
It's such a nice day.
Perfect weather for a class outing!
Episode 3
I Ran Away from Home with My Sister
Natsumi-senpai, what's that backpack for?
What're you talking about?
Our class outing is today.
What? I didn't know about that.
I only heard about it from Natsumi yesterday.
You and Nee-chan really ought
to listen to the teacher more.
And so, time for a fun, fun class outing!
Let the rice planting festival begin!
Today, you're going to help
plant rice in these fields.
Of course, these are actually
my family's rice fields...
Oh, it's not that we don't have
money to hire part-time help,
or that I just don't want to help my family.
That's not why I'm making my students work.
It's a class assignment to learn the value
of rice and have fun planting seeds.
Yes, uh...
Oh, are you upset that you weren't given
sufficient details about this trip beforehand?
Well, I meant to bring it
up yesterday, but I forgot.
I did tell Natsumi, though...
But when I told Ren-chon about this outing,
she was all excited and laughing!
Yeah. I'm laughing, all right.
Yeah!
Now, let the fun rice planting begin!
I forgot that she always makes us
help plant rice this time of year.
We have no choice.
Let's just get it over with,
eat our lunches, and go home.
I didn't bring a lunch...
Oh, if you don't mind rice balls,
I'll share the ones I made this morning.
Rice balls made by Senpai...
I'll work hard!
Hi-yah!
There.
And step, and step...
Ren-chon, stop!
You're stepping on the
seedling you just planted.
Oopsie.
You walk backwards,
planting the seedlings as you go.
Wow. The wisdom of the forefathers.
Don't call me a forefather.
Hi-yah!
What is this?
I wanted to go to a theme park!
I wanted to go to a zoo!
I wanted to go to an aquarium!
I at least wanted to ride the town's single-car
train with the manually operated doors!
I feel a little better.
But I still don't feel like planting rice.
You were there, Nii-chan?
The scarecrow's done!
I thought this would be funnier somehow.
Hey, Natsumi!
What? I'm not gonna plant rice.
I'm stuck in the mud and can't move.
What? What? What is this?
You actually got stuck?
How did you manage to get in that deep?
I wanna see an encore! Encore!
Stop laughing and help me!
I guess I'll have to.
You always get into these
messes when I'm not around.
You're stuck, too, aren't you?
I think I'm really in deep now...
Hotarun! Hotarun, help!
Rice balls... Rice balls... Senpai's rice balls...
She's been like that since I told her
I'd share my rice balls with her...
Does she like rice balls that much?!
We have no choice!
Use me as a stepping stone and save yourself!
But what will you do?
Trust me! I have strong legs!
Okay, hold on tight.
I'm never planting rice again.
You weren't in the first place.
Where's the teacher who
made us do this, anyway?
Yeah, machines beat manual labor any day!
Since I bought this,
I wanted to find out which was more efficient,
but the machine is way better!
Oh, you guys can go home.
Let's just eat lunch and go.
Um, can I have some, too?
Of course. I did promise.
Here.
It's delicious!
You really like rice balls, huh, Hotarun?
That's hot!
Blew up in your face, huh?
Finally got all the mud off.
No fair getting in the bath first, Nee-chan.
Shut up. I'm older, so it's my right.
What're you watching?
A lighthearted, emotional romance
movie from the rental store.
Tomorrow's the return date,
so I have to watch them all today.
Yeah, returning them is tough.
It's ten stations away.
If it's emotional, that must mean the hero or heroine dies of an illness.
Wasn't expecting a virus to
kill every single character...
I'm not sure how to feel now.
That's weird. It had good reviews.
I'm going to bed. Today wiped me out.
I'll go to bed after I watch all the rest.
You sure are uptight, Nee-chan.
Urban Legends
100 Scary Videos
You rented stuff like that, too?
I forgot.
But it's okay.
I couldn't handle this stuff when I was little...
Okay, goodnight.
...but I'm fourteen now.
Natsumi-chan's Room
Wh-What? Why are you in my room?
Your room is next door.
Y-Yeah, well...
The bugs sounded too loud from my room.
I know that. Your room's right next to mine.
Fine, I'll sleep in your room, then.
No, no, no.
You watched that horror video earlier.
Are you scared?
O-Of course I'm not scared!
I'm fourteen now, you know!
Ahh! There's something white behind you!
Kidding. It was just the screen door.
You really are scared!
You tried to talk big,
but you really are scared!
Did that scawy old ghosty
movie fwighten you?
Don't worry. Natsumi-chan ish here wif you.
Ow! The zipper on the pillow
cover hit me between the eyes!
My eyes! My eyes!
Settle down and go to sleep!
And set it to evening!
Evening?
The little light!
Oh...
But I can't sleep if it's not dark...
Oh, yeah.
I think I had an eye mask in this
treasure chest-slash-garbage bin.
Nee-chan, if you're scared of
the dark, you want a light?
I'm not scared, but bring it here anyway.
If you're scared,
I also have that Shokichi-san
doll you used to like.
I told you, I'm not scared!
Bring me Shokichi-san, though.
Just a sec...
Okay! Sorry for the... wait!
What's wrong, Nee-chan?
I just brought the lamp you asked for.
You really are scared, aren't you?
Shut up, stupid! Of course I'm not!
Fine, fine, but look.
Your bear's not in great shape.
Shokichi-san!
Why is my Shokichi-san in your room, anyway?!
I told you, he was in my
treasure chest-slash-garbage bin.
Don't just turn him into garbage!
Come to think of it,
I've been hearing a voice coming
from that drawer at night...
Saying stuff like "It's dark" and "Let me out."
It must be the curse of Shokichi-san.
Here you go. It's Shokichi-san.
What?! I can't get out of the futon!
It's dark!
You're so funny, Nee-chan.
Why are you being so condescending?!
No more. No more ghosts...
No more ghosts...
Don't wanna see any more...
Don't wanna hear any more...
There's no such thing as spirits
and the other world.
There's nothing to be scared of.
No such thing as ghosts...
Wait... If spirits and the
other world don't exist...
What happens after you die?
Hey, Nee-chan, if we don't have spirits,
does everything just go dark when we die?
No such thing as ghosts...
Just sleep.
Nee-chan! Wake up!
What? Natsumi's late?
She apparently had trouble getting to sleep.
So she's not a very reliable big sister,
but she can really be a good sport.
Like...
I'm telling you!
I didn't break it! It was a stray cat!
You gave me the same excuse when you broke that window before!
I mean it this time!
Nee-chan was playing catch with me!
She saw it, too!
Right? You saw it, right?
Uh...
Is that true?
W-Well...
Komari!
N-N—
You're trying to say "No," aren't you?
No!
No to what, Nee-chan?
Oh, yeah! The cat had chikuwa in its mouth!
Chikuwa?
I did leave some out so I
could use them for dinner,
but how do I know you didn't eat them?
Why can't you trust your own kid?!
Because your behavior is always so poor!
Just the other day,
you drew graffiti on the post
and blamed your brother!
But this time I...
And when you scored a zero on
a test, you hid it in the attic.
Well, it's not like I lied...
And you never clean your room.
You leave things lying around.
That has nothing to do with this.
The point is, you need listen to what I tell you and behave properly!
What are you saying?
You're the one who's not listening to me!
I've had it!
Come on, Nee-chan!
Hold it right there!
Are you stupid?!
How dare you say that to your mother?!
We're running away!
I'm not staying in this house!
Stupid Natsumi! I didn't want to run away!
Well, she made me mad.
It really wasn't our fault this time.
What do we do now?
Let's go to our old secret hideout for now.
Our secret hideout? You mean this one?
Yep.
Hurry up!
Hang on...
Ah, I'm gonna fall!
If we go through this tunnel...
I don't wanna go in there.
It looks just like it used to.
We'll live here.
Are you serious?
There's not even water or electricity here.
Well, let's just take it easy for now.
My skirt will get dirty if I sit here...
Don't worry about a thing.
I can support one sister.
If it comes down to it, I'll pick
wild plants or hunt boars.
Why are you talking like a parent?
I'm bored. Wanna play shiritori?
Shiritori? Can't you think of
anything more fun to do?
Ringo (apple).
You complain, but you play anyway.
Gorira (gorilla).
Raion (lion)...
Wait, one more try...
Rakko (sea otter)!
Koishi (pebble).
Shi... shi...
Shinkansen (bullet train)!
I didn't think you'd be so bad at shiritori.
So what if I am?
I'm starving.
Don't you have anything to eat, Nee-chan?
Weren't you going to be
the one to support me?
Oh, I bought this on the way home yesterday.
Way to go, Nee-chan!
Let's split it half and half!
Oh, fine...
That's good!
Huh?
Stupid stupid stupid! Mom is stupid!
Oh, I remember!
You wrote this when you were little.
You ran away here after an
argument with Mom then, too.
You even dragged me with you.
That actually happened?
Then you said you were hungry
and pulled up that grass to eat,
and it made you feel sick.
I remember that!
Wait... What happened after that, though?
Hang in there, Natsumi. We're almost home.
Natsumi!
Mom!
Mommy...
Natsumi! Natsumi!
Look!
Hey! What good is chasing it gonna do?
I'm gonna catch it and take it to Mom!
Wait up!
You're not going to follow them?
I'm getting kinda cold.
Guess we should go home.
Yeah.
Is Mom here?
I don't know. Just sneak in quietly.
You two.
Where did you wander off to?!
Well, you know...
We thought, even if we were running
away, we shouldn't break curfew...
Who cares about curfew?!
I've been looking for you everywhere!
W-Wait!
Stop! Stop!
It's so good! It smells like watermelon!
Mom, what's with all the sweetfish?
The neighbors shared them with us.
Hey, don't eat so fast.
Good thing that cat only took
the chikuwa and not this!
That's right! We found the cat!
Also, Nee-chan is really bad at shiritori!
Natsumi, don't point at
people with your chopsticks.
Will you drop it? So what if I'm bad at it?!
And Komari, don't talk with your mouth full.
What's your problem?
Leave me alone!
I'm coming in.
Why do you want to sleep with me?
Just because.
Nee-chan, do you have enough blanket?
This is kind of creepy...
Do you feel bad for dragging me
along when you ran away?
Well, I've got a lot on my mind, too.
I'm sort of regretting it, I guess.
You don't have to worry about that.
You couldn't get by without me, you know.
What?
That's all for today
Five!
So many fives!
Crab!
Camera!
That "bullet train" thing.
Renge-chan, can you play again tomorrow?
Yes.
Really? Okay, see you tomorrow!
Episode 4
Summer Vacation Started
Non Non Biyori
Please
Watch
Again
Tanuki
Crossing
Photo by: Motoi no Yukki