Closing Ceremony
Before summer vacation starts,
on the last day of the first semester,
Hotaru      Renge
we all eat the watermelons
we raised together.
When you put salt on watermelon,
it's really sweet after the
salty flavor goes away.
There! It went over there!
Crab!
You grabbed that like a
starving bear grabs a fish...
What're you gonna do
with that? Keep it?
Yes.
I'm going to call him Salt.
You don't have much of a gift
for naming things, do you?
Huh?
You're taking forever! What are you doing?!
We told you to bring back the
watermelons we left cooling in the river.
I forgot!
Why do you have watermelons
at the closing ceremony?
That's hard to answer...
It's just a tradition that the
students eat the watermelons...
...they raised in the school garden
at the closing ceremony.
Oh, a watermelon.
It's heavy.
Hand it here.
It's not damaged, is it?
It's nice and cool.
Then let's eat it now!
I'm handing out your report cards first.
Report Card
Asahigaoka Branch School
Miyauchi Renge
Here's yours, Ren-chon.
Five!
You're amazing, Ren-chon.
I didn't do very well in math.
Yay!
How's yours, Nattsun?
I'm too scared to look.
If my grades are bad,
Mom will yell at me again.
So many fives!
Congratulations!
Thank you!
You're smart, Nattsun!
You think so?
Maybe the age of Natsumi-chan
has finally come...
Oh, by the way...
Grade school students
are scored out of five.
Students from middle school up are
scored out of ten, so take note of that.
Now, it's finally watermelon time!
Okay!
Line up and take a slice as I cut them.
Noted.
Nattsun, have some watermelon.
Life is unbelievable.
These are good, for something
from the school garden.
Yeah.
If only life were this sweet.
I brought salt, too. Anyone want some?
Hmm... I might try some.
I guess I will, too.
Actually, I've never put
salt on watermelon before.
Yeah, we don't do that at home.
It's salty...
Like life?
What am I gonna tell Mom?
What're you doing with that crab?
I caught it earlier.
Are you keeping it?
Crabs are hard to keep in summer.
I can't?
Well, I won't say you can't...
But it is hot.
It'll probably be easier to keep in fall.
I'll catch another one when school starts again.
Well, we've had our watermelon.
Ready to head back?
Oh, we brought your bags
to the top of the steps.
Since I got bad grades,
maybe I should focus on
stress relief this summer.
If you say that,
you'll never finish your homework.
See you in the second semester!
Ren-chon, what're you doing?
I'm coming!
Episode 4
Summer Vacation Started
Do you start summer vacation
tomorrow, too, Nee-nee?
I wish.
I've got a lot of work to do.
By the way, your Nee-chan said
she's coming home today.
But you're here, Nee-nee.
No, not me.
Your sister Hikage, who's going
to high school in Tokyo.
She's coming home?
Well, it is summer vacation.
I'm home.
Oh, speak of the devil.
Man, it's hot out there!
Welcome home.
How long did it take to
get here from Tokyo?
Eh, like, six hours?
There's juice in the fridge.
'Kay...
Whew, that's cool.
Hika-nee, Hika-nee.
Huh?
What was the city like?
You wanna know?
You know, there are tons
of buildings in the city!
And they're really tall!
How tall?
You can't look at them unless you
tilt your head back this far.
That's tall!
The city must be so amazing.
Plus, I actually rode it today, y'know.
That "bullet train" thing.
Those long ones?
Yeah! The long ones!
Most trains are long.
And they even bring you
juice and stuff on a cart.
High-tech!
That's not really high-tech.
I wanna be the cart pusher!
Let's play bullet train!
Okay, go for it.
Roll, roll. Would you like some juice?
Bell pepper juice, mustard
spinach juice, spinach juice?
Those are all vegetable juices...
Excuse us.
Oh, Hika-nee, you're home?
Hey.
I just got back.
Oh, is she new?
Nice to meet you.
She moved here from Tokyo.
Toky—
How long did you live in Tokyo?
From kindergarten until this past April.
S-So you're more of a city girl than I am, huh?
More of one?
Hika-nee, you're a country
girl through and through.
She was trying to talk like a city girl earlier.
I was just trying to act a little cool...
Hotarun, have you ever
been on a bullet train?
No, not a bullet train.
Oh, really? You've never
ridden a bullet train?
Bullet trains are awesome!
Now, why don't I tell you
all about bullet trains?
Hotarun, you didn't ride a bullet
train when you moved here?
I came on an airplane, not a bullet train.
A—
Airplane?!
You flew? You actually flew?!
Why didn't you tell us?!
Airplane!
Come and tell us all about
airplanes in the other room!
Nice idea!
Here, Hotarun, sit!
C'mon, hurry up!
Okay...
How high do airplanes fly?
Well... above the clouds, at least...
The clouds?!
Wow!
Bullet trains, see, have these,
like, armrests on the seats...
Oh?
Nee-nee, it's time for breakfast.
So much food... So much money...
I don't know what to do with it all...
Nee-nee! Wake up!
Ouch, that hurts!
That means I'm not dreaming!
Oh man...
Foxtail, foxtail...
I'll play with you just like a cat...
My name's Renge.
My name's Honoka.
I came to stay at my grandma's
house for summer vacation.
Oh.
And my dad let me borrow his camera,
so I was taking some pictures.
Oh, camera!
If you want to take pictures,
I'll show you around.
Really?
Let's go this way.
Okay!
Where are we going?
There's something cool this way!
There it is!
A water wheel!
I've never seen one before!
I know lots of great places.
It's turning fast!
I'm gonna take pictures!
I got them!
Want to take a picture, too?
Yes, I do!
Here.
What do I do with it?
Um, you push that button.
Oh, point the lens that way.
I'm not really good with machines.
I'm a photographer!
I need more lighting!
That was my first time taking pictures.
I got some good shots.
It's actually my first time, too.
I think it set my photographer's spirit on fire!
I'll take you to some other places!
Oh, I'm supposed to be
back for lunch today.
You are?
Where's your house?
Close to that bridge I was on earlier.
Okay, I'll walk with you.
How old are you, Honoka-chin?
I'm in first grade.
So am I!
So we're the same!
We're the same!
Thanks for coming with me.
And thanks for showing me your camera.
Oh...
Renge-chan, can you play again tomorrow?
Yes.
Really? Okay, see you tomorrow!
Wanna take the bus to the
store with me tomorrow?
I'm busy.
Huh?
Well, Renge-chan, see you tomorrow!
Tomorrow, I'll take you where
there's a little waterfall.
Okay! I can't wait!
Bye bye!
Ren-chon, you've been getting
up early a lot lately.
I'm going to play with Honoka-chin!
Oh, the girl staying with the Ishikawas?
What about breakfast?
I'll take bread with me!
Change clothes before you go.
I know!
Ishikawa
Oh, hello there.
Let's see... You're Renge-chan, aren't you?
I came to play with Honoka-chin.
Oh, dear, I'm sorry.
My son, Honoka's father,
had a sudden call from work.
They had to leave quickly yesterday.
And you came all this way. I'm sorry.
Thank you for playing with Honoka.
Whew, it's too hot for shopping.
You chilled the watermelon, right?
It's been a week since
Honoka-chan left. You're still sad?
I'm not sad.
But I want some somen.
And plum kelp tea.
Oh? And should you really
be taking such an attitude?
What?
As a matter of fact,
we just got a letter from Honoka-chin
that her grandma sent over.
You should've told me!
What does it say?
She said she had fun playing with you,
and that she'll come back next year.
She's coming back next year!
And she included a photo.
Somen, somen...
I wanna write her a letter, too!
What about lunch?
That can wait!
Uh, I think the postcards
are in the bedroom...
An envelope looks better
than a postcard!
And I'll send her a drawing
in return for the photo!
I need crayons!
Right...
That's all for today
Mocchoroke... dancing!
They don't have these in the city?
I got lots for you!
There are tomatoes in the miso soup!
So we're at the beach...
Episode 5
I Pretended I Forgot My Swimsuit
Non Non Biyori
Photo by: Gate Bowler
Please Watch Again