This is my first summer
vacation since moving here.
The cicadas' voices are full of energy,
Hiyori Shrine Stop
and the sun is sizzling hot,
but there's always a nice, cool breeze,
so we don't need an air conditioner.
And every day, I wake up early for...
Exercises to move your body side to side.
With a bit of bounce!
Three, four, five, six, seven, eight!
One, two, three, four!
Five, six, seven, eight!
Hi-yah!
Mocchoroke dancing!
Well? What do you think of my dance?
This is supposed to be
calisthenics, not dancing.
I'm pretty sure this is supposed
to be Kazu-chan's job.
Nee-nee is sleeping again today.
I'll have to have a talk with her soon.
You should.
Today's fortune was,
"Misfortune will fall
upon someone you know."
I wonder if our chaperone is going to get
KO'd before we even get to the beach.
By the way, your parents leave to work in
the fields early every morning, don't they?
Since Kazu-chan is still sleeping,
want to have breakfast at our house?
Yes!
Would you like to come, too, Hotaru-chan?
Is that okay?
Sure. The more, the merrier.
Now that I think about it,
is this the first time you're
coming to our house, Hotarun?
I've never been.
We're all going to the beach
together later, so come on over.
Okay!
Breakfast at Senpai's house...
Episode 5
I Pretended I Forgot My Swimsuit
Sorry to make you come
shopping for breakfast with me.
Oh, it's fine. But was
there a store around here?
Yeah, right over here.
Where do you go shopping, Hotaru?
On the weekends, my family drives to the city.
Lucky. We might not even
go to the city once a month.
And we've arrived while we were talking.
Vegetables for Sale
Everything 100 yen
Payment
Huh? This is the store?
Hm? Well, there's no one working,
but it's open twenty-four hours a day,
so it's pretty much like a convenience store.
They don't have these in the city?
I can't say I've seen one...
That's pretty different.
Huh? It is?
Well, whatever. Let's head back.
Oh, I'll hold the tomatoes.
It's fine. They're not heavy.
But I feel bad. I'll hold at least half!
We're home.
I brought rice!
You're big, Hotarun, so I got lots for you!
Wow, you sure did.
Eat lots and get bigger!
Food's here.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Oh, not at all. I'm sorry for not helping.
You're a guest, Hotaru,
so don't worry about it.
Well then...
Let's eat!
Wow...
Is something wrong?
Oh, no.
This is just my first time eating
breakfast at a friend's house...
We do this all the time.
Munch, munch, munch, munch, non?
I could only understand "non."
So how are you liking
summer vacation here?
Doing radio calisthenics at a shrine,
buying vegetables from
an unmanned stand,
and having breakfast with everyone...
It's all so new to me.
Oh, really?
Yes!
Hotaru-chan is such a good,
honest girl, unlike Natsumi.
You don't have to compare us!
Let's just hurry up and eat
and go to the beach. The beach!
We're really going to the beach?
Of course!
Kazu-chan is going to the
beach with you guys, right?
Munch, munch, munch, munch, non.
Um, there's a tomato in my miso soup!
Sure there is.
You don't usually put them
in yours, Hotaru-chan?
We usually put in tofu and seaweed...
Well, we put in tofu, too...
It might be unique, but it just
adds a little sourness. It's good.
Well then...
So, we're at the beach.
It is indeed the beach...
But, this is the country.
Why are there so many people at the beach?
There are indeed a lot...
It's not like there's anything special
at a country beach like this.
Maybe they're people coming
home for the summer...
You're not swimming, Koma-chan?
Not yet.
Did you forget your swimsuit?
I just like to look at the ocean.
You say that, but I bet you
just don't like the fact...
...that you don't look like a middle
schooler when you wear a swimsuit.
Yes, that's right!
And I was trying to forget that
and just enjoy the beach...
Oh, sorry, sorry.
Um, how tall are you right now, Koma-chan?
I'm just under 140 centimeters.
You probably don't know because
you're not around kids your age,
but that's about average.
What?
I think the average for fourteen
year olds is about 140 centimeters.
What? Really?!
Uh... yeah.
Crap.
I can't let her know that this
is data from the Meiji era.
Meiji?!
Oh, did I say that out loud?
I'm smaller than people from the Meiji era?!
And I was padding it quite
a bit when I said 140, too!
Now, now, calm down.
You're only in eighth grade,
so there's still time.
You'll grow before you know it.
Wait, you padded your height?
Sorry!
It took me a little while to get my swimsuit on!
What are you doing?
Nothing. We're just playing a little game.
Where'd she go? Where'd she go?
See?
Huh?
I'm thirsty.
Juice!
I'll go buy some juice.
Nah, it's right over there. I'll go.
It's fine. I'd like to be alone.
Is something wrong with Senpai?
You should ask yourself that,
deep down in your chest...
More importantly, are you
really a fifth grader?
This is why I didn't want
to come to the beach.
It would have been a lot more
fun if we'd gone to the city.
Isn't this vending machine
way taller than necessary?
The vending machine's mocking me, too?
Oh, hey, you there.
Yes?
Do you have a minute?
Huh?
Um, isn't Senpai taking a while?
Hey, come back here!
Sorry!
Now that you mention it...
Man, what's that juice doing, anyway?
Don't turn your sister into juice...
It has been about thirty minutes,
and the shop is right there...
I wonder if someone hit on her.
No one would hit on a squirt like her.
Though, I could definitely
see her being kidnapped.
Just kidding.
S-Senpai was kidnapped?!
Hey... I was joking...
But it's not impossible!
Senpai's really cute!
And small! And easy to carry!
Easy to carry?!
But then again...
I wouldn't put it past Nee-chan to
follow anyone for a piece of candy.
Senpai's been kidnapped!
Wh-Wh-Wh-What are we going to do?
What am I supposed to tell my mom?
H-Hey, calm down and let's
think about this rationally.
Okay, first off,
I've come with you today as a
friend, not as a teacher, right?
So, I can't be held responsible
for any of this, and such. Right?
We have to...
...pull it together...
...or there might not be any hope.
All right! Anyway,
let's all go look for her!
Right!
We're gonna look for Koma-chan!
Right. Um... right?
Senpai!
Koma-senpai!
Koma-chan!
Hey!
Senpai, where are you?!
She's not here, either.
Senpai!
Senpai! If you're here, please respond!
Ice
Cream
Snacks, Locker Rentals
No sign of her at all...
We can't find her.
You don't think she was already
taken somewhere else, do you?
Shenpai...
Whoa, Hotarun, stop! Stop!
This is an announcement from
the lost children center.
We have a little girl who's about
130 centimeters, with long hair,
and her name is Koshigaya Komari-chan...
I told you, I'm not a little girl!
They took me to the lost children
center even though I wasn't lost!
They asked me where my
mom was! What the heck?!
Senpai, thank goodness!
There's nothing good about it!
Man, I'm glad it didn't turn
into anything big, Lost-chan.
I told you, I wasn't lost!
Sorry about that.
We apologize, as well.
We were convinced she was lost.
Come to think of it, I have a feeling
we're forgetting something...
Whoa, what's that?
Who knows?
Please don't push.
The beach was a lot of fun, huh?
But all those transfers are really tiring.
Yeah.
It's pretty dark out... What time is it?
Aw, it's already 8 o'clock?
Well, this is our last transfer. We can do it.
Oh, really?
Yeah. Once we get on the
next train, we can go home.
When's the next train coming?
Hm? The last train should be
here in about twenty minutes.
I can finally rest. Looking for
that lost kid wore me out.
I wasn't lost.
Don't worry about it.
Oh.
What is it?
There are a lot of oranges
lying around the tracks.
Looks like there's a summer
orange grove over there.
This is the first time I've seen one.
Now that I saw that, I'm hungry.
How does seeing oranges on
the ground make you hungry?
Well, we haven't had dinner.
Stand-and-Eat                  Konsuke
Noodles
Can we eat at that shop?
Sure, but I'm going to head
over to the other track.
Me! I want to eat, too!
Okay! Let's hurry!
Should we go, too?
Yeah, let's.
The next train's the last one, so if
you're late, I'm leaving you here.
Okay!
Here's your kitsune udon.
Wow.
This is my first time eating
in a place like this.
We must be in the city. It's so cool
to see food shops in the station.
And there are actually people
working at the station.
This seems pretty normal...
Ma'am, is one child seat enough?
Oh, thanks!
Only I get a chair!
Yep.
He asked if one would be enough.
Does that mean he was trying
to figure out if we needed two?
You're taking it too personally...
Red pepper!
Yeah, but the fact that he had to ask...
The fortune this morning was totally off!
It said, "Misfortune will
fall upon someone you know,"
but it was me that misfortune fell upon!
I think he was just asking in general.
You think so?
U-Um...
M-My mouf... burnth...
Wha ith thith?!
Senpai?!
Anofer mithfowtune!
Don't worry about it.
Were you watching, Ren-chon?
Senpai, are you all right?!
Hey, Nee-chan. If that's too hot,
do you want me to eat it?
R-Reawwy?
You're sush a nithe perthon, Nathumi.
Don't thank me.
It makes my heart hurt.
What the heck? It's not
nearly as hot as I expected.
You've got a ways to go if you're
saying this is hot, Nee-chan.
Are you okay?
What? Does it look like I'm trying too hard?
Yes, it does!
This is so good! Super yummy!
Ren-chan, what have you been staring at?
There's a bug flying around
the light on the ceiling.
You're right.
You were ignoring me to watch a bug?
Nattsun, why are you crying?
I don't really get it, but don't worry, Nattsun.
If you say so...
S-Senpai, the train is here!
If we miss this one,
there won't be another!
Hurry and get ready, Ren-chon!
Even I find myself daunted by these
smooth, yet chewy noodles. Slurp.
If you don't hurry,
we're going to miss the train!
Thanks for the meal!
Hurry! Hurry!
We made it. Somehow.
Indeed.
Thank goodness Senpai is so easy to carry.
So you're here, too, Nii-chan?
You're so fast at times like these.
When did you even get on?
Now we can just relax until we get home.
Did Nee-nee miss the train?
U-Um... Don't worry.
Don't worry, Ren-chon!
Yep! Don't worry!
D-Don't worry.
I fell asleep for a bit, but the
train didn't come yet, did it?
There's no way they all
forgot about me, right?
I mean, they are my students...
Nah, they couldn't have...
Natsumi, I'm going to go pick up Kazu-chan.
What are you doing?
Crap!
Hey, wait!
Hold it!
You're tracking water all over the house!
It's because I'm so hot!
Make sure you clean it up with a rag!
Fine...
I actually wanted to go in the water...
But with this swimsuit...
All because Mom said this one still fit,
and wouldn't buy me a new one.
I wanted to wear something
like Hotaru's, too...
Rag, rag...
That's all for today
I understand everything now.
There might be land mines...
If you say stuff like that...
Sliding door punch! Tile throw!
Something even scarier than Armageddon...
I'm gonna eat it!
Episode 6
I Became a Ghost and Tried Hard
Non Non Biyori
Photo by: Tarao
Please Watch Again