I know it's summer vacation, so I
won't tell you not to have fun...
But what's the meaning of these grades?
Well...
Um, where did you find that?
In your room.
I was cleaning and found
it underneath your desk.
You weren't hiding it from me, were you?
No, of course not...
The summer afternoons are still hot.
Our mom's temperature is
on the rise, as well.
Well? What's the meaning of these grades?
I won't yell at you, so just tell me.
Um...
Well, there was a lot material on the tests,
and all the questions were hard...
Don't make excuses!
My God! You just said you wouldn't yell!
You haven't finished your
summer homework, have you?
Well, I've been busy...
Don't make excuses!
Honestly, all you ever do is talk back!
That attitude is your problem!
You need to listen to what people tell you!
You can do things if you just try.
I want to watch TV in the living room.
Working hard every day is important.
Are you gonna be done soon?
Understand?
Forget about that. Just hide my tests.
Those wretched, priceless tests...
That has nothing to do with
me. It's your own fault.
Keep talking like that...
...and you'll see something
scarier than anything on TV.
Like our family's own Armageddon!
And just what are you doing
while I'm scolding you?
Oh, um, this is...
A bunny!
Yeah, I'm a bunny!
Bounce, bounce, bouncity-bounce!
"Bounce" this!
The end of summer is
always Armageddon here.
Episode 6
I Became a Ghost and Tried Hard
Oh, Nii-chan and Nee-chan,
are you in there?
Uh-oh...
Man, Onii-chan's fast!
By the way, Nee-chan, your English
grade dropped, didn't it?
If you're there, get in here.
Where are you going?!
You two say something, too!
Speak up!
What makes you think you can run away?!
We're not finished talking!
I heard the cicadas calling
and my body moved on its own!
You just don't know when
to give up, Natsumi!
No! I don't wanna!
From now on, you will prepare and
review before your lessons! Understand?
Yes. I understand completely.
You can do things if you just try.
Does that mean I can't
do anything right now?
I'm going to go air out the futons.
You can do things if you try, you hear?
Yes...
As if I'm gonna study.
Is it over?
Oh yeah, it's over.
These things end in no time if you
just keep saying "yes" and "okay."
Besides, it's the tests' fault for being too hard.
Natsumi-chan didn't do anything wrong.
You never think back or
move forward, do you?
Oh, did you hide my tests?
Yeah, for what it's worth.
Thanks.
So where'd Mom go?
To air out the futons.
Anyway, where'd you hide the tests?
In your closet...
...under the... futon.
When is this endless Armageddon
going to be over?
It's never gonna end as long as
the enemy keeps coming after me.
Sliding door punch!
Special move: tile throw!
It's the sliding door's fault
for being easy to tear.
And it's the tile's fault
for coming off so easily.
Did Natsumi-chan do something wrong?
No, it's never gonna end if you
don't think about your actions!
You think?
Yoo-hoo!
Hey, Ren-chon.
Where do you wanna go play?
Yep!
This might be the best Koma-plushie yet!
This is great. Koma-plushies are great.
Though, I might have made a few too many.
I definitely can't let Senpai and
the other girls see this room.
Well, I can't help that I already made them.
Where should I put them?
Hello.
Hi.
Meowning.
Oh, are you Hotaru-chan's friends?
Yes, nice to meet you!
Well, come in, come in.
Thank you.
Hotarun's house is so nice.
I bet her room is as clean as a...
U-Um!
Please wait here for a minute!
Hm? What's wrong?
W-Well, my room is messy...
So? My room's a mess, too.
It won't bother me.
Well, it's not just a mess...
Th-There might be land mines...
Why would your room have land mines?
Anyway, I'll clean it up right now!
Please wait here!
S-Sorry to keep you waiting.
We're comin' in.
Hey, it looks totally clean.
Well, I just cleaned it...
It's way cleaner than Natsumi's room.
Is that your album, Hotaru?
My Album
Can I look at it?
Sure.
Let's see...
Hey, this one looks like
you when you were little,
but isn't this place close to here?
Oh, my relatives live nearby,
so I've been here to visit several times.
Oh...
Were you in first grade here?
Um... That picture is from last year.
Last year?
Th-This is...
The latest game console!
Mind if I play just a little bit?!
Wow! Oh, man!
It looks like you already are...
This controller is so cool!
What?! There are buttons
on the back, too?!
What does this mean?
I wasn't sure how it would work,
but I guess they won't find out now.
There aren't any toys.
Are they in here?
Am I floating in the air?!
You sure are!
This is bad!
My Koma-plushies are in that closet!
If you don't have any toys, let's play tag.
We can't play tag in my room.
Non, non.
You can play my style of tag indoors.
It's a new kind of tag I made up!
The rules are easy!
The one who acts most like a demon wins!
I'll show you how it's done first.
O-Okay.
My hair is not naturally curly!
What is this?
Why do I feel like I just
told a joke that flopped?
I couldn't quite understand...
Should I have said, "Don't underestimate
the tiger stripes!" or something?
That might have sounded more like a demon.
I also could've said, "Hey, old man,
give me a discount on this daikon!"
Um, Ren-chan, are we even
imagining the same thing here?
Now it's your turn, Hotarun.
I can't impersonate a demon.
It's too embarrassing.
Then I'll look for some toys.
Stop! Stop!
She must have some kind of secret,
to develop this much in a year.
Then be a demon!
I'm... a demon...
I can't beat this level...
More! More!
I'm a demon!
Hotarun, how do you beat this—
Hotaru, did you do something
to grow up this much?!
I'm a demon! I'm gonna eat you!
What does that mean?!
So you have to eat a lot to grow bigger?!
Is there an eat command?!
What are you talking about?
I couldn't understand you. Say it again!
I'm a demon...
Your face is red just like a demon!
Is it milk?! Do you drink milk?!
I don't know what's going on,
but please make it stop!
Why do you have plushies of Nee-chan?
Why are there so many?
Um, this is... I was kind of practicing...
Of course. I understand everything now.
Y-You understand what?
All these plushies,
and the way you said practicing...
R-Ren-chan, what are you...?
This is your free study
project for summer vacation!
Huh?
Oh, yeah! I came over to ask if I
could copy your free study project.
I actually haven't done mine, either.
Me neither!
Since we have the chance, you can
teach us how you made these,
and we can all make plushies
for our free study project!
Okay, then I'm gonna make Ren-chon!
That okay with you, Hotarun?
Yeah...
What was I so worked up about?
My Ren-chon is done!
Done with your cat, Nee-chan?
Only the face. I guess it doesn't need a body.
I made this.
What is that?
It's Gu.
That's a tanuki?
Well, now our free study projects are done.
With that out of the way, our summer
homework is practically done!
You still have your drills, Natsumi.
Koma-chan, Hotarun, let's play house.
Sure.
But that's so childish...
Koma-chan is the dad,
and Hotarun is the mom.
Fine, fine.
So you'll be our child?
I'm a flying fish!
Slide, slide, slide.
Honey, I'm home.
Welcome home. We're having
gratin for dinner today.
Flop, flop.
I love gratin.
Actually, maybe I'll have a bath first.
Flop, flop, flop, flop, flop...
Okay.
Water...
Let's just play this normally...
Thanks, Hotarun.
Don't mention it.
We'll go home now.
Take care.
A dragonfly!
You're right.
I guess summer's almost over...
Wow!
Just the Basics
7th Grade Social Studies
Daily 15 Minute Drills
Just the Basics
7th Grade Science
Daily 15 Minute Drills
Basic English Terms
Memorize These and
it's Smooth Sailing!
This goes really fast with
three people! Triple speed!
Come to think of it, I seem to
recall doing this last year...
I should've had you guys
help me from the start.
That would defeat the
purpose of the homework.
I'll be finished by tonight at this rate.
Yeah, I guess there'll
be no more Armageddon.
Hey, let's do that.
Huh?
Something even scarier
than Armageddon...
Let's do a test of courage!
Since you called at night,
I thought you wanted to light
fireworks, so I brought some.
We're not doing fireworks.
We're doing a test of courage.
I actually wanted to do it at a graveyard...
But since it's dangerous in the dark,
we have to do it at the
shrine, where there's light.
Can't you just be happy that I
let you do this test of courage?
So the rule is:
you have to put a five yen coin on the edge
of the offering box and come back here.
I also brought props for the scarer
to use, so someone has to be the—
Are you stupid?!
What's your problem all of a sudden?
Well, I figured you'd do something like this.
But I have no intention of
doing something that silly.
Aw, you're no fun.
Just because you can't handle scary stuff...
I-I'm not scared or anything!
I just think we might get
spooked if a ghost shows up.
There are no ghosts.
That's why we need a scarer.
Come on, we'll decide with
rock-paper-scissors.
If you don't play, you lose.
W-Wait a second!
Rock, paper...
Scissors!
I won!
That means I'm the scarer, right?
Man, I lost...
It just shows that I've
been living my life right!
Oh, well. Go ahead and start
getting ready, Nee-chan.
Yeah, yeah. I don't want to scare
you all so bad you start crying,
so I'll go easy on you.
Wh-What, so there's only one scarer?
Anyway, I should hurry up and get ready.
What's this sheet for?
Oh, I'm supposed to put
this on and be a ghost?
Pretty typical setup Natsumi came up with...
Jeez, why do I have to do this?
Huh? I can't see...
It's dark!
What is this?
The eyes are just drawn on with a marker!
At least cut holes in it!
Not being able to see is...
...not scary, but let's
find something else.
I thought I heard footsteps behind me...
I-It's just one of them coming up here, right?
No... This sensation...
Th-There's no mistaking it.
It's definitely...
...a ghost!
I know you're behind m—
What's going on? No one's there...
What's goin' on?!
I slipped into a country accent...
I'll go where there's light.
I can't stand the dark...
Why did it turn out this way?
If I had to do this, I'd rather have
just done the test of courage...
Wh-Why is there a five yen coin...
...when no one's been here?
Wh-Who joined the game
without telling me?
Who's the mysterious participant?
A black cat...
I like cats, but...
I know what's going on!
You're the one who joined the
game without telling me!
You're a monster cat!
I-I-I'm sorry!
The sheet again?!
It's dark!
S-Someone help me!
Oh, Nii-chan's coming back.
Did Nee-chan do her job as the scarer?
All right! Now it's my turn!
Good luck.
So, I wonder how Nee-chan
will try to scare me.
Depending on how it goes,
maybe I'll try to scare her.
Evil spirits, begone!
What's a ghost doing that for?
I'm a ghost!
Armageddon!
I'm glad we brought the fireworks.
Yeah, aren't they pretty?
Senpai, come join us.
Huh?
Here.
Thanks.
That's all for today
Want some corn?
This is probably the main
reason why I'm poor.
Corn fishing!
It's a clio-neko.
Wow, Nii-chan, you're pretty good!
It looks like outer space because it's twisted.
Episode 7
My Rice Crackers Turned Into Curry
Non Non Biyori
Photo by: kochakin
Please Watch Again