Summer vacation is over and the
second semester starts today.
I finished my homework and I'm
excited to go back to school.
I'm sorry! I overslept!
But it's not my fault.
It's my sister's fault for not waking me up!
Wait, where's Sensei?
She seems to be late today.
Nee-nee's "five more minutes" in her futon...
went on for more than an
hour, so I left her there.
What's with her?
I woke her up lots of times,
but she wouldn't get up.
Ah, it's her own fault for not getting up.
Some teacher she is.
Oh, Nee-san! Good morning!
You're making me mad.
The second semester has begun.
Episode 7
My Rice Crackers Turned Into Curry
Grade 8 Class 1
+Grade 1
+Grade 7
+Grade 9
+Grade 5
Hey...
Since the teacher's not here,
does that mean we can play
outside until she comes?
This is supposed to be class time.
Just find something quiet to do in here.
Hmm, how to kill time...
Oh, you're playing cat's cradle.
Yes.
There was some yarn left
over from Home Ec class,
so I made up an original. It's a cat.
Wow, you can make up original ones?
I wanna play cat's cradle, too!
Maybe I will, too. Nothing better to do.
There's plenty of yarn. Help yourselves.
All right, I'm gonna come
up with an original, too.
Can you even play cat's cradle, Natsumi?
Of course!
With my unique sensibility,
it's a piece of cake.
There! It's done!
What do you think this is?
What is it? A house?
As you can see, the answer is...
...a piece of yarn!
You little...
I made an original cat's cradle, too!
Really? Let's see.
What is that?
I'm good at games you play by yourself.
As you can see, this is...
...something you all know...
...outer space!
Wow! It's outer space!
I knew you'd see it, Nattsun!
I see it, I see it!
The part by your left hand especially
looks like outer space!
Actually, I'd say the middle is the good part.
Oh, I get it!
Um, are you being serious?
Uh-huh.
Look closer. That's not outer space.
Why not?
Well, it's all twisted up in the middle.
It looks like outer space because it's twisted.
U-Um...
I'll read some manga.
Gave up, did you?
Also, you shouldn't bring manga to school.
Wow, you turned that page fast.
You're looking, too?
Oh, I like this one.
Oh, this?
I like this one, too.
I wanna see, too.
Make yourself at home...
What was that? Were you whistling?
This part is interesting!
The transition from this
page to the next one!
Oh, you skipped a page here.
Looks like a new manga
starts on the next page.
Oh, yeah, that really would be a big
transition if it's a different manga.
I don't really care for Top Banana...
It got weird once it turned
into a fighting story.
True...
I'm gonna play with clay.
Our tastes are too different
to hold a conversation...
Hmm, maybe I'll make
something with clay, too.
Me, too.
Let's see, what should we make?
I'm still deciding.
Senpai, yours is cute!
You think so?
It's a clio-neko.
It combines a clione and a cat.
A clio-neko sounds so nice...
Darn you, making cute stuff
when you're just Nee-chan!
Then again, this doesn't
look much like a cat...
Nii-chan, Nii-chan!
Help me make a cute cat.
That's it! You can do it!
When it's done, I'll say I
made it and show up Nee-chan!
Shouldn't you keep that secret?
Wow, Nii-chan, you're pretty good!
What? That's awesome!
I can beat Nee-chan with thi—
I can't show that to Ren-chon.
I made a moai. Isn't it cute?
No, it's creepy.
That's... a dumpling, right?
Or a ball?
Ren-chon...
That's a ball, right?
Or maybe an egg?
Following the trend from before,
it's obviously a paw pad.
O-Oh, a paw pad?
But wouldn't...
...this look more like a paw pad?
That's just a cat's paw!
Okay, I'm sorry!
You've all been acting weird!
I don't know what you're talking about!
Uh, sorry...
Wait, is that my fault?
Sorry. I overslept.
Let's start class.
Oh... I guess it's time
for lunch by now.
Oh, I've got a good idea.
Let's play outside and forget
about all these little things.
I wanna play!
Now, then...
Would one of you take this
garbage out before you go home?
I'm going fishing, so I'll pass.
That was a quick refusal.
You said when we needed to use the
incinerator, you'd take care of it.
I did? Guess I'll have to, then.
Better get it over with and go home.
Rabbit pen, rabbit pen...
Let's take care of the chickens.
Let's take care of the rabbits.
Let's groom them nice and pretty.
Then put it all together
and... dynamite!
I scraped my knee.
Well, I would imagine...
When I thought about going to
the rabbit pen, I got excited.
Do you like rabbits that much?
Of course I do!
Going to take care of them
on weekends is my hobby!
I even came over during summer vacation
sometimes to look after the rabbits!
Wow, I know how you feel.
I only got to take care of
a parrot at my old school,
but the animal I'd like
to care for most is...
A rabbit got loose!
You're right!
What should we do?!
Trying to catch a rabbit like
normal only wastes time.
Times like these call for...
...corn fishing!
We put down this bait to
lure it toward the pen...
...and put the rest of the food in the pen.
Then when the rabbit comes close,
I'll reel it in with carrots 'cause
they like those more than corn.
You close the door as
soon as it comes inside.
Okay, then I'll go hide.
I'll call out to it softly
so it won't get scared.
Come on... Come on...
Come this way and you can
eat lots of carrots.
Come on, this way.
Come on...
Instead of fishing up
a rabbit with carrots,
we're the ones who fell
hook, line and sinker.
Oh, good one!
No!
What?! Why?!
Why won't it open?!
It's locked from the outside.
I thought it was just a dumb rabbit.
I can't believe it planned this from the start.
He really got us.
This isn't the time to be impressed!
I know!
If we yell really loud,
won't they hear us back at the school?
Hmm... I doubt it.
It's a long way from here to the school,
and we didn't tell anyone
we were coming here,
so we might not even draw any attention.
But it's okay!
If worse comes to worse, the next person to
come look after the animals will find us!
When will that be?
Today's the first day of the semester,
but it's a weekend, so...
With Saturday and Sunday in
between, it'll be Monday.
Three days.
No! I don't want to be
in here for three days!
I wanna go home!
Mom said she was gonna make stew today!
Stew! Stew! Stew!
C-Calm down!
We'll be fine for three days!
We have all these vegetables we
brought to feed the animals.
They're kinda shriveled, though...
And if it comes down to it,
we've got chicken eggs, too!
There's about a 50-50 chance they'll
have chicks in them, though...
Someone help!
Hurry up and burn, hurry up and burn.
Burn hotter.
I'm so bored.
There's really no one coming...
Uh-huh.
I'm sorry.
If I hadn't tried that plan
to lure it back with food...
I'm sorry, too, for losing my
head even though I'm older.
Since we're in this situation,
I'll ask one more time.
Are you sure you don't
want these 50-50 eggs?
Found another corn.
I'll roast it in the incinerator
and make roasted corn.
What? You want some, too?
Go on, eat all you like.
Want some corn, you two?
Why are your eyes all
red like the rabbits'?
We actually caught something
with the food...
My Nee-nee.
No customers today, either...
If this keeps up, I won't
be able to make a living.
The truth is, I'm in danger right now.
Danger?
Hey, there's something here.
He's the reason behind it all.
His name is The Hungry Tapir.
He's a troublemaker who eats
anything he dreams of.
Which means, since I'm a dream,
he tries to eat me, too.
What?! That's terrifying!
Why are you laughing to yourself?
I was watching TV.
You by yourself today?
Kazuho-senpai's not with you?
It's just me today.
Nee-nee is burning garbage.
Beeping Watches
Wanna try for a capsule?
It's 100 yen.
I have money.
Oh, that one's really cool.
You can get a watch.
I know how these work.
They make you think you'll get a watch,
but something weird comes out.
Right?
Well, you won't know until you try.
The capsules are black so you
can't see inside. That proves it!
No, that's just how they're made...
If you think I'm lying, just try it!
I've never gotten a good prize before!
Fine, I will. Watch.
Horsetail-kun - Screaming Version
Sorry.
You can't fool me.
What the heck does
"screaming version" mean?
I'm gonna look at the snacks.
Gotcha!
Candy Store! How much is this?
Hey, call me by name.
I have one, you know.
It's Kagayama Kaede.
Nattsun calls you Candy Store.
If you copy her,
you'll grow up to be an idiot.
Which one?
This one.
Cherry
Oh, that?
That one's expensive.
300,000 yen apiece.
That's expensive!
I thought it would be cheaper...
We only have really good
stuff at this store.
I'll get something else.
I was kidding. They're thirty yen.
You fooled me?!
Why do you keep trying to fool me?!
I'm not trying to fool you.
Besides, you caught on
with the capsule toys.
Why did this one trip you up?
It's already 4:00!
You need to go home?
Greatman is starting!
What's that? A TV show?
Can I watch that TV?
It's kinda cramped.
Why don't you watch it
in the living room?
Okay! I will!
Greatman
Greatman! That's Greatman!
Hm... This is the stuff
kids watch these days?
Wow! Greatman!
I'll take you home. Hop on the bike.
'Kay!
Is it okay to leave the store?
No one will come anyway.
Wasn't Greatman awesome?
Nope, not at all.
Greatman Punch!
You wanna walk?
Doesn't this bike go vroom vroom?
It's dangerous to ride double.
You're pretty serious for a delinquent.
I'm not a delinquent.
Okay, we're here.
'Kay.
I'm home!
Welcome back.
Nee-nee, you're home?
Yeah.
Hey.
Oh, Kaede's with you?
I brought her home since it got dark.
So you didn't come straight home?
She let me watch Greatman!
Sorry about that.
That smell...
Is that curry?!
Nee-nee, are we having curry today?!
Yep. Leave your backpack there.
Well, I'm heading back.
Really? So soon?
Yeah, I left the store open.
Thanks for bringing Renge.
Sure thing.
All she got was the whole package
of rice crackers I gave her.
This is probably the main reason why I'm poor.
Candy Store!
What's up?
Take this!
Curry?
I got Nee-nee to pack you some.
Let's play Greatman together sometime!
If I feel like it.
Okay, you can be the hostess of
the bar he goes to all the time!
I take it back, you brat.
Later.
Or you can be a monster!
I guess I can spare the rice crackers.
The new semester started today.
I played cat's cradle and looked
after the animals. It was fun.
Then I watched Greatman at the
candy store. That was fun, too.
It was fun when the konpeito
hatched from the egg.
That's all for today
Talking about "grown-up stuff"
means talking about love!
I-I'm not flustered! I'm perfectly calm!
Is there someone you like?
Senpai! I'll draw you too, so make a cute pose!
Episode 8
We Cooked Rice at School
Non Non Biyori
Photo by: R.T.K
Please Watch Again