Autumn...
To a grown woman, it's a time to
breathe a sigh and get sentimental...
I caught some fish!
I picked eggplants!
Wow, those are pretty big.
That pumpkin's pretty big, too.
They look yummy!
We're gonna stew them together!
Hotaru
Aren't we grilling them?
Grill?
Okay, okay.
Yes, grill.
Go ahead and skewer them.
'Kay.
I can't wait!
Are you okay, Senpai?!
It's hopeless.
I can't get sentimental at all!
You get it?
This is a highly relevant class on
experiencing the tastes of fall.
Yes.
And now...
When you drain the water,
make sure there are no spaces
between your fingers,
and no rice will fall out.
Senpai, be careful!
Huh?! Wh-What?
Senpai, you need to make a
cat's paw with your left hand.
A cat's paw?
It's dangerous to leave
your fingers extended,
so you fold them like this.
O-Oh, yeah!
Okay, kitty hands...
The cut part disappeared...
It came this way.
Um, I can at least season them...
It's fine!
I'm gonna cook a delicious meal and show
you all what a good Onee-san I am.
But...
I'll take care of it!
Sit down and wait!
Okay.
How much of the seasonings
do we use, again?
Um, for that amount of rice,
two tablespoons of sake,
one tablespoon of mirin,
and a little salt and soy
sauce should be fine.
That's right! Okay!
Leave this to Onee-san!
It's hot.
Be careful.
Ah, hot...
The rice should be ready by now.
Let's see, how did it turn out?
Why does it sound like that?
And the grains are all separated...
Hey, Nee-chan, what did you do?!
What did I do? I cut the
potatoes, I seasoned it...
And I... Um...
I forgot to put the water in.
That's way too basic...
Episode 8
We Cooked Rice at School
Oh, Konomi-chan.
I brought that magazine...
Oh! Are you the transfer
student I've heard about?
Huh? Uh, yes...
I thought so! Nice to meet you!
I live next door. I'm Fujimiya Konomi.
Oh, um... Nice to meet you.
Yep, you're just as big
and pretty as I heard!
Okay, let's shake hands!
Um, I'm Hotaru.
Yeah? Nice to meet you, Hotaru-chan!
So, what were you doing?
Actually...
I splurged a while ago and
bought a portable CD player.
It feels like I took a step
up the stairs to adulthood.
Not an MP3 player?
MP3 player?
What's that? A game?
You can't use any magic with these.
No, not MP for magic points...
Well, if you don't know
what it is, never mind.
Anyway, I bought the most popular CD,
and it's so grown-up and sentimental!
Do you listen to music, Hotaru?
Well, I don't really know what songs
are popular lately or anything...
Really? Yeah, I guess you wouldn't.
Fifth grade is still a little young for J-pop.
Yeah, when you were in fifth grade,
you still carried plushies everywhere,
and ran around in the fields all day.
Huh?
Er, but my dad has some CDs and records,
so I listen to classical and Western music.
You listen to classical, too?
What? You mean you do, too, Konomi-san?
I listen to Western music, too.
Do you listen to classical
music, Komari-senpai?
I know what classical music is.
The kind with lots of people, right?
Yeah, I know what that is.
Well, yes, that's generally true...
But that's a broad description.
Y-Yeah, you're right!
Classical is great, too! Uh-huh!
It's like, you know... Uh...
A lot of the people hold sticks, right?
Like for violins and drums and
triangles, and the conductor's wand...
Komari-chan, do you really
listen to classical music?
What kind do you listen to?
What kind? Um...
L-Like, the Frog Song and stuff...
Isn't that a children's song?
I-I'm not flustered! I'm perfectly calm!
That's not what I meant...
What kind do you listen to, Hotaru-chan?
Well, let me see...
I like Vivaldi's "Spring" from his "Four Seasons,"
but "Summer" is also really
powerful, so I like it, too.
"Winter" is also nice.
When I listen to it with my dad's
headphones, it sounds so much better!
Really? Let me try it sometime!
What Western music do you listen to?
Well, it all comes from my dad's interests,
but I like jazz and blues...
Let's talk about fashion!
Hey, let's talk about fashion instead of music!
Fashion?
Yeah, I mean, look!
See?
As you can see, I'm just brimming
with womanly appeal lately.
I've gotta talk about fashion.
Womanly appeal?
Even the quiz king wouldn't
know the answer to that...
Oh, yeah. This is the magazine you asked for.
The special issue on autumn accessorizing.
Oh! Grown-up fashion!
Ta-da! I bought a new hair tie!
Well? How does it look?
Oh, a chou-chou! How cute!
Huh? What was that all of a sudden?
Were you impersonating a
steam engine? Playing train?
Huh? That is a chou-chou, right?
Well, it's true that we'll have
to buy winter clothes soon.
What I want right now is distressed denim.
That's skinny denim you're
wearing now, right?
Yeah. I want something with a
little more of a damaged look.
Aren't you interested in denim at all?
I don't usually wear pants when I go out.
Though if it's a tunic and leggings...
Stop! Stop!
I have no idea what you
guys are talking about!
Speak in Japanese!
What's "tunic" in Japanese?
Huh? Japanese?
And what do you call this
hair tie in Japanese?
So you really did buy it not even
knowing it was a chou-chou.
I did, too!
I know what a choo-choo is!
No, it's "chou-chou."
Enough talking about fashion!
Let's talk about more grown-up stuff!
You couldn't keep up, and you want
to raise the difficulty level?
Um, what should we talk about?
Okay, if we're talking about "grown-up stuff,"
should we tell stories about love?
That's it!
I'll start! I'll tell my story first!
Sure, if you actually have a
love story, let's hear it.
If you have one.
Really, Konomi-chan, what are you saying?
Even I have a story or two to tell.
My love story is...
...nuh.
I've heard people say "I have no words,"
but I guess you had a "nuh."
They don't come to mind
as easily as I thought.
That surprised me.
Not to mention the only boy
around here is Glasses-kun.
But, Hotaru-chan, you lived in Tokyo.
How about it, Hotaru-chan?
Huh? Oh, I...
Did you have someone you liked?
Um, well, "l-l-like" might
not be the right word...
What? Hotaru's eyes...
I don't know who it is,
but those eyes say she's in love!
Gah! Stop! No more talking about this!
I can tell without even asking!
It's written all over your
face that you're in love!
What?! M-M-My face looked like that?!
I'm older than you! Why are
you more like an onee-san?!
This sucks! I'm more mature!
S-Senpai...
H-Hey, Komari-chan,
that's not something you say
while throwing a tantrum.
This sucks! This sucks! This sucks!
S-Senpai, I'm way more of a child than you!
Hotaru, are you in love?
Um, I-I don't know if
I'd say in love...
Are you sentimental?
Huh?
Of course I'm not in love.
Of course not! You're not, right?
All right! Now we're tied!
When did this become a competition?
Girls, I brought snacks.
Oh, thank you.
Sorry. We're out of juice,
so all I had was coffee.
That okay with you all?
No problem at all. Thank you.
Works for me, too.
Hotaru, how much sugar do you want?
I'll get it for you.
Oh, black is fine with me.
Today's the day I start having a
sentimental autumn as a grown woman!
Hey, what are you two doing?
Koma-chan!
Senpai, good morning.
Meowning!
What are you gonna do?
I'll tell you! Fall is for the arts!
What does that mean?
Uh, in other words, we were
going to do some sketching.
Oh, sketching?
Would you like to join us, Senpai?
Art in autumn does sound nice...
Sure, I'll go.
How about here? It's a nice view.
Yeah.
Draw, draw... I'm gonna draw.
I didn't bring paper or
anything. Do you have some?
I have drawing paper and pencils.
And drawing boards.
Koma-chan, what're you gonna draw?
I haven't really decided,
but since we're here, maybe a landscape?
By the way, Senpai, did you
see that drama yesterday?
Hm? That romance show?
I missed it yesterday.
You did? It was the final episode.
What? It was?!
But I recorded it, so why don't
we watch it together sometime?
Really? Oh, good!
Natsumi took forever in the bath yesterday,
which made me late taking
mine, so I missed it.
Natsumi takes such long baths.
Renge, are you drawing me?
Yes. You're my model, Koma-chan.
What? Being a model is embarrassing...
You're doing it.
No way, I can't.
Everything can be chalked up to experience.
Okay, fine.
Do you need me to pose?
Just make a cute pose.
"A cute pose" is pretty vague...
I'll let you figure something out.
What? A cute pose...
L-Like this?
S-Senpai! I'll draw you,
too, so make a cute pose!
Huh?!
Okay, but it's a little embarrassing...
How about a pose like this?!
What? That's way too embarrassing!
Then how about this?
Oh, that could work!
Koma-chan, Koma-chan.
You don't have to get so excited.
Senpai! Look this way!
'Kay...
Hey, Renge, what kind of
picture are you drawing?
A picture of you condensed into a little
round ball and viewed from the back!
I-I don't know what you're talking about,
but can't you just draw me normally?
You want it to be normal?
I'm done.
That's good!
Isn't that kind of incredible
for a first grader?!
If you entered it in a contest, you could win!
What are you talking about?
There's nothing artistic about this at all.
This isn't what I wanted to draw.
No, really, you should enter that in a contest!
Shouldn't you draw like that all the time?
I don't know anything about contests.
Anyway, talking about
contests made me hungry.
How do contests make you...
Well, it is almost lunch time.
My house is close to here,
so why don't I go make
sandwiches for us?
Sandwiches!
Want some help?
That's all right. I'll be right back.
I'll be going, then.
Okay, take care!
Sandwiches!
What should we do? Keep drawing?
I'm taking a break until
Hotarun comes back.
Koma-chan, let's play with these.
What are these? Oh, toy gliders?
I was gonna use them with
Hotarun, so I brought two.
Okay, fine with me.
Now, whoever throws theirs farther wins.
Okay. I've done this with
Natsumi, so I'm pretty good.
Okay, here we go!
All right!
Mine went farther!
What? Mine totally went farther!
Okay, fine. I lost this time.
You're taking this so seriously,
even against a grade school kid.
D-Don't treat me like an adult...
Okay, let's try it again.
I'll beat you next time!
Hey, hang on!
Go!
Mine got ahead of yours this time!
What?!
Sorry! It took a little
longer than I expected!
Sorry I was late.
Man...
Why do we have to make dried
persimmons when we're on break?
We have to.
Our uncle sent them over for us.
This is boring. Let's play. Mom's not home.
No! Mom'll get mad if we don't
finish before she gets home.
What are you, the good little daughter?
The ally of justice, Stem Ranger, is here!
Hey, what are you doing?
If you cut off the stems,
we can't hang them up.
It's fine. I cut them from the ones we can eat.
If you're just gonna be childish,
bring in the other persimmons
from the kitchen.
Onii-chan should be peeling them.
Boo. You should just do Stem Ranger, too.
You're no fun.
I'm not doing that.
Nii-chan...
If you're playing the guitar,
does that mean you're done
peeling the persimmons?
They're in the kitchen, right?
What? I can't hear you over the guitar!
Stop playing for a minute!
Hello!
I came to play!
Oh, Konomi-chan.
You came at the best
time... or the worst time.
We were just making dried
persimmons. Help out.
Dried persimmons?
I've never made any. You sure I should help?
They're already peeled.
We just have to tie them up,
so you'll probably be fine.
There they are.
I'm the ally of justice, Stem Ranger!
Wha...
K-Konomi-chan! You're here?
Yeah, I just got here.
I'll help you with the persimmons.
S-So that's why I thought I heard
something from the front door...
Um, I was just, er...
It's fine. We've known each other forever.
I know you well. It's puberty, right?
That's not it!
Nee-chan, you're fourteen and
you haven't hit puberty yet?
Yes, I have!
I was just copying what
Natsumi did earlier.
Man, now I'm embarrassed!
When it comes down to it,
you wanted to do it, too.
Looks that way.
We tie these persimmons with string?
Yeah, around the stems.
Yay! Look, it's Kakijiro-kun!
Oh, cute! Let me see!
There, Kakijiro-kun's first evolution!
Hey! My Kakijiro-kun!
I worked so hard on him and
you're already tying him up...
Ready for the second evolution?
Anyway, that was the last persimmon.
So now we just dry them
and they're done?
No, first we soak them in hot
water so they won't mold.
Yow, it's hot!
Now I know how cooked vegetables feel!
Those were Kakijiro-kun's last words.
But it was also the beginning
of a nightmare...
...in which Kakijiro-kun became a mummy.
Nacchan, easy on my shoulders...
Didn't you have any other
last words for him?
There's a rod hanging from that beam.
Okay, you're probably too short to
reach it, Nee-chan, so I'll do this.
You only get motivated at times like this.
Come on, I'll do it, too.
Done!
Feels like fall.
Let's eat the persimmons
we saved for eating.
Okay!
Autumn... is nice.
Let's eat! Stem Ranger!
Senpai gave me dried persimmons!
That's all for today
A cultural festival?
Natsumi said she wants to do one.
I'm glad you came.
Welcome!
Welcome.
I'm going to drum on my belly!
Episode 9
We Tried Having a Cultural Festival
Photo by: Kuroneko Liner
Please Watch Again
Non Non Biyori