Color, color...
Natsumi-chan's Room
Color it all black...
Color over what happened back then, too...
Nattsun, I colored the cardboard.
Good, thanks.
Nee-chan, are you done with yours?
Not yet. I can't sew that fast.
We're preparing for a cultural festival.
It'll be the biggest event of the fall season.
Our school doesn't even
have cultural festivals.
Why did you have to say
you wanted one, Natsumi?
Don't you guys want to do a cultural festival?
Yeah, but having it this weekend
is really short notice.
It's partly Kazu-nee's fault for
agreeing to it, but still...
By the way, who are we going to invite?
Can't we just invite our parents?
What?! We can't invite our parents!
If our mom goes, the festival
will be like a scene from hell!
She's a messenger from hell, you know.
Make yourselves at home, you two.
Thank you.
Oh, and Komari,
Kono-chan brought the fruit over.
Huh? Konomi-chan's here?
She was helping me peel the fruit.
Kono-chan!
Hi, hi, hi!
You guys working hard? I came to visit.
Wow, what a mess!
What are you all doing?
Getting ready for a cultural festival.
A cultural festival?
I thought your school didn't
do fancy stuff like that.
Natsumi said she wants to do one.
What're you gonna do?
Well, an art display,
and we were thinking of opening a café.
Hirame-ou!
Um, I was gonna say "hirame (flounder)
king" as a play on "hirameki" (idea),
but since "ou" means king, I thought
"hirame-ou" might work just as well...
If you have to explain it, don't say it.
Alumni! Let's invite alumni!
Oh, are you gonna invite me, too?
'Course! And Hika-nee and Candy Store, too!
Episode 9
We Tried Having a Cultural Festival
Hello?
Oh, Renge, it's not often I hear from you.
How's everything there?
Well, I was just out getting
my hair cut with my friend.
Seriously, Tokyo's incredible!
They've got stylists and everything!
It cost a ton, but...
What? You don't care?
What about a cultural festival?
Our school's gonna have a cultural festival.
Can you come?
Come! Come! You have to come!
Huh? That's kinda last-minute,
and I don't have the money to get there.
No luck with Hika-nee. She's no fun.
Hand me the phone.
I'll use my masterful way with
words to talk her into it.
Hikage-chan, you'll come to
the cultural festival, right?
Wh-Who is this? Konomi, is that you?
You're okay with meeting at my place?
I can't! I don't have the money!
That doesn't matter.
Yes, it does!
Okay, I'll tell Kazuho-san to cover it for you.
You think she'll do that?
If she doesn't, we'll worry about it then.
Then I won't be able to come back!
Anyway, we'll go with that,
so make sure you come!
My masterful way with words was successful!
How was that a way with words?
She has momentum, yes,
but not a way with words.
Well, Hika-nee is easy to push
around, so we're good with her.
Should we try Candy Store next?
I wanna invite her! Let's go tell her!
Guess we should.
Knowing her, though, she'll probably
throw us out if we don't buy anything...
Just buy something and get out.
If you're not buying anything,
get out right now.
See?
Just like Nattsun said.
What'd you say? And don't point at me.
So, do you think you can
come to the festival?
I can't. I have to watch the store.
Aw, why not?
Nobody comes here except us.
Just come and bring lots of candy.
Are you stupid?
Aren't there snails in that
rice field out there?
Just eat those.
You eat snails, right?
Who would eat those?!
Candy Store, you can't come to the festival?
I told you, I can't.
I'm working on a project
to show at the festival!
Yeah?
I'm gonna help at the café, too!
And we're gonna do a play! And also...
Also...
You really can't come?
I can't help it. I have work.
D-Don't look at me like that!
Aw, Candy Store made Ren-chon cry.
Hey, what do you think you're doing?
It's not my fault!
I'm not going to any cultural
festival, you hear me?
Candy Store won't come...
N-No, wait! I wasn't talking to you, Renge...
Oh, fine! I'll go to your festival,
so stop looking at me like that!
You'll come?!
I guess even Candy Store
can't resist Ren-chon, huh?
Shut up! I'll make you eat snails!
Asahigaoka Branch School
Cultural Festival
Well, well, I'm glad you came.
Oh, hey.
I haven't been here in ages.
I was here until last year, so it
doesn't feel like that long to me.
Thinking about it now,
I can't believe we came to
a dump like this every day.
Welcome!
Thank you for taking the time to come.
Hey, what's that?
Oh, these?
We all decided to run the
café dressed as animals.
Hotarun is a kitty.
Oh, a cat, huh?
Hey, Candy Store, what do
you think I'm dressed as?
What are those things?
They just look like bug antennae.
They're not antennae.
You don't know, do you?
It's something everybody knows...
A giraffe!
No one would guess that!
Weren't there any more prominent
features you could use?
I thought you were a robot.
I'm a giraffe!
Oh, this is our menu and pamphlet.
Oh, thanks.
Thank you for coming.
Please enjoy our art displays and café.
Animal Café Menu
So you guys actually made stuff like this...
When I heard Natsumi organized all
this, I wondered how it would turn out,
but they're doing everything right.
Well, after I came all the
way here, they'd better.
So, can we go on inside?
Yes, go right ahead.
Yo!
Welcome! I am, as you all know, a UMA!
Welcome!! Cultural Festival!!
I'll show you to your table for four.
Please take any seat you like.
You're Natsumi, aren't you?
I am not Natsumi.
I am that which you call an
Unidentified Mysterious Animal, a UMA.
What UMA are you?
Well, putting that aside,
let me take your orders.
What'll it be?
I'll have apple cake and lemon tea.
I think I'll have the same.
I'll have an apple tea.
I'll have a grape tart.
Got it!
What's that black thing?
I made it!
That's my Nee-nee.
You notice things no one else does!
This is the latest toy that I came up with.
You stick your face through
the back like this...
D'oh. I've had it with these tricks.
That's how you play with it.
It makes you look like the end of a manga.
You come up with some
difficult ways to play...
It's fun for one or two people!
Try it with me, Candy Store!
Seriously, no.
I've brought some water.
Oh, thanks.
What's Koma-chan doing?
Senpai is on standby.
I made the ears she's wearing,
and they look best of all,
so look forward to it!
Well, we've got everyone's orders,
so let's go to the home ec.
room and start cooking.
Okay!
Ren-chan, take care of the rest.
You're not going to cook, Renge?
I'm doing a play.
You're going to play the recorder?
It's not just me. Koma-chan is in it, too.
Koma-chan, we're doing our play!
Um, I really don't want to do this...
What are you talking about? Hurry up!
What the heck is that?
U-Um, well, see...
I lost at rock-paper-scissors, and
Natsumi forced me to put this on.
And I think you'd be better off
doing this by yourself, Renge...
Koma-chan, stop complaining.
We're going to show everyone our play.
W-We're really doing this?
I'm going to drum on my belly!
Bum! Bum! Badda-bum!
Bum! Bum! Bum! Badda-bum!
Badda-bum! Badda-badda-bum...
Badda... bum... bum...
I can't take it anymore.
That was great, Komari-chan!
I could never do that! Way to go!
Koma-chan, we're not done yet!
Did you have to pour salt on the wound?
Huh? But she tried really
hard. We should praise her.
It's better to just let her go without a word.
Uh, I'm sorry.
It looks like our Koma-chan caused a scene.
Now that it's come to this,
as the one in charge,
I prepared a side show.
What? You're gonna do something else?
Hika-nee, you don't see any
tricks or setups, right?
No, I don't see anything.
Okay, then!
Uh... Well, what did you think?
Did you enjoy the show?
We did not! The floor's soaked!
You've never even done a tablecloth
pull before, have you?!
I thought I could do it, though...
Forget what you thought!
You blew it! No one could enjoy that!
But there were no tricks or setups.
Set something up! Anything!
Just do something right!
Okay, Natsumi, I won't
get mad. Just come here.
Come here and I'll put a joint lock on you.
Get her, Candy Store!
What?! What's going on?!
This is an unbelievable complainant!
Okay, I'm going to go start cooking,
so at least clean up the floor for me!
Rag, rag...
Komari gets depressed
and goes off to hide,
and Natsumi makes an
unnecessary ruckus...
What's wrong with the Koshigaya
family these days?
Faithful Dog
I don't care how, but you better
redeem yourselves, Koshigayas!
I'm begging you, Koshigayas!
Hey, how long has it been?
Thirty minutes or so.
That's pretty long, no matter
what they're trying to do.
Hey, we haven't gotten our orders yet.
Nattsun! You have to work!
Senpai! Please come back to life!
How can people be so unmotivated?
Are you even making the stuff we ordered?
Yeah, well, about that...
Even after looking at the recipes,
we still couldn't figure it out...
And then Koma-chan got all
depressed, and it's just chaos.
I give up!
Man, running a café is hard!
We shouldn't have done it
on the spur of the moment.
Oh, but we have the ingredients,
so you can eat whatever you want.
By the way, Candy Store,
I bet this would look good on you!
Here, try it on!
Yep! Just like I thought!
It suits you, Candy Store!
Delicious!
Food that we made ourselves
is ten times as good!
I'm glad you feel better, Senpai.
We got roped into helping in the end.
Well, we had fun, so it's all good.
Candy Store, isn't it yummy?
Yeah, and even better when I get
to see a fun side show with it.
Um, I am truly sorry for
getting carried away...
...and causing so much trouble for every—
Let's hear that one more time!
I am truly sorry for getting carried away...
...and causing so much
trouble for everyone.
I've had it with cultural festivals.
And now I'm five for five.
Man, you're too good
at this, Konomi-chan!
Let's play a different game.
You know, your family sure
keeps stuff for a long time.
This game console is from ages ago,
and your DVD player also
plays video tapes, right?
Well, the game console used to be our dad's.
There you are. Could you
come in here for a minute?
What's up?
Well, actually...
Could you help me clean my room?
No way.
You've gotta clean your own room.
I can't!
Mom said I don't get dinner
if I don't finish it today!
You've gotta help!
Well, we did use your room to get
ready for the cultural festival...
If you're helping her, I guess I will, too.
I won't have anyone to play with, anyway.
Thanks!
It's been a week since the
cultural festival, right?
You've left this mess here that whole time?
Well, I kinda got used to it...
Hey, you want me to put the
art supplies in the closet?
Yeah, that's fine, please.
Hey, what are these?
What? Not my zero test scores, right?
No, this.
Oh, that?
You flip it inside-out like this,
set it on the floor, and...
...it pops up like this.
Brings back memories. I used to
play with these all the time.
I don't remember that at all...
I might have other stuff like this.
Let's take a quick look.
I know I'm the one who brought it up,
but won't this distract us from cleaning?
Oh, come on.
My toy box is a box of memories,
so I want to share it with everyone.
Fine, but make it quick.
Recognize this?
Oh! I know that one!
The things that go down stairs, right?
Hika-nee and I used to always play
with these on the shrine steps.
You went to the shrine because there
are no stairs in the house, right?
I've been thinking this for a while now...
Those aren't toys that were popular
when we were kids, are they?
They were popular!
About five years ago, about half the
kids in school were into them...
Er, half the students is still only a few...
You bought that at the candy store, right?
Candy Store's grandma still
owned the store five years ago,
so apparently, their stock
didn't change in twenty years.
Seriously?!
Is that a caterpillar?!
What?! Where?!
By the way, this is...
I think that's from quite a while ago, too.
Really? That's weird...
Let's find something else.
Like slime or mini-cars...
See? We did get distracted.
Nacchan, if you're gonna play,
I won't help you anymore.
Just hang on...
Let's share our memories just a little longer.
Whoa! I found Nee-chan's
essay from first grade!
What?!
Let's see...
"My name is Komari."
"When I grow up, I want to be a flower."
"I want to be a tulip..."
Hey! Why are you reading it out loud?!
Give that back!
Come on, it's nothing to
be embarrassed about.
All first graders are like this.
I don't care! Just hand it over!
I know you're laughing
on the inside, anyway!
I'm not. I'm not laughing.
See?! You are laughing!
Give it back!
Hang on! I haven't finished reading it!
You don't have to finish it!
Aw, why not? Just a little...
I said no!
Hey, you two!
Don't just take it like you
did with Shokichi-san!
If you keep that up, your
mom will yell at you!
I didn't even mean to—
Hey! Natsumi! Are you done cleaning?
Oh, Kono-chan. Are you helping Natsumi?
I had nothing else to do...
What are they doing?
It looks like they slipped and fell somehow.
I'll keep an eye on them to make
sure they finish by dinner.
Sorry about that.
Oh, since you'll be here,
why don't you eat with us?
Sure. Thank you.
Whew, that was close.
Your mom's lightning bolts were
about to start coming down.
Konomi-chan, easy on the Iron Claw...
Well, it was better than your
mom yelling at you, right?
Why'd you do it to me, too?
All right, let's get cleaning.
Right.
That should do it.
I'm exhausted! You owe me, you know.
Thank you, dear sisters!
It's already 4:00.
What should we do until dinner?
Want to play video games again?
Oh, if you're doing that,
I found something cool earlier!
Ta-da! I found a video tape with
Pretty Cute recorded on it!
Wow, I remember that!
Isn't that anime from about ten years ago?
I used to watch that, too.
Though, even then,
nobody recorded on video tapes...
Now, now. Let's just steep
ourselves in memories today.
I don't remember for sure,
Pretty Cute
but that's not the tape we
accidentally recorded over, is it?
No way! Really?
Well, we'll find out when we watch it.
Oh, it's playing!
Natsumi!
Yes!
It's Nacchan when she was little!
Yay!
It's Nii-chan!
I love Nii-chan!
Guess what? When I grow up,
I'm gonna marry Nii-chan!
Hey, all little kids are like that.
Wasn't it nice sharing memories today?
Natsumi, wanna play?
You can pick whatever game you want.
That's all for today
Suddenly, out of the blue,
with a torn-up love letter in hand...
A quack doctor in the
depths of despair—
Episode 10
We Watched the First
Sunrise of the Year
Non Non Biyori
Photo by: SGO ALOPHA
Please Watch Again