Closing Ceremony!
We had our second semester
closing ceremony,
and winter break started.
Now it's already the end of the year.
Are you in charge of the rabbits
over winter break, Nee-nee?
No, people from around town
are taking care of them,
but everyone's busy around New Year's...
Rabbits don't hibernate?
Apparently not.
Well, we'd better head home
and get ready for New Year's.
We'll be back soon, rabbits.
Brr, it's cold...
Natsumi, what are you doing?
At least clean your own room.
Can't I do it tomorrow?
It'll already be the new year then.
Happy New Year
It's done! The New Year's version!
This is great. Koma-plushies are great.
Hotaru, help me shell these peas.
Okay!
Nee-chan! Renge!
What?
Mom's still making the osechi,
so she said to go ahead and
eat the New Year's soba.
Nee-chan, are you listening?
She's asleep.
What?
Nee-chan! New Year's soba!
Later...
The year's gonna end, you know.
I won't sleep... until it's time to eat...
Episode 10
We Watched the First Sunrise of the Year
We've gotta get moving.
Yeah.
Think the weather will be okay?
It's supposed to be clear.
Senpai, did you get the tea and hand warmers?
Uh...
Oops. I think I forgot the hand warmers.
Hurry it up. We'll miss the first sunrise.
Yeah, yeah. Just a sec, I'll get them.
Oh, Ren-chon...
When did you wake up?
I'm going, too.
I'm going to watch the first sunrise.
But it's still late. You should go back to sleep.
I slept enough.
I'm going to watch the first sunrise, too!
Renge, we'll be climbing a mountain.
You should stay home this time.
I don't want to stay home.
You're going to watch it, too, Candy Store?
Well, I'm the one who invited Senpai, so yeah.
I wanna go watch the first sunrise, too!
I'll do what I'm told.
I'll eat foods I don't like.
First sunrise...
You won't be picky?
You'll even eat your carrots?
Yes!
And spinach?
What about peppers?
Yes.
You paused that time.
I will!
Senpai, Renge says she'll eat her peppers.
Oh, really?
All right, then.
Go get yourself some clothes.
I'll change right now!
There's no time, so just change in the car.
We can drive part of the way.
Okay!
Watch for Deer
Okay, we'll have to walk from here.
Hikage, open the door for her.
'Kay.
It's so dark.
I've never seen such a dark mountain before.
Yeah, it's not even 4:00 AM yet.
Well, we have two flashlights.
Who's carrying them?
Me! I'll carry a flashlight!
Okay, Ren-chon can take one,
and I guess I'll take the other one.
Okay, Renge and Hikage will
carry the flashlights.
Okay.
Not nice. Ignoring me is
not nice. Don't do that.
Uh, what's with that mask?
Our grandpa used to use this for
working the fields in winter.
It's really warm.
You should probably leave your
hair down when you wear that.
Your head looks like an alien.
It does?
Hey, don't try to go up alone.
We have to hurry or the sun will come up!
I know. We'll go together.
Hey, how long do we have to climb?
About one hour.
One—
S-Seriously?
Nee-nee, it's okay.
If you sing while you walk,
it'll give you energy.
Sing, huh?
Yes, sing.
A quack doctor, in the depths of despair,
walked into a bamboo grove,
suddenly, out of the blue,
with a torn-up love letter in hand...
A quack doctor, in the depths of despair,
That's one harsh song.
walked into a bamboo grove,
She's trying her hardest
to keep walking, though.
suddenly, out of the blue,
with a torn-up love letter in hand...
Five years ago, she was
still just a baby...
Oh, that's right, when our
family was busy with the farm,
A quack doctor, in the depths of despair,
we used to have you watch Renge.
walked into a bamboo grove,
Yeah. I think she was one
when I first watched her.
suddenly, out of the blue,
Nationwide Weather Forecast
It will be sunny across
Japan today, perfect for—
It's time for "My Prize Cow!"
A hit! It's a big one!
It's going, going...
Gone!
A three-run home run to take the lead!
I'm so bored.
It's finally Sunday,
and here I am just watching TV.
Maybe I should ask someone to...
Yeah, yeah, I'm coming.
Hello? This is Miyauchi.
Oh, Hikage? Perfect timing.
I was really bored.
Really? That's perfect!
Are you bored, too?
Well, to cut right to the chase...
Could you come watch Renge?
Huh? What do you mean?
Well, exactly what I said.
Our parents are out working the fields,
and Nee-chan is staying in a
house closer to her college.
And our neighbor who usually
watches Renge isn't home...
So could you just keep an eye
on her for a little bit?
Our parents said they'd pay you.
Aren't you still home?
Well, I've got something to do, too...
What? I'm not really good with babies.
Can't you ask Konomi?
She seems to like kids.
Well... I'm going to town with Konomi.
Why couldn't you invite me for that?!
By the way, how much will they pay?
Get ready to be surprised.
5000 yen.
Hey.
I can't believe how fast that got you here.
It's true I came for the money,
but that kind of ticked me off.
Easy, easy...
Okay, I'm going out.
Renge's all yours.
Oh... Yeah.
Um, is there anything I should know?
There's a note on the living room table
with instructions for heating
her bottle and stuff.
Oh, okay.
If anything comes up,
our parents are in the fields.
Later, then.
Renge, look. A vapor trail.
What? What's wrong?
Hey, chill out!
Are you upset because Hikage left?
She'll be right back. It's okay.
Oh, I know! Look! You're way up high!
Ow!
Is that too high for you?
Here, how about this?
No? Then...
You're way down low!
Why the heck...
If you liked being way down low,
why'd you cry in the first place?
Is this the note Hikage was talking about?
Let's see...
"1. Renge likes her rattle."
This one?
Look, it's your rattle.
Here. You like this, right?
Hey!
What are you mad about?
What's your problem? You like this, don't you?
Okay, fine.
And here I was trying to play with you...
This is why I don't like babies.
I don't know what they're thinking.
Guess I should read the note again.
"2. Milk should match
your body temperature.
Start on low heat and then turn it up.
Don't start crying, even
if the baby does." What?!
"3. You can evade her binky bomb
if you watch for the signs."
Binky bomb?
That thing turns into a bomb?
"4. For some reason, fur seal
calls make her stop crying.
5. If you approach with her rattle when
she's playing with something else,
she'll think you're picking on
her and get mad, so be careful."
You should've made that number one!
Is this the right heat?
It'll be ready soon, okay?
Renge?
Oh, there you are.
Don't wander around like that.
Whoa! Kitty punch!
Renge, are you okay?
Don't cry.
Ah, don't cry! Don't cry! Don't cry!
Oh, yeah, the milk!
Crap! The bottle—
Ow!
Just wait a second!
Childcare... is hard...
I didn't know just giving a
kid milk was this hard...
Parents sure have it rough.
Jeez.
It wasn't easy getting that milk to match
my body temperature, you know.
You better appreciate it.
Don't make yourself at home on my lap.
You're heavy. Get off.
Hey, you hear me?
I don't know what you're saying.
Come on, get off.
Mama!
No, I'm not Mama... I'm, uh...
Cattle Crossing
I'm home. Sorry I'm a little late.
How'd it go, Candy Store?
Was Renge okay?
Huh?
Where'd they go?
Hey, are you in here?
Cand—
Peach Boy
Hey.
Is Renge here?
Yeah, but why?
We have people here to watch her today,
so you won't get 5000 yen.
I didn't come for that.
Or is this like, calling someone
out behind the school?
As if...
Hang on.
I brought her a snack.
Milky Biscuits
Renge can eat these, right?
Yeah, she can eat biscuits.
There were some leftover at the store.
It seemed like a waste to throw
them out, so I brought them.
Whoa, we can't give expired
snacks to a baby.
I never said they were expired!
They just came in!
Huh? How can they be leftover, then?
Shut up!
They're new, but these were
extra! That's fine, right?
I'm coming in!
What are those ribbons?
Oh, Konomi recommended new
hair ties for me yesterday,
so I don't need them anymore.
If you don't need them, can I have them?
Sure, but what for?
Hey, Nee-chan's gone!
I'm gonna look for her.
That's weird...
I've been singing, but I'm tired...
Well, considering the song...
Was that thing about how singing
gives you energy a lie?
Don't worry. It's not a lie, Renge.
The one who wasn't singing is even worse off.
This looks bad.
It looks like she's trying to say
something, but I can't hear a word.
Senpai, it won't be much
longer, so hang in there.
Hear that? We're almost there.
You okay, Renge?
If you're tired, we can take a break.
I'm okay. I wanna watch the first sunrise.
A quack doctor, in the depths of despair...
Renge.
You're walking on the way back, got it?
You sure are heavy...
This is much easier!
That so?
Ca—
What? I can't hear you.
Carry me.
Idiot! Just walk!
We made it.
Okay, get down.
I won't do that on the way back.
Okay. Thank you.
This is the place?
It does look like a good vantage point,
but it's pretty drab scenery.
What does it matter if it's drab?
What we're here to look
at will be far away.
Candy Store, can we climb up there?
Well, we can see the sunrise
fine from down here, but...
We still have time. Let's have some tea.
Here.
The sky is getting brighter.
Is the sun coming up?
If you look away, you'll miss
the moment it comes up.
Oh, looks like the sun's coming.
Where?! I won't miss it!
The sun came up!
It came up! The sun!
Happy New Year!
Yeah, Happy New Year.
Hey, the sun's up.
Hika-nee!
Yeah?
The sun's up!
It sure is.
You awake?
I'm awake.
Well, we've seen the first
sunrise of the year. What now?
Time for our New Year's allowance!
Nope.
I wanna eat ozouni!
Yeah. Let's head back home and eat ozouni.
I'll eat as many mochi as years in my age!
How old are you again, Renge?
I'm seven now.
Seven?
Wait, isn't seven mochi too much?
It's fine! I'll eat my ozouni!
And I'll eat seven mochi!
I'm telling you, that's too much.
Hey, where's Candy Store?
Did she go home?
No, she's still here.
That's all for today
My arm! My arm!
Hotarun is running through
the hallway at night alone!
Senpai! Hold out your hand!
Wham bang boom! Wham bang boom!
Wham bang boom boom boom!
Episode 11
We Made Snow Houses
Non Non Biyori
Photo by: Ohagi Naitou
Please Watch Again