Wow... I never thought we'd have
to spend the night at the school.
Night Duty Room
It started snowing hard out of nowhere,
the buses stopped running...
I bet it hasn't snowed this much in ages.
Thanks to a sudden snowstorm,
we have to stay at the school overnight.
This is the first time I've ever spent
a night at school with everyone.
It's okay, though. Stuff like this is fun.
Well, it's a big help that we had
instant ramen and heaters ready,
but there is one problem...
There aren't enough futons!
Episode 11
We Made a Snow House
The futon stored in the night duty room
and an emergency sleeping bag...
And the futon from one of the two
beds in the nurse's office...
That gives us three.
If two people sleep in each futon,
and one in the sleeping bag...
But the sleeping bag would be cold...
Yeah, a sleeping bag isn't the
best for a snowy day like this.
Right? Looks like we'll
have a fight over futons.
Th-Then, Senpai, would you
like to share a futon?
What a problem...
It's no use. She's asleep.
Hey, what's the deal?!
She's the one who said there'd
be a fight over futons,
and then she went right to sleep in one?!
I couldn't believe it either,
but she's actually asleep!
Um, what should we do?
Who gets the sleeping bag?
Don't ask me...
Okay, I'll sleep in the
same futon with Nee-nee.
That's fine, right?
Well, yeah, even if two people fit in a futon,
there'll be more room if one
is big and one is small.
I guess that'd be best.
That means Nee-chan should
have the other futon,
and either Hotarun or I
will get the sleeping bag.
I don't really like being
treated as the little one,
but if I get to sleep in a
futon, I can live with it.
Which are you going to
use, Natsumi-senpai?
I want the futon, obviously.
The sleeping bag's gotta be cold.
I was thinking I'd rather have the futon, too...
Sharing a futon with Koma-senpai...
What, really?
How should we decide, then?
Rock-paper-scissors wouldn't be much fun...
I'm fine with rock-paper-scissors.
Oh!
How about the one who still uses
a backpack gets the sleeping bag?
That leaves me with the
sleeping bag, no matter what!
Just kidding. Why don't we
arm wrestle for it, then?
Arm wrestle?
Wow, Natsumi, that's low.
Natsumi's really good at arm wrestling.
I've never seen her lose.
Well, I wouldn't go that far...
But I've never lost to Koma-chan or
Ren-chon, of course, or Candy Store.
Nii-chan's pretty good, too,
but he's no match for me.
Th-That's...
Come on, Hotarun, let's arm wrestle!
What?
I've never arm wrestled before.
There's no way I can win.
Ah, it's fine. Let's do it!
Ready... Fight!
My arm! My arm creaked! It creaked!
I'm sorry!
It hurts...
I think something's wrong with the muscle...
I bet it's spiral-shaped now...
I'm so sorry.
We can disregard that match.
No more physical competitions.
Let's compete with something else.
That's fine with me, but what should we do?
Let's see...
I know! Let's have a pun contest!
The funniest pun wins!
I have a feeling it'd be
hard to choose a winner...
What kind did you have in mind?
Like... Hmm...
An American pelican!
Okay, let's make it an
impersonation contest!
The closest resemblance wins!
Oh, we're giving up on the pun contest?
I don't care what you do, just make it quick.
I want to get some sleep.
Oh, sorry!
Don't be in such a rush.
We're just getting to the good part.
First, let's have our assistant
impersonation instructor, Ren-chon,
give us a demonstration.
I have to do a demonstration?
Yeah.
Oh, okay, fine.
Take it away!
Okay, this is my best
impersonation. Watch closely.
Pyramid!
Thank you very much!
Just like that! Good luck to both of you!
Yes, ma'am!
You're doing impersonations, right?
That's what I thought...
Okay, Hotarun, you can go first.
Me first?!
Just do a quick impersonation
of someone you know.
Good luck!
Senpai's cheering for me!
I have to do something...
something... something...
I... I like crayfish!
Is that supposed to be
an impersonation of me?
I'm sorry! I couldn't think of anything!
I like river crabs more.
Th-That's true! Crayfish are no good, right?!
They're not that bad.
This is why I didn't want
to do impersonations!
You copied the way she talks,
but it's hard to say whether
it really resembled her or not.
And second up is Natsumi-chan!
I'm going to do an impersonation!
The Daimonji fires.
Looks like it's a tie.
That was a quick judgment!
And why?! That wasn't bad!
It looked the same!
"Why," you ask...
That wasn't really an impersonation, was it?
Hey, Ren-chon, say something!
I'm not sure it can be called...
...and impersonation if it's not
a person, like Hotarun's.
Who's the one who did the pyramid before?!
Oh, fine! We're not getting anywhere this way!
Forget it, Hotarun! Just give me the futon!
B-But I don't...
I want the futon!
Wow, are you sure?
I can really have a full course?
This is delicious...
Goodnight!
...Non!
It's no use. I can't fall asleep.
Maybe it really is harder to
sleep in a different bed...
I'll get a drink of water.
So cold...
There's so much snow!
I don't think I've never seen so
much on the ground like this!
It's still the middle of the night, right?
What's Hotaru doing?
Since I can't sleep, it won't hurt
to go out and take a look, right?
Snow! Snow!
Hey. Hey, Natsumi! Wake up!
What?
Hotaru just put on her coat and left.
We can't let anything happen
to her. Let's go find her.
She probably went to the restroom. She's fine.
I'm pretty sure...
Here, carry this.
You sure you're not overthinking this?
Nothing that shocking is gonna happen.
Just take it!
And don't you dare do anything like that!
It stopped snowing, and I can see the stars!
It's beautiful!
I guess this is what they mean by "stars
you could almost reach out and touch!"
You can't see this in Tokyo!
Hotaru's standing alone in the school yard,
raising her hands to the sky...
What is she doing?
I'd say she's calling aliens.
Aliens?!
Shh! If you're spotted, you'll get mutilated!
What?! Is that gonna happen to Hotaru?!
Maybe I'll make a snowman
with Koma-senpai tomorrow.
We could make a snow house, too...
Uh oh! She's running this way! Hide!
She went inside the school...
Why was she running?
You think she's already being
controlled by aliens?!
Uh, to be honest, the alien
thing was just a joke...
But maybe we should check.
Everyone's gone...
Are they sleeping in the hallway?
Hotarun is running through
the hallway at night alone!
I get it! It's a festival, right?!
I wanna festival, too!
Oh, Ren-chan, did I wake you up?
Sorry. Wait just a second.
Yeah, I didn't shut off
the faucet all the way...
Good thing I came back.
Sorry I woke you up, but weren't you scared?
I came running up the hall like that...
I thought there was
a festival starting.
But I would've been more
surprised to see an alien.
That would surprise me, too...
But why an alien?
I was having a dream about aliens.
All these Martians with lots of legs came out.
Oh...
She's the usual Hotaru.
Yeah, no way the alien
thing could be true.
Let's head back. It's freezing.
Yeah, we might as well.
I wonder why she was raising
her hands like that, though...
Dunno. Why don't you ask her later?
What?! What was that noise?!
It came from outside!
This time... This time it's a festival!
Huh?
An eight-legged Martian with glowing
eyes is lying on the ground!
Oh, right, no school today.
Back to sleep...
Wham bang boom! Wham bang boom!
Wham bang boom boom boom!
Ren-chon, thanks for the little wake-up jig.
It's not a little jig! It's a huge dance!
Really? Well, today's a day off.
Let me sleep a little more.
Nee-nee, look outside!
Outside?
Wow, it snowed again.
We've had a lot this year.
I bet you could ski on that
open field near here.
Ski! Nee-nee, let's go ski!
What? No, I just said I bet you
could, not that you really can.
We don't have skis, anyway.
Why don't we have any?
What kind of question is that?
If someone has some, you can borrow them,
but I don't know anyone who does...
Wait, maybe I do.
You do?!
Then hurry up and check with them! Hurry!
Okay, okay, but I'd like to eat breakfast first.
Skiing!
Wow! I've never gone skiing before!
Hotarun, you really like snow, huh?
Yes, I do!
I'm surprised you found skis, though.
Yeah, I rented them.
Hey.
You run a candy store,
but you also rent out skis?
I couldn't make a living
on the candy store alone.
I just keep the ski gear around
because it's my hobby,
but I sell most daily necessities,
and I do rentals, too.
I also rent out futons for when
relatives make surprise visits.
And if you need anything by mail
order, I can send away for it.
Could you tell your mom that for me?
O-Okay...
Hey, could you refrain from marketing
yourself to my students?
Of course, I didn't have ski gear for kids,
so I had to bring a sled for Renge.
I like sleds better! Like Santa!
Well, good, then.
So, raise your hand if
you've never been skiing.
Me.
Me, either.
Nii-chan, you haven't, either?
Oh, all right...
Then let's start Natsumi-chan's
personal skiing lecture.
Just get on board with me and relax.
Are you sure that's okay?
Don't get ahead of yourself.
Her boat's made of mud! No mud boats!
I think your lecture just earned an objection.
Ignoring all objections...
You'll learn faster by just moving a few
meters at first to get the hang of it.
You can stop by leaning back on your butt.
Let's have Nii-chan give it a try first.
That's it, just glide straight ahead.
Okay, Nii-chan, lean back
on your butt and stop!
Uh...
Angle your feet like a V
when you want to stop.
That's a fundamental skiing rule,
so make sure you remember it.
Your butt won't always stop
you, so it's a last resort.
Got that?
Yes!
Okay, Nee-chan, give it a shot.
Even after that lecture, it's still kinda scary...
It'll be okay. I'll come down right behind you.
Okay...
I can't! I'm scared!
Help!
If I move, I'll fall!
Senpai!
Nee-chan stopped in a
pretty weird position...
Senpai! I'm coming to save you!
Hotaru!
Senpai! Hold out your hand!
I can't! If I hold out my hand, I'll fall!
Hurry! Your hand!
I did it! I've got you, Senpai!
Hotaru! Stop! Stop!
What do I do with my feet, again?
Make them a W?
That's not even possible!
You can't turn your feet backwards!
At least keep them pointing forward!
No one was able to make it down?
If they could learn that fast,
life would be pretty easy.
Since they all took off,
want to race to the bottom?
Uh, I'm not sure we should...
What? You scared of losing?
No, it's not that.
I've never been skiing before.
Huh?
Well, when I asked who's
never been skiing before,
I raised my hand, too, remember?
I just used stuff I've heard
somewhere for the lecture.
So, well, um...
Please teach me how to ski!
If turning your feet inward doesn't
stop you, lean back on your butt.
If that doesn't work, just give up!
This is Sparta!
Oh, you finally came down?
Everyone else is already here.
I can't do this! Skiing is really scary!
Oh, but I figured out how
not to fall while skiing!
You won't fall if you take off the skis!
That's not skiing. It's just walking.
Whoa, what's this? Are you making a hill?
It's a snow house, Senpai!
I-It's always been my dream
to make a snow house,
so I asked everyone to help!
Y-Yeah? You sure are fired up today.
Where'd you get the shovel?
Oh, Candy Store-san brought it for me.
She brought a gas burner, too,
and she's making pork miso soup for us.
Really?!
Huh? I've got all the help I need here.
You can play over there until it's done.
All right!
Oh, Natsumi-senpai, you'll help, too?
Sure, I'll help!
Oh, th-then use this shovel to...
Oh, Senpai, I'll add the cost of the
ingredients to your rental fee.
Okay, chill out...
What? Seriously?
Seriously.
Hotarun! Is this okay?
It's perfect! It's wonderful!
Sounds like you've approved, so here,
I brought a charcoal brazier.
The soup will take a bit longer,
so cook some mochi with it.
Mochi!
Wait, is it okay to light a
fire inside a snow house?
Yeah, it would be scary if
it melted and caved in.
Maybe we should use the
brazier outside...
Hotarun, that was quick!
Mochi! Mochi!
Mochi mochi mochi!
What's wrong? Hurry up
or the mochi will burn!
Uh, well, you're as aggressive
as usual, Hotarun.
You work fast.
When did you light that?
It's bigger inside than I expected.
Wow, you're right.
It was worth making it the right way.
I'm turning the mochi!
Ren-chon, you're in charge
of turning the mochi?
It already has grill marks!
Doesn't that mean it's almost ready?
Will the soup be done in time?
Hey, is the soup done yet?
Huh?
Yeah, the soup's been ready for a while.
What?! It's already done?!
Why didn't you tell us, then?
Pork miso! Pork miso!
Could you make them lay off
the "pork miso" chant?
Sure.
Here you go. Pork miso soup.
There's plenty more where this came from.
Okay!
All right! I'm gonna get seconds!
I'm gonna put mochi in my soup!
Me, too!
Here, Hotaru.
Thank you!
Well, then...
Let's eat!
It's delicious!
It is, isn't it?
Yes!
Seconds!
That's all for today
Since you suggested we
exchange homemade bentos,
I put some effort into it.
Really? That's great!
Yeah.
I guess this place really is
a lot different from Tokyo.
It's beautiful!
Episode 12
Spring Came Again
Non Non Biyori
Photo by: R.T.K
Please Watch Again