It's been a year now since I moved here.
Please walk quietly in the hallway
Sorry I'm late!
Senpai!
Did you finish already?
Yes. I cleaned the pen and fed them.
Thanks.
No problem.
Well, ready to go?
Yes!
Today, Senpai and I are
going on a picnic together.
Episode 12
Spring Came Again
I made lots of food for lunch.
Since you suggested we
exchange homemade bentos,
I put some effort into it.
Uh... Actually, about the bento...
Is something wrong?
Well, I kinda messed up.
I did bring one,
but it's not one that I can exchange...
Really, it's all right.
A few of the things in
mine are burnt, too.
Really?
This is how it turned out...
I did my best with it, but...
I'll eat this myself.
Uh...
I'm sorry.
I don't want to see that
look on Senpai's face!
I-It's no problem at all.
Let's exchange bentos.
What?! You don't have to do that for me!
It's totally black!
It's not the color that matters.
I love black foods like
black beans and nori.
Let's see... Can I start
with this squid ink pasta?
Uh, that's yakisoba...
Oh, I'll try the yakisoba, then.
R-Really, you can just try a tiny bit...
Okay, then, just a little.
I meant to get a little,
but it all came at once!
Ah, sorry! It stuck together?!
No, it's okay.
I like crispy yakisoba.
Uh, that's regular yakisoba...
Oh, I'll try the regular yakisoba, then.
Are you okay?
You seem to have stopped moving...
Huh? I stopped moving?
I'm fine! It's delicious!
It just tastes a tiny bit like ink.
Huh? Ink?
Squid ink!
It tastes like squid ink! It's very good!
Even though I only put regular sauce in it?
Huh... I've never had squid ink before.
So it tastes like yakisoba sauce.
Uh, well...
It might not be exactly like that...
B-But it is delicious.
That was very good.
Are you sure it was okay?
I thought it was pretty burnt...
That just made it more savory! Yeah...
Then, try this Salisbury steak, too!
This one gets my recommendation!
Huh? There's more?
Uh, I mean, okay!
The Salisbury steak, right?
I saw it on TV.
It has chocolate sauce on it.
All I can taste is chocolate!
Um, Hotaru? Is it...?
It's delicious!
Really? You liked it?
O-Of course!
I was just craving some chocolate!
Really? I'm so glad!
Ah! I'm so glad Senpai's happy!
I feel a little guilty, though...
Okay, how about these rice balls next?
R-Rice balls?
Um, is there chocolate in them?
Of course not!
Chocolate doesn't go with rice balls!
They're just regular rice
balls with a little salt.
O-Okay, I'll try one!
Oh, it's good!
Isn't it?
I've messed up at cooking rice before,
but I've never messed up
at making rice balls!
What's inside them?
Well, dried plums, bonito flakes,
salmon, things like that.
There's one with mustard leaf
that my mom pickled, too.
Oh, good. These are normal.
Oh, and I thought we could
play a little game.
There's one "Russian rice ball"
with wasabi in it, so we can—
What? Did you get the wasabi one already?!
Tea... Have some tea!
I'm sorry, I should
have told you sooner!
It's okay...
Oh, that's the noodle broth!
I actually brought some somen, too...
This one's the tea!
Uh, are you okay, Hotaru?
Really, you don't have to force yourself.
The rice balls and somen
turned out meaningless...
I'll just put my bento away.
Senpai feels bad!
I-I-It's all right!
I love your cooking, Senpai!
Is it okay if I eat it all?
Huh? It's okay with me...
You really ate it all...
It's
delicious!
Orenamin Z Drink
Are you saying it was delicious?
Really?!
I wasn't too confident, but if you
liked it, I'm glad I made it!
Good. Senpai's happy, too.
And I ate the whole bento. Now I can relax.
Actually...
I made an original dessert, too!
I didn't have pancake mix,
so I made pancakes
from okonomiyaki mix.
Think you can eat more?
Pancakes are a filling dessert as it is!
There's no way I can eat pancakes
made from okonomiyaki mix!
I feel bad for Senpai, but I'll have to refuse!
Senpai, I'm happy that you took
the time to make these—
Here, say "Ah!"
Yay! I'll have some!
The secret to the flavor
is sodium bicarbonate!
Yay!
What is that?
Hotaru, did you get your gloves?
I put them in Dad's bag.
Road Repair Information
Hey, Hotarun.
Oh, Sensei!
Good morning!
Morning.
Good morning.
Sensei, I heard everyone is
repairing the road today.
Yeah. Simply put,
we're cleaning up this area.
We check for irrigation ditches that
got dirty from the winter snowmelt,
and trim any branches that have
grown out into the roadway.
I think there'll be a more
detailed explanation later.
Okay, got it.
This work takes a lot of strength,
so the kids can just play around here.
The others are here, so go on and find them.
Okay!
I'm going.
Be careful.
I will.
Oh, here she comes.
Morning!
Good morning!
Hotarun, meowning!
Meowning.
What are you all doing?
We were thinking of picking
some edible plants.
We were waiting for you.
Oh, I'm sorry to keep you waiting.
It's okay, it's okay.
There's a lot of stuff
around that mountain path.
Let's pick some as we walk.
Okay!
This is my first time picking edible plants.
What kind will we find?
What's wrong?
Um...
Private Property Beyond This Point
No Trespassing
It says this is private property.
Won't we get in trouble?
Oh, it's fine.
It's okay, Hotarun.
My family owns all the
land on this mountain.
Huh? This mountain? Huh?!
What?! You mean all of this?!
I'm not really sure myself.
I just know we own all the
mountain land around here.
Is your family really rich, Ren-chan?
We're normal. We just own a mountain.
It's not that unusual to own a mountain.
My grandpa owns a small mountain, too.
Hotarun, didn't your family
own a mountain in Tokyo?
We couldn't even see any mountains
where we lived, let alone own one.
There wasn't even any dirt
or sand, except in the park.
No sand or mountains?
I guess this place really is
a lot different from Tokyo.
Hey! We found some edible plants!
Aw, they beat us!
Nattsun, what did you get?
Tara sprouts!
Okay, let's look for some, too.
Okay.
Let's look!
Hotaru, look! I found some fiddleheads!
Oh! I think I've seen
that in pictures before!
Okay, I'll find some, too!
Senpai, what's this plant called?
Um...
That's just a weed.
I don't know which ones are edible.
Come over here, then.
There are lots of fiddleheads.
Okay!
Nii-chan, did you find something?
Huh, there's less around
here than I thought.
Maybe it's too early in the season...
Hey, there's some creeping
wood sorrel right by your feet.
It tastes like sorrel if you chew it.
Sour, right?
Okay, I'm gonna go look somewhere else.
Pick, pick, pick... Pick, pick, pick...
I got lots of mugwort.
It's good in tempura,
and you can put it in mochi.
Mugwort bread and mugwort
tea are good, too.
I can't decide what to do with it.
Mugwort is such a sinful plant.
I'm gonna pick more mugwort.
What's wrong, Ren-chon?
That's just going too far!
Nobody does that in this century!
Hey! Find anything?
What's wrong, Ren-chan?
Hotarun, this really is the country, isn't it?
The city doesn't have mountains
or sand or even edible plants,
but there's lots here.
This place is different from
the city in lots of ways.
It has mountains, sand,
and even edible plants.
That's why I love it here.
Then it's okay if there are people
chewing on grass, too, right?
Huh?
I-I think that's fine.
I don't really get it,
but why don't we pick
some plants together?
Okay!
It's beautiful!
You can eat these flowers in
tempura or boiled with soy sauce.
They're actually pretty good.
You can eat these flowers?
What are they called?
Renge.
Why did you use my real
name all of a sudden?
What happened between you and
me in these last few moments?
What are you talking about?
These flowers are called renge.
They look even cuter,
knowing they have my name.
I like these flowers now.
All right, let's pick lots of them.
But knowing they have my name,
I don't want to eat them anymore.
What?
Oh... I know.
Nattsun, what did you make?
I made a renge crown.
A flower crown!
Why do you know how to
make something so girly?!
Well, I'm a girl, after all.
Nattsun, a girl? What does that mean?
What's the answer?
It's not a riddle or anything...
There!
Now you look like a fairy with wings!
Oh! I'm a fairy?
Yeah.
You look fancy now, Ren-chon. It looks good.
What's "fancy"?
I think it means you look cute.
What?! I look cute?!
Yeah, I think it's really cute.
Can I go show Candy Store and Nee-nee?
Okay, let's head back, then.
Va-voom!
Candy Store! Nee-nee!
Welcome back.
What's that you've got on you?
Nattsun made it for me!
I look f... f...
Funky!
Funky?
Y-Yeah, I guess you
could call it funky...
It's funky!
Let's play something
together after we eat.
Oh, and after we play for a while,
we could go to the candy store.
I wanna play fairies!
Koma-chan, you can be a fairy with me!
Nah, I'd rather play a human than a fairy.
Okay, fine.
Nattsun and I will be the fairies, then.
What? I don't think I can be a fairy, either...
Hold your hands out like this, lean forward,
say "Va-voom," and start running!
Va-voom!
You're really into this, Nattsun!
Hey, I know. When the cherry trees
bloom, let's go flower viewing.
Oh, that sounds great!
And this time, I'll make a proper bento!
Huh?!
Look forward to it!
Uh, I'll make a bento for you, Senpai!
In fact, let me make
bentos for both of us!
Oh? Are you sure?