STEEL-FANGED LYCAN
Eh?
My body feels light!
I've tried so hard
to get this second life!
I can't succumb to fear!
I will not die here!
Huh?
Is it because my strength ability
has improved?
But...
It's still stronger than me.
No, my attacks didn't work!
What should I do?
SOLO LEVELING
I can't do this alone.
I had no party or healers.
All I have is water and food.
If this goes on...
If only I had a weapon
with magic power...
A weapon?
Inventory!
Though I don't know
why this is in my inventory.
Mr. Kim said this sword
cost him 3 million.
This is an item that I couldn't afford.
I can't think about that now.
I'll use this sword for now.
Huh? My body stopped hurting.
As long as I have a weapon,
there's nothing to fear.
Huh?
What?
I can't pull it out!
Please, come out!
Your steel fangs seem genuine.
I finally got this sword.
Don't even try to damage it!
Now that I think about it...
Compared to those things,
these beasts are nothing.
Huh? I'm level 2 now.
I never leveled up
when I completed daily quests.
I see. Because this is actual combat.
And my wounds just healed before.
If I level up, will all my abilities
increase by 1 point?
A total of 5 points.
I only get 3 points from daily quests.
So leveling up through combat is faster.
How much will my abilities grow
with each point increase?
Even intelligence and perception
have been quantified.
Strength is the easiest to understand.
With only 32 points,
my movements became much lighter.
I'm only guessing.
But I think the higher
the basic ability,
the more points I'll be able to get.
So... I really can become stronger.
But they are just five small magic beasts.
I may have got carried away.
Do they have magic gems on them?
ITEM: LYCAN FANG
I got an item instead of a magic gem?
Strange things are happening to me.
If I am controlled by
a system like a game,
will this dungeon and magic beasts
differ from the ones in reality?
Ah, I found the shop.
Purchase.
SHOP
YOU CANNOT BUY ANYTHING AT YOUR LEVEL
New players can't use it?
Sell.
20 gold coins?
How much would that be in cash?
But this dungeon is at most E-Rank,
so 20 gold coins probably isn't much.
Alright.
What should I do now?
I can't leave unless I defeat the Boss.
It seems I could leave once
I get the teleportation stone,
but I have no idea where that is.
If this drags on, I'll be short of food.
Although it's an E-Rank dungeon,
it's still so hard for me
to defeat the Boss alone.
Wait...
If I keep leveling up,
I might stand a chance.
Although it's possible
I'll be dead before that.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
I've already died once before.
I won't die that easily.
So you all shouldn't die too easily either.
If I kill you in an instant,
I'll feel really bad.
You are qualified as a Hunter.
Now I can pay mom's medical bills.
If I could have another chance...
Let's...
Let's have a fierce battle!
As long as I'm alive,
I'll fight to the last moment.
As long as it makes me stronger...
I can abide by any rules.
NOTIFICATION LEVELED UP
YOU HAVE ACQUIRED TITLE:
WOLF ASSASSIN
That doesn't look good.
Can't the guild come
to deal with it quickly?
This sword is almost done for.
Weapons are just expendables after all.
No matter what weapon I get,
it'll wear out
after a few times in the dungeon.
However...
It seems like the battle is over.
TITLE: WOLF ASSASSIN
INVENTORY
34 wolf fangs.
Two worn-out short swords.
Traveler's attire.
And...
The teleportation stone is easier
to get than I imagined.
Should I return?
But, there's no guarantee that there will be
another chance to become stronger this easily.
What will happen to this dungeon
if I use the teleportation stone?
Will it disappear?
Will it disappear like
a time-limited event in a game?
Regardless...
It seems like I am being toyed
with by some unknown force.
And I cannot escape.
Should I continue forward or turn back?
Yes, this is Lee Joohee.
Ah, you're from the Hunter's Association.
I'm really sorry about earlier.
Eh?
That Gate had a Dungeon Break?
That's right around here.
It's all because I rejected him.
We're currently assembling
available Hunters to deal with it.
But there's a serious shortage of healers.
I understand.
Every time I level up,
my battles with magic beasts become easier.
The color denoting the magic
beast's name also changes.
White means it's weaker than me.
Orange means it has the same level as me.
And red means it's stronger than me.
Lycan, which was initially marked red,
is marked white now.
This indicates I have
become much stronger.
Even so...
I'm not sure I can beat that monster
down there with my current strength.
I don't know if it's because
my perception has improved.
I can clearly feel...
...that the monster below...
...is terrifying.
My level doesn't seem
to be rising anymore.
If I keep fighting like this,
this sword probably won't last.
I don't remember the stairs
at this station being this long.
It no longer looks like a station.
So fast!
The sword...
I've leveled up a lot.
But its name...
...is still orange.
KING OF THE SWAMP
BLUE VENOM-FANGED KASAKA
You're the boss here, right?
It is covered in scales.
This sword is useless against it.
Going bare-handed will be worse.
Its attacks are fast and heavy!
I can only try to weaken
its defense first!
But how can I pierce
through these thick scales?!
If I took this hit head-on,
I would be dead.
I thought I had become a bit stronger...
Is it still not enough?
How much stronger do I have to get...
...to escape this life of constant ridicule?!
The Weakest Hunter of All Mankind?
Everyone has been calling you that lately.
Yes.
Good grief.
There are always people
who speak childishly.
You must work hard and make them
change their mind.
Yes.
I understand.
They gave me that nickname
because I was too weak.
I was looked down upon
I also felt useless.
As long as I'm strong enough...
One with overwhelming power
can naturally remain undefeated.
The weak are powerless before the strong.
The weak can only stand still,
trembling in fear.
People are looked down upon
because they are weak.
Even if they're knowledgeable,
smart, or considerate,
before the strong,
they will be betrayed!
Gentleness is meaningless.
So I must become stronger.
That's why I came here!
I...
I must become stronger.
Not enough!
Compared to that thing...
Compared to the fear back then...
You have nothing to make me afraid!
I've put all my ability
points into strength!
With my current self...
I'm going to kill you!
Die!
NOTIFICATION LEVELED UP
It seems...
...I got a bit stronger.
YOU HAVE DEFEATED A KING OF THE SWAMP,
BLUE VENOM-FANGED KASAKA
Thanks to that, I got good stuff.
This dagger isn't made from bone
but from teeth?
Its power is twice that of Mr. Kim's sword,
and it comes with paralysis and bleeding effects.
By comparison...
This thing is too terrifying to use.
Anyway, I'll collect it for now.
AS THE BOSS HAS BEEN DEFEATED, THE DUNGEON
WILL NOW REVERT TO ITS ORIGINAL STATE.
Is it over?
HAPJEONG STATION
Not a person in sight.
What time is it?
Hey!
How can you just walk in here?
Didn't you hear the announcement?
Announcement?
Don't play dumb with me.
Are you a Hunter?
Yes, I am a Hunter.
Sorry for being rude.
I'll take you to the site.
This way, please.
Ah, okay.
Has something happened?
Dungeon Break.
Did magic beasts get out?
Almost all of them have been killed.
Only a giant magic beast
has been left.
I don't know if it's because
my perception has improved.
I can feel it.
That thing over there is the Boss.
Please do not take photos.
This place is very dangerous.
Kill it quickly.
What if the land prices here drop?
All healers!
Please focus on healing the Tanker!
I don't need you to tell me!
What are the Fighters doing?
Why is it not weakening at all?
Its defense is just too strong.
We have few Mages among us.
Excuse me, let me through.
Is it because it's a temporary team?
They don't work well together.
Their ranks are too low.
It should be eight E-Rank Hunters
and one D-Rank Hunter.
And because that Tanker is D-rank,
it became a prolonged battle
as no one could deliver a fatal blow.
As for the Healers...
Two D-Rank healers
and one B-Rank healer?
Hey, Miss!
Hurry up and heal them!
Aren't you a B-Rank healer?
What are you dazed about?!
Ah, yes!
Damn it, pull yourself together.
So she still hasn't gotten over it
after a week.
It's no surprise.
After all, I also...
No.
This is a D-Rank Boss.
It's weaker than
the one I just defeated.
We'll get wiped out if this continues!
We can't defeat it
without a high-rank Hunter!
As long as I can break its defense,
I can defeat it.
I'll give it the most powerful hit.
Take this!
Huh?
Good, its defense is broken.
We can defeat it.
We did it.
We defeated it.
All attacks were ineffective against it.
Why were we able to break its defense?
Our attacks had no effect.
What was that thing that just flew in?
A Boss Golem that remained unscathed
under the attack of a dozen Hunters
was defeated by this thing?
Sorry.
Yes.
Who threw this?
Oh, it was the Hunter over there...
Huh?
- He was just here.
- Such terrifying destructive power.
Is he a high-rank Hunter?
I didn't expect to take it
down with a single strike.
Perhaps that Golem was running
out of vitality anyway.
Jinwoo...
EPISODE 5: A PRETTY GOOD DEAL