Dongsuk.
Why do we make it so complicated?
We can just kill them there.
Are you an idiot?
If we do it there
and wake up that spider,
how will we take the mana crystal?
I don't care what his nickname is,
an E-Rank Hunter and a D-Rank Hunter
without combat experience
will never defeat that Boss.
We wait for that spider
to eat them and fall asleep again.
Then we can take the Mana Crystal out.
Do we blast it open again
with flash magic?
That'll wake up the spider again.
There's a small path above the cave,
we can go down from there.
I see.
You are a genius, Dongsuk.
But will it fall asleep?
If it doesn't,
we'll have to take it down.
That guy's name is Yoo Jinho, right?
Did you see his equipment?
His sword and shield alone
are worth hundreds of millions.
If we can't take the mana crystal,
we'll take his belongings instead.
Let me see which
wealthy family he's from.
At least we should attend his funeral.
By the way,
the noise we made
when sealing the road
must have infuriated that Boss a lot.
Kyuhwan,
do you think you can kill
that beast by yourself?
How could I possibly do that?
Honestly, me neither.
The Boss in Dungeon
cannot be underestimated.
In other words, those two...
...can't possibly leave there alive.
Please wait.
At least a B-Rank Hunter
can defeat a C-Rank Boss alone.
Or a top-tier C-Rank Hunter.
Jinwoo, you can't do it...
Let's find a way to get out!
Jinho is right.
Even though I've had a second
awakening and leveled up,
I am still very weak now.
The Venom-Fanged Kasaka
in the Instant Dungeon
should be D-Rank.
That Golem Boss is
probably D-Rank or lower.
This Boss is worlds apart
from those beasts.
But why?
I don't feel any pressure
that's making me tremble.
I've become strong enough
to no longer fear a C-Rank Boss.
My current level is 18.
Against a C-Rank Boss...
I have a chance of defeating it!
Hunters are called Hunters...
...because the real hunt begins now.
SOLO LEVELING
Thank you for your hard work.
Government officials, media,
and energy-related groups...
Having meetings with them for days
in a row is truly exhausting.
I've never been good at
beating around the bush.
I heard you have no plans coming up.
If possible, could I ask you
for a sparring match?
Perhaps it could change your mood.
I am already a withered veteran...
But I can't refuse when a young
person seeks my guidance.
Its hide is very hard.
Its attack is surprisingly powerful.
If I took one hit, I would be dead.
That kind of move...
He is definitely not an E-Rank Hunter.
Who is he?
Is he...
...a False Ranker?!
I've heard about them.
Very few Hunters can control their magic
power to deliberately get a lower rating.
Such Hunters are called False Rankers.
And they are usually...
...a psychopaths who take
pleasure in killing!
Why did I come here...?
Dad...
Damn it.
I can't deal any damage
to its hard hide!
My fatigue...
If it keeps increasing,
it will slow me down.
I need to get rid of it
before that happens.
Paralysis and drain.
This dagger's special abilities
are key to victory.
It'll take effect if I hit its weak spot.
That's the spot!
Acid?
It had this trick too.
Tough hide and the strong acid...
It's tougher to deal with than I expected.
If this continues,
I have no chance of winning.
I have to close the distance
between us.
The new skill, "Dash."
I'll use this move to get to it!
THE DEBUFF HAS BEEN CANCELED OUT
If one hit doesn't work,
I'll do it again and again!
He's so fast!
But can his vitality hold up?
What on earth is he planning?
Faster...
More faster...
Almost there...!
Jinwoo!
DEBUFF: PARALYSIS
DEBUFF: DRAIN
DEBUFF: PARALYSIS - DRAIN
DEBUFF: PARALYSIS
DEBUFF: DRAIN
YOU HAVE DEFEATED
THE MASTER OF THE DUNGEON
Thankfully I didn't claim
the rewards for the daily quest.
Otherwise, I can't even imagine
the consequences.
Unbelievable...
He defeated the Boss all by himself.
There's no mistake...
He's a False Ranker!
How much is this worth?
Umm...
S-Sir.
Do you need me to help you
with the magic gem?
I can carry the luggage too.
Have some water, Sir.
T-Thanks...
Why is he suddenly calling me that?
Please take a rest, Sir!
I'll mine the mana crystal.
What's with this kid?
Huh? They are still alive.
TRAINING ROOM
Are you okay?
Yes.
Thank you for your guidance.
I've relaxed a lot.
Thank you.
You are amazing, President.
There's no sign of your
skills getting dull.
No, I'm no longer as good
as I used to be.
Jinchul, your moves have improved.
It seems you've done
a lot of training.
Training can't increase
Hunters' level,
but it can improve their skills.
Yeah.
Don't take pride in the Hunter's strength.
Having physical and mental
training is indeed important.
Especially if you're going
to a dangerous place like a dungeon.
After all, in such places,
you see the worst of people.
Is the Boss dead?
Was this spider just big and stupid?
What a crap.
With his equipment, defeating
a C-Rank Boss isn't impossible.
Even so, it's embarrassing
to lose to a D-Rank Hunter.
Dongsuk, what should we do?
What else?
Yoo Jinho.
I looked you up because of
your expensive equipment.
You are no ordinary person.
The president of Yoojin Construction,
Yoo Myunghan.
He's your dad, right?
So what?
I'll give you a chance.
Kill Sung Jinwoo.
Eh?
You know what we do, right?
We kill the useless ones
who just come to fill numbers
to take the spoils for ourselves.
Yoo Jinho,
I want you to be our accomplice.
If you do, I'll spare you.
How can I...
That young Hunter killed a C-Rank Boss
on his own with that equipment.
Any special effects
would be troublesome.
If you refuse,
you can die together.
What's wrong?
What's there to hesitate about?
No one will know
what happened here.
Are you afraid of that E-Rank trash?
Huh?
You...
Are you taking his side?
Dongsuk, what do we do now?
You start with the weaker one.
Have you two...
...ever killed people?
AN URGENT QUEST HAS ARRIVED.
Urgent quest?
DEFEAT THE ENEMIES 0/6
What's going on?
Pay attention here!
Take this!
Sir Jinwoo!
Heejin.
Long time no see.
What's going on
at the White Tiger Guild lately?
Nothing much.
It's the same as usual.
How about your Hunters Guild, Gina?
The same as usual too.
By the way,
you went to Hunter Cha's
A-Rank dungeon training, right?
How did it go?
It was awesome.
It ended in an instant.
Those A-Rank magic beasts
we struggled with...
...were instantly taken down by her.
She defeated enemies effortlessly.
Needless to say,
we were surprised.
Kihoon was quite shocked.
Because his goal was to
become the next Captain.
He's really worked hard, hasn't he?
What about Kim Chul?
He also wants to be
the Captain, right?
He's not a bad guy...
That says it all.
But after all,
we are pretty lucky,
as we are able to join large guilds
like Hunters Guild and White Tiger Guild.
That's true.
Yes.
After all, there are ominous
rumors in some places.
Ominous rumors?
The teams with an abnormally
high casualty rate.
Something like that.
Yoo Jinho, he's already dead.
How can you do that?!
How could I forget?
This is a place that believes
in the survival of the fittest...
A place full of violence and deceit...
How could I...
I see.
I've become numb.
Careless,
arrogant,
and deluded.
Enemies...
The system is forcing me to kill people.
Does that mean
it doesn't want me to die?
This is neither coincidence nor kindness.
The system needs me.
I must be strong.
Sir! Thank goodness.
Hey, he's still alive.
I see.
The system is using me,
and I am using the system too.
Hey, Kyuhwan, don't hold back.
How could I forget?
The weak will have
everything taken from them.
This place is just like that.
You understand it very well,
The Weakest Hunter of All Mankind.
That means...
You are ready to face
the consequences, right?
What?
What are you saying?
If you guys are Hunters...
...you should be ready
to become hunted.
Dongsuk, let me do it.
Buddy.
It seems like you don't quite
understand the situation.
Ready to be hunted?
What can a boastful
E-Rank Hunter do?
The Weakest Hunter of All Man—
What?
NUMBER OF ENEMIES DEFEATED: 1/6
One.
Ju-Juntae...?
No way.
When did he have
a weapon in his hand?!
Where did he hide it?!
Even if he was careless,
Juntae was still a D-Rank Hunter!
How could an E-Rank Hunter
manage to kill him?
I killed someone...
I killed...
I am following the system's instructions...
But the fact is...
...I killed someone.
But if I don't,
I will be the one to die.
There's no turning back now.
Since only the strong can survive!
Go to hell!
Die!
Huh?
How can an E-Rank Hunter
have such skills?!
You bastard...
Kyuhwan!
Y-Yes!
Take this!
NUMBER OF ENEMIES DEFEATED: 5/6
So strong.
I think he's even stronger
than he was when fighting the Boss.
H-He wiped out my team
members in an instant...
So you were hiding your ability?!
You defeated the Boss too, didn't you?!
But even if I'm also a C-Rank Hunter,
I'm not the same as them!
Enhancement!
Even if he is as strong
as a demon,
he must be exhausted after
fighting the Boss and five Hunters.
He relies on his speed
and the special abilities of that dagger.
But my enhanced body
is as hard as steel.
Your dagger...
...won't work on me.
Take this!
Captain Hwang,
you are very strong.
But let me tell you something.
That is...
...I am always leveling up.
W-What happened?
He knocked me to the ground?!
This guy...
...is no way an E-Rank Hunter!
W-Wait!
Don't kill me!
Please spare me!
Money... I'll give you money!
You can keep all the Mana Crystals
and Magic Gems here!
Is it not enough?
I understand.
I'll double the money for you.
- I'll pay...
- Three times...
You tried to kill me three times.
And you begging me
to spare your life?
P-Please stop!
Do you think you can
get away with this?!
No one will know
what happened in the dungeon.
You said it.
You bastard!
Do you even know
who my brother is—
NUMBER OF ENEMIES DEFEATED: 6/6
URGENT QUEST: DEFEAT THE ENEMIES
After the Boss dies,
the dungeon will begin to close.
Let's get out quickly.
Hmm...
All C-Rank Hunters have perished.
The survivors are...
...a D-Rank Hunter
and an E-Rank Hunter?
That's right.
Well...
You.
Y-Yes?
That sword in your hand
is the Claymore Kallion
from the Maya Company, right?
It just hit the market.
Y-Yeah.
I didn't know there'd be rewards too.
- That is from the Gredos Royal Series.
- Skill: Murderous Intent.
All abilities are halved?
I see. If you are using that equipment,
I can understand.
You defeated the Boss alone
and this E-Rank Hunter
hid away, right?
Thank you for your help today.
The investigation ends here.
S-Sir Jinwoo...
Thank you, Sir.
Yeah.
Is something wrong?
No.
I'm glad...
...I had her take an umbrella.
EPISODE 7: LET'S SEE HOW FAR I CAN GO