SOLO LEVELING
Excuse me, Chief Woo.
What is it?
Please take a look at this.
This is a report on the six Hunters
who died in a C-Rank dungeon.
The survivors are a D-Rank
and an E-Rank Hunter.
Looks like they ran away.
It happens all the time.
No, they didn't run, but they managed
to kill the Boss and escaped.
The D-Rank Hunter Yoo Jinho
had quite expensive equipment.
It's not surprising that they—
What do you want to say?
Investigate it yourself
if you think it's suspicious.
No...
It's just one of the survivors
is the survivor from the Double Dungeon,
Hunter Sung Jinwoo.
Sung Jinwoo?
And one of the six who died
is Hunter Hwang Dongsuk.
The brother of
Hunter Hwang Dongsoo, huh?
Then it is indeed concerning...
I'm back.
Welcome home.
Eh?
Ah, souvenirs?
It's fried chicken!
Did something good happen?
I'm not sure if it's a good thing.
I've saved up for Mom's medical
bills and our living expenses.
That's unusual for my stingy
brother to spend money.
Oh, right.
What happened last time?
What?
The raid mission.
They paid you a lot, right?
But you didn't seem
to have any injuries,
so I thought your companions
must be strong.
Well, yeah.
So you guys killed
the enemies easily, right?
Yes, that was easy.
Regardless of the difference in strength,
at that moment,
I had no hesitation.
Moreover,
I didn't even despise them.
If it were the old me,
I would have tried to run away.
Has my bravery increased with my level?
But my opponents aren't magic beasts.
They are people...
Brother?
You okay? Are you feeling sick?
I thought the clerk didn't give me
the change, but I was mistaken.
What?
Seriously, don't scare me.
Don't think about that now.
I must keep getting
stronger for my family.
And I mustn't die.
If the same thing happens again,
I will do just the same.
What is this?
Harmful substance?
Is it detoxifying me?
Thanks for the food.
Are you done eating?
Then I'll eat it all up.
Then don't complain
if you getting fat.
I can't get drunk at all.
The system's special ability
has broken down the alcohol.
Is it the effect of some skill?
SECRET QUEST: COURAGE OF THE WEAK
Blessing...
Health and longevity...
Improved my regenerative capacity
and disabled toxic and abnormal conditions...
This is it.
The reward for the Double Dungeon mission.
So much has happened,
so I never bothered to check.
Is this why my limbs could regenerate?
There are many things
I'm unclear about.
Brother.
Someone named Yoo Jinho
called for you.
Huh?
I'll be right there.
You've drank too much.
Alcohol is poison to the body.
I'm fine.
Even if I became a doctor,
I wouldn't treat you.
CAFE PENE
Sorry for suddenly calling you out.
I didn't expect to see you again.
I'm really happy.
You saved my life after all, Jinwoo.
Thanks for giving me the magic gem too.
You helped a lot.
And thank you,
for keeping quiet about that "incident."
T-That's because they tried to kill us first!
It was self-defense.
So, what did you want from me?
Sir, I plan to build an attack te—
I refuse.
Huh?
U-Umm...
At least hear me out first.
I'm not interested in
hanging out with a rich guy.
20 times!
No...
Just 19 times!
19 times?
You want to be a Guild Master?
Please let me finish first.
Please!
Go on then.
Yes!
As you speculated,
I want to obtain
the Guild Master's license.
One of the conditions
is that a Hunter must participate
in raid missions at least 20 times.
And the last mission was my first one.
To take over the company,
I've studied hard.
So I'm confident about the written exam.
But...
My real combat skills...
Aren't you the second young
master of Yoojin Construction?
I'm also doing this for our company.
Honestly, my father wants
to establish a guild.
Yoojin Construction
wants to establish a guild?
Yes.
Dungeons are certainly dangerous,
but they contain many rare treasures.
Magic gems and mana crystals
are just a part of it.
The bodies of high-rank beasts can
be used as materials for equipment.
One can say that everything
in the dungeon can be monetized.
You plan to have your own Hunters conquer
the dungeons and take all the spoils,
so as to establish
a self-sufficient system?
That's right.
My father plans to hire an S-Rank
Hunter to be the Guild Master
and my brother as the Vice-Guild Master
to run the guild like a company.
A S-Rank Hunter?
There are only seven of them nationally.
Yes.
Moreover, Min Byung-Gu,
the only one who hasn't joined a guild,
has already retired.
Are you planning to poach
from other guilds?
I advise you not to do that.
The guilds that you poach
from will give you trouble.
My brother is not one of the Awakened,
so he can't be the Guild Master.
So you want to gain experience
and become the Guild Master
to compete with your brother?
If you want to hide your power
and participate in missions,
you will need companions.
Rather than teaming up
with high-ranked Hunters,
completing the raid missions
with an E-Rank Hunter
would be more convincing to my father.
You are at least B-Rank...
No, it might even be higher.
Teaming up with
the wrong one could be fatal.
But if it's you...
Take a look at this.
This building is planned
to be the guild's office.
It's currently valued at 30 billion.
This is the reward I am offering you.
30 billion for 19 C-Rank missions.
Before, I would have accepted right away.
But...
If I'm the only one in the world
who can level up, that's a different story.
If I keep developing like this,
someday I will be S-Rank...
No,
I may be even higher than that.
In that case, 30 billion seems trivial.
More importantly,
teaming up with people
without understanding
the impact of leveling up
is too risky.
Sorry.
Please wait!
As long as you help me,
I will keep this secret
for you for a lifetime.
I want the information
on those two survivors.
Bring me their documents immediately.
Excuse me.
I have brought the documents.
Mr. Hwang.
My brother was killed.
This has not been confirmed...
The documents?
Yes, right here.
Laura, what would happen if I killed
someone in another country?
Are you serious?
In a country with a treaty regarding
Hunter crimes, you would be prosecuted
under that country's laws.
But if there's no extradition treaty,
you would be subject to
the laws of our own country.
So...
Depending on negotiations with
the government, there might be leniency.
Adjust my schedule.
Sudden changes in schedule will affect
the operation of the guild.
What's my schedule like?
It's fully booked for now.
Then clear it for later.
I understand.
I will arrange it.
D-Rank Hunter Yoo Jinho.
E-Rank Hunter Sung Jinwoo.
I just hope you both
are still alive until then.
It's rare to see you exercising.
Studying all the time
is harmful to health, right?
Oh? You ate too much fried chicken, right?
Hmph!
Hey.
If you had 30 billion,
what would you do?
Why are you asking?
Just a random question.
Pay mom's medical bills
and college tuition fees.
And the rest?
Hmm...
Save it up.
I don't know.
That's too much money.
Hmm.
That's true.
Just keep up at your own pace.
Eh?
Wait, brother!
Even as an E-Rank one,
he is still a Hunter.
Yes...
No, don't check.
11 kilometers?
Why are the numbers exceeding
when I accomplish the goal?
I see.
Then let's see how far I can go.
Brother...
I finally caught up...
I'll have another lap.
Eh?!
It stopped at twice the goal.
Then the rest...
SECRET QUEST:
STRENGTH TRAINING HAS ARRIVED
The daily quest became the secret quest?
Yes.
I can choose different boxes.
CURSED RANDOM LOOT BOX
Guess I'll choose Blessed Random Loot Box.
A key again?
The Demon's Castle...
Acquisition difficulty of S-Rank?!
Cures all illnesses with powerful magic...
...Elixir of Life!
If that Elixir of Life
really can cure all illnesses...
I've decided.
If the acquisition difficulty of the key
is proportional to the difficulty of dungeon,
then I am opening an S-Rank dungeon.
If so,
what awaits me inside will be magic beasts
similar to those on Jeju Island
that even S-Rank Hunters can't handle.
With my current strength,
can I deal with beasts of that level?
It'd be a lie to say I'm not scared.
If things don't go well,
I will use this teleportation stone
I got from the Instant Dungeon.
If I give up, everything is over.
I need to become stronger,
to level up even higher.
HELL'S GATEKEEPER CERBERUS
I must take back everything.
How could I die here?
TITLE: WOLF ASSASSIN
ACTIVE SKILL: DASH
I can hardly inflict any damage.
The gap is still so huge
after I use the title skills?
ACTIVE SKILL: MURDEROUS INTENT
THE DEBUFF HAS BEEN CANCELED OUT
It's useless!
DEBUFF: PARALYSIS. DRAIN.
THE DEBUFF HAS BEEN CANCELED OUT
A warning?
A third of my HP was gone in an instant!
HELL'S GATEKEEPER CERBERUS
HAS USED SKILL: RAGE
ALL ABILITIES +100% WITHIN THREE MINUTES
All abilities doubled?
So fast...
Only a half left?!
There's no other way.
Full Recovery!
I stabbed it.
NOTIFICATION:
THE ENEMY DOES NOT FEEL PAIN.
What?
ACTIVE SKILL: WILLPOWER
HP: 30% OR LESS, BUFF: DAMAGE -50%
The warnings keep popping up.
The system issues warnings at critical
moments to prevent my death
because I am a player?
No matter what,
this thing can't be
an ordinary second awakening.
I must hold on for at least
3 minutes until its skill ends...
No, this is too dangerous.
I must use—
What can I do to survive?
A few more hits and I'll be dead.
Is there any way?
The shop...
I completely forgot it!
EXCLUSIVE HEALING POTION, 300G.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO PURCHASE
EXCLUSIVE HEALING POTION?
One bottle costs 300 gold coins...
3 bottles.
One bottle only restores
100 points of HP?
This is simply...
Poison?
You've drank too much.
Alcohol is poison to the body.
I'm fine.
I have to do this.
Okay.
It's not over yet!
I can still move!
Its skill effect has ended!
YOU HAVE DEFEATED
THE HELL'S GATEKEEPER CERBERUS
Is this the item I obtained?
Another key?
Is this the door that
Cerberus was guarding?
What is this?
FORMULA: ELIXIR OF LIFE
The pattern for the Elixir of Life...
THREE ITEMS ARE NEEDED
TO CRAFT ELIXIR OF LIFE.
This experience made me
understand my current strength.
Entering the castle at my current level
would surely mean death.
But...
I will return in the near future.
Definitely.
EPISODE 8: THIS IS FRUSTRATING