The Apothecary Diaries
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all of the characters, organizations, and so on
are imaginary. It also bears no connection to any specific real-life events.
Episode 5:  Covert Operations
I yield.
You've improved, Basen.
No...
My brute force is still no match
for your techniques, Master Jinshi.
But that force of yours is quite astounding.
You truly carry the Ma clan's blood.
How's the apothecary doing, Gaoshun?
What specifically do you mean?
Has she gained weight?
I believe she has regained some, yes.
I see. Well...
Don't you understand why this stuff was banned?!
I told you, it's poison.
It was unexpected, seeing that side of her.
Are you all right, sir?
Hmm? What?
You seem very concerned.
No, it's nothing.
I knew I'd find it!
Yes!
Oh! Over here, too!
And here, too!
Where should I eat it? The kitchen?
But I don't want people
asking where I found it...
Oh, but before that...
Wow, looks so good!
Thanks as always, Maomao!
It's so kind of your higher-ups to share snacks
with you every time there's a tea party.
You need to eat more!
Gain more weight!
Don't be shy!
Oh, did you hear?
Hmm?
I heard a palace servant
was able to seduce a military officer
who was famous for hating women.
Huh...
Guess how she did it.
Who knows?
They say she used an aphrodisiac!
Aphro...disiac?
That one.
What's wrong, Maomao?
N-Nothing. It's not related. Probably.
Good morning.
Oh, hey little lady! What's going on today?
There's a secret I'd like to discuss with you.
What is it?
This.
Wow! Those are fresh matsutake mushrooms!
I'm glad to see you seem to like it.
We'll need charcoal!
And some soy paste and salt!
Somehow, I've ended up being
buddy-buddy with the quack doctor.
Oh, how irresistible!
I think it's ready.
Pour on some soy paste, add some salt...
Here.
Delicious!
Now he's an accomplice.
D-Doctor!
A c-curse...
Can you make a medicine that cures curses?
A curse?
What do you mean?
It's this.
That's quite a bad rash.
Maybe an ointment, for starters?
Could you make some?
Understood.
So, what's this curse you mentioned?
It was two nights ago.
Trash that comes out of the rear palace
is burned in the pit on the west side.
I was doing work as usual that day, when...
What's that?
A woman's dress? The bottoms of the
sleeves are burnt.
And wood writing tablets...?
I was a little curious, but I just
threw it in the fire anyway. Then...
It's a curse! That must be
what got to my hands!
Was the fire this color?
Or perhaps this color?
This would do the same thing.
Little lady, what is that?
It's similar to how fireworks work.
Some things change the color
of a flame when burned.
Then, what about my hands?
There was probably something
on the wood tablets.
I think it caused the rashes
when you touched them.
Try this medicine, and let us know how it goes.
Oh, thank you.
The little lady's medicines
work like a charm!
You'll be better in no time!
Well done as always, apothecary.
Master Jinshi!
I'll make you some tea.
Greetings, Master Jinshi.
What business do you have with me today?
Do you mean I shouldn't talk
to you unless I have business?
Of course not.
Follow me for a moment.
Thank you for waiting, Master Jinshi—
Oh.
How many colors are there?
I can't say specifically.
Then, how does one apply these colors?
With salts, you can dissolve them in water.
Some will dissolve in
other things, like oil.
But this is outside my area of expertise.
I see.
If that's all, please excuse me.
Wait.
What is it?
I like them teapot-steamed.
I'm counting on you, apothecary.
So, he knew...
I'll see if I can find more tomorrow.
Find everyone who's suffered burns
on their arms recently.
Understood.
The colored wood tablets are
probably some kind of code.
People would only use something like
that for... something secret?
What would that be?
None of my business. Nothing a food
taster should be concerned about.
Thank you. Oh, please take that over there.
I'm back.
Welcome back.
Maomao! Nice timing.
Over there, please.
Try this on, would you?
Huh? I have a bad feeling about this...
What is this?
Isn't it obvious? It's your dress
for the garden party.
Garden party?
Twice a year, the emperor and his
high officials gather in the courtyard
to enjoy food and entertainment.
The emperor isn't married yet,
so he has no empress consort, right?
In that case, it's customary to bring
the upper first-rank concubines.
Upper first-rank concubines...
Current Emperor
(Contender for Empress Consort)
Upper First-Rank Concubine
The four high-ranking concubines who are
the best contenders for the empress consort.
Concubine Gyokuyou, Precious Consort.
Concubine Lihua, Wise Consort.
Concubine Lishu, Virtuous Consort.
Concubine Ah-Duo, Pure Consort.
Last time, Lady Gyokuyou
Lady Lihua couldn't attend,
because they had just given birth.
So this time, they decided
to invite all four concubines.
And what do we do there?
Well, nothing, actually.
We're invited as guests.
We just have to follow the emperor.
Some officials come by
to pay their respects.
So, don't forget to smile.
Huh...
Is everyone required to attend?
Of course!
This is Princess Lingli's
first public appearance,
and a rare event with all four
high-ranking concubines!
This is a war! We have to brace ourselves!
Let's do this!
Lady Gyokuyou has so few
ladies-in-waiting to start with.
The newbie can't sit this out.
Besides, if there's a meal,
the taster is indispensable.
I guess you do need to
stuff the chest area a little.
I want to bulk up your waist, too. Is that okay?
I'm in your hands.
We'll be doing some nice makeup, too!
You should hide your freckles occasionally.
Staying outside in the strong winds,
watching the entertainment, eating the food,
smiling at the officials who come by...
I'll definitely need an iron
bladder for this one.
In that case...
Good.
That smells nice.
What are you making?
It's candy made of ginger and oranges.
Candy?
Orange peels improve blood flow,
and ginger warms the body.
Wait, is it for the garden party?!
Yes. I also made this, just in case.
I sewed pockets into my underrobe.
By putting pocket warmers in there,
it should help me withstand the cold.
Maomao!
Huh?
Please, make enough for everyone!
S-Sure...
I guess getting too used to custom
can stifle the simplest ideas.
A little work can make things better.
Come in.
I'd like to ask for one, myself.
Me too, please...
Okay.
Please teach me how to make that.
Please.
The emperor's own seamstress and cook, too?
So cold!
Finally finished.
So, it's tomorrow.
Let's make some of those too, just in case.
Regarding the search for those
with burns on their arms...
No luck yet?
I'm sorry.
I hope the garden party goes smoothly...
Wow...
You're beautiful, Lady Gyokuyou!
Crimson looks so good on you!
Such wonderful beauty...
No wonder they say crimson suits her
better than anyone in all the land.
Yes, you outshine all others.
Thank you. And for you all...
Here. I have to mark you, to make
sure you don't attract any bad bugs.
Maomao.
Remember, Maomao. You are my lady-in-waiting.
Uhm, thank you.
Got her!
Um, wait.
Makeup time!
Time to become as cute as you can be!
We'll wipe off your face
and apply some scents.
Then we'll deal with your freckles...
There.
Huh?
Maomao?
No...
Why?
Maomao, you're...
Ah...
They caught me.
All right, let's go.
Concubine Lishu, I look forward to
seeing you later in the garden party.
Yes, Master Jinshi.
Last is the Precious Consort, Lady Gyokuyou.
He seems to favor Concubine Gyokuyou.
Could it be because of his favorite toy?
He can be so troublesome.
Maomao, you've helped out quite a bit.
Glad to be of service.
Greetings, Concubine Gyokuyou.
Oh, greetings.
My lady, you certainly
look wonderful in crimson.
Your gorgeous, yet somewhat mysterious
style must stem from your jade eyes.
Thank you.
Now, to check in on the princess...
Greetings, Master Jinshi.
Oh, it's you, apothecary.
Are you wearing makeup?
No, I'm not.
Your freckles are gone.
Yes, I removed them.
You covered them with makeup, you mean?
I removed my makeup. That's why they're gone.
That doesn't make any sense.
You're contradicting yourself.
Ugh, what a bother.
I should have just nodded along.
Every day, I put dried clay
on my face to add freckles.
I already had makeup on every
time you saw me before this.
Cosmetics aren't just for making
a face more beautiful.
Why would you do such a thing?
You really want to know?
It's to prevent being
dragged into a back alley.
I lived near the brothels, but not
every man left sexually satisfied.
Some had empty wallets, violent
tendencies, and venereal diseases.
A short, skinny, ugly girl
rarely becomes a target.
Were you ever dragged away?
Attempts were made. Instead, I got kidnapped.
My makeup was faded. They seemed
to think I was borderline marketable.
I see.
I'm sorry we couldn't police them.
I don't particularly care.
A buyer can't tell if you were kidnapped, or just sold off
legally so there'd be one less mouth to feed.
Doesn't that make you angry?
Obviously, it does. But it's not your fault.
I'm sorry.
He's being straightforward for once.
That hurts.
Sorry. It's yours.
See you at the party.
A man's hairpin? Why?
Wow! So nice!
I'm jealous!
I want one, too!
I could give it away,
but how would I split this?
Oh, you broke our promise already.
You're no longer mine alone.
Um, what does that mean—
It's starting.
The garden party begins.
Next Time
Next time: "The Garden Party."
Episode 6: The Garden Party