The Apothecary Diaries
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all of the characters, organizations, and so on
are imaginary. It also bears no connection to any specific real-life events.
There's just no sense of decency.
So picky with her food.
It's not like it's going to
kill her or anything.
Episode 6: The Garden Party
So cold!
The pocket warmers certainly help, but...
Not having anything to do
in this cold is quite an ordeal.
The wind is so cold!
Couldn't we get a tent or something?
This arrangement seems made to instill
rivalry between the four concubines.
Look, that's the Empress Dowager.
She seems very youthful.
She is young. She gave birth
to the emperor when she was...
Wow, she must have worked
really hard to give birth...
The Empress Dowager has two children,
the emperor and his younger brother.
The rumor is that the brother is
too sick to leave his house.
I think he was here until
a few moments ago, though...
I see.
Huh?!
Who are you calling basic?!
We ladies-in-waiting serve our mistresses!
What's the point in dressing up?!
Pfft. Did you hear that?
Having ugly servants hurts
the mistress, obviously.
Grr!
Those are Lady Lihua's ladies-in-waiting.
Oh, Yinghua. And so, the proxy war begins.
Let's go.
I guess you can't help it, seeing
how you hired that ugly girl.
"Ugly girl?" Does she mean me?
Having someone like that
around is truly a shame.
What did you say?!
Yinghua!
Calm down!
They haven't noticed? And after all the fun
we shared at the Crystal Pavilion, too...
If you keep acting up,
I'll tell my father about you!
I'll have to do things to your body that
you'd never tell your father about, then.
N-No!
It was just a bit of courtesan-style humor.
Apologize to Maomao!
Heh.
Wh-What, nothing to say all of a sudden?
W-Well, I guess that's enough for now!
You should thank me!
What's her problem?
Hey Maomao, are you all right?
Your real face is so pretty,
but those bullies...
It doesn't bother me. That aside, isn't it
time to change your pocket warmers?
Not only did she grow up in poverty,
her distrust of men is strong enough
to make her ruin her own face...
She endured two months of awful
bullying at the Crystal Pavilion...
Yet she won't complain at all,
and instead looks after us...
It's only natural that the benevolent
Master Jinshi looks after her!
They're being delusional again.
Have you no decency? A crimson dress?
Another proxy war.
Ah, the Virtuous and
Pure Consorts' servants.
They don't get along, either.
The Virtuous Consort is
fourteen and arrived later,
the Pure Consort is thirty-five
and has been here the longest.
No wonder they don't get along.
Besides, they used to be
daughter- and mother-in-law.
Daughter- and mother-in-law?
Um... It's a bit complicated.
Ah-Duo
Pure Consort
Previous
Emperor
Empress Dowager
Current Emperor
Lishu
Virtuous Consort
Before, one was the previous
emperor's concubine,
and the other was our
current emperor's concubine.
But the previous emperor passed away, right?
The previous emperor's concubine
left the palace once,
but returned as the current
emperor's concubine.
The previous emperor
passed away five years ago.
Back then, Concubine Ah-Duo
was thirty years old,
30 years old
and Concubine Lishu was nine.
9 years old
I guess it's all politics, but becoming
a concubine at nine? Wow.
Unbelievable, right? Being
a mother-in-law at nine years old.
Nine... Mother...
M-Mother?!
Ah-Duo
Pure Consort
Lishu
Virtuous Consort
Empress Dowager
Current Emperor
Previous
Emperor
Ah-Duo
Pure Consort
Lishu
Virtuous Consort
The one who was the previous emperor's
concubine was Lady Lishu?!
So that's the young mother-in-law?
As you probably saw,
Lady Lishu is still very young.
Yes, I see that.
Normally, a white dress would
suit the Virtuous Consort,
but that dark pink color...
It obviously clashes with
Lady Gyokuyou, the Precious Consort.
Maybe she can't read the room?
Thank you for the pocket warmers.
We'll certainly need them again.
Yes.
It's freezing...
Hold these if you're cold.
Here.
Here!
You're too kind.
Suggesting sharing the warmers with
the Crystal Pavilion ladies-in-waiting...
And getting Lady Gyokuyou's permission, too.
Well...
A hairpin?
It's how they try to recruit talented
workers hidden in this flower garden.
Huh.
It has another hidden meaning, though.
I see.
I said, there's a hidden meaning!
Meaning, huh?
Please have this, young lady.
I guess he's handing them out to everyone
to make sure no servant feels ashamed.
Thank you.
I'm Lihaku! Good to meet you!
Like a big dog...
Woof! Woof!
Did he give you that? Let me see!
Just a participation award.
I believe you should have more.
It's been some time.
Yes, my lady, it has been a long time.
That's all for today.
Lady Lihua...?!
We'll take our leave. Have a pleasant day.
Lady Gyokuyou won't like this.
What an understatement.
What will you do with all these hairpins?
Oh.
He looks pretty good there.
I guess he's higher up than I thought.
He doesn't seem out of place
among the military officers.
Oh look, that officer from earlier.
He's at the very edge, but given
his age, I guess that's still impressive?
Our glittering eunuch
isn't there, but who cares?
More importantly, food tasting.
No clouding on the contact point.
No strange smells.
But swallowing is part of the job as taster...
Now to rinse out the mouth with water... Hmm?
The life of the food taster is expendable.
I guess I'm the only one
that enjoys eating poison.
You know what would be good? Puffer fish.
Sneak in some innards in the soup...
That stinging sensation
on the tongue is so wonderful.
Oops. Must concentrate.
This vinegar fish-and-vegetable dish
is the emperor's favorite.
I saw it a few times at the rear palace.
Usually it includes blueback,
but it's jellyfish today.
The cook responsible for the emperor's food
would never mistake
the emperor's favorite ingredient.
Lady Gyokuyou has no prominent
likes or dislikes, either.
Seems like the server messed up.
I guess she doesn't like fish.
She can't refuse to eat it.
Not in front of the emperor.
I wish I hadn't seen that.
Did you see that, Lihaku?
One of the food tasters
is really excitable.
Where's the fun in watching
someone eat while terrified?
Come on, just look.
Huh? That taster... it's that girl from earlier.
J-Just how delicious is that?
This is poison.
The Precious Consort's soup was poisoned?!
Poison?! Are you sure?
Concubine Gyokuyou?!
The taster swallowed it!
Minister!
What are you doing?!
Formal attire is too tight.
Hey! The minister drank
the soup and collapsed!
The apothecary...
Phew.
Apothecary!
Good day, Master Jinshi.
Your day seems better than mine.
Oh no, I got too excited about
the poison. It's like I smiled at him.
What are you doing?
Taking you to the infirmary!
I coughed up the poison. I feel quite well.
I would have loved to swallow it, though.
If I did, the poison would have coursed
through my body by now, and...
Master Jinshi, uh...
What is it?
Give me the rest of the soup.
You're an idiot.
I'm just eager to improve.
After you left, someone tried the soup to see
if it was really poisoned, and collapsed.
Who was that stupid?
A minister. Now it's become a huge incident.
Use this, then.
It's an emetic agent.
I made it strong enough to
turn your stomach inside out.
Isn't that also a poison, then?
A new hairpin?
So the eunuchs gets hairpins, too?
His collar is a little disheveled, too.
Plus his normal glitter is gone.
Is that why he wasn't at the party?
But right now, he's acting
his age more than usual...
Or rather, he looks quite a bit younger.
I prefer him like this, somewhat.
Really does the trick!
The palace infirmary has some good drugs!
Are you all right?
Yes, I'm all empty.
Well, let's talk about who
poisoned Concubine Gyokuyou.
I'd like for you to bring
someone to talk about that.
Who?
Lady Lishu, the Virtuous Consort.
Master Jinshi, how may I be of service?
I'm sorry to bring you to this inelegant place.
This lady-in-waiting wanted to speak with you.
Huh?!
Hmph. A lady-in-waiting?
Excuse me.
I knew it.
Is it fish that you can't eat?
What is this?
Some people have things they cannot eat.
In my case, I can't have buckwheat.
Yet you eat poison?
Leave me alone. I tried to build a tolerance.
However, it made my throat swell
and it was hard for me to breathe.
Even a little bit caused rashes,
so it was hard to adjust the amounts,
and I took a long time to heal.
That's what I mean by "cannot eat."
Lady Lishu, how is your stomach?
I can get you a laxative if you....
How did you know?
It was clear that the rear palace
prepared the food for the garden party.
However, the vinegar dish used
a different ingredient from the usual one.
It seems like Lady Lishu's dish got swapped
with Lady Gyokuyou's dish by mistake.
I see.
Is it mackerel that you can't eat?
Yeah...
This isn't about just liking
or disliking certain foods.
It was just hives this time, but sometimes,
it can cause difficulty in breathing.
Feeding her this knowingly...
would be the same as poisoning her.
You're her food taster, correct?
Y-Yes!
I've taken note of what to be
careful of in an emergency.
Of course, avoiding these
foods entirely is best.
Please take a look.
It's not difficult.
However, if something goes wrong,
not even the palace doctor could fix it.
It could become deadly.
Please keep that in mind.
That should have scared her enough.
What was that about?
I am of lowly birth. Please don't touch me.
You're the only one that says that to me.
Well, everyone's just being kind to you.
Anyway, I must report to Lady Gyokuyou. So...
Wait. Why did you call the food taster in, too?
What do you mean?
Don't play dumb. You asked me to bring her.
To tell her what to be careful of.
So, you're saying the servers made the error?
I don't know. I'm a mere lady-in-waiting.
At least answer me this.
The target was the Virtuous
Consort, Lady Lishu, right?
Assuming none of the other
dishes were poisoned.
I see.
What a day.
Is this related to the matter of
the wooden tablets from the other day?
The lady-in-waiting who came earlier
had no burns on her.
Who could it be...?
Not just some superficial sweetness
I want more warmth than I can even use, oh
Having these selfish idealistic thoughts
I swallowed them again today
before putting them into words
Still in my memories,
the scent of fragrant olive
The color of twilight in the city
We were laughing...
Filled with sadness,
the tears welled up in my eyes
I found a glow during those days
I guess I took everything for granted
The wind was so loud I covered my ears
I gotta stop being like that
Even if I stumble over the words of love
Next Time
Next time: "Homecoming."
Episode 7: Homecoming