The Apothecary Diaries
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all of the characters, organizations, and so on
are imaginary. It also bears no connection to any specific real-life events.
Dad!
Episode 7: Homecoming
I wonder if Dad's doing okay.
Right. Yesterday, after the garden party...
What are you talking about?!
The minister who ate the poison
is in terrible condition!
You're sick. Get lots of sleep!
Thanks to them, I got a good deal of sleep.
But sleeping until noon is too much.
I can't go without makeup now.
Oh.
You could have taken a day off.
I can't allow myself to do that.
Please put me to work.
Oh? Your freckles.
I'm uncomfortable without them.
Can I keep them on?
I understand.
Everyone kept demanding to know
who that lady-in-waiting was.
My apologies.
It's fine.
Anyway, Gaoshun came by this morning
and hasn't left. What do you want to do?
He seemed bored, so I asked him
to pull up some weeds.
Weeds...
Back at the garden party, he was
in a pretty high-ranking seat.
I guess he really is caring.
He must win the hearts of
the ladies-in-waiting in his own way.
May I use the parlor?
Sure. Hongniang.
Yes.
Is it just me, or is Hongniang
being sparkly-eyed, too?
Master Jinshi wanted me to bring you this.
This is the soup that Lady Gyokuyou
was supposed to drink, right?
Yes.
How kind of him.
Please don't eat it.
I won't.
Silver corrodes quickly.
This is oxidized and no longer tasty.
Tasty...
Did you pick this up with your hands?
No, I didn't touch the bowl.
I only picked up the contents
in a spoon to see if it was poison.
Shoop shoop shoop.
After that, I immediately
wrapped it in cloth.
One moment, please.
Clip clip clip.
Clunk clunk clunk.
Cotton, powder, and a brush.
Yes.
What will you do with these?
In the apothecary I used to work at,
we used to put dyes on containers
that weren't supposed to be touched.
This is a similar technique.
It's simple. I put some powder
on this cotton ball.
I dust the bowl with it...
Finally, I brush off the excess.
And there.
There's some white marks.
That's where a human hand made contact.
When you touch this with
your fingers, it leaves a mark.
It's especially visible on silver,
which is easily corroded.
That's why you thoroughly
wipe silver items before use.
In other words, the finger
marks remaining here
were from people who touched
the bowl after it was wiped clean?
Indeed.
The size and placement of the finger marks
allows us to guess how they held it.
The bowl was held...
What is it?
Nothing.
The bowl was held by four people, I think.
Four people.
First, three people who touched
the side of the bowl.
The one who poured the soup,
the one who carried it,
and Lady Lishu's taster.
But there was one more.
An "outsider" that touched
the rim of the bowl.
I believe this unknown
person poisoned the food.
If that's true, why is the taster's finger
mark on the high-rank concubine's bowl?
That's simple. Lady Lishu's taster swapped it
on purpose as a form of harassment,
not knowing it was poisoned.
Swapped it?
It's bullying.
A lady-in-waiting is bullying
a high-ranking concubine?
Sounds like you can't believe it.
Can you explain?
Let me first say that this is all
just conjecture on my part.
That's fine.
Do you remember Lady Lishu's
dress during the garden party?
Yes. I believe it was a flashy pink color.
Normally, you'd think that if a concubine
picked a color that would clash
with Lady Gyokuyou's dress,
her ladies-in-waiting would
recommend another one.
Or, at least, they'd wear something
that matches it themselves.
However, all of her servants
were wearing white.
That makes Lady Lishu appear like
a buffoon who can't read the room.
Ladies-in-waiting should
allow their mistress to shine.
Come to think of it, that day...
Have you no decency? A crimson dress?
Lady Ah-Duo's ladies-in-waiting
were scolding Lady Lishu's
servants for not doing their jobs.
The rear palace is full of enemies,
so the only people a concubine can
truly trust are her ladies-in-waiting.
I suspect the ladies-in-waiting recommended
that dress to their young Lady Lishu,
and she wore it without realizing
they'd done it to humiliate her.
She didn't suspect a thing.
Not only that, but she also tried to swap
the food to further harass Concubine Lishu?
Yes, though she was unaware it was poisoned.
It ended up saving her.
But it's still quite distasteful.
Why would they do such a thing?
Lady Lishu became the previous
emperor's concubine at a very young age.
Then she left the rear palace
soon after. Her situation is unique.
A wife must sacrifice everything
to devote to her husband.
We are all taught this from a very young age.
I guess, from that perspective,
to wed her deceased husband's son
is an indecency beyond words.
I think the mark near the bowl's edge
was left by the person who added the poison.
They must have held the edge
while stirring in the poison.
I see.
Your fingers must not touch the area
that noble lips are supposed to go.
That is the teaching of Hongniang.
That's all I came up with.
May I ask one more thing?
What is it?
Why did you try to protect that
taster yesterday?
I'm just curious. This isn't
an investigation or anything.
The life of a serving girl is worthless
compared to that of a concubine.
Especially if that life
belongs to a food taster...
I'll try to explain this to Master Jinshi.
Thank you.
Well, I should be thankful, since she
did go out of her way to make the swap.
I was able to taste that poison thanks to her.
I really should have swallowed that soup.
That is all.
I see. You always impress me
with how you word things.
Is that so?
This is clearly an inside job, right?
The situation indicates as much, yes.
You make it sound so simple.
I haven't had time to sleep
at all because of this.
I haven't even been able to change clothes.
I want to stop thinking.
Your natural self is showing.
Who cares? There's nobody here.
I am here.
Can you cut me some slack?
No.
Nothing I say will move you, huh?
We've had a long relationship.
It's not easy having someone
look after you since you were born.
Master Jinshi, you forgot
to remove your hairpin.
Oh, oops. Totally forgot.
It was hidden in your hair.
I don't think anyone noticed your true status.
Take care of it for me.
You're treating it roughly again.
It's something only special individuals
can wear, so please take care of it.
I know.
You don't.
Excuse me.
Let's do this...
Oh right, did you get any hairpins?
A few.
I see!
So, now...
You can get out of the rear palace!
Huh? What did you say?
You can get out of the rear palace?
More details please!
Yes...
You can't meet men from the outside
while at the rear palace,
but if you get special permission,
a man can escort a female worker outside.
I see, so that's what the hairpins
they hand out at the garden party means.
Exactly! You can also use the hairpin to ask
someone to take you out of the rear palace.
I see. Thanks, Xiaolan. I'll give it a try.
No problem.
Maomao, thanks for the hawthorn!
It was yummy!
I received a total of four hairpins.
Two are from men.
Or rather, since one of the two
lost his important parts,
maybe I shouldn't call him a "man"?
Apothecary!
Right!
Master Lihaku, a lady from
the rear palace sent you this.
Oh, understood.
Yikes, did she take that
consolation hairpin seriously?
But if it's a pretty lady,
it would be a waste...
Jade Pavilion
Maomao
I only gave out one hairpin
at the Jade Pavilion...
Which means...
That one?
Wonder how I should turn her down...
Excuse me.
Thank you for waiting.
Huh? Who are you?
I get that a lot.
Do people ever tell you that
makeup changes you drastically?
I get that a lot, too.
But anyway, you called me up...
I'd like to go back to my family.
Your family?
Do you know what this means?
I was told that I could go home temporarily,
as long as you can vouch for me.
You're quite bold.
You, a mere lady-in-waiting, are demanding
that I, a military officer, vouch for you?
Yes.
And you summoned me just for that?
I don't know if you're dauntless or clueless.
So, little girl, you're trying to
exploit me for your homecoming?
No, I believe I can offer you
something valuable in exchange.
Huh?
Verdigris House - Introduction Letter - Pairin
Verdigris House - Introduction Letter - Joka
Verdigris House - Introduction Letter - Meimei
Could I interest you in a flower-viewing
session at the Verdigris House?
Th-The Verdigris House?!
You've gotta be kidding!
A night at that super high-class brothel
could cost a year of my salary!
If you're worried, you can show them
one of these introduction letters.
Pairin. Joka. Meimei.
Th-That's even less believable!
Those are the Three Princesses that not even
the highest-rank officials can afford!
If you can't believe it, that's just too bad.
Huh?!
My deepest apologies for
having wasted your time.
W-Wait...
It's very unfortunate, but I'll just
have to ask someone else.
Please forget I mentioned this.
She has other contacts?!
Hairpins with rose quartz and silver?!
They're obviously from
people who far outrank me.
Just who is this girl?!
In that case, what she said might be...
No, it's too suspicious!
But if it is true, I'll never get another
chance to meet the Three Princesses again...
What should I do?!
So, what will it be?
I lose.
Congratulations, Maomao!
Who would have thought
you'd go before any of us...
I'm so glad!
You must've met someone nice!
Uh, thank you?
Why are you so casual about this?!
Don't worry, I'll bring back souvenirs.
How'd you meet this guy?
Um, coincidence?
I'm pretty sure she has no idea
what the hairpin means.
Yes, I'm sure of it. I feel so
sorry for a certain someone.
This is so amusing.
I wonder what kind of face he'll make...
I suspect some turmoil in the future...
Jinshi was finally able to finish up
his work and find time to visit
the day after Maomao had already left.
Maomao took off with someone.
On a three-day homecoming.
The pleasure district where
I grew up isn't far away.
It's walking distance from the rear palace,
just beyond the walls and moats.
A carriage? How extravagant.
Well, the Three Princesses
of the Verdigris House are
idolized by the population. Worshiped, even.
Just being able to meet
them would be an honor.
Oh, there it is...
The pleasure district!
There are girls who enter the brothels,
wanting to become like them.
But it's not easy.
Even if they become a serving girl,
a courtesan-in-training,
there's no guarantee that they'll make it.
So, this is the Verdigris House...
Yes.
Verdigris House
It's very dignified.
It's a long-standing, reputable brothel,
providing everything from middle-
to super-high-rank courtesans.
Hey, long time no see, Grams.
How has everyone—
What do you mean,
"long time no see?!" Stupid girl.
Are you okay?! What's with this old woman?!
This is the old madam,
proprietor of the Verdigris House.
I remember this used to help me
spit out all the poison I tried.
So, is this the good customer?
He's got a handsome face and a good build.
I heard you're a rising star, too.
Hey, why say that out loud to his face?
Hey, get Pairin.
She should be making tea today.
Yes, ma'am!
Pairin...
Master Lihaku, how strong are your arm muscles?
I do train pretty regularly.
This could be...
This way, please.
I'm getting nervous...
Make a good impression, okay?
Yeah.
So, why'd you vanish for ten
whole months without a word?
I had no say in the matter.
Didn't you read the letter I sent?
Of course I read it! That's why
I'm taking care of that guy for you,
even though we're introduction only!
I know, I know. I got half of my pay at
the rear palace early, as a special deal.
This isn't enough for Pairin.
Can we say it's enough for just some tea?
Idiot! Pairin won't leave
those muscles alone.
I knew it. But that's not
something I can control...
That won't fly! I'll add it to the tab.
I could never afford that...
In that case, bring more good customers.
Similar to that guy. Young, so that we can
drain him over a long period of time.
Would a eunuch be an acceptable customer?
No way. The courtesans
would pull out all the stops
and put the brothel out of business.
But I'd feel bad for Gaoshun
or the quack doctor...
Maomao, your old man should be
at home. Go visit him already.
Cross just one street, and the face of
the town changes dramatically.
Rough shacks, beggars,
and syphilitic streetwalkers.
Things haven't changed.
I'm home, Dad.
Welcome home. You were out for a while.
I'm finally home.
Yeah, on that day, I was out
getting dyes for my freckles, when...
I still have time left on my term, so I'll
go back to the rear palace in two days.
I see.
I'm sleepy, but I also want a bath.
You should borrow a bath at
the Verdigris House tomorrow.
Yeah, I'll do that.
The rear palace? What a twist of fate.
Not just some superficial sweetness
I want more warmth than I can even use, oh
Having these selfish idealistic thoughts
I swallowed them again today
before putting them into words
Still in my memories,
the scent of fragrant olive
The color of twilight in the city
We were laughing...
Filled with sadness,
the tears welled up in my eyes
I found a glow during those days
I guess I took everything for granted
The wind was so loud I covered my ears
I gotta stop being like that
Even if I stumble over the words of love
Next Time
Next time: "Wheat Stalks."
Episode 8: Wheat Stalks