The Apothecary Diaries
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all of the characters, organizations, and so on
are imaginary. It also bears no connection to any specific real-life events.
That man can't be trusted!
Episode 9: Suicide or Murder?
That'd create other issues.
Drinks! Bring more booze...
Wow, he's changed a lot.
Seeing his face makes the drinks taste bad.
On that, I can agree.
Hey... Thanks.
How much longer are you going to sulk?
I'm not sulking.
Please don't forget that
you're still on the job.
I understand.
He doesn't understand.
The one known as Jinshi does not
respond in such a childish way.
attach himself so strongly to a toy.
Here is some more work.
It took considerable effort to get
Concubine Gyokuyou to stop laughing
uncontrollably and explain.
Misunderstanding...?
The payment she gave in return
for acting as her guarantor
was a meeting with a star courtesan.
Who knew that girl had such connections?
Who knows what image
the master had in his mind?
Youth is a scary thing.
That said, to put so much effort
into finishing work quickly...
And going out to meet her...
Only to find out she had left
for home with another man...
That must have been quite a shock, for sure.
They should put more thought into these...
Many bureaucrats try to pass bills
that benefit them personally.
I feel sorry for my master, who has to do
extra work for those useless bills.
Master Jinshi!
It's already after hours. Can this wait?
It's not about work... Well...
Sir Kounen?!
Master Jinshi.
Let's go!
That's terrible news...
Someone high up bit the dust.
Maybe this is callous, but I can't
sympathize with someone
who I've never met or heard of.
A man past the age of fifty,
who died from drinking too much.
Clearly self-inflicted.
Since he went out of the way to make
the head lady-in-waiting leave...
Apothecary, do you think
the alcohol was really what killed him?
I knew he'd ask.
Anyone who likes alcohol should know that
overindulgence in drink is poison in essence.
Drinking constantly can sicken the organs.
Drinking too much in one
sitting can lead to death.
It was a party for a group of co-workers,
and I heard he had a lot to drink.
That could kill him.
But Sir Kounen could
really handle his drink.
I don't think overindulgence would kill him.
The man who died was named Kounen.
He was a dynamic warrior
who drank entire jars of alcohol,
and had a well-liked personality, to boot.
Gaoshun.
Yes.
This is the drink from that party.
Ooh, booze!
The specific jar that Sir Kounen drank from
got dropped on the floor
and the contents were lost.
So, if that jar had poison in it,
we'd have no way of knowing.
Indeed...
How modest. He realizes
he's asking for the impossible.
He should just be excessively
shiny like his usual self.
For a while now, Master Jinshi has seemed
much more childish than before.
It's both sweet and salty.
Like someone took a sweet
drink and added salt to it...
What's wrong?
It's a distinct taste.
Yes. Sweet, isn't it?
That's how Master Kounen liked it.
He had a serious sweet tooth.
He'd never lay a finger on even
the finest smoked meats and rock salts.
Huh...
I heard he used to love spicy foods, but
suddenly developed a sweet tooth one day.
Even his meals became all sweets.
That'll cause diabetes.
Stop spoiling my nostalgia with reality.
You're having more?
From spicy to sweet, huh?
Were there salts available at the party?
Yes. Rock salts, moon cakes, and dried meat.
Do you want those, too?
No, I'll be done with the drink by then.
That's not what I meant...
Can you get the jar that
Master Kounen was drinking from?
It's broken and in pieces.
That's fine.
Also, there's one thing
I want you to look into.
Excuse me.
Here is the report.
Thank you.
I knew it.
Here's the bottle.
Is it safe to lick that?
There's no poison here.
Salt?
Yes. Master Jinshi, you mentioned how Master
Kounen suddenly developed a sweet tooth, right?
And that he only ate sweet foods after that?
Yes.
Yet this jar contained so much salt
that it left crystals behind when it dried.
Salt is essential to the human body,
but too much salt can also be poisonous.
So, the cause of his death is...
Given the amount he drank,
and the salt included,
it's easy to conclude this was the cause.
Yes, but you should be able to tell
if something tasted this salty—
But he didn't. Please take a look at this.
It's a report on Master Kounen's lifestyle.
Judging from what's written here,
it seems like Master Kounen
lost his ability to taste salt.
Oh, no...
Kounen seemed like a serious
and skilled bureaucrat,
with a stoic personality.
Many years ago, he lost his wife
and child to an epidemic.
From that day on, he was all work, all day.
His only forms of entertainment
were drinking and sweets.
There is an illness that
eliminates the sense of taste.
It can be caused by
an unbalanced diet or stress.
Serious people will sometimes
repress their feelings,
and that stress could lead to illness.
So, who put the salt in the bottle?
That's not for me to determine.
However, there was also salt
in the drink I had yesterday.
It could have been put there
by someone at the party
who didn't like sweet drinks.
Alternatively, there are many who
resent overly serious coworkers.
Maybe they put some salt in the drink
because they didn't like him and
wanted to pull a little prank.
But because he kept drinking
seemingly without issue,
perhaps they kept adding more,
hoping he would notice.
Gaoshun.
Yes.
Understood.
I'm a coward.
I've practically named the culprit at this
point, given the amount of hints I dropped.
But I don't want to be directly
responsible for someone getting punished.
Sorry for your trouble. Thank you.
It's fine.
An obsidian tassel...
He's in mourning.
Was he such a person of high esteem?
Yes. He helped me a lot when I was younger.
He seems like a normal young man.
I guess he is human, after all.
Oh, right.
Huh?
Here's your reward.
A bottle?
Yes. It's not the same
as the one from yesterday.
Booze!
Don't drink it out in the open.
Yes! Thank you!
You don't seem all that grateful.
Is that so? Perhaps you
should return to your work.
That reaction... I bet he's slacking off.
Perhaps you should finish it
before it starts piling up.
I am working seriously...
What kind of work?
For example, there's a certain bill.
The idea is to set an age limit
for alcohol consumption,
to prevent young ones from
losing themselves in drink.
Huh?
The bill proposes a ban on drinking
alcohol until the age of twenty.
Master Jinshi...
Please, please don't pass that bill!
Hmm. Well, it's not something
I can decide on my own.
M-Master Jinshi!
Doctor!
This way!
There it is!
We're lucky it's winter now.
She's still in good shape,
despite being a drowned corpse.
How can you look directly at her?
Where was she found?
She was floating in the outside moat.
From her dress, we assumed
she was a servant at the rear palace.
I see. That's why they called our doc.
But a doctor in charge of
autopsies acting like this...
He truly is a quack.
Little lady, can I leave this to you?
Nope.
Huh?
I've been ordered to not touch corpses.
That's unexpected.
Master Jinshi!
Greetings, Master Jinshi.
You don't seem to be
uncomfortable around corpses.
I've gotten used to them.
The pleasure district is just
one street away from lawless chaos.
Why can't you touch corpses?
My teacher told me not to.
Is it an aversion to death?
No...
It's because humans can become
medicinal ingredients, too.
Given your curiosity, once you give that a try,
it wouldn't be long before
you start digging up graves.
Do not cross that line, ever.
Y-Yes.
I see.
What a rude response.
Doctor, could you please
do a proper autopsy?
Understood...
Eek!
"Eek," indeed...
She's tall. Hard wooden shoes...
Bandages on one foot...
Fingers are all red.
It must have been cold in that water.
The girl was a servant and was
working normally yesterday.
The guard believes she climbed the wall
last night and threw herself in.
A suicide.
Suicide...
What do you think?
I can't tell if she committed suicide,
but I think it was impossible
for her to do it alone.
What do you mean?
There were no ladders on the wall,
and no other climbing tools.
The rear palace walls are at least
four times my height.
So, you mean she couldn't
have climbed it without tools.
In most cases.
Strictly speaking, scaling the wall
without tools is possible.
Do you remember the ghost issue
from a while ago?
Concubine Fuyou?
Yes.
I was wondering how she climbed the wall,
so I did a thorough investigation of it.
That's where I found the protrusions
that I believe the craftsmen used.
That said, it would be difficult
for most regular women,
especially those with
bound feet, like that servant.
Foot binding is a custom where
small feet are considered beautiful.
It's not done on all women,
but I do occasionally see the distinct
walking style in the rear palace, too.
If it's not suicide,
are you saying it's murder?
I don't know that.
But I think it's fairly certain that
she was alive when she fell in the moat.
She must have clawed at
the walls to try to climb out.
Her fingers were bloodied and red.
Yes...
Suicide, or murder...
I would never think to take my own life.
I'd hate if someone killed me, too.
If I died, I wouldn't be able
to test any more drugs or poisons.
But if I were to die...
What are you thinking about?
About what kind of poison I would use to die.
Are you trying to die?!
Not at all. But nobody knows when they'll die.
Even if it's not something they
wished for, a malicious third party
can cause an undesired death.
Like with Master Kounen.
Nobody knows when it could happen.
There is no way to resist fate...
Master Jinshi.
What is it?
If you're ever tasked with executing me,
can you make sure it's with poison?
Where'd that come from?!
If I made a mistake, you would
probably be the one to give the order.
Did I step in it just now?
I'm sorry, it's not my place to say.
I won't complain if it's
a hanging or a beheading.
No, really, why are you saying all this?!
Because I'm a commoner.
My life is easily taken away
over the slightest mistake.
I would never do such a thing.
It's not a "would-or-would-not"
type of issue. It's "can-or-cannot."
Looks like I struck a nerve there.
If there's no further
business, I'll excuse myself.
Later, I heard through rumors
that the dead servant was at the garden
party where the poisoning took place.
They found a will with
some relevant content in it,
so the case was closed as a suicide.
The report from the other day is finally ready.
It's been two months since I asked for
you to find someone with burns on their arms.
You took too long.
I'm very sorry.
So, who is it?
Yes. It's actually higher up than I thought.
Fengming, from the Garnet Pavilion.
Head lady-in-waiting under Concubine Ah-Duo.
I see.
You're excused.
Concubine Ah-Duo...
Not just some superficial sweetness
I want more warmth than I can even use, oh
Having these selfish idealistic thoughts
I swallowed them again today
before putting them into words
Still in my memories,
the scent of fragrant olive
The color of twilight in the city
We were laughing...
Filled with sadness,
the tears welled up in my eyes
I found a glow during those days
I guess I took everything for granted
The wind was so loud I covered my ears
I gotta stop being like that
Even if I stumble over the words of love
Next Time
Next time: "Honey."
Episode 10: Honey