The Apothecary Diaries
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all of the characters, organizations, and so on
are imaginary. It also bears no connection to any specific real-life events.
Episode 10: Honey
I heard about the servant
who drowned. It was a suicide!
She was a servant at the Garnet Pavilion.
I heard she was the one who poisoned
Lady Lishu's food at the garden party...
I wonder if she did it because
she served Concubine Ah-Duo?
You mean, Pure Consort Ah-Duo?
Yeah. She's going to lose her title
as one of the four consorts
to be replaced by a new,
younger concubine, I hear.
Concubine Ah-Duo is one year older
than the emperor, at 35 years old.
She had a male baby with the emperor once,
back when he was still a prince, but lost him.
It's too bad, but the whole rear palace
system is built for creating many babies.
Mother of a dead male baby.
Will the same thing happen to Lady Lihua,
if she can't have another baby?
There's no guarantee that Lady Gyokuyou
will continue to have the emperor's love.
Even the most beautiful
flowers wilt over time.
The flowers of the rear palace are
meaningless unless they bear fruit.
I gotta go now.
Oh. Take this, too.
They're leftovers from yesterday's tea party.
Thanks!
Enough snacks to have leftovers?
Tea parties are awesome.
I'm not so sure.
A tea party is definitely a form
of work for a concubine.
Maomao, help us set up!
Another one?
You're working quite hard for this one.
Obviously. This time,
it's a high-ranked concubine,
the Virtuous Consort, Lady Lishu!
The politics of the rear palace
is well-represented here.
Welcome, Concubine Lishu.
Thank you.
Non-stop probing of each other's thoughts.
Is it part of the nature of being a woman
to be cautious of the same sex?
To be honest, they seem more wary
than when the emperor is here.
The way Lady Gyokuyou gleans
information through polite conversation
shows how skilled of a concubine she is.
I heard she sends the information
she gathers to her family back home.
Being a trade hub, it must be
important to understand the times.
The taster at the garden party.
I'm glad to see she hasn't been
too harshly punished.
I'm not going to bite her head off or anything.
The other servants aren't paying
attention to their mistress at all.
That said, it doesn't seem like they're
actively harassing her, either.
If my report to Master Gaoshun
was mistaken, that's fortunate.
Do you have any issues with sweets?
I love sweets.
Great.
It's cold out, so I was
wondering if you'd like this.
It's orange peels boiled
in honey. It'll warm you up.
I hope you like it.
Hmm? She can't handle honey, either?
Is she being a picky eater again?
She won't even eat something served to her?
I know, right?
Lady Gyokuyou.
Oh, my. Ailan, I'm sorry.
I think this one needs to
be boiled a bit longer.
Let me get you something else.
How about hot ginger water?
Yes, that's fine.
Unfortunately, it seems like
I wasn't wrong about the bullying.
We'll clean up here.
Maomao, you can rest.
I can clean too, you know...
How was the tea party for
Concubines Gyokuyou and Lishu?
I thought it was odd how that
tea party happened so suddenly.
So, it was this guy's idea, after all.
They had a enjoyable time.
I'm not done with you.
Could you please let go?
Did you hear that
the garden party poisoning
was done by the Garnet Pavilion
servant who committed suicide?
I heard the rumors.
Do you think she really committed suicide?
That's not for me to determine.
Why would a common servant
poison Concubine Lishu?
I don't know.
Well then, can you go help out at
the Garnet Pavilion, starting tomorrow?
"Can" I? It's not like I have a choice.
Understood.
Mansions are painted in their
masters' colors, figuratively speaking.
Concubine Gyokuyou's
Jade Pavilion feels homey,
while Concubine Lihua's
Crystal Pavilion felt refined and noble.
The Garnet Pavilion, home to Concubine Ah-Duo,
was practical and simple,
yet polished and classy.
My apologies for summoning you so suddenly.
I'm looking forward to working
with you over the next three days.
Master Jinshi didn't tell me
to do anything specific.
I guess I should just work.
These are new faces.
Fengming, who are they?
Temporary help for our big cleaning day.
I see. Thanks for the help.
Ah-Duo, the Pure Consort.
She's neither showy nor voluptuous,
but she has an androgynous,
almost gallant kind of beauty.
She's really thirty-five?
If she dressed differently,
she'd pass as a young civil servant.
She'd probably look better in a riding suit,
instead of her skirt and dress.
Whoa, those longing stares.
Does she remind me of someone?
Lady Fengming, the head lady-in-waiting.
I expected the Pure Consort's
head lady-in-waiting
to be from an important family,
but she's surprisingly approachable.
Can you air the books out?
You can ask the eunuchs
to handle the heavy items.
She really is the oldest
high-ranking concubine.
Despite the efficient look,
the mansion has a whole lot of stuff.
Similar to the Jade Pavilion, the servants
at the Garnet Pavilion are hard workers.
Certain fools who are all talk
could learn a thing or two.
Phew.
I guess that's it.
Incredible. You did this much already?
And so thorough, too. Can you
help with the parlor, as well?
Yes.
She's friendly, observant,
and praises others well.
Seems like she's skilled at handling
others as head lady-in-waiting.
I haven't done so much
physical labor in a while.
Good work. Thank you for your help today.
You're welcome.
Oh, I know. You'll be
staying here tonight, correct?
Follow me, please.
A sweet smell?
Please use this. It'll get cold tonight.
Thank you.
Rest well.
Master Jinshi didn't tell me
to do anything specific.
But...
Is the mastermind behind
the poisoning really here?
They really are all hard workers.
Not just the ladies-in-waiting, but...
Lady Fengming! We can take care of that!
Don't worry about it.
It's just something I noticed.
Lady Fengming is the leading example.
She's well past her prime,
but would have made a great wife.
I wonder if she never
considered getting married.
Did she choose to serve
Concubine Ah-Duo for life?
Strong loyalty is a possible
motive for the poisoning.
Now that a new concubine is about to enter,
the high-ranking concubine at
the most risk is Concubine Ah-Duo.
But what if a vacancy
opened up elsewhere first?
The emperor is only interested
in ripened fruit.
He doesn't visit Lady Lishu.
That's fine, given her age of fourteen,
but one could also claim she's not
serving her role as concubine.
If someone were to poison
someone for Concubine Ah-Duo,
it wouldn't be out of the question
to target Lady Lishu.
Can someone help me out here?
Honey?
Lady Fengming's family runs an apiary.
No wonder there's so much honey here,
despite it being so expensive.
That must have been
the sweet smell from last night.
Lady Lishu?
Accompanied by just the one taster?
Why is she at the Garnet Pavilion?
Coming to think of it, at the tea party...
That's what happened at the Garnet Pavilion.
I see.
And?
That's it. No "and" or "but."
I don't know what he wants.
I'm just an apothecary.
If he wants a spy,
he's asking the wrong girl.
What's with his casual
attitude recently, anyway?
Let's change the question, then.
If one of them could contact the outside
using some special method,
who would that be, you think?
What a roundabout way of asking.
I suppose the only possibility would be
Lady Fengming, the head lady-in-waiting.
Based on what?
She had bandages around her left wrist.
Those colored text plates were wrapped in
a woman's dress with burns on the sleeves.
Why would anyone make multi-colored fires?
One possibility is that it was a code.
Honestly, that gentle head lady-in-waiting
didn't seem like she was
part of a conspiracy.
But that's just my opinion.
I suppose that's acceptable.
I'm sure he knew this already,
eating honey so ostentatiously.
A good child needs to be rewarded.
I r-respectfully decline.
No need to be modest.
No, thank you! Please offer it to someone else!
This guy thinks he can get away with
anything because he has a pretty face!
Oh, right, that's the kind of
pervert he's always been!
Master Gaoshun!
He's getting laxatives in his food later!
Do you not like sweets?
I like spicy foods.
But you can eat this, right?
Damn it, he won't listen...
If he weren't so high up,
I'd kick him in the groin...
Wait, there's nothing to kick there.
Should I just accept this as an order?
Or escape to maintain my dignity?
If this was aconite syrup,
I'd have just accepted it.
Do you have any issues with sweets?
I hope you like it.
Honey?
Lady Fengming's family runs an apiary.
Lady Lishu?
Syrup...
Honey.
Apothecary?
What are you doing to my lady-in-waiting?
Concubine Gyokuyou! I was just—
On whose authority are you doing this?
Xiaomao, this was just a prank gone too far.
Could you forgive Master Jinshi?
In that case, next time you can do
the licking for me, Master Gaoshun.
L-Licking? That's a bit...
Fine, you get the point.
Also, there are a few things
I want to check on.
Excuse me.
Welcome, I—Oh?
Master Jinshi's not with you?
I'm afraid not. Apologies
for the sudden intrusion.
So, what do you want,
Jade Pavilion lady-in-waiting?
I have a question for you.
I remember you from the garden party.
What is it?
Do you dislike honey?
How did you know?!
I saw it on your face.
Did honey upset your stomach in the past?
It's common for someone to get food poisoning
and have trouble with honey after that.
That's not it. I don't remember.
It was when I was a baby.
I heard it was life-threatening.
Banned
Since then, my nurses told me to not eat it.
Where are your manners?
Probing Lady Lishu like that.
Says the lady-in-waiting who didn't even
try to protect her at the tea party.
What's with that look?
There's no need to listen to her.
That's right, she's being rude to
the Virtuous Consort. We should expel her!
So this is how they paint outsiders as the
villain to pretend they are the only allies.
We're always looking out for Lady Lishu.
It would be easy to trick a naive girl.
Who does she think she is?
The isolated concubine has nobody
to rely on but her ladies-in-waiting.
Not knowing she's being harassed...
It's a vicious cycle.
I am here on orders.
If you have objections, please take
them up with Master Jinshi.
To Master J-Jinshi?!
Directly?!
He owes me this much, at the very least.
Let's see what reasons they come up with
to approach the pervert eunuch.
And one more thing.
Are you familiar with Lady Fengming,
head lady-in-waiting at the Garnet Pavilion?
Xiaomao?
Master Gaoshun, is there
any way I can learn about
past events that happened
in the rear palace?
I can search the court library.
Thank you.
What did she figure out this time?
She's a smart girl, especially
given that she's only seventeen.
Her knowledge and calm composure...
Her ability to logically think through
and deal with various issues...
She does have some peculiarities,
but it's still impressive.
Seventeen years ago, when
the current emperor was still a prince...
He had a son with Concubine Ah-Duo.
The baby's already gone, but...
He was born around the same time
as the prior emperor
and empress dowager's son,
In other words, the current
emperor's little brother.
That was the only child
the emperor had as a prince,
and Lady Ah-Duo was his only concubine.
It says the current emperor and
Concubine Ah-Duo are foster siblings,
so that explains his attachment to her...
But it's surprising to learn a man that
lustful only had one concubine back then.
Sixteen years ago, the baby died.
The baby was delivered by...
Doctor Luomen
I did have that hunch.
Several of the herbs growing in the rear
palace were the same ones I used growing up.
Someone must have transplanted them.
A man who drags his feet like an old woman.
A doctor overqualified for the position
of a pleasure district apothecary.
A former eunuch with a bone
removed from one knee.
...Luomen, expelled...
What were you doing,
Dad?
Not just some superficial sweetness
I want more warmth than I can even use, oh
Having these selfish idealistic thoughts
I swallowed them again today
before putting them into words
Still in my memories,
the scent of fragrant olive
The color of twilight in the city
We were laughing...
Filled with sadness,
the tears welled up in my eyes
I found a glow during those days
I guess I took everything for granted
The wind was so loud I covered my ears
I gotta stop being like that
Even if I stumble over the words of love
Next Time
Next time: "Reducing Two to One."
Episode 11: Reducing Two to One