The Apothecary Diaries
Jade Pavilion
Maomao
What should I do...
What should we do?
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all of the characters, organizations, and so on
are imaginary. It also bears no connection to any specific real-life events.
After Fengming's execution,
her family's assets were confiscated,
and all underwent varying degrees
of corporal punishment.
Fengming was determined to
be the sole perpetrator,
so fortunately, her mistress
Concubine Ah-Duo was not blamed.
And now, here is the list of Fengming's family
members and those connected to them.
The list includes those
who did business with them.
They had many businesses
in addition to apiculture.
There are about eighty children of those
families here in the rear palace.
Eighty out of two thousand, huh?
That's quite a hit ratio.
Jade Pavilion
Maomao
The family that the apothecary was kidnapped
and sold off to was one such family.
If you wish, we could conceal this.
If "I" wish...
Indeed.
It doesn't matter if it's right or wrong.
If I say so, it will be done.
Given how she likes to separate
the commoners from the nobles,
she'd obey any order, no matter
how much she disagrees.
It would be simple to give the order.
I should just simply give the order.
Conceal the facts, and keep
her at the rear palace.
But if that goes against her will...
How would she feel, if she learned she'd been
forced to stay in a place she disliked so?
I'm so afraid of the rift between
the two of us widening any further.
Master Jinshi.
I thought she was just a convenient pawn.
Mass layoffs?
Yep.
Episode 12: The Eunuch and the Courtesan
The daughters of anyone who did business
with that family are being let go.
And it seems like there's quite a few of them.
Huh...
There are girls around who have to quit
all of a sudden and are in a real bind.
I guess that family really
did a lot of business.
I have a bad feeling about this.
Getting fired now would be bad.
It's just bad timing.
After Lihaku, I haven't been able to send
any more paying customers to the old lady.
If I go back now...
I'm home.
You have a customer!
She'll sell me off for sure!
Maomao?!
Last I checked, the family on my
paperwork were merchants.
If Fengming's family ran an apiary,
there might be some sort of connection...
Master Jinshi!
That's rare. You're out of breath.
Uh...
Calm down. You're red all over.
I would like to talk to you!
Sure. Let's speak inside.
This is about the mass layoffs, I take it?
Yes. What's going to happen to me?
Here's the list.
Jade
Pavilion
Maomao
So, I'm being let go.
What do you want to do?
I thought she was just a convenient pawn.
As Lady Gyokuyou's lady-in-waiting,
I can test for poisons and
hang out in the medical office.
I have to admit I'm enjoying my current life.
But I'm just a servant, after all.
I'm in no position to request to stay.
I have to make sure
I don't appear like I'm begging.
I am a mere servant.
I'll do as you order, whether it be
manual labor, cooking, or tasting.
As I order...
Yes. I'll do my best, if ordered to do so.
If I take a pay cut, so be it.
As long as I can buy time before getting
sold off, I'll figure something out.
So please, don't fire me!
Understood.
Do you mean...
I'll make sure you're compensated.
Huh?
Negotiation failed. Maomao is let go.
There we go.
How long are you going to stay like that?
Perhaps you should have
ordered her to stay.
Not another word.
A week after being fired,
Xiaomao went home to the pleasure district.
I heard she politely went around
saying her farewells to every single
place she had business with.
You're going to regret this.
Finding a new toy to replace his favorite
one has always been a challenge.
No! I want that one!
Or perhaps...
That girl should not be treated
as the same as a toy.
He only let her go because
he didn't want to treat her as a tool.
What a troublesome master he is.
If finding a replacement won't do...
Perhaps I can speak to that military officer.
Wah, wah, boo-hoo, sob, sob...
You do look much better without your freckles.
You can use my lipstick.
I never thought I'd be going
to a party with Maomao.
My workplace tonight is a noble's
party outside the brothel.
Calling a courtesan to one's
own mansion costs quite a sum.
In addition...
A night of drinks with one of
the Verdigris House's Princesses
costs what most make in a year.
So to call on all three at once...
I guess there's no limit to
how rich a rich person can be.
I'm going with you, but just
so you look better by comparison.
Here you go, Maomao.
Because I was paid more than
expected when leaving the rear palace,
I was able to avoid getting
sold off immediately.
That's an important job, too.
Looking forward to it, Maomao.
Oh! So cute.
It's time! Hurry up! Hmm?
Well, well, that's not bad at all.
You could take on customers
of your own too, you know.
The old lady really wants me
to become a courtesan.
Go make a fortune!
I can't recite poetry or play the erhu.
Dancing is out of the question.
I'm just an apothecary's daughter,
with no interest outside of medicine.
So why is she so insistent,
especially these past few years?
This person sure is loaded.
Every piece of furniture is
unimaginably expensive.
I'm sure they wouldn't notice
one thing taken as a souvenir...
No! Knock it off.
This room, please.
I heard Master Lihaku introduced us
to these high-ranking palace officials.
They're younger than I expected.
Yum.
Come, let's go.
If he knows so many rich people, he should
have introduced them to me sooner.
With his connections, I could
have lessened my loan amount.
Anyway, off to work.
Work is work, but staying
all smiles is quite an ordeal.
Hmm? Is he bored?
Excuse me.
Leave me alone.
I want to be alone.
Huh? Where have I heard this voice before?
Master Jinshi?
Why avoid me?
Please don't touch the courtesans.
Do people tell you that makeup
changes you considerably?
I do get that a lot.
Besides, why are you dressed like that?
I'm working part-time.
As a courtesan?
Yes.
Does that mean you're...
This guy is really prone to
casting doubt on my chastity.
I don't take personal customers.
Yet.
"Yet..."
So, what if I bought you out?
Huh? What kind of joke is—
That might be a good idea.
Working in the rear palace again
wouldn't be too bad.
I thought you quit
because you hated it there.
Huh? When did I ever say that?
I tried convincing you to let me stay,
but you fired me anyway.
True, there was a lot of trouble.
But where else would I be able
to perform as a taster?
The only thing I missed
were my poison experiments.
You should really stop
experimenting with poison.
He's even more childish today than before.
That's right. That's the kind
of person you are.
What does that mean?
Do people ever say that you
don't express yourself clearly?
I do get that a lot.
So why flinch?
Rules are rules.
Can't you bend them a bit?
No.
It's not the end of the world.
It's ending my spirit.
Just one hand. Just the tip of my fingers.
That's right, this guy
can be really persistent.
Fine, just the fingers.
This guy!
The color sticks!
Goodness, what's this?
Oh, Maomao.
I can't watch.
Come on, big sisters!
Master Gaoshun?! What? Huh?!
I couldn't make sense of any of it.
I don't remember much of
what happened after that.
So, who was that?
How do you know him?
Not bad, you!
I do remember that it was really hard
answering all my big sisters' questions.
Verdigris House
And...
I should make some, just in case.
Wandering around without
my freckles leads to no good.
That was winter last year...
Getting kidnapped was enough of a surprise,
but to be sold off
to the rear palace, of all places...
Then to get promoted to a lady-in-waiting.
I wanted to lay low until
my term was over, but...
Maomao. Is it ready?
Yeah, here.
I need you to take a look at
someone. Can you come with me?
Got it.
The rear palace, huh?
I really wanted to avoid
that place at all costs.
I wonder if everyone's okay.
Oh, I'll get out.
Take your time. You don't get to
come here all the time.
Yeah.
What are you going to do from now on?
I'll pay back my loans, I promise.
That's a given!
Are you going back to the rear palace?
I don't know.
But... the rear palace and
the brothels are pretty similar.
Hmm.
Having trouble sleeping?
I'm going to go get some air.
Take care.
I will.
The rear palace and
the brothels are no different.
A garden, and a cage.
What's going to happen from now on?
It's freezing.
Verdigris House
A few days later, a beautiful noble
comes to the pleasure district.
With him, he brings enough cash
to make the old lady's eyes glisten,
and for some reason...
A strange herb growing from an insect...
And in exchange, he asks for a certain girl.
The Apothecary Diaries
Next Time
Next time: "Serving in
the Outer Court."
Episode 13: Serving in the Outer Court