The Apothecary Diaries
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all of the characters, organizations, and so on
are imaginary. It also bears no connection to any specific real-life events.
Episode 14: The New Pure Consort
Are you serious?
Of course.
Maomao's back. I have to make
the best of that situation.
That should do for now.
Unlike the rear palace, there are barely
any herbs growing in the outer court.
I need to work on fixing that.
Xiaomao.
I thought I asked you to clean the office.
Right away!
Don't spend too much time on gardening.
She's tough.
What's going on?
I have no idea.
Crystal Pavilion
Wise Consort
Lihua
Jade Pavilion
Precious Consort
Gyokuyou
Hmm.
Excuse me.
Hmm?
Do you know about the new Pure Consort
who just entered the Garnet Pavilion?
Yes.
The replacement for
Concubine Ah-Duo, who left.
Well, the rear palace wants
to educate the concubine.
And for some reason, they want
you to be the teacher.
Teacher
Maomao
Hah, that's a funny joke.
Nobody's joking. Look who recommended you.
Recommended?
Precious Consort
Gyokuyou
And here's another.
Wise Consort
Lihua
Lady Lihua, too?
Oh...
It was that, huh?
I'm counting on you.
I can't ignore a request from two concubines.
They were nice enough to clearly
write the payment amount.
Our old lady is surely
hiking up that price, though.
Now's my chance...
This is all teaching
material for your class?
Yes. And here's the invoice.
This seems about right.
I wonder why the ink is
a different color here.
Yikes!
She really is tough.
I guess I can't prey on our young master
while this old maid is around.
What's inside?
I can't let him see my
precious teaching material.
F-Fine, I won't look.
Do you need help carrying it?
I'm fine.
If I have to do it, I'm going all the way.
It's been a while.
It's relaxing, this weird girly atmosphere.
It's Master Jinshi!
He's so beautiful as always.
This is quite a crowd.
They must have heard
the rumors about the lesson.
Just so you're all aware, only the high-ranking
concubines will be attending today.
If you have no other business, you may leave.
Is this eunuch some
sort of mythical monster?
No!
Why?
Only the high-ranking concubines will
attend the lesson. You said so yourself.
Dammit, he's built tougher than he looks.
What we'll discuss is a secret
technique for women only!
Lady Gyokuyou.
Beautiful, as always.
Seems like Lady Hongniang
hasn't changed, either.
Lady Lishu seems very nervous.
I guess it's natural, seeing how there are
three other high-ranking concubines here.
As long as that taster is with her,
she should be better off than before.
Lady Lihua seems to have recovered
fully to her healthy, voluptuous form.
Hmm? Is that the lady-in-waiting
from the face powder incident...?
She doesn't have to be so wary of me.
And Concubine Ah-Duo's replacement,
the new Pure Consort, Concubine Loulan.
Is that flashy southern
outfit her usual style?
Her face seems northern, but I can't tell
what she really looks like under all that.
Given her age, the emperor
will most likely spend time with her.
It seems the power balance at the rear
palace shouldn't be negatively affected.
Eh. Who cares.
My name is Maomao. I will be
serving as your instructor today.
What I will be teaching you today
is a secret technique
shared only amongst women.
Please do not share it with others.
Now, here are the learning materials.
Wow!
Oh... Oh...
What's going on in there?
I can't tell.
Phew. Hmm?
Good work. That took a while.
This guy was eavesdropping for sure.
What's wrong?
What's going on here?
Goodbye, tired routines!
Do this, then this...
No way. No way, ever...
Lady Lishu!
I just taught them, as ordered.
At least I made the two who
recommended me happy.
I couldn't tell what she was thinking at all.
Use the knowledge as you see fit.
Hey, what kind of lecture did you give?
You can ask the emperor later
if he liked it or not.
Hey.
I'm spent.
Looking forward to that bonus reward!
This way!
I'll stay out of it.
So cold...
Master Lakan! Master Lakan!
Master Lakan, there you are.
Hmm.
Something of interest?
No, nothing at all.
I wonder what that sound was last night.
Even though he's a eunuch, he has work
outside of the rear palace as well?
It's not like he can just ignore silly bills.
It's good paper. I could sell these
for a pretty good amount.
What a waste, burning it all.
The trash burning place is over
by the military offices...
Xiaomao.
It's cold outside.
Thank you.
He's so thoughtful. Shame he's a eunuch.
This is from Master Jinshi!
I merely delivered it!
I see.
He needs permission just to give warm
clothes to a servant? What a bother.
Thank you, Master Jinshi.
Don't worry about it.
The outer court is several times
larger than the rear palace,
yet I see hardly any medicinal herbs growing.
I guess the only notable ones
are dandelions and mugworts,
which are abundant anywhere.
It's winter, so they're hard to spot, too.
Maybe I'll plant some seeds
around here as well.
Ooh, red spider lily!
Here too! And there, too!
They're so tasty when
the bulb root is put in water.
If I fail to remove the poison, it causes
horrible stomachaches, though.
Hmm?
It's Master Lihaku.
His belt's a different color.
Did he get a promotion?
Hmm? Oh hey, little lady.
Master Lihaku.
Accompanying a concubine or something?
Rare to see you outside the rear palace.
He doesn't know I got fired.
Master Lihaku. He fell in love
with Big Sister Pairin,
one of the Three Princesses
of the Verdigris House.
He's working hard to get a promotion
for his love. How adorable.
Hmm?
The cost of a night with Pairin is equal to
half the annual salary of a commoner.
Since that's too expensive,
I hear he often visits the Verdigris House
to have tea with the servant girls.
I never ran into him there.
I guess once a man has a taste
of the heavenly nectar,
he can't help but try to get at least a glimpse.
He's really working hard.
Hmm? What is it?
Nothing. I've been transferred
from the rear palace
to the personal quarters of a certain official.
Personal quarters?
Who's crazy enough to do that?
Yeah, I wonder the same.
By the way, were you busy with something?
A little.
Just a small fire, not rare
at this time of the year.
I've been brought out to investigate
since they can't determine the cause.
Unknown cause? So that must be
what the noise from last night was.
Was anyone injured?
Just the warehouseman.
He's not critically injured, but—
Hey, don't get too close.
Understood.
Why wouldn't you expect me
to get curious after hearing that?
Soot reaching the adjacent building.
Shrapnel all over the building.
This is more like an explosion than a fire.
I see.
They suspect arson.
That's why Master Lihaku is here,
not a lower-ranking official.
This isn't just some random warehouse.
It's the palace, where the emperor is.
Our empire is overall pretty peaceful,
but there's always someone with issues.
There's the occasional barbarian attack,
and a famine or drought here and there.
Who knows how long peace with
the neighboring nations will last?
I'm sure some people in some foreign
countries have some complaints.
Charcoal? No, it's a burnt potato.
What a waste.
So this was food storage.
Ivory? Looks like a smoking pipe.
Quit snooping around by yourself!
A pipe...
An explosion. Food storage. A pipe.
Hey!
Can you hear me?!
I can hear you.
I'm just not listening to you.
Does this warehouse store the same kind
of stuff as the burnt one?
Yeah. The oldest things go in the back.
Can I have this?
I suppose so.
And this, too?
I also need a hammer, a saw, and some nails.
What are you trying to do?
Just a quick experiment.
This will do.
You're strangely good at this.
I grew up poor. I'm good
at making things I don't have.
That's flour, right?
Yes. It was in the warehouse.
Is this what you needed?
Yes. And the flame source I asked for?
Right here.
Thank you, sir.
I don't get it.
It's ready. Please stand back. It's dangerous.
Y-Yes...
Master Lihaku, it's dangerous.
What danger could there be?
Whatever you do, I'm a military
officer. How can I be at risk?
Understood. But it really is dangerous,
so please do be very careful.
You have to run right away.
Huh? Run from what—
Put it out!
See? I told you so.
So, what caused the explosion?
It was this.
Flour?
Yes. Fine powder, like wheat
or buckwheat flour, burns easily.
The particles can catch fire when airborne.
This was likely what sparked it.
A pipe...?
If someone snuck inside to take
a quick smoke in private,
the outside wind could flow in,
blowing the powder into the air.
If the pipe was lit at that time...
The flour filling the air would
catch fire, and cause an explosion.
Please let the warehousemen know
not to smoke in the warehouses.
How do you know these things?
Once, at the Verdigris House,
I blew up a room I borrowed.
You...
You stupid girl!
The old lady was real scary back then.
But powders exploding? How strange.
Almost nothing in the world is truly strange.
Anything that feels strange
is just not yet known.
Achoo!
Please take care to not catch a cold.
If you do, find Luomen in the pleasure
district. His medicines work well.
Right.
Dad's so bad at marketing.
I should help him out a little.
Hopefully, he'd pay a visit
while he's out there for Pairin.
Well, I'm heading back to work now.
Sure.
Oh, I accidentally brought this with me.
If I clean this up and put a new mouthpiece
on it, would it be good again?
It might sell for a pretty good price.
That said, it seems too impressive
for a warehouseman to own.
Might be something precious.
Maybe I'll clean it up and give it back.
Dammit!
I'm worthy, too... Dammit!
Next Time
Next time: "Raw Fish."
Episode 15: Raw Fish