The Apothecary Diaries
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all of the characters, organizations, and so on
are imaginary. It also bears no connection to any specific real-life events.
Hey, did you hear about the fire the other day?
Lihaku did a really good job with it.
I never expected he'd be able to solve it.
Actually, I heard a rumor that
a servant girl helped solve it.
A servant girl?
They say she's a personal
attendant of Master Jinshi.
Wow, really?
Didn't Master Jinshi buy out
a courtesan from the Verdigris
House the other day?
I hear she's a beautiful
intellectual with cold eyes.
Yeah, the guys who saw her
wouldn't shut up about her.
Master Lakan?!
Mind telling me more about that?
Episode 15: Raw Fish
Xiaomao, could you spare a moment?
Master Gaoshun. What is it?
There's something
I'd like you to take a look at.
Records of an old incident.
Ten years ago, at a merchant's home,
there was a food poisoning incident
involving a raw pufferfish dish.
Pufferfish poison...
I love how it tingles and stings.
Oh, I really want some now!
I can take you to a place
that serves it sometime soon.
So, what about this?
A while ago, I was officially
involved with this case.
A colleague asked me for advice, because
a similar incident occurred recently.
A similar incident?
A bureaucrat ate pufferfish, raw and seasoned
with vinegar, and fell into a coma.
A coma?
Master Gaoshun, my apologies.
Is it appropriate for me to learn about this?
That won't be an issue.
You are someone who knows her place.
In other words, stay silent about this.
Besides, this story involves poison.
Are you sure you want me to stop here?
Please, do continue.
Pufferfish
In this instance, they served
parboiled pufferfish skin and meat.
He ate this and fell into a coma.
The meat? Most of the poison is in the gut.
Yes, the skin and the meat.
The meat isn't supposed
to have much poison in it...
Maybe it depends on the type of
pufferfish or the environment it's from.
Nothing seems out of place, then?
The thing is, in both cases,
this time and in the past,
the cook claims they hadn't
used pufferfish in the dish.
That sounds interesting.
That's not the only thing in common.
The two who fell ill...
The bureaucrat from this case
and the merchant from the past one
were both gourmets who loved eating rare foods.
They both often ate raw fish and
pufferfish was one of their favorites.
After the incident, all of the organs
and skin were discovered in the trash,
so it was determined that
the guts were never consumed.
In both cases, the cooks claimed innocence, said
the pufferfish was served the night before,
and that on the day of the incident,
they'd used a different fish.
However, there were
no witnesses to provide proof.
The bureaucrat ate all the food served,
then became intoxicated
and collapsed half an hour later.
He was discovered convulsing.
He did a more thorough
investigation than I'd expect.
Plenty of other bureaucrats would put
in zero effort and just make up a suspect.
What do you think?
The symptoms do sound
like pufferfish poison,
but I can't say for certain
without more details.
Master Gaoshun, can you try
to find more information?
Understood. I will look into it.
At this time of year, it's not rare to
have food trash sit out for a few days.
The testimony of using different fish
matches the evidence of the leftovers...
What were you talking about?
That look would wound anyone, even me.
You seemed to be listening
very eagerly to Gaoshun's story.
People naturally pay attention to
stories that are actually interesting.
Wait, hold on. You often
cut me off mid-speech—
Oh dear, it's getting late.
With that, I'll take my leave.
Hey, I'm not done talking—
Oh no, don't move.
Come on, stay still.
Xiaomao, about the discussion
we had yesterday...
These are the cook's notes.
According to the servant, it describes
everything served to their master.
Thank you.
"Parboil the fish. Add cut vegetables.
Season with vinegar."
The recipe looks normal.
There are several types of
vinegar mixtures outlined,
but the list of ingredients lack detail.
That must be because the types of fish
and vegetables available differ by season.
This won't help us understand the key facts
around what was actually used to cook the dish.
You can't understand?
He wants to join in.
So, what can't you understand?
It will be mealtime soon.
I know.
That's quite childish.
When did the incident occur?
About a week ago.
Meaning winter vegetables,
so probably radishes and carrots?
Actually, I hear they used seaweed.
Seaweed?
Seaweed.
If he likes rare foods, I guess
he could have tried strange seaweeds.
If possible, could I take a look
at the kitchen involved?
I'm here under Master Gaoshun's orders.
I'm Basen. I've heard about you.
I am Maomao.
We're heading to the mansion now,
but remember, you're my follower.
Don't do anything without my permission.
Understood.
Once we arrive, the servant there
will show us to the kitchen.
Understood.
Master Gaoshun sure does work fast.
That aside...
I've never seen this officer before.
He looks familiar, though.
He doesn't seem to have
a good impression of me.
Oh, well.
This is the kitchen.
It hasn't been used since the poison incident.
Hmm? Hey!
Who let you in here?! Get out!
What are you doing?!
Did you bring these people here?!
I've gotten permission from the mistress,
and this is official business.
Is that true?
May we continue? Or would that
inconvenience you in some way?
Whatever.
Who is that?
That is the master's younger brother.
After the master fell into the coma,
and the mistress took ill from fatigue,
the younger brother manages the mansion.
I see.
Master Basen.
Yeah.
The cook washed all the cooking utensils.
Other than that...
What is this?
Ah, the master loved that.
It's his favorite. He ate it often.
I don't think it's poisonous...
He doesn't seem to be lying.
So that's that.
If you're done here, please leave.
Indeed.
Sorry to bother you.
Why did you back down so easily?
I don't consider that backing down.
You brought it with you?
This is strange.
This seaweed isn't in season quite yet.
But even if salted and preserved from
last year, it wouldn't last this long.
I see.
I don't think it was gathered in our region.
Perhaps it was imported from the south.
It would be good if we could
find out where it came from.
I think he gets what I mean.
In that case, I'll do what I have to do.
What's this?
The seaweed I got from the mansion.
I've split it into two
and put it in some water.
Why is Master Jinshi here?
The seaweed was indeed
imported from the south.
According to the servant, the master
never ate that seaweed in the winter.
The cook also said this is the same
as the seaweed they normally use,
and can't be poisonous.
You can't assume it's not poisonous
just because it's the same seaweed.
Maybe this seaweed
isn't eaten often in the south.
Perhaps a merchant learned that
it's a favorite of this bureaucrat,
and, looking to profit from that,
went out of his way to get some locals
to make a salted version of it?
Why is that a problem?
Sometimes, poisons can become not poisonous.
For example, eels are originally poisonous,
but by bleeding them out or cooking
them, they become edible.
In the case of this seaweed, I think
it had to be soaked in limewater first.
What I have here is one batch soaked in
limewater, and one batch without that.
What are you doing?!
It's fine.
Probably.
What do you mean, "probably"?!
Don't worry. I have
an emetic agent right here—
Don't say that so proudly!
Gaoshun!
Yes.
Hey—
Vomit, now!
I wanted to test if the detoxification
could be done overnight...
Um, back on topic.
So, the issue is: who suggested that
the trader bring the salted seaweed?
If the one who ate it imported it himself,
it'd be his own fault, in a sense.
But, if he didn't...
Bringing it in from a region
that doesn't eat it
is obviously taking a pretty big risk.
I understand.
The people here are smart.
I don't have to elaborate further.
I guess that settles it for now.
Hey!
The culprit was the official's younger brother.
When we found where he bought the seaweed,
he confessed to being
the one who'd purchased it.
His motive was that, being
the younger son, he wasn't treated well.
He wanted to remove his older
brother from the picture.
A commonplace story.
But how could a person who'd plot to murder
someone for such a thoughtless reason
have learned about the seaweed poison?
He happened to hear about it from a person
sitting next to him at a tavern, apparently.
"Happened to," huh? Sure...
In the end, I didn't get to try
the poisonous seaweed...
By the way, what should I use it for?
That mushroom the color of dry leaves
growing from the dead insect!
Should I make medicinal booze?! A pill?!
Welcome home!
What's going on?!
It's not my fault.
You seem tired.
I have so much work piled up,
but there's someone
I just don't get along with.
We just can't see eye-to-eye.
I never would have thought you'd
ever have trouble with people.
This man's a razor-sharp
high official in the military.
He comes from a good family, but even
though he's past forty, he hasn't married.
He adopted his nephew as his son
and has him handle his household.
A famous weirdo.
A forty-plus, high-ranking
military officer... and weirdo?
His only interests are go, shogi, and rumors.
He files complaints, barges in,
and keeps extending deadlines
on decisions that need to be made.
I think he has it out for me for some reason.
He's been camping in my office
for several days in a row.
Okay, let's forget about this!
No good can come from dwelling on this.
However, no matter how hard I try to forget,
as usual, my bad hunches are correct.
This matter was settled already.
Flower viewing in the winter is difficult.
I thought this would be better instead.
This man is Lakan. He is a strategist.
It seems like the reason
he's confronting me
is because I made Maomao, who is connected
to the Verdigris House, my servant.
Come to think of it, I have an old
acquaintance in the Verdigris House.
That's unexpected. I thought
he had no interest in romance.
What kind of courtesan is she?
Shoot, I asked without thinking.
She was a good courtesan.
She was very good at go and shogi.
I could beat her in shogi, but never in go.
Defeating our master strategist?
She must have been good.
I considered buying her out,
since I felt I would never meet
another woman as interesting as her.
But sometimes, things just don't work out.
Two rich men with curious tastes
endlessly tried to outbid each other.
Is that so?
It's said, at times,
buying out a courtesan
could cost about as much as a small palace.
She was a strange courtesan.
Where is he trying to go with this story?
She would sell her skills, but never herself.
In fact, she didn't treat
guests as customers at all.
Even when pouring tea,
she had an arrogant look,
like she was being charitable
to a lowly peasant.
But there were many with curious tastes
who were head over heels for her.
Myself among them, naturally.
That chill down my spine
was truly irresistible.
Oh, how I wanted to try
to force myself on her one day.
In the end, I couldn't give up on her,
so I had no choice but
to use a bit of a dirty trick.
Meaning?
If something's too expensive,
you simply lower its value.
I made her less exquisite.
Do you know how I did that?
Why play hard-to-get all of a sudden?
Well, before I get into that,
I have a favor to ask.
What is it?
I heard that the servant girl you hired
recently is quite intriguing.
They say she has a strange
knack for solving puzzles.
I was acquainted with a metalworker
who was the palace purveyor.
He suddenly passed away a few days ago,
and failed to name a proper successor.
He had three children who
were also his apprentices.
Unfortunately, he died before passing on
his secret techniques to his children.
He left a puzzling will, which might be a hint.
That's been bothering me for a while.
Where are you going with this?
Nowhere special, really.
I just wonder if there's some way
to learn that secret technique.
Perhaps, for example,
by having your clever servant girl take a look.
Well... I suppose I could hear the whole story.
That's a lot of rain.
Next Time
Next time: "Lead."
Episode 16: Lead