The Apothecary Diaries
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all of the characters, organizations, and so on
are imaginary. It also bears no connection to any specific real-life events.
This is a bit troublesome...
Huh?
He usually doesn't hesitate
to bring trouble my way.
How out-of-character for him.
What is it?
Well...
It's something related to
an acquaintance of an acquaintance.
A metalworker who was
the palace purveyor passed away
without passing on his techniques to
his sons, who were also his apprentices.
They say some of those techniques
were completely secret and unknown.
So, you want to figure out
the metalworker's secret technique.
You make it sound so simple.
Besides, why are you so
enthusiastic this time around?
Does it seem that way?
The metalworker's three sons
were all his apprentices.
As the father died, it's said that one of
the sons will take his place as the purveyor.
There were distribution instructions
for the father's mementos in his will.
The workshop shack for the eldest son.
Furniture with excellent workmanship
for the second son.
A fishbowl for the youngest son.
And one final note: "You all should have
a tea party together, like old times."
A tea party? What a mysterious will.
Did he mean a literal tea party?
Or does that have another meaning?
The sons have no idea after
hearing the will, either.
The mementos seem very unbalanced, too.
A shack, furniture, and a fishbowl?
The younger the son,
the lower the value, it seems.
What were those items like?
I haven't heard the details. But...
If that piques your interest,
here is the address.
He said, if it piques your interest,
you should go take a look.
How well-prepared.
It's like he expected this
to happen. Interesting.
If I can have time tomorrow...
Yeah...
I'll probably get more work
on my plate when I get back.
Episode 16: Lead
Oh, that's...
Basen, was it?
Like the last time, you're my follower.
Don't do anything unless I allow it.
Understood.
Like last time, he only
says the bare minimum.
I don't think he likes me much.
If he's harmless, I don't mind.
Coming.
Master Basen. We've been
notified of your visit.
Hmm?
Ah, yes, that belonged to my father.
He had a strange hobby,
collecting weird things.
Huh...
Is that the workshop shack?
Yes. That said, we do our work
in the main house now.
The shack is used as a tea house
for the craftsmen.
Come in.
Hey, I brought the guests.
Yeah.
Thank you for coming out.
These must be the elder brothers, and
the first man must have been the youngest.
The furniture is placed strangely.
Hey.
Indeed...
Having things in the center
like this would get in the way.
The room still looks kind of nice though,
probably because of how the table
weirdly brings the room together,
and how classy this chest of drawers looks.
There's metalwork on the corners.
The top row has three drawers. A keyhole
in the center drawer in the second row.
A different metal is used as an accent here...
Hmm?
Is this bolted in place?
Hey, that's mine.
You're free to look, but don't touch.
Right, the second son was given
furniture as his memento.
Hmph!
If this chest is the
aforementioned furniture,
then this man must be the second son.
Which must mean that the
tall man is the eldest son.
The window placement is strange, too.
It's western-style, and strangely tall.
Despite the ample sunlight
that could have come in,
the huge chestnut tree outside ruins it.
The sunlight that gets in is
filtered through the branches.
And this is the only spot
that gets that light.
Hmm?
This mark. Was something
placed here for a long time?
Can you really figure out
what our father left behind?
That's...
You'd have to elaborate on
your end for us to know more.
It's exactly as you heard.
Our father kicked the bucket without
giving us the secret technique.
And the only thing he left me is this shack.
And for me, this chest of drawers.
F-For me, this.
Made of glass, so it's expensive.
I assumed the fishbowl would
be wooden, or ceramic at best.
In that case, I guess all
the mementos have some value.
What was he thinking?
Thanks for this gift, but it only has
one key, which doesn't fit the keyhole.
Doesn't fit the keyhole?
This is probably the key for the center
row, but it won't fit the keyhole.
The three drawers on top are
supposed to open with the same key,
but the actual key is nowhere to be found.
What's the point of inheriting it?
I'm in the same boat. What's the point of getting
this shack if I can't move the chest out?
What a bother.
Dad was...
D-Dad was probably thinking...
I envy you. You got something
you could easily sell.
Yeah. It's not much, but it'd still be
worth enough to live off of for a while.
I don't get Dad at all.
What possible benefit could there
be to having tea party now?
Hmm, now what should we do?
The two elder brothers don't
seem too fond of the youngest.
All of you, stop this!
That's no way to behave in front of guests.
I'm so sorry. I don't know when
they started acting this way.
The two older boys have become so cynical.
And the youngest can't
even express his opinions.
My husband was worried about
them until the moment he died.
I guess being worried about your kids,
no matter how old they get,
is part of being a parent.
Please enjoy the tea. Excuse me.
They all moved. I guess
they each have a set position.
I suppose it must be just habit,
in order to not block the window.
This time of day, the sunlight
comes through the window.
If the sunlight reached a little
further, it might hit the chest...
But there's no sign of sun
damage on the chest.
Sun damage...?
Hey.
The sunlight doesn't come in
for too long of a time.
Is something stuck inside?
Did you figure something out?
Ah! I was thinking he looked familiar.
He looks like Gaoshun!
So?
The center drawer
with the lock won't open, right?
It used to open, but apparently
it got stuck after Dad worked on it.
And there's only one key?
Just this one.
Dad said if we broke the lock,
it would break whatever's inside.
So we can't force it open, either.
The mementos given to each son.
A shack, a chest of drawers, and a fishbowl.
The chest is bolted down in the shack.
The chest has drawers that can't be unlocked.
And...
"You all should have a tea party
together, like old times."
Could it be...?
Excuse me. Was the fishbowl
originally placed there, on that shelf?
Huh? Um, yes.
We used to have a goldfish
in it, and put it here.
If it got too cold, the goldfish would die,
so in the winter, we'd only put it here during
tea parties, when the sunlight kept it warm.
Around this time of day, actually.
We haven't had any goldfish
for the past few years, though.
Hmm.
Hey, you!
I'm going to go ask for some water.
Darting off without my permission again!
You filled it with water, like this?
Yes. This pattern should face this way.
I knew it.
H-Hey! What is this?!
Don't touch that!
I'm sorry. It could blind you
if it shined into your eyes.
Also, please step back, as you're blocking it.
You won't be able to unlock it.
It seems like the chestnut tree
is casting a shadow now.
It's hot. Also, there's a strange smell.
Hey, what's the meaning of all this?!
Now, please unlock this drawer with that key.
I told you, it doesn't fit.
Please.
Hmph.
W-What's going on?!
Did your father happen to suffer from
persistent anemia and stomachaches?
Yes, that's correct.
Nausea and depression, as well?
Those, too.
I don't know much about metalwork,
but do you use solder in this workshop?
Yes, we do.
What does that mean?
I just followed the instruction from the will,
to have a tea party like you used to.
A mold for a key.
May I remove it from the mold?
S-Sure.
It's still warm, and soft.
The metal stuck in the keyhole
must have melted from the heat,
and flowed into the mold
below it before hardening.
It's open!
What's inside?
What is this?!
This bluish crystal seems to be the same
kind as the one near the entrance.
Dammit! What does he mean, get along?
We all just got played by his final prank!
What a bother!
Lead and tin...?
I knew a grumpy craftsman of a customer who said
techniques should be seen and stolen.
I took that seriously and tried to make
my own medicine based on what I saw my dad do.
I ended up poisoning myself, and...
You should ask first.
That was the lesson he taught me.
It seems like the youngest son was the only
one who understood his dead father's intent.
I've heard that, by mixing several
different types of metals together,
solder melts at a temperature lower than
that of the individual metals originally.
Of the three chunks, two were lead and tin.
Those and whatever this third thing is
might mix to create a new metal.
Also, the light was
concentrated by the fishbowl,
but it wasn't heated for very long.
The melting point must be very low.
The differently-sized
drawers might represent
the ratio at which
the metals should be mixed,
but I don't need to comment on that.
What kind of will is this? Let's go.
What a waste of time.
Wait, guys!
It's not a prank.
What is it, then?!
Dad really did leave a will to make
the three of us get along again!
So I want the three of us
to continue working together!
Together? The three of us?
What a joke. You're different from us.
You have talent. Dad actually
cared about you, and only you.
T-That's not true!
Dad always trusted you two!
He always told me...
Chang, you're always so calm
and accurate with any work you do.
Dad said he could rely on you for anything,
because you don't make mistakes!
Tzu, you're good at getting to know people.
He said you should be proud of your gift,
the ability to be friendly with anyone!
Dad viewed the three of us equally.
At least, that's what I think.
Excuse us.
Oh, um, sorry.
Father... Well, it's got nothing to do with me.
Thank you.
But I should tell him just this one thing.
Hey.
There's an apothecary named
Luomen at a brothel called
the Verdigris House
in the pleasure district.
He's also a skilled physician.
If you start to feel unwell,
please pay him a visit.
Y-Yes.
Thank you for the other day.
It turned out quite interestingly.
The youngest son truly was
the most skilled, after all.
This strategist must have known all along.
He suddenly started to
show that skill of his.
They say he'll take his father's place and
begin selling his metalworks to the palace.
The older two sons are no longer
going to work as craftsmen.
Is that...
It can't be all that bad.
They took the hint from
their dead father, perhaps.
The eldest will take care of bookkeeping.
The second son will find new clients.
They're both going to help
the family from different angles.
In other words, they all found their place.
I don't know what happened at the mansion.
The apothecary girl must
know and is keeping silent.
The late metalworker's works
were truly wonderful.
It was a simple metal part, but if used on
a ritual utensil, it would look fabulous.
Indeed.
What an annoying person.
He must know, given my position,
ritual utensils don't mean anything to me.
I wonder why, master strategist,
you brought up—
Come now, I just didn't want
to keep good talent buried.
Elder or younger brother shouldn't matter.
Those with talent should receive attention.
He has a point. Lakan may be a shady man,
but he definitely can
discern talent in people.
It can be argued that he used that
ability to climb to his current rank.
By the way...
May I hear the rest of that story from earlier?
Which story?
The one about the courtesan.
Ah, yes! The way to decrease
the value of a courtesan.
You should direct that inquiry
to someone who knows that world.
Oh goodness, the time!
My subordinates would scold me
if I stayed any longer.
Please give this to your serving maids.
It's a good drink, not too sweet.
See you tomorrow.
Master Jinshi.
Hmm?
I'm sorry to bother you
when you're so tired, but...
Did you need me?
Do you know much about makeup?
Well, yes, the basics.
In that case,
can you do my makeup for me?
Huh?
Next Time
Next time: "A Jaunt Around Town."
Episode 17: A Jaunt Around Town