The Apothecary Diaries
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all of the characters, organizations, and so on
are imaginary. It also bears no connection to any specific real-life events.
In that case,
can you put makeup on me?
Huh?
He definitely doesn't need it.
There are many silly wars in history,
but several of them were
caused by beautiful women.
If this man, in all his heavenly
beauty, were to put on makeup...
Are you trying to topple a nation, or what?
Where'd that come from?!
Why does your imagination do that?
How do you make your freckles?
Ah, he wants to be less beautiful, not more.
I make some powder out of dried clay,
then mix that into oil.
Can you do that quickly?
Yes, preparing it takes just one night.
It's a bit too dark for you.
If only there was a drug that can change faces.
Applying lacquer to your face would do it.
But that would be permanent.
Sounds about right.
If you want to pretend to be a commoner,
that can be managed.
Do that for me, then.
I want to look like a completely
different person.
I wonder what he's up to.
That said...
If I'm doing it, I'm going all the way!
Episode 17: A Jaunt Around Town
Ugh, so cold.
Good morni—
Why the bad mood
first thing in the morning?
Nothing. I'm sure you're
going to be beautiful all day.
Is that a new form of sarcasm?
Master Jinshi, do you really want to
become a different person?
That's what I said last night.
In that case, excuse me.
Oh dear!
W-What are you doing, all of a sudden?
No commoner burns such expensive incense.
Your current outfit is, at best,
that of a lower-ranking official.
The most exquisite incense from overseas
should not be within your reach.
How do you know this?
I've trained my sense of smell to separate
medicinal and poisonous herbs.
Do you know how a brothel
identifies good customers?
No. Is it body build, clothing,
and things like that?
Those too, but one important thing is smell.
Those with multiple showy scents tend to
be rich but have venereal diseases.
Those who smell like livestock
don't bathe and are unclean.
Most new visitors to the Verdigris
House are shooed away.
Ah.
You should direct that inquiry
to someone who knows that world.
Master Gaoshun, can you find
a new set of clothes?
If possible, some that haven't been
washed yet and still smell.
Oh dear.
Understood.
Hey.
While he finds that...
What is that?
Oil and salt.
It dulls the sheen of his hair
and roughens the texture.
Excuse me.
That should do.
Goodness, must you use
a fabric scrap to tie it up?
Commoners use whatever is
available, as long as it works.
Are you sure this is acceptable?
Sniff. Sniff sniff sniff.
It could be smellier, but this will do.
Master Jinshi, please take your clothes off.
S-Sure.
Even though he's like a heavenly maiden,
he has a well-balanced, muscular physique.
May I use those towels?
Of course, but for what?
I'm going to alter his build.
Would you both mind helping me a bit?
Master Gaoshun, over there, please.
Yes.
Lady Suiren, please take this side.
Understood.
Now, with clothes on top of that...
My goodness.
Wow.
Having Master Jinshi's face on that
awkward body is quite strange.
Next is the face.
Huh?
I mixed several dark-colored shades.
I'll use them to make a suntanned
complexion, like a commoner.
Close your eyes, please.
Yeah.
So needlessly beautiful, even to the touch.
Not a trace of facial hair,
nor any pores for that matter.
If I applied feminine makeup
on him, I wonder...
Here it is, the one that Meimei forced on me.
Hey, will this take much longer?
Please close your lips,
but don't purse too hard.
Huh? Right...
What's wrong?
I'm glad we were alone here.
If anyone else were here,
it would have been a disaster.
Hey, is something the matter?
No, there's nothing.
That hurt! What happened?
Nothing happened.
Nothing at all.
Right, nothing happened.
Back on track.
Use makeup to paint blotches on the face.
Add circles under the eyes with dark colors.
Add some moles, and draw over
the eyebrows to change their shape.
The remaining makeup can be applied to
other body parts to make the skin blotchy.
Push some under the fingernails
to make the hands look unclean.
Solid, manly hands.
I guess he can't have beautiful lady hands...
Hmm? He has calluses.
What does he use other than
brushes and chopsticks?
Does he train in sword or polearm fighting?
Not something a eunuch
usually needs to do, but...
Well, there's no need to ask
such a silly question.
Wow, that looks dirty.
Please.
A drink?
Whoa! What is this?
Please drink it slowly, licking it
like you're wetting your lips.
It will make your lips and throat
swell, to change your voice.
What is it made of?
Several different irritants.
It's very spicy, but don't worry,
it's not poison.
Drink all of it.
The final touch.
Cotton.
Please fill your cheeks with it
to change your face shape.
It's finished.
Wow, young master, is that really you?
Please don't call me that.
And yet he's still pretty handsome.
Must be hard to have such natural beauty.
Anyway, I did the best that I could.
Now, time to head home! It's been too long.
Xiaomao, you said you'll
be returning home today, yes?
Yes, I've been granted leave until tomorrow—
I haven't seen him make that face before.
In that case, Master Jinshi's
destination is on your way.
Yikes!
Even with his disguise, it would be
suspicious if he had his usual companions.
Oh, that's true.
Don't you agree, Master Jinshi?
You're right.
It would be great if you could come along.
No! Master Jinshi likes the idea, too!
Unfortunately, I don't think it would
improve matters much if I w-were there...
Perhaps having a bland attendant accompany
a bland master would look natural,
but I am also known to be
your personal servant...
I think it would be fine.
In that case, why don't you also
wear a disguise, Xiaomao?
Huh?
That's a fine idea!
I have all the tools for putting on makeup.
But...
You just have to look completely different
from your usual appearance, right?
Ugh...
Right?
Y-Yes...
I have such a bad feeling about this...
Master Jinshi, your posture is too graceful.
You stop addressing me so formally, too.
Also, don't say my name.
That would ruin everything.
Then what should I call you?
Let's see...
You can call me Jinka, my lady.
Huh?
I believe that would be appropriate,
given our appearances.
True, this outfit belongs
to Lady Suiren's daughter.
Both the fabric and design are nice.
Doesn't look outdated or anything.
I suppose I could come off as
a young lady from a good family.
Why is he enjoying this so much?
Here is the map. For Xiaomao...
I will take care of the young lady.
Please.
Well, Master Jinka...
Hmm?
Jinka.
Yes, my lady!
Your posture is too straight.
"Jinka," huh? Not the strangest of pseudonyms.
But to use the character "ka,"
for flower, in the name?
I guess "Jinshi" isn't a very manly
name to begin with, but still.
Maybe I should have made him
dress up as a woman, after all.
No, I can't do that, if I want to
maintain peace in our realm.
Where are we headed?
A restaurant just outside
the pleasure district.
I'm meeting an acquaintance there.
Why do I have to be the bodyguard?
And while hidden? Why would—
The attendant walking in front of
the mistress? He has a lot to learn.
Jinka.
Apologies, my lady.
Good.
Not many leafy vegetables yet,
given the season.
Hmm?
Now that I have my allowance,
perhaps I'll get a chicken too,
and boil them together.
Grocery shopping?
In that outfit?
I wanted to feed my dad.
He is an impressive doctor
and apothecary, second to none.
But for some reason, he has absolutely
no sense of profit or loss.
That's why he lives in that miserable shack,
despite having what should be
a lucrative profession.
If he were on the verge of starvation,
the old lady would probably
force-feed him something, but...
What is it?
Why are you so silent?
Because there's nothing to discuss?
Was that the wrong answer?
Hmm? This smell!
Chicken skewers!
Wait here a moment!
Mister, two skewers please!
Gotcha!
Here. Eat it before it gets cold.
Sure.
The savory skin, the tasty fat...
You can't get this in the palace.
Aren't you going to eat it?
As you can see, no poison.
No, I...
Ah.
Here.
How is it?
Yeah, it's better than I remember
at camp. The salt is good.
Camp? I thought that type of thing
was for soldiers, not eunuchs.
He really does seem to be enjoying it.
Oh, welcome back, Gaoshun.
Please don't touch the suitcase.
I just applied persimmon tannin to it.
The young master's toys are
full of memories, aren't they?
Yes.
So, how was he?
He was extremely pleased.
It was a surprisingly good suggestion, for you.
Once the young master found
a favorite toy, he would never let it go.
If I hid it, he would cry like
the world was ending.
You worked so hard to find him a new toy
to get him to settle down somehow.
Fixating on one thing...
That is not a luxury that Master
Jinshi is allowed to have.
Do we have to rush so much?
I thought you're meeting someone.
Isn't it best to arrive early?
You sound like you want to split
from me as soon as possible.
Do I?
True, I do want to split from him and go
back to buy some radishes and chicken.
Is...
Is life at the palace so bad?
I'd think it's better than life
out in the pleasure district.
It's certainly not bad.
I left for work of my own free will,
and the room I've been given is quite pretty.
However, I worry about my adoptive
father, who I left all alone.
What's wrong?
I just didn't expect you to care about
anything other than medicine or poison.
He's also my teacher in the art of medicine.
I need him to stay alive for much longer.
He must be quite the skilled apothecary.
He knows not just Eastern medicine,
but has studied Western medicine, as well.
I heard he studied abroad,
in the west, when he was young.
That must mean he was extremely talented.
Only those chosen by the empire
are allowed to study abroad.
Yes, he's extremely talented.
They say heaven only grants
a person one talent,
but there are some who receive more than one.
That's quite impressive.
Why is someone so remarkable working
as a pleasure district's apothecary?
It must be because he's short
on luck, of all things.
He was given two talents, but lost his manhood.
Are you saying your adoptive
father is a eunuch?
Yes.
I guess the brothel-style joke didn't land.
Apparently, because of his study abroad,
he was made a eunuch by the previous empress
dowager, the former emperor's mother.
Eunuch, apothecary, doctor...
Did I fail to mention that?
Oh, is that it?
An inn upstairs from a restaurant.
Come, stop in!
Hey, hey, hey.
I see. Now I get why he had to
disguise himself and everything.
In that case, you could have just
come to the pleasure district.
Huh? What do you mean?
Nothing.
Apothecary, do you know the regulars
at the Verdigris House?
Well, the customers that stand out, yes.
Who are they?
I can't say. I have a duty of confidentiality.
Then...
How does one decrease
the value of a courtesan?
That's an unpleasant question.
There are many different ways,
especially with high-class courtesans.
At the Verdigris House,
girls take most of the important
lessons while working as servants.
At that time,
they are separated into those with
beautiful appearances and those without.
The latter, after debuting, immediately
take on customers to sell their bodies.
Those with talent, however,
are taught tea ceremony and given a higher
education with which to entertain patrons.
Their prices go up and up.
Once high enough, they start
to appear only very rarely.
At that point, you get
a top-ranking courtesan,
who costs a year's salary just to have tea with.
Some retain their chastity
until the day they're bought out.
Their value comes from their purity.
Losing that purity would
easily halve their value.
In addition...
A pregnancy would reduce it to nearly nothing.
Next Time
Next time: "Lakan."
Episode 18: Lakan