The Apothecary Diaries
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all of the characters, organizations, and so on
are imaginary. It also bears no connection to any specific real-life events.
How does one decrease
the value of a courtesan?
A pregnancy would reduce it to nearly nothing.
Is that the place you're looking for?
Now, if you'll excuse me.
You're leaving now?
Me going in there would ruin all
the work we put into your disguise.
Right...
Goodbye.
It's fine. I pulled it off
with no apparent emotion.
Enjoy yourself tonight, good sir.
A dream of the past...
Or rather, from when I was a baby.
Episode 18: Lakan
I bet it's because I talked about it.
Good morning.
Morning, Dad.
What are your plans for today?
Nothing.
If you're not busy, can you
pay a visit to the Verdigris House?
Sure.
Hmm? Hey, Maomao. Are you off work?
I got a vacation.
You're at the apothecary even on your off day?
Just passing by. It's not
the main reason why I'm here.
Hold it, Pairin!
Haven't we discussed this enough by now?
Oh? Maomao!
Good to see you back!
You're suffocating me, Pairin.
I'm the one suffocating from our
old granny nagging me all the time.
I'm not done with you!
You have to choose one or the other!
Really?
I don't know what this is about, but it
looks like Pairin has a lot on her plate, too.
Granny, you're so persistent.
It's your fault for not making
up your mind. Now decide!
Besides, you're the one that's making me
bring these offers to you by hanging around!
I didn't ask! You're always so pushy!
Sneak, sneak, sneak.
What do you mean, pushy?!
Hmm? Was Maomao here?
She's been here for a little while.
Is she going to the annex?
Good morning.
She used to hatefully chase me out,
but I guess she doesn't
have the energy anymore.
Or perhaps she's forgotten
how to talk entirely.
With her illness worsening,
her memories are in shreds.
Dad's medicine works well, but at this point,
it won't even provide temporary relief.
Still, giving her the medicine is
the only treatment we can think of.
That customer is back again.
He's got a good nose on him.
Get Meimei in here.
The Verdigris House is now
a reputable establishment,
but a decade or so ago,
it used to operate in shame.
This courtesan served
customers during that era,
and was unlucky enough
to catch syphilis as a result.
By the time Dad came to the Verdigris
House, the illness was in incubation.
If he'd known about the illness,
he might have been able to treat her,
but nobody trusted a eunuch
who suddenly appeared out of nowhere.
She had to serve customers.
There was no other way to live.
That was the law of the courtesan.
A few years later, when
the rashes started to reappear,
the sores spread almost instantly.
Since then, this woman has
been locked up in this annex,
out of sight of the customers.
It's quite generous. Courtesans who can't work
are usually just thrown out into a ditch.
This room's pretty stuffy.
Maybe I'll burn some incense, too.
What is it?
Big Sis told me the weirdo
with the monocle is here,
so you shouldn't go out there for now.
Right, got it.
As long as I stay put, that man
won't come out here.
A long-time customer of the
Verdigris House, an old acquaintance...
Stupid woman.
Thanks for being so patient.
That guy's gone now.
Meimei, did you spend time with him?
Who else can?
Oh, I'm glad Big Sis seems
to be doing well today.
Maomao, you're getting that offer again.
I don't see how you put up with him, Sis.
It's not so bad. The old lady
doesn't care as long as he pays up.
That's probably why she keeps
wanting to make me a courtesan.
If I didn't have my job,
I might have been sold off by now.
It's a really good deal, from where I'm standing.
Do you know how rare it is for
a courtesan to get everything they want?
Since our old lady would easily
let the weight of silver overrule that.
Who can blame her? She's saving up
for her boat fare to heaven.
I'm getting older now.
I should start taking this seriously.
She's not even thirty yet, but as a courtesan,
that's retirement age already.
Why not strike out on your own?
Just a while longer.
I'll keep working here for just a while longer.
I don't know what's going
through Meimei's mind.
It's not a rabbit hole I want to delve into.
If it's what everyone knows as love,
that's an emotion I'm sure I left behind,
in the womb of the woman who birthed me.
Let me scrub your back.
Haven't done that in ages.
Huh? No thanks.
Come on, come on.
Yeah, it's been a while!
Let her do it.
You're going to be gone again
for a while, right?
Huh?
I'm doing this as a freebie, so you have
to help me find good customers, okay?
I didn't expect the meeting place to
offer services like in the pleasure district.
That wasn't what I was there for.
Apothecary, do you have a moment?
Yes.
Share this with Suiren.
It's a souvenir from a weirdo.
From a weirdo? Thank you.
Yeah.
Well then, I'm getting back to work.
Oh, dear.
We're having a vegetarian dinner today,
so Xiaomao, don't eat
any meat or fish, all right?
You're taking a break, but don't
completely lose consciousness.
Right, vegetarian!
Dammit, I thought working
would get my mind off of it.
Also.
No more hiding weird plants in the warehouse.
Yikes. She's sharp.
If you can't find anywhere to put it,
why don't you ask Master Jinshi to
let you use one of the vacant rooms?
No, I can't use a noble person's
home as a medicine cabinet.
Xiaomao, you appear apathetic,
but you're actually very keen when it
comes to knowing where you stand.
I am of lowly birth. It's a small
miracle that I'm even here.
Perhaps.
But remember, just because
a person is of noble birth
doesn't make them inherently
different from the start.
Nobody knows how a person's
life can twist and turn.
Separating everything based only on
status can lead to missed opportunities.
Really?
Yes, really.
Now, back to work.
Can you run an errand for me?
Excuse me!
I've come to pick up some medicine!
Yes, wait just a moment.
This is nothing like the rear palace pharmacy
that the quack doctor was running!
This place is close to the military,
so they must get a lot of injuries.
Ah, this smell that leaves
a bitter taste in my mouth...
I wonder what they have
in the medicine cabinets?
I'd love to rummage through this whole place...
No. I must control myself!
What are you doing?
She's that...
Just waiting for some medicine.
Suirei!
You're here.
I'm here to resupply
the medicines at the guardhouse.
Right.
The guardhouse?
How are you? I'm fine.
Come to think of it, the last time
I saw her was near the military wing.
She must smell like herbs
because she works there.
I wonder why she seems to dislike me.
Is there anything else you need?
No, nothing else.
A court lady shouldn't be doing this...
F-Forget I said anything!
You need medicine, right?!
I wonder what kind of medicine this is.
Lick!
Potato flour?
This is for Master Jinshi, right?
Thinking about it, Master Jinshi
is pretty mysterious.
Not just the work he gets
assigned every few weeks,
but taking long baths the day before,
and burning incense before leaving...
The vegetarian food, too.
It's like a purification ceremony.
Are eunuchs allowed to
perform ceremonial rites?
It's not out of place for a noble to do that,
but if he's of such high rank,
why is he a eunuch?
Was he also made a eunuch by the unilateral
decision of the previous empress dowager?
Like my dad?
The girl's adopted father
is a eunuch and former doctor.
If she studied under a former doctor,
it explains why she's so knowledgeable, but...
A eunuch?
Yes.
Did we ever have such a skilled
doctor among the eunuchs?
Pardon me.
Shall we pick up the discussion
from the other day?
It seems you played quite a few dirty tricks.
How rude! I don't want to
hear that from a thief.
I spent a decade convincing that old madam,
and you stole her out from under my nose.
So you want your prize returned?
No, I'll pay whatever you ask.
I'm not keen on repeating my past mistakes.
And if I refuse?
Then there's nothing I can do, is there?
You can count on one hand the number of
people who can defy someone as high up as you.
As I thought, he does know who I really am.
I'm just concerned about what
my daughter would think, is all.
Ugh. So that's really what it is.
I don't want to admit it,
but Lakan is Maomao's father by blood.
Could you just let her know
I'll be visiting her sometime?
Bye, now.
Apothecary.
Yes.
There's an official who wants
to meet you sometime soon.
Who is he?
It's the weirdo I've been telling
you about. His name is Lakan—
I'll turn him down somehow.
Thank you. I'll get back to work now.
I've never seen her make a face like that.
And I never want to see it again.
So, he found out.
This smell...
It's an herb garden!
Here! And there! And there, too!
You again?
Oh, no. This is way too suspicious.
Don't worry. I haven't taken anything yet.
Is it safe to assume
from the dirt on your hands
that you were just about to?
I'm not trying to punish you.
This is an unofficial garden, anyway.
But the doctors know about this place too,
so I'd advise against frequent visits.
Are you in charge of this place?
Who knows? I'm just allowed
to plant what I want here.
She's pulling up the weeds.
Suirei, I think her name was?
Not that I'm one to talk,
but she doesn't seem very excitable.
What are you planting?
A medicine to resurrect someone.
Is that...?!
A medicine that can bring
the dead back to life...
If such a thing exists,
I want it more than anything!
Just kidding.
A joke...
I heard you're an apothecary.
Just how good are you?
I don't know.
A little while from now, I'll be
planting some morning glories here.
Goodbye.
Next Time
Next time: "Chance or
Something More."
Episode 19: Chance or Something More