The Apothecary Diaries
Also, regarding today's schedule,
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all of the characters, organizations, and so on
are imaginary. It also bears no connection to any specific real-life events.
there will be a medium
ceremony in the afternoon.
Yeah...
I think I know what's on your mind.
But please, don't forget about work.
I know.
Episode 19: Chance or Something More
Master Lihaku, what's wrong?
We have a problem.
Trouble, is it?
Remember that fire at the warehouse?
Ah.
Apparently, a thief broke in to a different
warehouse on the same day.
I'm sure they were taking advantage
of all the chaos at the time.
A looting. What got stolen?
Not something to discuss openly, it seems.
Sneak.
Ceremonial tools. And not just one.
Were they being managed that haphazardly?
Well, I don't really know.
There's no knowledgeable
managers right now.
The last one passed away last year.
What about the current manager?
He must know the basics, right?
Well, he got food poisoning awhile back.
Food poisoning?
His favorite seaweed made him
sick and he hasn't woken up.
He can't come back to work. Trouble, right?
Where have I heard that before?
Was it that official who likes rare foods?
How did you know?
A lot happened.
Theft at the time of a fire.
The warehouse manager is missing
due to food poisoning.
It's a bit too suspicious to be a coincidence.
Who was the manager who passed away last year?
Hmm. I remember that he was
famous for being really by-the-book.
I forgot his name. I remember he had
a sweet tooth and things like that, but...
Was it Master Kounen, by chance?
Oh, that's it! Hey, how'd you know?
A lot happened.
Master Jinshi told me about the
tough official with a sweet tooth.
The man who died of salt overdose.
These are all coincidental?
Each incident looks like an accident,
but if they were all done
in pursuit of some goal...
So, what can I do for you?
Right! The main point.
Remember this? You gave it to me back then.
Ah, from the fire.
I tried to give it back,
but the owner declined.
He doesn't want it anymore.
It seems very expensive.
I assumed it was important.
Apparently, he got it from some court lady.
From a court lady?
Sounds weird, right?
Why give this to a random warehouse guard?
Apparently, the guard escorted
the court lady outside the castle,
because she was walking alone in the dark.
She gave him this pipe as a token of gratitude.
Receiving such an expensive item might
compel him to use it right away.
Start a fire to divert the guards' attention,
and break into another warehouse.
If the court lady gave the guard
the pipe for that purpose...
Master Lihaku, about that court lady...
Yeah, I tried to get the details about her.
But she was wearing a scarf
that hid her face, apparently.
Maybe she was hiding her face intentionally.
Yeah.
But she was "quite tall for a woman,
and smelled like medicine."
I know it's not you, given the height.
Can you think of anyone else?
A tall court lady smelling of medicine...
Don't speak based purely on conjecture.
Were there any more strange incidents
other than the events we mentioned?
Hmm. I can't say...
Do you think there's something to find out here?
There could be.
Or there might not.
Which is it?
Two coincidences can often
occur simultaneously.
Three at once isn't that rare, either.
But when several of them pile up
and become clearly intentional...
What if a person who fits the description
of a tall court lady appeared here?
This way, even if Suirei's name
comes up, it has nothing to do with me.
Wow, you're a lot smarter than you look!
Conversely, Master Lihaku, you're as big
a brute as you look, so please go easy on me.
Looks like fun.
There's nothing fun here.
I'll take my leave!
You seem very close to that officer.
Do I?
He just came to talk to me
about some concerns he had.
I can't say for certain that this has
nothing to do with Master Jinshi.
May I explain the details to you?
What a strange way they connect.
Yes.
So, what do you think is behind them?
I don't know.
None of those incidents are certainties.
It's more like setting several traps in
the hopes that some of them work out.
In that case, do you think
there are other traps?
I can't say for certain.
It's hard to determine which are
accidents and which were plotted.
It's still possible that these
are all just coincidences.
You're not excited?
Excited?
I'm just a servant. I only do what I am told.
Hmm.
In that case, how about this?
The other day, I visited the trader.
He told me there's
an interesting item in stock.
Ox bezoar
This is what it was called.
Ox bezoar, a medicinal gallstone from a cow!
The most exquisite medicine
only found in one in a thousand cows!
Are you going to give me that?!
Ox Bezoar
Really?!
You'd better not be lying!
Do you want it?
I do!
Xiaomao.
Excuse me.
Looks like you're excited now.
Will you really give me this?
Ox bezoar
Depends on how well you work.
I'll keep you updated.
Understood.
As you wish, Master Jinshi!
And so, Gaoshun, take care of it!
This is the incident from the other day.
The officer who got food poisoning
was from the Board of Rites.
Which one was the Board of Rites, again?
The education and foreign affairs one...?
If only I'd studied for
the court lady exams properly...
I'll leave these here.
Thank you.
No problem. Feel free to ask me
if you have any questions.
Um, what does this division do?
Hmm?
They deal with ceremonies.
Ceremonies?
Do you have anything to write with?
Huh? Y-Yeah.
Ceremonies, ceremonies...
The food-poisoned official and Master Kounen
were both were related to ceremonies.
If the incident with the pipe was
a way to help steal ceremonial tools...
These events, disguised
as coincidences, must line up
to form an intentional incident, somewhere.
If someone went through so much
trouble to steal ceremonial tools,
it has to be a ceremony of some importance.
Medium or higher, most likely.
I should find out when all
of these ceremonies take place.
Come to think of it, Master Jinshi
did purify himself often.
If you're interested in ceremonies,
here's something good.
Is this a picture of a ceremonial building?
Yes. It's at the west end of the outer
court, and called the Altar of the Sapphire Sky.
Quite an interesting design, don't you think?
There's a large pillar
hanging from the ceiling.
There are these banners
hanging above the central altar.
They lower the pillar to
add festive texts every time.
You're very knowledgeable.
Yeah. I'm ashamed to admit it, but
before I got assigned to the archives,
I was doing more important
work at the Board of Rites.
I talked back to my superiors once,
and got demoted to this role.
I used to be worried about the build
strength, but I'm glad to know it's fine.
What are you talking about?
You see how the pillar is hanging
from the ceiling like this, right?
It's big, so I was worried
about it falling down.
When I voiced my concerns
about the parts' strength,
it got me sent to this place.
That is indeed scary.
If the metal parts fixing the pillar in
place broke, and the pillar fell...
The person directly underneath performing
the ceremony would be at the highest risk.
Someone of truly noble birth could be lost.
Strength issue... Strength...
What was the stolen ceremonial tool, anyway?
If something so important went missing,
surely they'd make a new one.
Make a new one...
Excuse me!
When is the next ceremony
taking place at this venue?!
When? Well...
Oh, today, actually.
If my predictions are correct, this is a plan
that was concocted over a long period of time.
Not ever piece is likely to work.
But by placing numerous traps everywhere,
some are bound to work and overlap.
And finally, it connected to this.
It's just conjecture on my part.
But if I happen to be correct...
There!
Hey!
What are you doing?!
I need to get inside!
No.
This is an emergency!
What right does a servant like you
have to interject in this ceremony?
He's absolutely right. I'm just
a servant with no authority at all.
But if something happens, it'll be too late.
That's always the case with
things that can't be undone.
There are lives at risk.
Please stop the ceremony.
That's not a decision for you to make.
If you have something to say,
put it in the suggestion box.
That will take too long!
No!
A fatal defect was discovered in the altar!
There is reason to suspect
that someone tampered with it!
If you don't let me in now, you'll regret it!
If, after listening to my
warnings, you still reject...
Oh, I get it, so that's what it is!
I see. You're obstructing me and
waiting for the incident to happen!
In other words, you're in league
with the ones who tampered with the—
I'm about to lose consciousness.
It's only natural for him to get upset,
hearing a girl talk to him like that.
That was intentional, so it's fine.
It's no use. This isn't a big enough of
a commotion to stop the ceremony.
I'm fine. I can't lose consciousness now.
Do you feel better now?
Please let me through.
There is a person of the most
noble birth inside, isn't there?
If something happens, you all will
be the ones to lose your heads.
I won't ask you to cancel the ceremony.
Please just let me through.
Just say a rat got in accidentally.
In that case, the only person
getting beheaded will be me!
Why should I trust the words
of a girl like you?!
What about my words, then?
S-Sir, you're...
Now, why would you strike
a young girl like that?
She's hurt.
At any rate, why don't you just
go ahead and do as the girl says?
I'll take responsibility.
I don't even want to see who's behind me.
It's perfect timing, as if
everything was planned...
No, I can't concern myself with that right now.
It doesn't matter who this voice belongs to.
I must look terrible.
I'll ask Master Gaoshun after all this is done,
and take a nice, long bath.
But first,
I have to avoid getting beheaded.
I made it...
Gotta stitch that...
Hey.
What's going on here?
Master Jinshi...
Can I have the ox bezoar now?
This isn't the time for that.
What's happened with your face?
Why is Master Jinshi here...?
What's that look on his face?
Sorry, I need to stitch up my leg first—
H-Hey!
Hey, wake up!
Wake up! Hey!
Hey! Stay with me.
Hey!
Next Time
Next time: "Thornapple."
Episode 20: Thornapple