The Apothecary Diaries
Fengxian...
I wanted to be with the daughter she left behind.
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all of the characters, organizations, and so on
are imaginary. It also bears no connection to any specific real-life events.
That was my only wish.
It's only natural for her to hate me.
But I still wanted her near me.
At any rate, a bet is a bet.
I'll have to try again another time.
But that man...
Advisor
I'll never forgive him.
He put his hand on my daughter's shoulder
three times during that match.
Advisor
Now, I wonder how to take my revenge...
Hmm?
Finally awake?
I hear you're trying to buy out one of our courtesans.
You realize it'll cost you more than
a few thousand silver, right?
I know. If ten thousand isn't enough,
then twenty, thirty, whatever.
A hundred thousand, though,
might be a bit much.
Is that so? Then come this way.
I'll let you have your pick.
Sheesh.
Are you sure you want to include
one of the Three Princesses?
I told you, you can have your pick.
Of course, you'd have to pay accordingly.
This is troublesome.
No matter how beautifully they dress,
they all look like go stones to me.
In that case, I guess I can request Meimei,
since she's been so good to me.
Master Lakan.
I do hold pride in my work as a courtesan.
If it is me that you desire,
I will accept without hesitation.
But...
If you're going to choose, please choose well.
Sleep, my baby, sleep.
Little cuckoo sings as the sun goes down.
Meimei! I didn't allow you to open that!
What are you doing?!
W-Wait!
A flower that retains its beauty
even when withered!
If that was supposed to be a message...
Could it be?!
Sleep, my baby, sleep.
Where is she? She cries.
Little birds are so innocent.
Off they fly to somewhere far.
Sleep, my baby, sleep.
Sleep now, and I'll see you tomorrow.
What are you doing?!
This place is for the sick!
Get out of here, now!
Hurry up and pick a courtesan from out there!
Yes. I have to choose, don't I?
Are you listening to me?!
I want this woman.
Stop this nonsense!
You're the one who said
I can pick anyone I want.
I'll pay whatever you ask. A hundred thousand,
two hundred thousand, whatever.
What are you talking about—
Let's play go.
Oh, so that's your move?
Your moves are always so sudden and unexpected.
Maomao must have gotten that from you.
Big Sister, you should have been
honest from the start.
Why so late...
I will buy out this courtesan.
This woman, beautiful as a balsam flower.
Episode 24: Jinshi and Maomao
Basen was the one that accompanied me to the Verdigris House to drop off that man.
I'm tired.
Hmm?
Dammit, the wicked father-daughter duo.
That's Concubine Loulan.
I guess they stayed out here
after the garden party.
So that must be her father,
the one that pushed hard to get
his daughter in the rear palace.
At any rate...
I really wish this guy would quit bad-mouthing
high-ranked officials in public.
If someone overheard, I might get
mistaken for saying it right along with him.
I guess he's still young.
Hey.
Master Jinshi wants to see you.
You must be tired.
No, not really.
Oh!
Oh my, you've lost so much weight!
I'm fine.
Here you are, Xiaomao. Eat up.
There's plenty more where that came from.
I thought you hated our master strategist.
Master Jinshi.
It's not that I hate him.
After all, I'm here because
he was able to land that shot.
Was there really no other way to phrase that?
It's just facts. I'm not sure
how you imagined it,
but she wouldn't have gotten
pregnant if she didn't want to.
There's drugs to prevent
or abort pregnancies.
Ending it would have been easy, early on.
She must have given birth
because she wanted to.
Rather, perhaps he was the one who was tricked.
The strategist?
Women are clever.
It's not hard to make a good estimate of
when one is most likely to become pregnant
by tracking blood flow cycles.
As a courtesan, she was able to control
the date of his visits by sending him letters.
That must have been why she lost her
mind when things didn't work out.
So much so, that she was
willing to hurt herself.
Not only that, but she sent
the baby's little finger as well.
Master Jinshi, that man never talks to you
outside your office, does he?
Now that you mention it...
That man isn't able to recognize human faces.
Unable to recognize faces? What do you mean?
He can tell the shapes of eyes and mouths,
but he's unable to view
the parts together as a whole.
I hear that everyone's faces
look the same to him.
That's unfortunate.
Yes, that's what my adopted father
told me too, when he explained it to me.
He's an unfortunate fellow.
It has troubled him all throughout his life.
Huh...
But, for some reason,
he's able to discern my face,
and my adopted father's.
That's why he has that
strange attachment to me.
Master Jinshi,
if that monocled face came at you and told you,
"Call me Papa!", how would you react?
I'd be tempted to shatter that monocle.
Right?
He keeps stressing that he's my father,
but he's a stud-horse, at best.
I wonder if he understood the message
behind the withered rose?
Well, it's fine if he didn't.
I do dislike him, but I don't hate him.
I'm grateful that I was able
to become Luomen's daughter.
You seemed pretty disgusted when you saw him.
Master Jinshi, you still have a lot to learn.
When I tried to stop
that ceremony, he helped me.
I think he had the feeling
something was going to happen.
The strategist? I didn't think he knew
anything about it at that point.
He doesn't collect evidence
to make predictions like I do.
He goes off gut feelings to sense when
something's not right, and he's rarely wrong.
The annoying part is that he's too lazy
to actually do anything himself.
If that guy actually took action,
I might have had the resurrection
drug in my hands right now!
I know this is just jealousy.
He's so talented that my dad would
praise him with no caveats.
He doesn't realize how blessed he is.
Hmph!
He will never become your ally, but you
shouldn't make him your enemy, if possible.
Understood.
What's wrong?
Nothing, just...
Please remember that
no father wants to be disliked.
A few days after returning to the rear palace,
Meimei sent me a package.
Inside was a letter
describing who bought out who,
and a beautiful shawl.
Listen, Maomao.
When I get bought out,
you have to dance for me.
To be honest, I wanted to send off Meimei.
That courtesan, kinder than anyone else...
I'm surprised I still remember all of that.
Hey.
Wha—
What are you doing?!
Master Jinshi? Why are you here?
I got a report that another weird
woman was climbing the outer wall.
I had no choice but to respond.
I thought I was being sneaky, but...
Of course I'd get caught.
Stop causing trouble.
Why'd you have to be the one to investigate?
They could have just sent someone else.
A kind guard recognized your face
and came directly to me.
You might think you're keeping a low profile,
but not everyone agrees. Remember that.
Understood.
Now, your turn. What were you doing?
In the pleasure district, when sending off
a courtesan who's been bought out,
it's customary for the other
courtesans to dance.
What is it?
Well, I'm surprised you know how to dance.
I was taught dancing as part of
the bare minimum of education.
There were rumors on the outside
that the weirdo was buying out a courtesan.
I'm sure there were.
He also sent a notice of leave.
He's going to take a vacation
for at least ten days.
What a troublesome man.
My elder sister told me that
they're hosting a banquet
not just for three days and three nights,
but a whole seven days and seven nights.
There's no way to know how much
he spent on the courtesan,
but just from the number
of lamps being put out,
it's only natural to assume
it's no normal courtesan.
But the actual courtesan being
bought out is never seen in public.
Rumors of the Verdigris House continue to grow.
Just how old Grams planned it.
By the way, who did
the strategist buy out, anyway?
Who knows?
You do.
No matter how beautiful,
she will be no match for you.
That doesn't answer my question.
But you still don't deny it.
The woman who the man
bought out won't last long.
Nobody told me about the woman who
birthed me during my days at the brothel.
The old lady probably kept everyone silent.
But those types of things tend to leak out
from seemingly small cracks.
That I was the reason the Verdigris House
almost went out of business, once.
My relationship with the woman who always
chased me off, ashamed for losing her pride.
That nightmare was a thing
that really happened in the past.
That woman has no memories of being a mother.
All she has now is a crooked little finger.
None of that matters to me anymore.
I'm happy to be Luomen's daughter.
Master Jinshi.
What is it?
You can cut off the tip of a finger
and it grows back.
Is now the time for that?
Whoa!
W-What happened?!
Looks like my wound opened up.
Sure looks that way to me, too!
I guess the dancing got my body warmed up.
I have a high pain tolerance,
perhaps due to my drug experiments.
It's fine, I'll stitch it right back up.
Master Jinshi, I can't work like this.
Don't do that here!
Um, Master Jinshi—Whoa!
Please let me down.
You'll open up your wound further.
What if someone sees us?
It's too dark to see, anyway.
Besides, this is the second time
I'm carrying you like this.
The other time must have been when
I was knocked out from that injury.
Master Jinshi.
This may not be the best time,
but there's something I've meant
to say for a long time.
What's this, all of a sudden?
It's a very important thing I have to say.
Out with it, already.
Master Jinshi...
I'd like that ox bezoar, please.
Ow!
Wait, you don't have it?!
Don't be absurd!
I don't even...
How immature, headbutting me out of nowhere.
But I guess he's easiest to talk to
when he's being immature.
Maomao!
Master Jinshi's here to see you!
Coming.
Excuse me.
Are you feeling better now?
Yes. Everyone's very nice to me
at the Jade Pavilion.
So, how may I be of service?
Well, something interesting came up.
I'd like to ask something of you.
Oh, this again.
So, what is it that you
would like for me to do?
Maomao's story has just begun.
What kind of incident
will she get mixed up in next?
The Apothecary Diaries
Season 2 Production Confirmed