As of this moment,
the first exam is over.
FIRST PARTY:
TON, METHODE, LÄNGE
SECOND PARTY:
Six parties of 18 people
LAWINE, FRIEREN, KANNE
passed the first exam.
FOURTH PARTY:
LAND, FERN, ÜBEL
EIGHTH PARTY:
The second exam
SCHARF, WIRBEL, EHRE
will be in three days.
THIRTEENTH PARTY:
RICHTER, DENKEN, LAUFEN
SEVENTEENTH PARTY:
The details will be notified in due time.
BLEI, EDEL, DÜNSTE
That is all. Dismissed!
FRIEREN: BEYOND JOURNEY'S END
EPISODE 22: FUTURE ENEMIES
So it's already evening...
It's actually pretty nice to be
able to laze around like this...
Who's that?
I'm coming!
Wait, Fern?
Didn't you two go
to the first-class mage exam?
We returned last night
after the first exam was over.
Master Stark,
it's already evening, you know?
You were sleeping, didn't you?
Did you stay up late?
Yes...
Anything else?
I also drank a juice
in the middle of the night...
Argh! Sorry! I said I'm sorry!
Oh boy, you've made her angry.
You just woke up too,
Mistress Frieren.
Now she's angry at me as well.
Looks like we're going to spend
this whole day trying to please her.
Do we have any plans?
How about we go eat something delicious?
Something delicious?
It's a little expensive,
but I found a nice place the last time
I was here with Himmel and the others.
That was over 80 years ago, right?
Will it still be there?
Oh my, the light is back on.
Like I said, it's not hard to fix.
Thank you as always, Richter.
Of course.
Oh, almost forgot.
You can have this.
Bye then.
Hey, old lady!
I'm not a kid anymore.
I'm a grown man.
In my eyes, you're still a child.
You liked those, right?
I'm sorry, but the shop is closed.
Some crazy old man made me
have a fistfight, you see.
So I have to get some rest.
Why, that must be rough, Richter.
Then how about we get
some food together?
There's a restaurant I'm looking for,
but Laufen and I don't know
our way around here.
Before that, why are you even
with Denken in the first place, Laufen?
And what's with those?
The old man bought it for me.
I'm not giving them to you.
Come on now, he's totally
treating you as his granddaughter.
Go home.
We are no longer a party.
You don't know how to
succeed in life, do you?
If you're going to keep
living as a mage,
you can profit
from getting on my good side.
There are tons of restaurants here.
Just pick any of them.
My wife...
It's a place I went to with my late wife.
I still can't forget the taste.
I assume you're paying?
Of course.
I told you, you won't regret this.
Glasses boy.
Übel.
Nice to finally meet you.
So you don't use your
clone in town, huh?
If you want to chat,
can we do it while we talk?
I mean, sure,
but I might accidentally kill you
if you started running.
Can I ask you a question?
You...
You don't think much
about murdering people, do you?
So why didn't you kill Wirbel?
You had the chance, right?
So you were watching?
I can't ever let my guard down, can I?
It's a bit hard to explain, but...
What a surprise.
You already had blood
on your hands for a long time,
and yet you still wish
to stay human?
That's right.
All this time is to prepare me
for the killing.
Maybe it's because
I empathized with him.
I also want to take my time
before I kill.
I can't move my body.
This is...
Sorganeil.
A spell to restrain
someone the user sees.
Magic that a certain
person specializes in
is deeply related
to their life and character.
You see, I've been this way
for a long time.
By empathizing with others,
I can use their magic.
But if I can't empathize with them,
then I can't use their magic.
Glasses boy,
your clones are perfect replicas, able to
have the exact same capabilities as you.
What goes in your head?
What kind of life have you lived?
Tell me.
I see.
So you're the type
that uses magic by feelings.
You can use magic without fully
understanding how it works.
I don't like dumb kids like you.
That doesn't answer my question.
I'm saying I'm not telling you
because I don't like it.
I don't care if you kill me.
Though you'll never be able to
empathize with me if you do that.
Actually, never mind.
I think I understand
who you are a little bit.
Is that so?
I'd like to get to know you better.
Where are you heading to?
Who knows.
Don't follow me.
This is it.
You have excellent taste, Denken.
This is the best restaurant in town.
I often come here as well.
It's been over 50 years since
I visited this place with my wife,
yet the atmosphere is still the same.
How curious.
Are you serious?
I can order as many
desserts as I want?
Yup.
Denken, It's Frieren.
Which one should I pick?
My recommendation would be...
Can I really have all these
even when it's not my birthday?
Leave them be.
They seem to be having fun.
Food is something to be enjoyed.
We're here for the same reason.
All right, time to gobble up.
That sure is a lot...
Mistress Frieren does this
every now and then, doesn't she?
I thank you for retrieving
the heirloom knife from the demons.
I, Lecker, the greatest
culinary genius of this century,
shall honor you with the utmost hospitality
and reward as much as I can offer.
You ordered quite a lot.
The food here is amazing, after all.
I need to savor the flavor.
No need to eat all that at once.
You can just come here again.
There have been many flavors I thought
I could experience again, but I couldn't.
Worry not, Mistress Frieren.
I intend to keep the flavor of this
restaurant for the next generations.
Even after 100 or 200 years
in the future.
Is that so?
It's funny.
Every chef always says that.
Yet they change the flavor
of other people's dishes
in order to leave their mark in history.
When that happens, you can go
search for even better flavors.
With all due respect, Master Himmel,
there is no one who can create
flavors that surpass mine.
Then make sure it stays
that way in the future.
That is the reward
that I ask from this quest.
If that is what the hero wishes for,
then I shall accomplish something
no other chef has ever achieved.
Frieren, this tastes really good!
Is it really okay for me
to feel this happy?
Well well.
Even after all that talk,
the taste did change.
That said,
I didn't have to go out
and search for better flavors.
This is much better
than how it was back then.
This is really great.
It's on your cheek, Master Stark.
You must eat your vegetables, too.
You really are turning
into her grandfather.
Huh, you surprisingly
don't eat much, do you?
What's wrong with that?
That was really delicious,
Mistress Frieren.
I'm glad she's feeling better now.
By the way, is your wallet doing okay?
There go my secret savings...
That is truly the state
of spiritual nothingness.
I'm proud of you for reaching
the quintessence of the art of war.
I have nothing left to teach you.
Who was that old man?
I don't know.
He just started talking to me
while I was training.
You always attract weird people,
don't you, Stark?
Well anyway, do you have a minute?
I need your help.
What happened?
She looks really angry.
This looks even worse than yesterday.
What did you do?
I overslept even though
I was in charge of shopping today...
But that happens all the time.
Why is she making a fuss now?
Fern is the type who keeps
bottling things up until it explodes.
And what happens when she does?
She completely ignores me.
What is this, a fight between kids?
I'm begging you, Stark!
Step in for me!
She won't talk to me at all!
What? No way!
I'm scared as well!
Right, of course.
I'm sorry for asking the impossible.
Um, Miss Fern?
Frieren has reflected
on her mistakes, so...
I want to eat.
I want to eat snacks.
She's such a pain...
W-Why don't we all go
get something to eat together?
Do I even have any
secret savings left?
Wait, isn't that...
Wirbel from the Northern
Magic Corps, wasn't it?
You're a warrior, aren't you?
Huh? What is this all of a sudden?
What do you think?
W-What...?
Nah, he's no good.
What are they doing?
Sorry to keep you waiting, Kanne.
You're wearing a much cuter
outfit than usual, Lawine.
It's because my brothers
returned from the royal capital.
They always brought back
so much unnecessary stuff.
I'm not some dress-up doll.
And my Mum enjoys it so much,
she just can't stop.
You're more spoiled than I am.
If that's how you think,
then please switch places with me.
Always being compared
to my excellent brothers is hell.
Come on, let's go.
I'm suffocating in this.
Then, let me be your escort
for today, sweet Lawine.
Ouch! Ouch!
You're going to tear them off!
Umm, Miss Fern...
Which one would you like?
Any will do.
You can choose, Master Stark.
Whenever she says that,
it means that none of them are good.
What must I do...?
I can't exactly help with that either...
Isn't that Frieren?
What a coincidence, I was just
thinking of visiting you at the inn.
Who are they?
They were in my party
for the first exam.
You see, Frieren helped us a lot!
Oh, and she was like a teacher to us.
Only because you two
kept fighting each other.
That's Lawine's fault.
It doesn't feel right
being the only guy here.
Hey!
- You're a warrior, aren't you?
- Huh?
Uh, hold on...
Please stop... What is this?
You're excellent, you know?
What does that even mean?!
The Continental Magic Association
gave a request
to exterminate a Fresser that's been
laying waste to some fields.
So we've been searching
for a vanguard.
I saw you back at the exam.
Is he your comrade? Can we borrow him?
- Go ahead.
- So mean!
- She's so mean...
- Are you sure it's okay to let him go?
I'm sure he'll be fine.
I didn't sense any malicious intent.
I almost couldn't believe
he was the same person.
Maybe he's the type that keeps
his work and private life separate?
My brothers are the same.
Here you go, Frieren.
A token of my gratitude.
But I didn't do anything
to deserve it.
That's not true.
If you weren't there, we couldn't have
advanced to the second exam.
Thank you again.
Thank you, Master Himmel!
You don't have to worry anymore.
Okay!
Go on. Your father
and mother are waiting.
Okay!
Why do you help people?
Because I'm a hero.
That's not what I meant.
Right...
Perhaps I do it for myself.
Maybe I want someone to remember me,
even for a little.
To live is to have someone to know
and remember you.
What do you need to do
to be remembered?
You just need to change their life,
even for just the slightest bit.
I'm sure that will be enough.
So you see, back then, Lawine was...
Nope, that was you, right?
Wait, was it?
Even that other time as well,
remember?
Mistress Frieren, this sweet
she gave is really delicious.
You're finally in a good mood...
Speaking of which, Frieren,
it took you a while to get up
on the second morning.
Please don't talk about that.
It'll put her in a bad mood again.
Hmph...
Frieren.
If it's anything like the previous ones,
the mage exam will have three parts.
We'll be rivals next time.
You're right.
What's that?
It's a notice of the next exam.
The location and date
are written here.
And the examiner in charge as well.
Sense is the examiner, huh?
We're so unlucky.
It's a shame after
we passed the first exam.
What do you mean?
Sense has been in charge
of four exams in the past.
No one passed in any of them.
This meat is delicious!
You're amazing.
That was some real art of war.
Such a cruel exam you're planning.
Is it?
I'm a pacifist.
Unlike you, Genau.
- Didn't know that would be here.
- Gargoyles!
- That's a mimic.
- How nasty.
- I'm afraid that is impossible.
- Not even any bone was left.
They're turning into
a fearsome threat.
EPISODE 23: CONQUERING THE LABYRINTH
The second exam is a dungeon raid.