NORTHERN LANDS, RUINS OF THE KING'S TOMB
All of you here are the 18 people
who have passed the first exam.
PROCTOR OF THE SECOND EXAM
SENSE, FIRST-CLASS MAGE
First of all, congratulations on passing.
Regarding the exams
that I have been in charge of,
there have been many rumors
of their results all over the place.
I'm sure some of you
have heard about them.
That said,
there is no need to be so wary.
The exam itself is simple.
Anyone aiming to become
a first-class mage
should be able to clear it
without difficulties.
Now then, I shall explain
the details of the second exam.
FRIEREN: BEYOND JOURNEY'S END
EPISODE 23: CONQUERING THE LABYRINTH
The second exam is a dungeon raid.
You will all attempt to conquer
the Ruin of the King's Tomb.
There is only one condition
to pass the exam.
You must reach the innermost
depths of the tomb.
You see, I'm a pacifist.
I do not enjoy bloodshed.
Therefore, anyone who reaches
the goal will pass.
Wait.
This is an unmapped dungeon
where many adventurers never returned alive.
Are you trying to make
everyone fail again?
What are you talking about?
You're all aiming to become
among the greatest of mages.
First-class mages make
the impossible possible.
You must keep going forward, even if
the path is unexplored or untrodden.
How should we prove that
we've reached the innermost depth?
Do we need to bring back
treasures or the like?
There is no need to prove it.
I will accompany you
all the way down.
Of course, I won't lend a hand
to any of the participants.
One more thing,
I'm giving you these bottles.
This thing was designed
by the first-class mage Lernen.
It's a golem that will help you escape.
By breaking the bottle,
you will summon the golem,
and it will carry you
out of the dungeon.
It's still a prototype,
but it's safe enough.
If you use it, you will fail the exam,
but if you think you can no longer
continue due to injury or the like,
do not hesitate to use it.
I can't let people
with promising futures die.
Also, the bottles will break
on their own at dawn tomorrow.
That is the time limit
of the second exam.
Now then, let the second exam begin.
Looks like there are several entrances.
This seems to be a dungeon
from the Unified Dynasty era.
The dungeons from that era
tend to have multiple entrances,
but they all lead
to the innermost depths.
If we take a look at each entrance,
we should be able to figure out
the internal layout to a degree.
We should divide the work and...
Why do you think
we would cooperate?
There's no element
of competition in this exam.
We should all work together.
I'm not doing that.
Unlike the first exam, the survival of
allies is not a prerequisite for passing.
Even if we form a team,
we're not obligated to help each other.
There's also the risk that I might be
used as a sacrificial pawn if needed.
Especially by you, who seem
to know a lot about dungeons.
I'm going alone.
Well, we at least knew each other
from the first exam.
At the very least, I'm not going to
team up with someone I don't know.
Let's go.
Hey, wait for me.
Fools.
They can't even see
the advantages of cooperating.
Let's go, Fern.
Are you sure, Mistress Frieren?
They won't be cooperating.
It's impossible at this point.
Hmm...
Then I shall follow you two.
It would seem to be
the safest way to reach the depths.
Just don't get in the way, okay?
I won't.
I will not bother nor help you.
This is the safest route.
Let's move forward carefully
and make a map as we go.
That tile over there.
It's a trap, so be careful.
You're always so knowledgeable
about dungeons.
I didn't use to be like this.
But Himmel liked dungeons.
We've raided lots of dungeons
on quests to exterminate monsters.
What do you mean
by liking dungeons?
It's literally what it means.
It makes him excited.
It's so weird, isn't it?
This stairway should
lead to the next floor.
I see. So this is the wrong route.
Let's head back to the branching paths.
Right.
Why?
Our target is the monster
down in the depths.
When will you learn, Eisen?
You only proceed to the next level
of a dungeon after exploring every corner.
That's the basics of being an adventurer.
I've never heard that before.
You must think I'm being ridiculous.
But wouldn't it be best if we could help
others while also enjoying ourselves?
This can't keep on forever.
As we continue our journey,
the dungeons will become more dangerous.
That's right.
I intend to enjoy it to the end.
I'll enjoy the adventure,
raiding dungeons,
defeating monsters,
and finding treasures.
By the time I realized it,
I already saved the world.
That's the journey I want.
Besides,
we might find a rare grimoire
at the end of the other route.
What are you waiting for?
Let's hurry back.
Huh...
It's so, so weird, isn't it?
Let's go, Kanne.
In the end,
only the five of us stayed.
Had we cooperated
and divided the tasks,
we would've had a good chance
at beating the dungeon.
With all the talented people here,
it would've been possible.
Denken, not everyone
can be as rational as you.
You said so yourself
at the end of the first exam.
They just don't like it.
At least the more clever ones stayed.
Just look at it that way.
At least, among these people,
there's nobody stupid enough to fall
for simple traps like mimics.
Isn't that enough, Denken?
As if a fool like that would make it
to this exam in the first place.
Let's go.
This mana...
There might be a grimoire inside.
Mistress Frieren, you saw the result
of the Mikheit spell, didn't you?
It's a mimic.
Fern,
that spell is 99 percent accurate.
And your point is?
It's only because there are great mages
that see through that one percent
that historic discoveries can happen.
Yes, I'm sure of it.
There is a rare grimoire inside.
That's what my experience
as a mage tells me.
It's so dark in here! It's scary!
So dark! So scary!
It's dark! It's scary!
Did I choose the wrong people to follow?
Don't step on the middle floor.
The ceiling will fall on you.
Don't tell me,
that person-shaped stain is...
How gruesome.
Not even any bone was left.
Gargoyles!
Denken, someone got trapped.
I know.
She's behind that wall.
Stand back.
I knew it, it's not enough.
There's no other choice.
Break the bottle!
Wow...
So we already lost one person.
Even letting our guard down
for a bit can be fatal.
So this is the Ruins of the King's Tomb...
Say, Fern, listen to me for a bit.
Can you stop pulling me for now?
You'll tear me apart.
Sure.
In this situation, you should do
the opposite and push me in.
The mimic will gag and stop biting.
Is it a dog or something?
I'm saved...
Goodness me.
How did you deal with these
when you're alone?
I would blow them up from
the inside with an offensive spell.
But I don't like doing that
because it makes my hair frizzy.
I'm back...
I got ringlet curls...
So that's why you sometimes
have different hairstyles.
But why?
All right, let's pull ourselves together
and continue raiding the dungeon.
It's gargoyles.
We'll defeat them
before they start moving.
We've seen these medals
in several places, didn't we?
Apparently, some people
with unusual tastes collect these.
This seems like the right route,
so let's head back.
But why?
It's going smoother than expected.
You're right. It's quite strange
for an uncharted dungeon.
Structurally speaking, we should be
close to the innermost depth, as well.
In any case,
we shouldn't let our guard down.
How about we take a break
when we find another burial chamber?
We got quite some good stuff here.
They all look like junk to me.
I don't get it.
Me neither.
How could she be
so happy from just that?
She's even rubbing her cheeks on it.
What I don't get is you, Fern.
I've never seen a young mage
as talented as you.
You must have gone
through many trainings.
And yet I don't sense any passion
or obsession from you.
You're a strange girl.
I became a full-fledged mage
to repay my debt to a certain someone.
That was my goal in life at the time.
I kept pouring all my effort into it
without ever thinking
about the future beyond.
I must have exhausted
all of the passion I had back then.
Then why do you continue
your pursuit of magic?
Doesn't Mistress Frieren
look happy to you?
She does.
The first time I raided a dungeon,
I saw how much fun she had collecting
magical tools that looked like junk.
That made me smile as well.
It must've been that I liked
seeing Mistress Frieren happy
that I decided to pursue magic
together with her.
We should start moving.
Seems like I was right
to follow you two after all.
I'm sure you can have fun
even in this cruel dungeon.
The atmosphere changed.
I guess we're close
to the innermost depth.
Wirbel.
What is it?
Are you too tired to walk...
I've been restrained.
There are three mages concealing
their mana. It's an ambush.
Scharf, block their vision.
Ehre is restrained
with a Sorganeel spell.
I know.
No wonder the Ruins of the King's Tomb
has been impregnable.
I certainly didn't expect
anything like this.
Scharf, you take care of me.
Ehre, you go after Scharf.
I'll take down Ehre.
We'll break through them.
A clone made through magic.
It must be the work
of a demon or a monster.
But I've never seen such
a perfect copy of another person.
Its mana and skill were exactly
the same as Laufen's.
It even behaves the same way.
There's a chance
it copied her memories.
I can't say I feel happy about this.
If there's a silver lining about this,
is that we can tell it's an impostor
from a single glance.
At least there's little
to no chance of friendly fire.
If this caster can control
multiple clones at the same time,
then it would be a terrifying threat.
In any case, teaming up
was the right call.
With it, we have more options
on how to deal with them.
Denken,
can you deal with that, too?
The only thing I can say is that...
if this weren't an exam,
I would have already broken my bottle.
- Now then, what shall we do?
- If our ability is equal...
- Can't even laugh at this.
- ...then it's all up to luck.
- Look into my eyes.
- So it's not impossible.
- How long do we need to hold it off?
EPISODE 24: A PERFECT REPLICA
What it creates is a perfect replica.