No wonder the Ruins of the King's Tomb
has been impregnable.
I certainly didn't expect
anything like this.
Denken,
can you deal with that, too?
The only thing I can say is that...
If this wasn't an exam,
I would have already broken my bottle.
FRIEREN: BEYOND JOURNEY'S END
EPISODE 24: A PERFECT REPLICA
We refer to the lord of that dungeon
as Spiegel, the Water-Mirror Demon.
It's a monster from a mythical era
that appears in Ewig the Sage's heroic tales.
It is believed that Spiegel can read
the memories of those who enter the dungeon
and create clones of its targets.
There are similar monsters
that exist today like the Einsam,
but what the Spiegel produces
isn't some illusion.
They're perfect physical clones
with the original's strength, mana,
and even techniques.
That is why the Ruins of the King's Tomb
remain unmapped to this day.
Why did Sense choose
this dungeon as the exam location?
The clones are equal opponents.
In order to defeat them
without casualties,
one would need to calmly analyze
their own selves and work with others.
A very fitting exam
from a pacifist like her.
This is bad.
We must fall back for now.
Denken!
Now then...
What must we do here?
A dead end, huh?
Looks like we've been cornered.
Glasses Boy.
I'd like to ask for your opinion as
an expert in duplication magic. Can I?
How many times must I remind you
that my name is Land?
You can ask, though.
How much do you think
that clone perfectly copied me?
You know, Übel,
you still talk a lot
even during battle, right?
As if you'd die if you ever shut up.
Looks like you've been
observing me well.
Yeah, I might actually die if I did that.
Yet that thing is so quiet.
Does that mean it didn't copy
my memory or personality?
No, it probably just can't talk.
When it first attacked me,
it snatched my escape golem
from my pocket.
I see. It is indeed
what I would've done.
It also has knowledge about us.
The reason it hasn't given chase
despite cornering us
is because it's wary
of your Sorganeel spell.
Or maybe because
it likes toying with its prey.
That's not funny.
You're losing a lot of blood.
At this rate, you won't last long,
Glasses Boy.
So it seems.
Can I ask you one last thing?
Are you the real Glasses Boy?
Who knows? Can't say.
Use my bottle.
That is for your own survival.
Is that so?
All right then.
Wait here for a bit, Glasses Boy.
I'll go get your bottle back.
Hey, wait—
Right, of course it would
close the distance.
The requirement for activating Sorganeel
is to have the target's
entire body in sight.
The first one to misjudge
the distance will lose.
If our abilities are equal, then this battle
will mostly be decided by luck.
I've never been good with luck,
so I never liked fights
where luck is a deciding factor.
That's why I never thought
about fighting myself.
Good grief, I really do have
a death wish, don't I?
See? I really am unlucky.
This is why I hate this thing.
That said,
seems like your luck
is even worse than mine.
That was faster than expected,
Glasses Boy.
Huh, so even the bottle was fake.
Übel.
You must've already known
the dying me was just a clone.
So why did you do
such a dangerous thing?
Maybe because I'm sure
you would come to save me.
Do I seem like such
a nice guy to you?
No, not at all.
In fact, it doesn't matter
if you are nice or not.
You see, you didn't try
to take my bottle.
That's because you don't want to let
somebody die from your action, right?
That's why I created a situation
where I would die because of you.
Thank you, Glasses Boy.
I feel like I learned
something new about you.
Is that so? Good for you then.
Will you be able to sympathize
with me soon?
Hmm, I think that's still
going to take some time.
We should be really close
to the innermost depth.
Mistress Frieren,
there's a stairway over there.
Fern.
Can I double-check the map?
I believe we already explored
every corner of this floor.
There's a secret room behind this wall.
I'm sure there's a treasure in it.
Judging from how it feels,
it might even have
a rare grimoire in it.
But I couldn't see anything
resembling an entrance.
Indeed.
But structurally speaking,
there's no mistake
that there's a room here...
This is amazing, Mistress Frieren.
This seems to depict
the achievements of the buried king.
I've never seen a mural from the Unified
Dynasty era this well preserved.
This is a valuable discovery.
What a magnificent view.
Things really are going
as smoothly as they possibly can.
Maybe things will keep going smoothly
and we'll pass the exam before we know it.
Maybe.
What's wrong?
Why are you all gathered here?
Judging from the structure,
we should reach the depths once
we get past the hall beyond this door.
And?
That thing has been in there
for half a day.
It's finally getting interesting.
This is how dungeon raids should be.
A perfect clone, huh?
It does indeed seem to have
the same strength as me.
We cannot reach the depths
unless we deal with that clone.
Do you have any ideas?
Let's see...
If that thing is a perfect replica of me,
then the weakness should be
the same as any living mage.
In order to defeat a stronger mage,
we need to use restraining magic
or hypnosis magic.
I'm resistant to both, though.
But it might be able to create an opening,
no matter how small it is.
That should be enough for you
to defeat that thing.
Methode.
You're good at those tricks, right?
I wouldn't say I'm good, but...
Then, excuse me.
How interesting.
The restraining spell
doesn't work on her.
Smells nice.
It usually would work as long as
there isn't a big difference in mana.
Miss Frieren,
please look into my eyes now.
Seems like hypnosis magic
isn't working either.
I can't break through
her mental defense.
Oh my.
So she really is resistant to both.
The structure of her mental defense
may be complex and strong,
but it seems to be a very old technique.
An expert in mental magic
might be able to find a vulnerability.
Do you know any of that
among the participants?
Second-class mage Edel
might have a chance.
That said, unlike me, her combat
capabilities are pretty much non-existent,
so I'm not sure
if she can make it here.
And to begin with,
hypnosis magic only works
if the target has a mind to affect.
I am not certain whether the clone
has replicated that as well.
I see we lack many
important information.
Edel, what do you think that is?
Dunno.
But it definitely has powers
equal to the first-class mage Sense.
We can only conceal our mana
and hide for so long.
Our only choice is to fight it.
Do you think you can defeat it, Blei?
My lack of combat capability aside,
both you and Dünste can't fight
properly inside this dungeon.
Modern magic is not suited
for dungeon battles to begin with.
To think the fact that
most dungeons have been raided
during the Demon King's reign
would bite us here.
We've spent too many resources focusing
on creating powerful defensive spells.
As a result, more offensive spells
now rely on natural elements.
Rather than creating
something from nothing,
it's more mana-efficient to manipulate
or change nearby elements instead.
But that thing is really good
in that regard.
Its hair is infused
with multiple layers of magic.
You might as well assume it has
countless ways to fight in this dungeon.
From how I see it, there is
no way to win against it.
The world of magic
is the world of imagination.
The fact that it can freely control hairs,
which may as well be countless strings
means she can imagine far better
than normal humans.
In other words, she's a much
stronger mage than we are.
To be honest, I think it's a miracle
that we've managed to escape so far.
We already did our best.
We're not even fighters
to begin with.
This might be the time for us to give up.
To be honest, I'm scared
and I want to go home already.
Edel, won't your voice reach it?
Hypnosis magic certainly has been
the business of our family,
but I doubt I can make
that thing follow a high-level order.
At best, I could probably make it
kneel to give us an opening.
But even then, I will still need to
make eye contact and call out to it.
So it's not impossible, then?
Only if it has a mind, that is.
How long do we need to hold it off?
Fifteen seconds.
Or rather, that's probably
all you can manage.
What do you mean?
You're about to find out.
Put defensive spells in all directions.
Huh?
In modern magic battles, there are
two ways to overcome a defensive spell.
Either you smash it
with overwhelming mass,
or you try to slip past
with techniques.
Those who attack in numbers
tend to do the latter.
Call me surprised.
I didn't think it could do both.
They weigh like huge boulders.
I thought the all-direction defensive
spell would last for 15 seconds,
but it was actually broken much sooner.
But we've made eye contact.
The tendencies of superior mages to make sure
to keep their enemies in clear sight.
Kneel!
I see. I understand it now.
It doesn't have a mind.
It's just imitating the original's mind,
down to the details.
It's impossible for us to win.
Our only choice is to rely
on other stronger mages.
Do everything you can to run
and find the ones that can fight.
I'm done and giving up,
so I'm going home.
I don't want to get hurt anymore.
How convenient.
It even ensures my safety.
Let's get away from here, too.
Can anyone even make it to the depths
with things like that around?
Just like I said,
she never has any intention
of letting anyone pass.
We have very little information
at the moment.
I suggest we prepare for the possibility
that it doesn't have a mind.
Though in that case, we'll have to
take it down by brute force.
Can you do that?
Dunno, I'm not sure.
Good grief, there's no way
to tell what they're thinking.
But we might be a good fit
for each other, as expected.
Ehre can easily overwhelm me or Scharf
when it comes to a simple contest of mana.
However,
I know how to win a fight.
No matter who's the opponent,
no matter what the situation.
Brute force, huh?
Excuse me, if that is the case,
then I might be able
to kill Mistress Frieren.
Is that so?
Yes.
Okay then,
let's come up with a strategy.
- Looks like things are mostly done.
- Let's come up with a strategy.
- So you have some information.
- Can we cooperate?
- Maybe you should apologize to him.
- How unpleasant.
- That thing has no weakness.
- You seem to be having fun.
EPISODE 25: FATAL VULNERABILITY
This is Frieren's fatal vulnerability.