We have very little information
at the moment.
I suggest we prepare for the possibility
that it doesn't have a mind.
Though in that case, we'll have to
take it down by brute force.
Can you do that?
Dunno, I'm not sure.
Excuse me,
if that is the case,
then I might be able
to kill Mistress Frieren.
Is that so?
Yes.
Okay then, let's come up with a strategy.
FRIEREN: BEYOND JOURNEY'S END
EPISODE 25: A FATAL VULNERABILITY
Okay, just to confirm,
in case the clones do have a mind,
then the plan is to use
Edel's mental magic
in order to break my mental defenses,
and have Fern kill it, okay?
Okay.
Okay? Just like that?
Dünste.
Where is Edel?
Sense's clone attacked us
and she decided to drop out.
I see.
Did Blei drop out as well?
He bought some time
that allowed me to escape.
I hope he managed
to escape to safety.
Don't mind me, just go!
B-But...!
It's better than
not having any of us pass!
I have information for you.
Can we cooperate?
That was my intention all along.
Is there anyone here who can heal?
I have a holy scripture with me,
so I can cast simple healing magic.
Please do.
I see.
So the clones do not have a mind.
Yes. According to Edel,
they only imitate
how the original's mind works.
They don't have a mind of their own.
So we've lost
the easy way to defeat it.
We need to form a strategy
with that in mind.
Even so, Frieren,
there are still too many
unknown factors.
The biggest issue is the true identity
of the clone and its summoner.
We mustn't take action
until we understand their nature.
We need to figure out whether the clone
has any weakness specific to them.
If that clone really is
as strong as Frieren,
there will likely be casualties.
I am not telling you.
Right, of course.
They don't have any weaknesses.
The one controlling the clones
is a monster from the mythic age
called Spiegel.
Lawine...
How do you know that?
My eldest brother was a member
of the advance party
that the Continental Magic Association
sent to raid the Ruins of the King's Tomb.
So you have information
regarding this place.
No wonder you could make it this far.
But your action doesn't seem logical.
You should've shared your information
and cooperated with us from the beginning.
It doesn't seem like everyone was
in the mood to work together back then.
And before we knew it,
Frieren and Fern were already gone.
Besides, old man,
you're the type to ruthlessly abandon
their allies unless there's a rule, right?
What makes you think
we'd cooperate with you?
They sure hate you, huh?
Yes, I may already be old,
but it's still not nice
to hear it so directly.
Maybe you should apologize for that.
My bad, old man.
According to the advance
party's observations,
the Spiegel is beyond that door,
inside the treasure vault.
They say that the monster itself is frail
and incapable of attacking.
If we defeat it,
all of the clones will disappear.
We reached the same conclusion
after using our mana detection.
The main body is beyond that door.
But the door has a powerful seal on it.
I can confirm that as well.
It has to be the work of my clone.
It's a spell that shuts the door
of a treasure vault at the risk of one's life.
It's one of the folk magic's
strongest binding spells.
That door won't open
until the caster dies.
We can bypass the door
by breaking through the wall,
but it's probably ready
for that as well.
So what you're saying is,
in order to defeat the Spiegel,
we have to defeat that clone
no matter what, huh?
If you want to defeat it,
I suggest you hurry.
What do you mean?
Spiegel creates clones
of everyone in the dungeon.
Those clones have a habit
where they start gathering
at the innermost depth as time goes on.
The last advance party was mostly
annihilated aside from my brother's unit.
They were defeated right before the depth,
which happens to be exactly here.
I see.
Umm...
The clones imitate
the target's mind, right?
Then if the original has
a weakness in their behavior,
the clone must have it as well,
correct?
I would believe so.
In that case,
I believe we might have a chance.
What is that weakness
you're talking about?
Mistress Frieren.
Could you please stand
next to that wall?
Sure.
My word...
Impossible...
How could this be?
Did you notice it?
You noticed something?
Nope.
Indeed, this is Frieren's fatal vulnerability.
How did I miss this
when I was fighting her?
No, it's exactly because I expected her
to be an expert, so I didn't realize it.
The second she casts a spell,
her mana detection breaks off
for just a split second.
Isn't that a common mistake
that apprentice mages make?
I've never been good at it.
If you were aware of it,
why didn't you tell us?
I mean, it's embarrassing...
This isn't the time for that.
But she's still too skilled
in all other areas.
I doubt there's any mage
that could make use of that opening.
In any case, we're going
to hold a strategy meeting.
Even if we can somehow
defeat Frieren's clone...
Mistress Frieren,
you seem happy for some reason.
I am.
I think we've mostly
figured it out now.
So, Eisen, you keep the enemy's attention,
and we'll flank it.
You provide covering fire, Frieren.
What about Heiter?
He's got a hangover today,
so he's no good.
He's gone...
I'm just reminded
of how we used to discuss things
like this to defeat dungeon bosses.
All right.
Let's begin conquering this dungeon.
Can we win?
Don't worry.
There isn't a dungeon
that can't be beaten.
And I can say that
as the mage of the party
that has conquered
the most dungeons in history.
Are you sure we should leave fighting
Frieren's clone to just you two?
It's easier to predict its movement
with a smaller party.
It's true that we'd most certainly win
if everyone fought together,
but most of us would end up dead.
There probably won't even be time
to use the escape golems.
So you're saying...
It's more important for us to stop
the other clones from reaching here?
If they flank us,
we'd be wiped out, after all.
All right, let's proceed with the plan.
Very well. I pray for your success.
Open it.
Now then.
Let's tell each other who would be
the worst opponent for you to fight against.
Judrajim.
It's moving exactly
as Mistress Frieren said it would.
Vollzanbel.
Its mana detection is interrupted.
"I" would be wary of Fern
who took the opportunity to hide.
But it would have its hands full with
fending an opponent of equal strength.
It can't possibly afford
to look for Fern.
After all,
no one knows how dangerous I am
more than myself.
It'll be all right.
Even I can't easily detect you
once you completely conceal yourself.
But would it really be enough
to attack it with just Zoltraak?
It's the quickest to cast, after all.
Besides, Zoltraak is
a relatively new spell for elves.
It hasn't been around long enough
for me to block it by instinct.
No matter what I do,
it may be for just a moment,
but when I have to deal with it,
my reaction is always slightly delayed.
But it's different for you, Fern.
For you, Zoltraak is something that
always existed since you were born.
Since it's fundamental to mages now,
you should be able to do it without thinking.
Your Zoltraak will be able to kill me.
Put every bit of your mana into it.
Frieren.
I'm pretty sure you hate me.
So why did you come to me?
I honestly thought
we'd never see each other again.
I've come to deliver my master's will.
It has been 50 years since then...
I see.
So Flamme has died.
Aren't you sad?
She's just an apprentice
I raised on a whim.
This is almost like a report.
What did she write?
It seems the Emperor approved
nationwide research into magic.
Until now, humans always considered
magic to be the work of demons,
so any open research
was considered taboo.
Flamme convinced him to change it,
and has been working as the instructor
for the newly established imperial mages.
She's asking me to take over
that training in this will.
What a greedy girl.
Getting an approval for the research
of magic is already a huge achievement,
and yet she's asking for more?
Is that something incredible?
It means that the largest
single empire on the continent
will begin researching magic
and using it for military purposes.
The surrounding countries
won't ignore this.
In just a few decades, the use of magic
will spread throughout the continent.
The era where any human
can use magic is coming.
This means that in the near future,
humanity will have the power
to fight back against the Demon King.
I see. That is indeed
very incredible.
It really is.
But, that is not what I want.
Go home, Frieren.
I can't possibly comply with her will.
It truly disgusts me.
An era where anyone can use magic?
Magic is meant to be special.
I have no intention of teaching it
to those without the potential.
How dare she ask me for this.
In the end, Flamme and I
could never understand each other.
She was nothing but an apprentice
I raised on a whim.
My master said
that you would get angry
and tear up the will.
Even so, she wanted to let you know,
that her dream came true.
I don't really understand it, though.
I will be leaving, then.
I don't think we'll ever
see each other again.
Frieren.
Before you leave,
how about a little walk?
We have all the time
in the world, after all.
An era where anyone can use magic.
That was Flamme's dream.
I'm sure that she initially didn't
even think about helping humanity
or gaining the power
to fight back against demons.
It didn't matter to her back then.
Do you know her favorite spell?
It was a spell to produce
a field of flowers.
A pointless spell
that is good for nothing.
She truly did love magic.
She seriously wished that everyone
in the world could use it.
It was revolting.
It was like a cute dream
a little girl would have.
But that was actually the case.
It was a fantasy that she would tell me
when she was far shorter than me.
To be honest, I think such a time would
only come much farther in the future,
or that it wasn't something
that she could make happen.
I always thought that her life is so short
that it may as well be nonexistent,
and yet she ascended to become
the bringer of magic to humanity.
Master would always
make decisions so quickly.
As if something was rushing her.
Humans have a limited lifespan.
They're in a place much closer
to death than we are.
There are many moments in life
when we all must make important decisions.
And for them, they cannot afford
to delay those choices.
We can postpone a decision
for a century or two.
It won't even hinder us in the slightest
if we leave it for a millennium.
Our time is nearly infinite, after all.
Frieren.
A long time has passed since humans
established what they call civilization.
Things will move faster
and faster from now on.
In just one thousand years...
In just one thousand years,
the era of humans will arrive.
We will be overtaken by humans.
Do not neglect your training, Frieren.
If someone would end up killing you,
it would be the Demon King...
...or a human mage.
Isn't that exciting, Serie?
From this point,
we will see so many mages,
and so many different kinds of magic.
- Now then, let's get this over with.
- Worst case scenario, we both might die.
- Amazing...
- I'm counting on you.
- This opening won't do either.
- Mistress Frieren...
- This is within expectations.
- I guess I have no choice.
EPISODE 26: THE HEIGHT OF MAGIC
This is the height of magic.