If someone would end up killing you,
it would be the Demon King...
...or a human mage.
FRIEREN: BEYOND JOURNEY'S END
EPISODE 26: THE HEIGHT OF MAGIC
It blocked it.
It's still within our expectations.
From here on,
it will be a battle of attrition.
They're really here.
Just like Methode predicted.
Don't get in my way.
That's my line.
Methode figured out
the exact location of the clones.
We have no chance of winning
if it becomes a free-for-all fight.
Before the clones can gather here,
we have to split up
and hold them back.
We have told each other
who our worst match-ups are.
Any opponent you find difficult
will also be a tough opponent
for your clones.
Our advantage is that we can
communicate and cooperate.
By choosing the right opponent,
we can make the fight more favorable
for us to some degree.
Against enemies
you can't win on your own,
you fight them with numbers.
It's almost amusing
how easy this fight is.
This way, we can hold back the clones.
All right, let's proceed with the plan.
Very well.
I pray for your success.
I have one concern.
The number of clones I detected
is slightly less than
the number of participants.
Most importantly,
I cannot detect Sense's clone,
which is our biggest threat.
You're right.
I couldn't detect it either.
We definitely cannot ignore Sense's clone.
If we got hit by a pincer attack,
I wouldn't be able to protect Fern.
Worst case, we might both die.
I still haven't figured out the locations
of Fern's and Denken's clones either.
Our only choice is to use more accurate
close-range detection methods.
We wouldn't have to worry this much
if you weren't here.
A first-class mage must be able
to overcome unreasonable odds.
This is still nowhere near that.
Besides, you can pass
by watching each other's back.
It's truly a kind and peaceful exam.
We defeated them.
It doesn't exactly feel good, though.
A surprise attack!
You monster...
I never even let up my mana detection.
Lawine, break your bottle, too.
You're old enough to know
when to quit, right?
We can retake the exam in three years.
Dammit...
I didn't make it in time.
That said, even if I helped,
the result probably won't change.
Even when its back was facing me,
I couldn't feel any opening.
In any case,
I need to at least buy some time.
You're Denken,
the imperial mage, wasn't it?
What's the situation here?
Are you planning to fight that?
I don't think you can win.
I'm well aware of that.
Say, Denken.
Is doing this
necessary to beat the dungeon?
Right now, Frieren is...
No need for the details.
Is it necessary or not?
It is.
Then I'll defeat it.
What are you talking about?
Denken is the strongest amongst us here.
You couldn't even beat Wirbel
in the first place.
That's not the problem here.
I certainly am a third-class,
inexperienced mage.
I'm so much weaker
compared to Denken or Wirbel.
But if it's against Sense,
I think I can win.
This is the spell I'm best at.
The spell that slashes
almost anything, Reelseiden.
It can cut anything I think I can cut,
and it can't cut anything
I think I can't cut.
What's your point?
That spell can easily be blocked
with defensive magic.
Oh right, you were watching my fight
with Wirbel, Glasses Boy?
Well, defensive magic is something that is
supposed to block other magic.
Makes it hard to imagine
cutting through it, you know?
I see. Then all the more reason
it won't work on Sense.
Even from just what I can see,
her hair has layers of spells equal
to defensive magic cast on it.
I'm saying that logic
doesn't matter here.
This is all about visualization.
Hey, wait.
I knew it.
Sorganeel doesn't work against it.
Well, hair is still a part of the body.
It's impossible to get
her entire body in sight.
Reelseiden.
As expected, Übel would be
the one facing my clone.
I already know who will win.
It's probably not even much of a fight.
It was back at the second-class
mage exam two years ago.
The examiner for the second exam
was Burg, a first-class mage.
Ever since becoming a first-class mage,
he has never been injured even once
because he specialized in defense.
The Immovable Cloak.
The cloak he created
with magic is embedded
with defensive techniques that prevent
any offensive spells from getting through.
In the second exam,
the participants have to use offensive magic
on Burg who is wearing his cloak.
If they can make him take a step back,
they pass. A very simple test.
There is a rule
that disqualifies anyone who kills.
It encourages the participants to at least
control their offensive magic,
to ensure the safety of other candidates.
Next.
No one was worried about Burg.
Oops, cut a bit too much.
And yet a no-name girl who had
just become a third-class mage...
...killed him like it was nothing.
I'm getting disqualified, right?
I know.
Can I go home now?
I have just one question.
Go on.
How did you cut through
the immovable cloak?
Let's see...
Have you ever sewn anything, Sense?
No. Why?
Of course, you look like you come
from a good family.
Or maybe you just take care
of those kinds of stuff with magic.
Well, I've never sewn either
since I'm so clumsy.
But I often watch my sister do it.
When you cut fabric,
you place the scissors like this
and cut it smoothly.
It makes such a good sound.
I always liked that sound.
I don't see your point.
It's about visualization, you see.
You see, fabric is something
that can be cut.
It's something meant to be cut.
She lost her mind.
Of course, anyone can
visualize cutting fabric.
Even an idiot can do that.
But the world of magic
is not that simple.
You can't make something happen with magic
unless you can visualize it perfectly.
Just like how a small ant can't imagine
crushing a huge dragon with its foot.
And against a cloak protected by
the iron-wall defensive techniques,
barely any mage
can visualize cutting through it.
If one is a mage,
they can tell from a single glance
that no offensive spell
can get through that cloak.
They would know
no matter how stupid they are.
Humans cannot escape that
as long as they are intelligent beings.
And yet, she followed her feelings.
Even though she has the intelligence
to know that she cannot cut it,
she managed to visualize slicing through
the Immovable Cloak with her feelings.
I'm not sure she can even think
like a normal human being.
This is in the realm of genius.
Can I go now?
Yes.
By the way, Sense.
Your hair is so beautiful.
It must be hard
to take care of them, right?
Perhaps I already lost
to her at that point.
I cannot imagine beating her.
She's the worst opponent for me.
Everyone thinks too much.
Hair is something to cut, isn't it?
Taking care of my hair?
It's pretty much hell.
I don't even want to think about it.
You should've just cut them off.
I think I get what
you're trying to say.
You guys are buying time
for Frieren to defeat that Spiegel.
Yes, that is correct.
We also took out
three clones ourselves.
Then I can cut to the chase.
So...
Oh my.
I think Sense's clone
has just been defeated.
This mana...
Übel the third-class mage
must be the one who took it out.
Quite surprising.
You think? That thing
has no chance against her.
A battle between mages is like
a rock-paper-scissors match, after all.
But we have countless moves to win,
so it's an extremely complex
rock-paper-scissors match.
And that's why you want to increase
the number of moves as much as possible.
Sure.
I'll help you hold back the clones.
I'm not the type to trust others easily,
but I'm not stupid enough to let
a winning horse get away.
Currently, there are two dangerous clones
that we must stop no matter what.
And I've figured out the location
of one of them. Denken's clone.
I'd like to ask you people
to deal with that.
As for the other one, Fern's clone,
you can leave it to me.
It seems she's especially good
at concealing her mana.
If I don't find it, there will be
casualties from its ambush.
Are you sure you'll be okay alone?
I can focus my mana detection
better if I'm alone.
She's quite strong, you know?
I have many talents,
but what I'm really good at
is stopping others.
Also, I've made sure that...
- There.
- ...restraint magic would work
- I can't move...
- by testing it on Fern herself.
All right then.
Time to kick some ass.
So, Übel...
I'm not hallucinating, right?
Probably not.
I mean, you can't move, right?
My clone has returned.
Does this mean this will continue
until we defeat that Spiegel thing?
It's a war of attrition.
Now things are getting exciting.
Quite so.
Shouldn't we just give up already?
This opening is no good.
Right now,
Fern isn't good enough to notice it.
I guess I have no choice.
Just an opening from lack of
mana detection won't be enough to kill it.
You're right.
We could've won if we can
create a bigger opening.
You can beat it then, right?
Then let's make that opening.
Is that possible?
If I let my guard down,
it will let its guard down even more.
But then you would...
It won't be a fatal wound
if I focus on my defense.
So the strategy in that situation is...
I leave it to you.
If you think you can win,
then you will.
How can you be so certain?
Because I have always
underestimated you.
That's good then.
That means we have more
than enough of a chance to win.
It's still standing.
But it has taken a fatal wound.
I need to finish it...
What happened?
Was that an attack?
I don't sense any mana.
I don't recognize
this attack as magic.
Incredible, Mistress Frieren...
So this is the height of magic.
But that's so unlike you.
Your guard is completely down.
You did great, Fern.
It's been 80 years or so
since I was cornered into showing that.
Now then, let's get this over with.
So it is over.
I can't move...
Wirbel, carry me on your back...
Why do you two always
end up collapsing?
So this is the innermost depth
of the Ruins of the King's Tomb...
You have successfully conquered
the Ruins of the King's Tomb.
This is a historical achievement,
enough to make you equal
to first-class mages.
As promised, everyone who made it
to this innermost depth
has passed the second exam.
And where did the biggest
contributor to our victory go?
It's dark in here!
It's so scary!
So dark! So scary!
- So dark, so scary.
- Well, I guess I know the feeling.
So dark, so scary.
And with this,
the second exam is over.
See, it can even use healing magic.
Well? Isn't that amazing?
Who are you again?
- It has always been with me since I was little.
- You were unlucky this time.
- The spell Flamme taught you, huh?
- Despite how it looks,
- You're severely depressed, huh?
- I'm in the worst mood right now.
- The third exam will now begin.
- Let's go home already, Fern.
- Just make fun of me like always.
EPISODE 27: AN ERA OF HUMANS
The era of humans has arrived.