The path of the warrior is without end.
You've taken yet another step
toward mastering its secrets.
There is nothing left for me to teach you.
You say that every time.
Huh? Fern?
Hmph.
She's pissed? Why?!
I'm scared...
You're there like the wind
Closing your eyes at sunset
I wonder what's on your mind
Beyond Journey's End
With your eyelids open
Your eyes shone like glass
It faintly smelled like a sunny day
Clear up the sky, let flowers bloom
Bloom and blame it on the sunny sky
Even the rain, when it stops
Will make you shine in the sunlight
Calm the stirring sounds in my heart
We go like the sunny wind
Go on and fly over that cloud
Further and further away
Episode 27: An Era of Humans
Ms. Frieren and I had an argument.
Again? You've been arguing a lot recently,
don't you think?
Isn't the third test the final one?
This is hardly the time to be squabbling.
She was truly awful this time.
My staff broke in battle
in the Ruins of the King's Tomb,
so I told Ms. Frieren
I wanted to get it repaired.
She told me it'd be better to buy
a new staff than to repair my old one.
You mean that staff, don't you?
She said it couldn't be repaired
since it was already in pieces.
Still, Mr. Heiter gave me that staff.
It's been with me ever since I was little.
We're talking about Frieren, though.
I doubt she meant any harm.
At the very least, I never even
would have thought of throwing it away.
Three years until the next
first-class mage exam, huh?
Three years is a long time.
Just make fun of me like you always do.
Do you want me to?
No.
In that case, Little Miss Lawine,
shall I pat your head?
What? You wanna fight?
Hurry up.
You're in really rough shape.
Hey, it's Frieren.
What's with the bag?
Hey, how long are you going
to hang around here?
I failed the test. There's nothing
keeping us together anymore.
You're interfering with my business.
Get out of here.
I'm here as a customer.
Then hurry up and choose something.
You can have some.
I don't want any.
You were unlucky this time.
You got the short end of the stick.
It could've happened to
anyone in that position.
A loss is a loss. I wasn't strong enough.
Either way, don't bring that up again.
I may seem fine, but I'm actually
in a terrible mood right now.
But you opened your shop regardless.
Denken, you may not realize this,
but people have to work to make a living
no matter how foul their mood.
Is that right?
Maybe it's for the best
that I'm the one who failed.
The first-class mage exam
is held once every three years.
A decrepit old man like you might not
be around three years from now.
You're right.
Don't agree with me.
Richter, you truly are an insolent youngster.
You mock authority
and have no qualms about mistreating
the weak in order to achieve your goals.
Your behavior is hardly praiseworthy.
And yet I feel no hatred for you at all,
probably because I was once
an insolent youngster too.
And now, I'm an imperial mage.
What are you trying to say?
I'm telling you not to be so discouraged.
Three years from now, you'll be
far stronger than you are today.
Laufen, let's go.
Sorry. The old man's not good with people.
What's your relationship with Denken, exactly?
Damn it, old man.
He didn't buy anything after all.
Is today my unlucky day or something?
I asked around town and was told this shop
can fix any staff, no matter how broken.
Show me.
What is this broken pile of scrapwood?
Don't tell me this is meant to be a staff.
I'm not a trash disposal service, you know.
It's not trash.
Probably.
My mood was starting to improve,
but because of you, I feel terrible again.
I have the right to choose
which jobs I work on.
You should give up on this staff.
I see.
If you can't do it, then never mind.
Frieren, you really get on my nerves.
When did I say I couldn't do it?
Can you finish today?
I want it to be repaired
in time for the third test.
Don't be ridiculous.
Frieren.
What?
I'm sorry for calling it trash.
It's a good, well-maintained staff.
Someone must've taken really good care of it.
Fern, let's head back already.
Ms. Frieren doesn't understand me at all.
I don't understand you either.
Stop! Don't take it out on me!
What matters is that she
tries to understand you.
I think Frieren is doing her best.
You're Frieren's kid.
Her student, right?
Am I wrong?
No, that's right.
Either way, the second test
only ended yesterday,
but I had another terrible day
because of your master.
I would've made more profit
if you'd just bought a new one.
Take good care of it.
My staff.
Frieren struggles to understand emotions.
I'm sure it will cause
difficulties and disagreements.
But there is one good thing about it.
Frieren will worry and care
about you just as much.
Few masters are better than her.
Ms. Frieren, about yesterday…
What?
Actually, never mind.
I see.
The third test will now begin.
Do you know why I came
all the way here, Sense?
Nothing to say, huh?
You always remain silent
in troublesome situations.
Twelve test-takers passed the second test.
It's an anomaly. It's too many.
I have no problem with a test that requires
all participants to work together,
as the current first-class mages
lack cooperativeness.
Forgive us.
But there is one among the test-takers
who is far too powerful.
You mean Ms. Frieren.
Because of her, many have passed
despite lacking the requisite strength.
A typical third test would kill all of them.
Sense, that's hardly what you want,
and not even I wish to see
such pointless deaths.
Ms. Serie.
There's no need to apologize.
It's all Frieren's fault.
An anomaly calls for an anomaly.
I will proctor the third test.
It will be a peaceful selection.
In past years, you've proctored the test.
You don't object, do you, Lernen?
Your willfulness is nothing new, Ms. Serie.
Besides, I could not
possibly test Ms. Frieren.
I could tell at a glance that
she's suppressing her own mana.
Her mana is tremendous, equal to yours.
Falsch, did you notice?
No, I have no idea
what he's talking about.
I observed her mana myself
at the testing area.
It didn't seem to me like
she was suppressing it.
I observed none of the typical fluctuations.
No living creature with mana
can conceal these fluctuations.
Even if it were possible, it would take
an extraordinary amount of time to master.
It would hardly be a practical skill.
Frieren has devoted her life
to mastering that impractical skill
in order to deceive demons.
Demons are far more sensitive
to mana than us humanoids.
Without innate talent, it takes more than
a century or two of practice to fool them.
It truly is a waste of time.
You'd become far more powerful devoting
your efforts to training something else.
It's incredibly inefficient.
But that inefficiency
breeds weakness in others.
In a battle between experienced mages,
miscalculating your opponent's mana
can lead directly to death.
Frieren is in fact relatively
unskilled for her age,
and yet she's defeated demons.
Her mana control is simply that refined.
As far as I knew, only the Demon King
was able to see through it at first glance.
That is, until this moment, Lernen.
It was a coincidence. I just happened
to see a minor fluctuation.
That's all.
Ever modest and dependable.
It's been more than half a century since
you became the first first-class mage.
But you're still the same timid boy.
That's my only disappointment.
You've achieved this level, and yet
you don't have much longer to live.
I doubt you'll ever get the
chance to fight Frieren,
even if it's a battle you could win.
I shouldn't take on human students.
It's truly disappointing.
In the end, that boy never saw
the fluctuations in my mana either.
The third test will be an interview
with Serie the Great Mage.
So that's how it's going to be.
You will be called one at a time
when she is ready for you.
Serie intends to fail us both.
Please wait here until then.
You know her?
From a long time ago.
She probably intends to choose who passes
based on her intuition.
But Serie's intuition is always right.
I still haven't become the mage
Serie wishes I were.
Excuse me…
You fail. Now leave.
May I ask why?
My mana frightens you.
You know the limits of your own abilities.
You can't imagine yourself
as a first-class mage, can you?
In the world of magic, that which
can't be visualized cannot be.
It's the most fundamental principle.
Now leave.
Fail.
Frieren, you can't imagine yourself
as a first-class mage either,
but for a different reason
from the rest of the test-takers.
You don't believe I'd ever let you pass.
It's true, isn't it?
I'll give you one chance.
Tell me your favorite spell.
A spell to create a field of flowers.
That's the spell Flamme taught you.
How truly useless.
You fail.
Uh-huh.
You won't even stand your ground
when I mock you?
I find it hard to believe a mage
like you defeated the Demon King.
I didn't do it alone.
Himmel, Eisen, Heiter, and me.
If any one of us hadn't been there,
we couldn't have won.
So you were blessed with strong allies.
You were lucky.
That's right. I was lucky.
Himmel, why did you recruit me?
Because I was looking for a powerful mage.
There are plenty of powerful mages
in the royal capital.
It didn't have to be me.
I wanted you.
Why?
Frieren, you may not remember,
but I once met you a long time ago.
Yeah, I don't remember that at all.
I know you don't.
When I was a child, I got lost
while gathering herbs in the forest.
Wandering the woods for hours at night,
I experienced loneliness
for the first time in my life.
I thought I'd never be able
to return to my village.
That was when a lone elf pointed me
in the direction of the village.
All she did was show me which way it was.
She spoke not a word of encouragement.
To the eyes of a child,
she seemed so cold-hearted.
Perhaps she sensed my unease,
or perhaps it was on a whim...
You showed me a spell
to create a field of flowers.
I thought it was beautiful.
For the first time in my life,
I thought magic was beautiful.
It's probably just a coincidence,
but it was that useless spell
my master taught me
that brought me and my companions together.
Also, Serie, I'm sure you intend
to fail Fern as well,
but I doubt you'll be able to.
She will exceed your expectations.
The era of humans has arrived.
Exceed my expectations? Hardly.
The sight of my mana has her frozen in place.
She's no different from the other test-takers.
Wait. What do you see?
It's fluctuating.
Fern, was it?
Be my student.
What? No.
I'll treat you well.
I can take you to greater heights.
To heights no other mage has ever reached.
Does this affect whether or not I pass?
Perhaps.
I see.
Ms. Serie.
Fern.
I'm sure Serie will have
a lot of things to say to you,
but there's no need for you
to accept her demands.
Just as Serie will fail me
no matter what I say,
she will pass you no matter what you say.
After all, Serie's intuition is always right.
I am Ms. Frieren's student.
Frieren coached you, didn't she?
I'm not foolish enough
to overlook a promising mage.
You pass.
Next.
And I'm alright (I'll be alright)
Yeah, I hear you (I care about you)
The wind teases this hair that's longer now
There's meaning in everything
Even the days that came to a halt
Now that I finally understand,
I've caught up to you
See, things that couldn't have been
Seen if it weren't for these eyes
Why? They begin to overflow
I won't ask to see you, so at least
Let me remember the past, just for today
So, if we were to meet again
No more hesitations, I'd choose the present
Anytime, anywhere, yah (wherever you are)
Anytime, anywhere (smile for me)
I'll be there (close your eyes,
and I'll always be there)
Even if there are no absolutes
I'm always aware of your thoughts
Those tears will be alright,
dawn will surely break
I'm whispering our lullaby
for you to come back home
Episode 28
It Would Be Embarrassing When We Met Again
See you later.