CP, this is α2.
Location 1, no anomalies.
α2, this is CP.
Continue your surveillance mission.
- Emergency Kaiju Alert.
- An Emergency Kaiju Alert has just been issued.
(Emergency Disaster Alert)
- Emergency Kaiju Alert.
- An Emergency Kaiju Alert has just been issued.
(Please Evacuate According to Instructions.)
Repeat.
At South District and Central District
of Yokohama City in Kanagawa Prefecture…
(Emergency Underground Shelter, Yokohama Entrance)
At South District and Central District
of Yokohama Cityin Kanagawa Prefecture…
(Emergency Underground Shelter, Yokohama Entrance)
- Please calmly move to the shelter.
- At South District, Central District
and Isogo District of Yokohama City
in Kanagawa Prefecture,
an Emergency Kaiju Alert has been issued.
Residents in the mentioned areas.
Please move to the shelters immediately.
Regarding the future movement
of the earthquake focus…
Ah.
The target is moving from Yatobashi
towards Yamashita Town.
Estimated length is 60 meters.
Fortitude is 3.5, over.
No thermal response within 3 kilometers.
Understood.
All units, fire.
Repeat, fire.
Understood. Lead the target to TO.
Fire.
(Special Kaiju Alert)
Will the intimidation attack work?
(Evacuation Alarms Sounded in Yokohama City)
I wonder which division will come.
In Yokohama,
it will be the Third Division.
(Kaiju No. 8)
Wow, it's everywhere.
Looks like we'll be
working overtime for a while.
Okay, let's get to work.
Okay.
The citizens are all cheering
the Third Division…
(Thank You, Defense Force)
The citizens are all cheering the Third Division
for the successful defeat of the Kaiju.
The Third Division once again
completed the mission with no casualty.
- I heard Captain Ashiro has come.
- Because of the Third Division,
- That's great.
- we get to live in peace.
I would like to thank them
along with this cheer.
- Hey, capture the footage of the victims too.
- Citizens in the affected area in Yokohama,
- Ah, sorry.
- It's okay.
- Citizens in the affected area in Yokohama,
- Ah.
- please be careful of possible Yoju.
Report back to me after it's done.
Yes.
Our battle
only begins after everything is over.
The work that no one cares about
and is grateful for.
However, this is
our unknown battle against Kaiju.
(Kafka Hibino)
Kafka.
Izumo Tech. said they want a sample.
Thanks.
No.
There's too much grease here
to cut through.
Bring me a heated chainsaw.
Got it.
Hey!
Don't hoist it up.
That hurts.
Bring the stretcher over here!
Don't worry.
It's a superficial wound.
I've had a few injuries like this.
Remember to file for
workers' compensation.
Okay.
The Third Division does indeed leave a mess.
It's hard to distinguish the viscera.
But…
Do we really need to
get this done this week?
Kafka, you'll take charge of another area.
We're short-staffed there.
Where am I going?
The intestines.
- No!
- The higher-ups have approved. Just go.
My condolences.
I've heard the rumors.
Is working in the intestines
really that tough?
(Roar)
Just think about what's in there.
(Anatomical Diagram)
When working there,
you'll temporarily lose your appetite.
I'm exhausted.
The baby panda is really cute.
Let's witness it growing up.
I can still smell it.
Next up is today's special feature.
The protagonist is the one who subdued
the Kaiju that appeared in Yokohama City,
the Third Division of the Defense Force.
(Special Feature: Third Division is Deployed)
(Japan Defense Force up Close)
the Third Division of the Defense Force.
(Third Division Returning in Triumph)
And the leader of this division…
(Captain Mina Ashiro)
And the leader of this division
is Captain Mina Ashiro.
At the age of 27,
she not only became the Captain,
but also slayed
(Captain Mina Ashiro)
hundreds of Kaiju.
Let's eliminate all the Kaiju together.
Hmm.
(Captain Mina Ashiro)
Her calmness and dignified appearance
have made her become
the most popular captain.
It is believed that she'd be a candidate
for Commander.
(Future Commander Candidate)
It is believed
that she'd be a candidate for Commander.
(Future Commander Candidate)
We're looking forward to her future performance.
Why I wind up on this side of things?
No, don't think about it.
Cleaning is also an important job
in helping people.
I live in a nice room
and eat the food I like.
Isn't that enough?
My head hurts so much.
Damn, all because of that special feature.
Good morning.
Here you are.
Kafka, come here.
I'll go get ready.
Okay.
Kafka, good morning.
Morning.
This is Ichikawa, the part-time student
who will start working with us from today.
He is determined to join the Defense Force.
(Reno Ichikawa)
Well.
Let me tell you
this guy dreamed of that too.
But he gave it up long ago
and has become a veteran of our company.
That sucks.
Tokuda.
You are embarrassing him.
Why?
Why did you give up?
I have tried hard in my own way.
But there's always someone better.
(Thoroughly Cleaned 10 Kaiju)
(Health Check All Pass) (The Best Record)
I kind of realized that my abilities are limited.
When you get older, you'll understand…
I don't understand.
I will never give up.
I will never understand that logic.
And I don't want to.
Hey…
I'm going to get changed.
Well?
I thought he would get along with you.
So cunning.
No matter how I answered,
it'd just make me look miserable.
But,
is giving up really that bad?
Hey.
- Okay, let's get to work.
- Hey.
Uh… The Mitsuike crew,
keep on cleaning the bones.
Hand those parts in original shape
directly over to Izumo Tech.
Okay.
The Yoshimura crew is
in charge of dissecting the legs.
This part will be completely destroyed.
Okay.
Newcomer, to the intestines, follow me.
Yes.
Great.
You had it coming.
Kafka, you're also on intestines,
come along.
Me too?
Dealing with the intestines
for two days in a row?
You're good at dealing
with the intestines, right?
Damn it.
I'll show you.
Although he complaints,
he still works diligently.
If he had passed the exam,
he would've been a good officer.
Really?
He must have been grossed out too.
Though I am no better.
Hey,
you only brought that bento for lunch?
I don't have much appetite.
That makes sense.
Take this.
What…
Ah.
(Multivitamin V)
That's for you.
Eat as much as you can.
Otherwise, you won't make it
through the afternoon.
I'll be fine…
Here, take these too.
You'll feel much better with them.
No, that… I don't quite understand
what you're saying,
but I really don't need that.
Come on.
Just try it on, kid.
Senior, please don't do this.
- That's an abuse of power.
- Everyone has to do this in our line of work.
- Don't be shy.
Take your own luggage, okay?
(Monster Sweeper Inc.)
Good work.
Everyone, well done.
We're leaving first.
Okay.
Good work.
The worst part should
have been cleaned up now.
Senior.
Ichikawa.
What? Are you here to take revenge
for what happened this noon?
Thanks to…
Thanks to your help, I was able
to get through the first day.
Thank you very much.
Oh!
Oh.
I just came to say this.
Goodbye.
Ah.
Also…
The age limit for
Defense Force recruitment
has been relaxed to 33 years old.
It is due to the effect
of a declining birthrate.
Actually, other people's life choices
have nothing to do with me.
But when you talked about giving up,
you looked sad.
Well,
I really don't care what you do.
If I misunderstood,
you can just give it up.
Goodbye.
Ichikawa.
Thank you.
You are a better person than I thought.
I… I said I didn't mean that…
Senior?
A Yoju?
Ah.
Ichikawa, run!
Leave as fast as you can!
Call the Defense Force once you are safe!
But senior, you are alone…
Even the two of us can't handle it.
Don't you want
to be a Defense Force Officer?
How can you die here?
Look, I am here!
Over there.
It worked.
This will do.
Damn it!
All of these were destroyed.
Your home, my home, and the school.
Hmm…
I won't forgive the Kaiju!
I was so close to finishing my Pokemon game!
Is this what makes you sad?
I…
I'm sad because Miiko died.
That tri-colored cat?
I want to become a Defense Force Officer.
What nonsense are you
spouting, you little kid?
(To Miiko)
You're a primary school student.
So…
Let's compete to see who can
become the coolest officer.
Let's eliminate all the Kaiju together.
Damn it.
It shouldn't be like this.
So what about the Kaiju?
I must attack its legs.
Hit its legs.
Why has it come to this?
Let's compete to see who can
become the coolest officer.
Ichikawa?
Idiot, why did you…
I've already notified the Defense Force.
That's not what I mean.
If I were to abandon you,
I would never become an officer.
(We regret to inform you of the selection result.
Not Qualified)
Damn.
(Japan Defense Force is Recruiting)
Damn it.
How can I be so useless?
Nothing has changed at all.
Whether it's my game console
or a friend's cat.
I even failed to protect a junior.
Damn it!
Target has been eliminated.
There are casualties at the scene.
Our team will switch
to a rescue operation.
(Japan Defense Force, Third Division)
Igarashi, Takaraki,
take care of the injured.
Everyone else, follow me.
Search the area for any remaining Yoju.
(Captain Mina Ashiro)
Are you okay?
Stay still.
Mina is really amazing.
She killed something so scary in an instant.
She has gone to a place I can't reach.
Senior.
Oh.
When the Kaiju appeared,
if you hadn't told me to run
and you hadn't saved me,
I would have been dead by now.
You're so cool.
Let's compete to see who can
become the coolest officer.
You really should be
a Defense Force Officer.
But, that's your own choice.
It has nothing to do with me.
Yeah.
How long do I intend to turn a blind eye?
Thank you, Ichikawa.
You really are a good person.
Although I don't think
giving up is a bad thing,
it's not good to deceive myself.
I will once again aim to be
a Defense Force Officer.
Eh?
Found him.
Kaiju…
Senior?
Are you hurting?
Senior!
Ugh.
Eh?
Ichikawa, it's me!
Calm down.
(Bang Bang Bang)
Ah.
Notify the Defense Force.
Run, senior!
Eh?
(Episode 1: The Man Who Became a Kaiju)
If you encounter a Kaiju,
first, you should attack its legs,
then tie it up
to immobilize it.
It's a bit scary.
What?
To think about fighting a Kaiju
several times bigger than myself.
Don't worry.
When the time comes,
I will be by your side.
Liar.
Yes.
Kaiju was spotted
at Yokohama Minami General Hospital.
Yes.
No, no problem.
I'll dispatch the officers immediately
and exterminate it.