What?
A pair of sleeping skulls?!
Hah! I win.
Don't hold it against me.
Hey, Ryuk, wanna join us?
Come hang out with us
for a change.
No, I'll pass.
Listen for the voice of God
and never guess you will...
I didn't do a thing, but he still got upset...
Really? And then?
Yagami, what's the matter?
Please translate the following sentences.
Follow the voice of God.
Then the blessings of the sea will become bountiful
and there will be no storms.
Today, at approximately 11 a.m.
in Kanagawa Prefecture in Yokohama,
the body of a man appearing to be about 30 years old
was found in an apartment, covered in blood.
Kanagawa Police have opened a homicide investigation.
In other news...
Today, shortly after noon,
in the Shibuya district of Tokyo,
a 25-year-old woman was gagged and killed by her live-in partner.
35-year-old Tofuji Naoki is being
held in custody charged with her murder.
Day in and day out...
the same thing over and over again.
Jeez...
It's so ridiculous.
This world...
...is rotten.
Another is the extinction of many species of life on the planet.
No way! You went to see that?
Species are becoming extinct
at a faster rate than has occurred...
It was a complete waste of time.
I should've asked for a refund!
Well, you did watch it.
Species are becoming extinct
at a faster rate than has occurred...
Death Note?
Literally translated as "a notebook of death."
How to use it...
The human whose name is written in this note...
shall die?
What a joke...
This is so sick.
It's no different than a chain letter.
"The human whose name is written in this note shall die?" C'mon.
Seriously... I must be going insane.
There will be no effect when the face of
the targetted person is not in the writer's mind.
Therefore,
people sharing the same name will not be affected.
If the cause of death is written within
40 seconds of writing the person's name,
it will happen as it is written.
If the cause of death is not specified,
the person will simply die of a heart attack.
After writing the cause of death,
in the next 6 minutes and 40 seconds,
details of the death should be written.
So you can let people die peacefully or make them suffer.
A prank this intricate isn't too bad, I guess.
Write their name and they die, huh?
This is so stupid!
Wait a minute.
If someone actually dies,
does that make me a murderer?
No way. It'd never happen.
The assailant who killed six people yesterday at a busy shopping district in Shinjuku
has now taken eight people hostage,
including children and teachers, in this daycare center.
The police have now identified the suspect as 42-year-old Otoharada Kurou, unemployed.
The police will begin negotiations with the suspect.
Otoharada Kurou
A heart attack in 40 seconds,
right?
Well, that is not clear at the moment.
You can't help but be worried for the hostages right now.
Absolutely.
This has been a report from the scene.
Thank you very much.
What do you think, Mr. Hashimoto?
Well, I'm hoping for a quick resolution to this.
Oh well, nothing happened.
What did I expect?
Just a minute.
There seems to be something happening.
The hostages are coming out!
They all seem to be fine!
And now it looks like the SWAT team is entering!
Has the suspect been arrested?!
Yes!
We just received word that the suspect has died inside the daycare center!
The suspect is dead!
Dead?!
The police are strongly denying that they shot the suspect!
Then could he have felt cornered and committed suicide?
According to one of the hostages,
"The suspect just suddenly collapsed."
A heart attack...
N-No way...
This is a coincidence.
It's gotta be a coincidence!
Light!
It's almost 6:30.
Don't you have cram school tonight?
Yeah, I'm getting ready now.
The Death Note...
It's a long shot, but if this is the real thing,
it's worth testing once more.
In which case, the victim should probably be a criminal.
But it can't be someone too infamous.
If they die, it's possible that
their deaths will be covered up.
I need an immediate result.
Hey, Ryo baby!
Wh-What is it, Sudou?
Lend me 'bout 2,000 yen, will ya?
Wh-What? Again?
Sudou...
What? You refusing?
Shall I kill him?
No, I'd better avoid people I know.
No...
Why should I worry?
If one or two people like him were to die,
not a single soul would care.
Now we can go to the arcade after school.
Maki, wanna party with some guys tomorrow?
Absolutely!
Hey, me too!
Dammit, that stupid old hag!
She's not here to pick me up!
It's sickening.
Every single one of them...
I'd do society a favor
by killing them.
Hey girl!
Fancy having some fun with us?
Hey, Taku! You've got a beauty there!
I'm Shibuimaru Takuo. Shibutaku, for short.
Hang out with us for a while, baby.
I-I don't think so.
She doesn't think so!
How cute!
C'mon, grab her.
Get those clothes off!
Can we?!
Stop!
Please!
All the different variations of writing the name "Shibuimaru Takuo."
Now let's see...
what'll happen!
Hey, wait!
Taku! Watch out!
This... This settles it!
The Death Note is real!
Taku!
I-Idiot!
He just jumped out in front of me.
I guess...
I'd better get going.
It's been five days since then.
I guess...
I'd better get going.
Huh? Going out, Ryuk?
This place is barren everywhere you go.
I dropped my Death Note.
You really messed up big time!
Hey, weren't you carrying around
a second one behind the old man's back?
Don't tell me you lost both of 'em?
Do ya even know where ya dropped it?
The Human World.
What?!
Welcome home.
You're home early, Light.
Yeah.
I'm back, Mom.
Huh?
Oh, you want the results of
the national mock entrance exams?
Hurry!
Here you go.
Goodness! Number one again!
You really did your best, Light!
Well, yeah.
I'll be studying, so don't bother me.
All right.
Oh, Light...
Do you want anything?
Anything at all?
Not really, Mom.
I already have what I want.
You seem to like it.
Why are you shocked?
The one who dropped that notebook was me, Ryuk, a Shinigami.
From what I just saw,
you're already aware that that's no ordinary notebook.
A Shinigami, huh?
I'm not shocked, Ryuk.
In fact,
I've been waiting for you, Ryuk.
Oh?
I didn't think the Shinigami's Notebook was real,
but after seeing its results,
I can act with certainty.
I see.
You really surprise me.
I've heard of Death Notes getting down
to the Human World a few times before.
But you're the first one to use it to this extent in just five days.
Most people would be too scared to try it out.
I'm prepared, Ryuk.
I used a Death Note knowing it belonged to a Shinigami.
And now the Shinigami's here.
So what'll happen to me?
Are you going to take my soul?
Huh? What's that about?
Some fantasy you humans came up with?
I'm not going to do anything to you.
Once the Death Note lands in the Human World,
it belongs to the Human World.
In other words,
it belongs to you.
It belongs to me?
If you don't want it, give it to some other human.
But if you do that, all memory of
the Death Note will be erased from your mind.
So using the Death Note
doesn't come with a catch?
Well, if anything, there is...
only the fear and pain humans who
have used the Death Note will experience.
And when you die,
it falls to me to write your name in my Death Note.
Don't think for a moment, that any human
who's used the Death Note can go to Heaven, or Hell.
That's all.
You'll find out about it after you die.
Light...
Don't worry.
Answer her.
What?
I brought some apples.
They're from our neighbors.
Why is it so dark in there?
You'll ruin your eyesight!
What's going on?
Geez.
Mom can't see him?
That notebook originally
belonged to me.
And since you're the one using it,
only you can see me.
Of course, my voice...
Only you can hear it.
In other words, the Death Note
is a bond between Light the human and Ryuk the Shinigami.
Tasty.
Let me ask you one more thing.
Why did you choose me?
Hey, are you listening?
Apples in the Human World are awesome.
What would you call them?
Juicy?
Answer my question.
I didn't choose you.
I just dropped the notebook.
Did you think you were chosen because you were smart?
Don't flatter yourself.
It just happened to fall around here and you just happened to pick it up.
That's all.
That's why I wrote the explanation in English,
the most popular language in the Human World.
Then why did you drop it?!
Don't tell me it was by mistake after you went to the trouble and wrote all those instructions.
Why'd I drop it?
Because I was bored.
Bored?
The truth is that Shinigami these days have a lot of time on their hands.
They're either taking a nap or gambling.
If others see you studiously scribbling names in the Death Note,
they'll say, "What are you working so hard for?" and laugh at you.
Writing names of other Shinigami doesn't work.
But since we live in the Shinigami Realm,
it's no fun at all to kill people who live in the Human World!
So I figured it'd be more fun to come down here myself.
But you sure wrote a lotta names.
But why'd you write down the cause of death only for that guy who was hit by the truck?
Without the cause of death written down,
they all die of heart attacks.
That's the best thing about the Death Note, Ryuk.
I can write down the names of the criminals
and slowly reduce the number of evil people.
What's the point?
Any fool can figure it out if someone is just "eliminating the bad guys."
I want the world to know of my existence!
That there is someone passing judgment on them!
But what's the point in passing judgment?
Why do it?
I, too,
was bored.
Naturally, I didn't believe it at first.
But that Death Note
has the supernatural power to tempt people
to want to try it at least once.
I... I killed them.
Two men...
I killed them!
Human lives...
shouldn't be taken so lightly!
Do I have the right
to judge people like that?
No...
I'm not wrong!
I've always thought about this.
The world is rotten!
Rotten people deserve to die!
Someone...
Someone has to do it!
Even if it means sacrificing
one's conscience and life!
Things can't stay like this!
If the Death Note had fallen into someone else's hands,
would they have had the resolve
to erase unwanted people from this world?
No way!
But I...
I can do it!
In fact,
only I can do it!
And I will! With the Death Note!
I'll change the world!
At first I kept writing the names of criminals
as if I were cleaning up the world.
So that in time, no one would do evil.
While those guilty ones who truly deserved to be punished for their crimes die of heart attacks,
people who were immoral or harass others,
would slowly be erased through illness or accidents.
Then the world would truly move in the right direction.
And I would create a new world of earnest, kind humans.
Then you'd be the only
fucked-up person left.
Huh? What are you saying?
Ryuk,
I'm probably the best, most diligent honor student in Japan.
And I will become...
the god of the new world!
I knew it! Humans...
sure are interesting.
The entire world is watching
to see what happens to those who defy me,
L.