The human whose name is written in this note...
shall die?
Please!
Stop!
Now let's see...
what'll happen!
The Death Note is real!
Don't think for a moment, that any human
who's used the Death Note can go to Heaven, or Hell.
I want the world to know of my existence!
That there is someone passing judgment on them!
And I will become...
the god of the new world!
He was overflooded with satisfaction...
I had no idea what he was thinking, so I'm through with him.
Really? Then how was it with that other old guy?
Uhm, Yagami.
Please translate that sentence into Japanese.
Okay.
"When finally, he fully succeeded in making his dream a reality,
he was immersed in beatitude."
Very good.
As expected from you, Yagami.
A perfect answer.
Well then, class is dismissed.
It's finally over.
School sure is boring.
Hey, Light!
Light, are you listening to me?
Don't talk to me.
Others can hear my voice when I talk, unlike yours.
You're no fun.
Hey, Light! We're going to go—
Sorry, I have something to do.
You don't have anything to do.
Aren't you just going home like you usually do?
What are you talking about? I have something to do.
Something very important.
Yamada is suspected of stabbing a fellow employee in the
abdomen at a restaurant in Kabukicho, Shinjuku, yesterday.
The knife was from the restaurant
and was roughly twelve inches long.
The suspect said,
"He was being rude, so I just lost it."
Hey!
Hey, Light!
What is it?
You sure are working very hard.
I can't waste any time.
I only have a limited amount of time to write names in the notebook.
The only time I have is when I get home from school and until I go to bed.
I also need to maintain my grades.
I can't sleep during class.
I need to do all of my homework for school and my prep classes.
Lack of sleep is dangerous.
It'll affect my health and concentration.
After all, I'm trying to change
this world into a utopia without evil.
There's never enough time.
Huh? Why did you lock the door, Light?
It's Sayu. What is it?
Help me with my homework.
Okay, sure.
It's on quadratic equations.
I'm sorry if you were studying.
But it just doesn't make any sense.
Please help me.
All right.
Light, be careful.
Any human who touches
the notebook in your drawer
will be able to see me.
He waits until now to tell me that crucial detail?
Damn Shinigami!
What's wrong, Light?
Hm? It's nothing.
Well, what exactly don't you understand?
Well, um...
I think everything.
From what we know, there have been fifty-two deaths just this past week.
They all had heart attacks.
They're all criminals who were wanted or being held in prison.
There are probably other criminals
whose deaths are still unaccounted for.
Does that mean the death toll
could easily be over a hundred?
Chief, we've already started.
I know. I had a call from headquarters.
At any rate, they were all criminals
who probably would have been executed.
Perhaps we shouldn't concern ourselves.
How stupid!
It doesn't matter if they're criminals
or on death row. Killing them is murder.
We aren't even sure that they were murdered.
There's no way over a hundred people
could have heart attacks at the same time!
It has to be murder.
Is it even possible to kill
that many people at the same time?
We believe that a large organization carefully orchestrated these killings.
If you say a large organization is involved,
I can't help but think that the FBI or CIA is involved.
I dare you to say that again!
Now, now.
Let's stop joking around.
We have to first clarify if these are murders,
or strange coincidences.
But don't all the autopsy reports say that
the deaths were caused by inexplicable heart attacks?
I don't see what else can be learned from just the way they died.
That's right!
It would be worth looking into
if they were stabbed with knives!
If that's the case, we'll just have to have L solve this!
Chief, what is L?
This is your first time at this conference, isn't it?
No one knows L's name,
location, or what he looks like.
But he's managed to solve every case he's taken,
no matter how difficult it's been.
He's cracked many of
the world's unsolved cases.
He's our trump card,
our ace in the hole. Our last hope.
Something like that.
But isn't L an arrogant individual who'll only take on cases he's interested in?
That's right.
We can't even contact him.
L is already involved.
L is already investigating this case.
Huh? Watari?
Who's Watari?
He's the only man who can contact L.
Furthermore, Watari's identity is also unknown.
Please be silent.
L will now speak.
Members of the ICPO...
I am L.
What are we doing,
sneaking around in such a desolate place, Light?
People who touch the Death Note can see you, can't they?
I can't just walk around with something this dangerous.
Up until now, I thought that if my family saw the notebook...
I could pass it off as a record of cases
which I'm using to study to become a detective.
But I'm walking a fine line right now.
If I'm not careful, I might end up killing...
my own family.
This case is unprecedented in scope and difficulty because
it involves more people than any other case has before.
It is also an unforgivable crime of serial murder.
In order to solve this case,
I need the ICPO—
no, various worldwide organizations, to cooperate fully.
I want you to decide whether
you'll support me at this conference.
Also,
I strongly desire to work with the Japanese Police.
Huh?
Wh-Why Japan?
Regardless of how many suspects there are,
there's a strong possibility they're Japanese.
Even if they aren't Japanese, they are hiding in Japan.
What grounds do you have for your claims?
Why Japan?
I think I can show you very soon by directly confronting the culprit.
A direct confrontation?
At any rate, I would like to set up headquarters in Japan.
That was pretty easy to make.
Hmm?
Does that mean you were able to hide the notebook?
Yeah, in this drawer.
Does that count as a hiding place?
You left the key in the lock.
That's fine.
It's better that I intentionally left the key in a noticeable place.
It's just a regular diary.
Most people will probably be satisfied
with the secrets of this drawer
after reading this diary.
But...
the real key...
is this.
There's nothing suspicious about
having one of these on my desk.
It's just a regular ballpoint pen.
I'll use the ink cartridge.
That's the key?
Yeah.
On the back of the drawer,
there's a small hole that's hard
to notice if you don't look closely.
You put this in the hole.
I see. It's got a false bottom.
Well, you also have the fake diary,
so I doubt anyone will find it.
That's not all.
Even if they discovered it has a false bottom,
there would be no way that they could take the notebook.
You see...
This ink cartridge is an insulator,
so it doesn't channel electricity,
stopping its flow in the circuit.
When the bottom of this drawer is closed,
this piece of rubber also stops the flow of electricity.
However, if someone were to force open the bottom,
gasoline in thin plastic bags will ignite at that moment...
and the notebook will instantly be set aflame.
All evidence will be completely destroyed.
That's how it's set up.
I can just say the reason I burned it was that "I didn't want anyone to see my real diary."
It's a believable excuse.
It is a notebook, after all.
I've heard that when a human gets a Death Note,
the biggest problem they have is finding a good place to hide it.
But, Light, you're probably the first to go this far.
That setup is really dangerous, though.
If you make even the slightest mistake,
you could be badly burned.
Dangerous?
You're talking nonsense again, Ryuk.
I've been putting myself in danger from the very beginning.
Ever since I first got ahold of the Death Note.
Compared to that, this is hardly dangerous.
In fact, quite the opposite. It protects me.
A small fire in the house, or being executed?
Which is worse?
Last night, within the Tokyo West Penitentiary,
Kurotsukayama Naoki, aged thirty-two, who was detained for armed robbery,
is reported to have died of a heart attack.
In response to the endless, bizarre deaths of prisoners...
That's amazing.
Bad guys just keep dropping dead.
It's a little scary, but it does feel great.
But now we really can't do anything bad.
I wonder if the police are behind it.
The police don't have that kind of power.
Don't you know about him?
Huh? About who?
You know, Kira. Kira!
I wonder who's going to be killed next.
Ryuk, take a look at this.
Hmm?
Someone's already created a website.
"The legend of Kira the Savior."
That's pretty cool. Is this about you?
Yeah.
"Kira" seems to come from the English word "killer."
I don't like that,
but I've become "Kira" to the world.
Just searching the word "Kira"
brings up countless sites like this one.
Television and newspapers have only publicized
"the successive, mysterious deaths of vicious criminals."
But the people of the world can already feel it.
The existence of someone passing judgment.
Oh?
Humans are like that, Ryuk.
For example,
there's no way that anyone in homeroom at school would bring up the topic of killing bad people.
But if someone were to do so, everyone would act pious.
That's wrong.
That's what they're bound to say.
Of course, it's the right thing to say.
Humans must put up a front like that in public.
But their true feelings are there.
They may be afraid, or not acknowledge my existence on the surface,
but on the Internet, where one can remain anonymous,
Kira is already thriving.
They don't talk about it,
but they all understand.
Someone is making the bad guys disappear.
Those who have a clean conscience
are cheering for Kira in their hearts.
And those who have done wrong
fear that heaven's judgment will strike upon them.
It's perfect.
Everything is going exactly as planned.
We interrupt this program to bring you
a special, worldwide broadcast from the ICPO, Interpol.
Hmm? What's this?
Interpol?
We'll start now.
I am the sole person able to mobilize the world's police.
I am Lind L. Tailor.
Also known as L.
Wh-Who is this?
It's finally started.
He's never shown his face, right?
So why now?
It means that L is serious.
All right, L. We're doing exactly what you told us to do.
Now, let's see you prove
what you said at the ICPO conference.
There has been a string of
serial killings targeting criminals.
This is the most atrocious act of murder in history,
and it will not go unpunished.
I will definitely catch the one behind the murders,
commonly known as "Kira."
He said he'll definitely catch you.
The fool. There's no way he can catch me.
This is the Death Note!
If you don't have this,
there's no evidence.
It's impossible to catch me.
I knew that the police would start investigating and that someone like you would turn up.
Kira, I have a pretty good idea behind your motive.
But what you're doing
is evil!
I'm evil?
I am justice!
I'm saving the meek, who fear evil.
I'm the man who will become the god of the ideal, new world!
All who oppose that god...
It is they who are evil!
You're too stupid, L.
This could've been more interesting if you'd been a bit smarter.
The entire world is watching
to see what happens to those who defy me, L.
Just five more seconds.
Four...
Three...
Two...
One...
What's wrong?
Why don't you say something?
Unbelievable.
I had to check to be sure.
You're capable of this?
Kira,
it seems you can kill people without direct contact.
I couldn't believe it before seeing it with my own eyes.
Listen to me, Kira.
If you just killed the man on-screen, Lind L. Tailor,
you just killed a man who was scheduled to be executed today.
It wasn't me.
What?!
This criminal was someone
whom the police caught secretly.
His capture wasn't broadcast on television or the Internet.
It seems that even you couldn't get information on him.
He got you.
But I, L, do exist!
Bring it on! Try and kill me!
Th-That bastard!
What's going on?! This is unreal!
What's wrong? Do it quickly!
C'mon! Kill me!
Are you trying to die, L?!
What's going on?
It's Kira versus L!
It's a live murder!
Come on, Kira!
This is scary!
Try and kill me!
What's the matter? Can't you do it?!
It seems that you can't kill me.
So, there are some people whom you can't kill.
You've given me a good clue.
I'll tell you something good in return.
I told you that this is a live broadcast worldwide,
but this is only being broadcast in the Kanto region of Japan.
I was planning on broadcasting this in different areas
at different times, but it seems that I no longer need to.
Now I know that you are based in the Kanto region.
This L guy is pretty good.
The first victim was the killer in Shinjuku.
The police overlooked that case because it was so minor.
Of all the criminals who died of heart attacks,
this one's crime was the least serious.
Furthermore, his crime was only broadcast in Japan.
I have been able to deduce this much.
You are in Japan,
and your first victim pwas your guinea pig.
You're just lucky that you're in Kanto,
the most heavily populated region in Japan.
I never thought that things would go quite so well, but...
Kira,
it won't be too long before I can sentence you to death.
L certainly lives up to his reputation.
Yes, he's proved that Kira exists, that the killings took place, and that Kira's in Japan.
Kira, I'm interested in how you commit the murders.
But I'll find that out when I catch you.
Until we meet again,
Kira.
He's going to...
sentence me to death?
Interesting.
I'll accept your challenge.
They have to hunt each other down,
but neither of them know the other's name or face.
And the first one who gets found is dead!
Humans sure are interesting!
L...
Kira...
I will definitely find and finish you!
I am...
justice!
I'm not the one who's going to find L.
The police will track him down.
And I will eliminate him.
Looks like I may be able to provide you a little more entertainment, Ryuk.