Members of the ICPO...
I am L.
Regardless of how many suspects there are,
there's a strong possibility they're Japanese.
Kira, I have a pretty good idea behind your motive.
But what you're doing
is evil!
Th-That bastard!
Bring it on! Try and kill me!
What's wrong? Do it quickly!
I am justice!
I'm saving the meek, who fear evil!
C'mon! Kill me!
I'm the man who will become the god of the ideal, new world!
L...
Kira...
I will definitely find you and finish you!
I am...
justice!
All right then, let's start with the tip-line reports.
Yes, sir.
Until now, there have been 3,029 responses about the murders from telephone calls, etc.
Most of them are from curious members of the public.
But there are fourteen people who say that they either "know the killer" or "have seen the killer."
Each account was followed up and recorded carefully.
But no one had information that hasn't already been released to the public.
There are also twenty-one people who claim they are Kira.
We didn't want to rule out any possibilities,
so all twenty-one people were put on record and filed.
Okay.
Next up: victims.
Sir!
Upon further investigation,
we have confirmed that information of the heart attack victims was, in fact,
publicly available in Japan prior to their deaths.
Also,
concerning L's request that we investigate the times of death for each victim...
We found they occurred between 4 p.m. and 2 a.m. on weekdays Japan's time.
Sixty-eight percent of them occurred between 8 p.m. and 12 midnight.
Furthermore, we have a great variation of times
on Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays.
That is extremely interesting.
Judging from those times of death,
the culprit may be a student.
I have other grounds for this belief.
Drawing from the fact that the perpetrator is only killing criminals,
he's probably driven by his own idealistic sense of justice.
He may even be trying to become a god.
You could say that he has a very childish mentality.
I can't believe that...
This is just a mere possibility.
But please get rid of the assumption that the culprit couldn't be a student.
Considering various possibilities
is the shortest route to arresting Kira.
Please continue your investigative report.
Y-Yes...
Has anyone else noticed anything?
Um, yes...
What is it, Matsuda?
Um... I'm in no way saying this to give credit to Kira's actions...
But for the past few days, worldwide... and especially in Japan,
the number of violent crimes more serious than robbery has dropped drastically.
Well,
I suppose that's to be expected.
Anything else?
That about sums up our investigative report for today, L.
Thank you, everyone. I feel as if we're closing in on the culprit.
Still, I'd like to make another request.
I want the teams investigating the victims, the news, and the Internet
to examine once more how the victims' identities were made public in Japan.
I want to know if pictures of the victims' faces were shown.
I leave it to you.
Chief...
You seem exhausted.
Thanks.
I've been pulling all-nighters lately.
What I said about crimes dropping drastically...
Now that I think about it, everyone knows already.
I'm sorry.
What are you talking about?
Keep speaking the truth.
Especially when it's about things people hesitate to bring up.
However, if you had gone on to say that
we should commend Kira for admirably reducing crime rates,
now that might have been a problem.
I-Impossible! Support that killer?
I'm just kidding.
Just as I expected, Light!
Hey! Did you understand any of that by yourself?
Huh? Yeah, kind of.
Oh, it seems like Dad's home.
Welcome home, Dear.
He's home early!
Hey! At least figure out the last problem by yourself.
I will, after dinner!
Really...
Helping your little sister do her homework...
You sure are confident.
Yeah. There's one thing that gives me confidence to fight the police if they move against me.
Welcome home, Dad.
Good to be home.
Light, how are your studies?
Hmm? They're okay.
He's at the top of his grade as usual.
Yes, my wonderful big brother!
Yes, my wonderful son!
Dad, you seem a bit tired.
Yeah...
I can't tell you any details,
but this current case is very difficult.
I see.
Your father is one of the police.
That must be the reason you're so confident.
Yeah.
I can hack into my father's computer from my own without leaving a trace.
I can always keep track of the investigative situation.
Here it is.
The police are beginning to suspect that the culprit is a student.
Doesn't that mean you're in trouble, Light?
If the cause of death is written within 40 seconds of writing the person's name, it will happen.
If the cause of death is not specified, the person will simply die of a heart attack.
After writing the cause of death, details of the death should be written
in the next 6 minutes and 40 seconds.
Is that right, Ryuk?
Yeah, so?
In other words, if I write "heart attack" as the cause of death,
I can write down the circumstance and time of death.
Looks like I may be able to provide you a little more entertainment, Ryuk.
Number 148, what's wrong?!
Get ahold of yourself!
What?!
Th-There were another twenty-three heart attack victims yesterday?!
Y-Yes.
The day before, there were another twenty-three victims.
One at every hour...
The fact that this has continued for two weekdays straight...
...means our sketch of the culprit has become doubtful.
No, anyone could skip school for two days.
That's not it!
It does appear less likely now that the culprit's a student.
But that's not the message Kira's trying to send!
Why one every hour?
And why are all the victims in prisons, where they can easily be found?
Kira is trying to say that
he can freely control
the time of death.
But something's not right.
As soon as we began to suspect that Kira was a student,
the timing of the killings changed as if to contradict our theory.
Is it a coincidence?
No, the timing is too convenient.
Does that mean that Kira knows what the police know?
This is obviously
a direct challenge from him!
L is probably quaking in his boots by now.
I still have fifty criminals left especially for times like this.
Oh...
Now, L should be starting to suspect someone involved with the police.
Kira has found a way to obtain information from task force headquarters.
I cannot ignore this fact.
What is Kira's real objective?
What is he trying to do?
But I don't get it.
By getting rid of the student theory, aren't you at a bigger disadvantage if L thinks you're connected to the police?
My reason is...
It's in order to find L and finish him off.
What do you mean?
In human society,
there are only a few people who actually trust each other.
That's true even among police.
In particular, L and the police don't trust each other at all.
Could you trust someone whose name and face you don't know?
When L discovers that the findings from the investigation were leaked,
he's bound to search for leads on me within the police force.
When he does,
it's only a matter of time before the police get as mad as a hornet.
On the surface,
L and the police are working together to try to catch me.
But in reality,
L is investigating the police and the police will start investigating L.
I'm not the one who's going to find L.
The police will track him down.
And I will eliminate him.
What is this?!
As you see, these are our letters of resignation.
Transfer us to a different case.
If you can't, we will quit the police force.
B-But why?
Why?
Because we value our lives, sir.
By L's deduction,
Kira can kill people indirectly through supernatural powers, right?
If I were Kira,
I would try to kill anyone who tried to catch me.
That's because he'll be executed if he gets caught.
Earlier, in that media stunt, L challenged Kira.
"Try and kill me," he said.
But L never showed his face or revealed his name.
Just recently, L ordered us to find out
if the victims' faces and names were broadcast in Japan.
That's right!
All the victims were those whose faces were broadcast to the Japanese public!
We, unlike someone we know,
carry around our personal identification as well as our photos in our police IDs.
We don't hide our faces. We're out in the open!
We...
could be killed at any time by Kira.
This is why we wish to be removed from our post.
Excuse us.
H-Hey!
You guys!
Wait a second!
Here's the solution to this problem.
Take x squared equals
large x.
You can think of large x's quadratic equation
as the multiple of two integers.
We had the FBI come to Japan four days ago.
They are currently investigating the police involved.
This is the list, isn't it?
Yes.
There are 141 people within the police force alone
who have access to classified information on the Kira investigation.
But one of the 141 people
or someone close to them...
Kira is definitely among them!
Light, you gotta second?
Didn't I tell you not to talk to me as much as possible when we're outside?
How many times do I have to tell you?
Well then, I'll just talk.
Cover your ears if you don't want to hear.
I don't have anything against you, Light.
I don't think the notebook could've been picked up by a better person.
And I have to stick around with you until you or the notebook is finished.
But I'm not on your side or L's side.
I knew that much already, Ryuk.
That's why I'll never say anything about
whether what you're doing is right or wrong.
But I'm going to say this as your roommate.
What's wrong, Ryuk?
Why are you telling me this all of a sudden?
This isn't like you.
I'm going to tell you this,
not because I'm an ally of Kira,
but because it's giving me the heebie jeebies.
Get to the point already.
Someone's been following you all this time.
He's been getting on my nerves.
He can't see me,
but because I'm always hovering behind you,
I feel like I'm being watched.
That's a problem.
I'll be sure to finish him off, Ryuk.
Who in the world could he be?
Does that mean that L has begun to suspect the police?
He must need quite a large number of people to investigate them.
Even if he had fifty people investigating,
there is no chance that I'd be suspected of being Kira.
I should only look like a regular high-school student.
But if I leave it alone for several months,
that possibility won't remain at zero.
I must learn my tracker's name.
When I find that out, I can get rid of him.
Light...
I'll let you in on something good.
There are two big differences between
Shinigami and humans who have a Death Note.
Do you know why Shinigami have to write people's names in the Death Note?
Why would I know that?
You're really talkative today, Ryuk.
It's because Shinigami receive the human's remaining life span from them.
You get their remaining life span?
Let's say that there's a person who will live till sixty in the Human World.
You write that he'll die at forty in the Death Note.
Sixty minus forty equals twenty.
Those twenty years in the Human World
are added to a Shinigami's life span.
As long as we don't slack off,
even if we're shot in the head
or stabbed in the heart with a knife, Shinigami will not die.
But no matter how many names you write in the Death Note,
your life span will not lengthen.
That's one difference between Shinigami and humans who have a Death Note.
Hmm...
To humans, that's very kind of the Shinigami.
That's kinda interesting.
Our second difference is probably of more interest to you.
Instead of lengthening life, it's about cutting it short.
Cutting it short?
When a Shinigami sees a person's face,
they know their name.
Do you know why?
With Shinigami's eyes,
a human's name and life span can be seen above their head.
Name and life span?
Of course, in my eyes, I can see your name and life span right now.
If I convert it to human time, I'll know how many years it is.
Of course, I wouldn't tell you even if you stretched my mouth open.
Even if my mouth is stretched out as it is.
Shinigami never have problems knowing the names of the people they kill.
They also know how much life they're going to receive.
Our eyes are different.
That's the crucial difference between you and me.
Shinigami can also turn the eyes of whoever picked up their Death Note
into Shinigami eyes.
But only if a deal is made.
One that's been with us since ancient times.
A deal?
The price for a pair of Shinigami's eyes
is half of that person's remaining life span.
Half of my remaining life span...
Yeah.
For example, if you were to live another fifty years, you'll have twenty-five years.
If it was one year more, you'll have half a year.
And since you're neither Kira's nor L's ally,
you won't tell me the name of someone I want to kill, even if you see their name.
In other words,
I can't get your help.
Is that what you're trying to say?
Yeah. It's also part of the Shinigami code.
I'll say this once more.
Give me half your remaining life and I'll give you the Shinigami eyes.
If I do that,
I'll know everyone's name.
It means that it'll be easier to use the Death Note.
So...
What'll it be, Light?
Exactly 11:45.
Everything went as planned.
The Death Note never fails.