What?!
Th-There were another twenty-three heart attack victims yesterday?!
As soon as we began to suspect that Kira was a student,
the timing of the killings changed as if to contradict our theory.
Does that mean that Kira knows what the police know?
When L discovers that the findings from the investigation were leaked,
he's bound to search for leads on me within the police force.
Someone's been following you all this time.
That's a problem.
I'll be sure to finish him off, Ryuk.
With Shinigami's eyes,
a human's name and life span can be seen above their head.
Also,
Shinigami can turn the eyes of whoever picked up their Death Note
into Shinigami eyes.
The price for a pair of Shinigami eyes
is half of that person's remaining life span.
So... What'll it be, Light?
I haven't seen Ryuk around lately.
Did he really lose his Death Note in the Human World?
His Death Note was probably picked up by a human before he got to it.
Couldn't be... If that happened to him, he'd have to stick around
until that person dies or his Death Note is destroyed.
Yeah.
I can't picture Ryuk doing something so tedious.
I heard that he was carrying two Death Notes.
Seriously? Why would he need two?
I don't understand what he's thinking.
In order for me to gain the eyes of a Shinigami,
I have to offer half of my life.
Is that right?
Yeah.
What are you gonna do?
Do you wanna make a deal with me?
Ryuk.
This deal...
is out of the question.
Now listen.
I want to create an ideal, new world free from criminals.
I also intend to reign as the god in that world for a long time.
I would consider the deal if it lengthened my life,
but it's not worth talking about if it's going to shorten it.
You, most of all, should know that.
Yeah, I just felt I should tell you a deal like this exists.
I don't want you to complain that I didn't tell you about this earlier.
If you didn't tell me about this earlier?
Don't you think you're too late already?
You should have told me this when we first met
or included this when you were writing instructions in the Death Note.
I-I guess you're right.
Even though I'm a Shinigami, he's not frightened nor does he try to suck up to me.
He has no problem giving me a hard time about things like this.
Well?
Hmm?
You sure there isn't anything else you want to tell me ahead of time?
Shinigami Ryuk...
Nope, nothing else.
Probably...
Is that so? How disappointing.
Disappointing?
I may have seriously considered the deal
if you offered me wings rather than eyes.
Soaring around freely in the sky is very god-like.
It's a dream that man has had since ancient times.
You'd stand out if you sprouted wings and started flying around.
I'd bet you'd get arrested by the police just for that.
That was a joke, Ryuk.
However, if I continue to deal for eyes and wings,
I'm going to end up becoming a real Shinigami.
That could be amusing, don't you think?
Don't worry.
Even without all that, you're already...
a worthy Shinigami!
The Shinigami Realm is rotting these days.
They all live vacant lives
and only take human lives because they don't want to die.
No one even knows
why we exist.
I doubt there's any reason at all for our existence.
You're much more of a Shinigami than they are.
Well, from what you're saying,
it sounds like I'm doing a lot more work.
But I don't want to be lumped together with the Shinigami.
I am using this Death Note as a human for humans.
But I wouldn't say that the Shinigami Realm is meaningless to humans either.
What do you mean?
Well, think about it.
Whenever a Shinigami like you comes to the Human World once every hundred—no, every thousand years,
the Human World changes greatly.
The Shinigami Realm's existence is fearfully meaningful.
I-Is that so?
You told me that the Shinigami Realm is rotten.
When you return from this world,
how about using what you've learned here to try to change it?
Light,
you may be quite the optimist.
Of course I am.
If I weren't,
I wouldn't be trying to use the Death Note to try to make the world a better place.
That's it!
I've got it!
What's up? What did you get?
How to find out the name of the guy who was following me today.
How are you going to do it?
I'm going to use the rules of the Death Note to my advantage.
If I write a cause of death, I have an additional 6 minutes and 40 seconds
to record specific conditions and time of death.
I wonder how free I can be with these conditions.
I'm going to test it out.
Yes, it's me.
Another six inmates...
Heart attacks?!
It's Kira.
What?
Three exhibited bizarre behavior before they died?!
Wh-What do you mean?!
They didn't just die from simple heart attacks?
Well, they died of heart attacks, but before one of them died,
he drew a strange picture on the wall with blood from his finger.
Another left a letter that doesn't seem like a will or anything meaningful.
The third escaped just to go to the employees' bathroom.
What is it, Watari?
More victims, but their circumstances are unlike those we've had before.
Unlike those we've had before?
I shall send you an image of the picture and letter left at the scene.
If you could.
A note describing a fear of Kira.
This can be taken as something a criminal might do,
but Kira can control the time of death.
If he can control actions right before death as well,
that would mean...
Chief!
It's about these current victims.
Don't let the media know anything aside from the fact that they died of heart attacks.
It's possible that Kira was performing some kind of test.
If that's the case,
we'd only be giving him the answer.
I see.
I-I understand.
Performing tests on criminals?
That's horrible.
He's playing with people's lives as if this were a game.
This is unforgivable!
If Kira is using criminals as test subjects...
what is he trying to achieve?
Look at this, Ryuk.
The results of yesterday's test have already been input into Dad's computer.
The results are just as I expected.
The Death Note will work for what I have in mind.
What do you mean by that?
One escaped and went to the bathroom I had designated in the Death Note.
Another drew the same picture I had drawn in the Death Note.
Yet another wrote the same letter I had written in the Death Note.
These three did exactly what I wanted.
I purposely wrote very difficult tasks for the other three.
The first was to "die in front of the Eiffel Tower in an hour."
It's physically impossible to go from a prison in Japan to France in an hour.
So this never happened and ended as just a regular heart attack.
The next was to
"draw a picture of L's face on the prison wall",
but one can't draw the faces of people they don't know.
I see.
For the final one,
I specified that he would write a note that would read,
"I know L is suspicious of the Japanese police".
I thought this one might work, but it didn't happen.
Which means that people can't write about
things they don't know or things they couldn't come up with on their own.
In short, it means that even the Death Note can't do the impossible.
But as long as it's something the person is realistically likely to do,
I can control them as much as I want before they die.
You've figured that out,
but what are you trying to do, Light?
L and the police will never figure out my true goal.
The great detective is probably trying to decipher the picture and the letter those criminals left.
It's an absolutely meaningless dying message.
If Kira used those criminals for a test,
he's about to start something.
If he moves now, there is the chance that the FBI will notice someone acting suspiciously.
But if he has a different goal in mind,
the letter and picture might be some kind of message.
Is this it?
Well, it's time for the real thing.
The real thing?
Yesterday on the news,
there was a drug addict who failed robbing a bank.
He attacked civilians and ran away.
I'll use him.
It's last minute, but I'm sure I can find someone.
I'll ask out several people.
Ask out several people?
Yeah.
Ryuk, I may not look it, but I'm pretty popular.
Hello?
Huh, Light?
G-Good morning...
He's still following me, isn't he?
That's perfect.
If I don't have my stalker, there would be no point in what I'm going to do next.
Light!
A date?
Yeah.
It's a date, no matter how you look at it.
Even to my stalker.
It's no normal date, is it?
You said you had a way to find out your stalker's name,
but what do you plan to do?
Huh? Ryuk, didn't you see what I wrote in the Death Note?
Nah. It would be boring to peek.
Then just be patient and watch what happens.
Sorry, did I keep you waiting?
No, not at all!
Anyway, I haven't been to Space Land since junior high!
I'm so excited! And I get to be alone with you!
Yeah.
On weekdays, he only goes to school and his prep courses.
An occasional date on his days off.
He's pretty normal.
No, he's a serious high-school student.
Chief Yagami's son, Light.
I have no reason to suspect him.
At any rate,
I'll finish my surveillance of him today.
Light...
Didn't you say that you weren't going out until entrance exams were over?
Yeah, but I did score number one in the practice exams.
You're awful!
It's him! He's here!
Aside from him, there are seven passengers.
Everything will go smoothly.
Huh?
I'm taking control of this bus!
A bus jacking?! At a time like this?
Don't make a fuss!
I'll kill anyone who moves.
Driver, you know the phone number for Space Land's offices, don't you?
Call them!
All right.
This is Sasaki, the driver of bus number 174!
Tell them what's happening!
A man with a gun has bus jacked us!
Give me that.
You hear that? Listen carefully.
Bring Space Land's profits from yesterday to two bus stops away from there.
Have a woman bring it by car alone!
Do it before this bus gets there!
If you try anything funny
or call the police,
I'll kill all the passengers one by one!
Yuri, don't worry.
I'll look for a chance
to grab his hand that's holding the pistol.
That's dangerous. Don't do it.
If it comes to that, I'll do it.
It's all right. We don't have to pass notes.
As long as we whisper, he won't hear us over the sound of the bus.
Do you have proof that you're not his accomplice?
A-Accomplice?
It's pretty common.
The culprit pretends he's alone
and just in case, he'll leave someone to keep watch in the back.
What's wrong?
No... you really think so?
I-I have no choice.
There is no way that Light Yagami can be Kira.
Kira could kill the culprit with a heart attack.
This is my proof. Take a look.
FBI?!
I see. L's using the FBI to investigate those connected to Japan's police force!
His name is Raye Penber.
I trust you.
I won't ask why an FBI agent is on this bus with us.
Do you have a gun?
I do.
So if something happens, I can rely on you, right?
Yes.
Shut up!
Do you want to die?!
That man was on the Japanese news two days ago.
He's a drug addict who tried to rob a bank,
killed three civilians, and ran away.
He's very dangerous.
It's all right.
He'll never shoot at us.
Oh!
Hey, you! Don't move.
What's that piece of paper?
Hey you!
You were planning something back here with notes, weren't you?
Damn!
If he sees that note from earlier,
he'll discover that Light was planning to jump him when he had the chance!
Heh. Plans for a date?
How stupid.
All right!
Wh-Who the hell are you?!
You in the back!
Wh-What are you trying to pull?
How long were you hiding back there?!
Huh? You mean me?
You can see me right now?
D-Don't move!
I-I'll shoot! You monster!
This isn't good! He's hallucinating!
Everyone, get down!
Oh, I get it!
That note that Light just dropped
was cut out of the Death Note.
So he has this guy touch the note and now, only he can see me.
That's so smart.
D-Don't come near me!
Sorry, pal.
I'm a Shinigami, so that's not gonna kill me.
"Anyone who touches the Death Note will be able to see me."
"I'm always hovering behind you."
"Shinigami can't die from gunshots."
That's all stuff I've told Light.
Pretty impressive. It's not surprising he's the top exam scorer nationwide.
He even used this bus jacking to get the name of the guy who was following him, without much hassle.
Stop the bus and open the door.
Exactly 11:45.
Everything went as planned.
Osoreda Kiichiro. Accidental death.
At 11:31 a.m.,
he will get on a bus heading to Space Land from the bus stop near the eastern entrance of the park.
He will enter with a gun,
but will see a phantom from another world
and fire all his bullets at it.
Then, he will flee from the bus.
Immediately afterwards, at 11:45 the same day,
he will die in an accident.
The Death Note never fails.
You're next, Raye Penber.
He doesn't suspect me at all.
The remaining agents will all die of heart attacks.
Farewell, Raye Penber.