You there.
Yes?
I'm here in Japan on a secret investigation.
Keep this a secret from the Japanese police.
I understand.
I won't tell anyone that I met you.
Including my father...
Well, I'll be off now.
It's just as I thought.
I also don't want the police to know that I've come into contact with an FBI agent.
If my father ever found out, he'd tell L.
Raye doesn't suspect me at all.
The police will deal with what happened just now as a regular accident.
Welcome back.
I'm home.
What's the matter?
Why the big sigh?
Raye, what happened?
Oh...
By chance, I was involved in a bus jacking.
A bus jacking?
Yeah. A man who robbed a bank two days ago tried to hijack a bus.
Japan has become a scary place.
Does that mean you were also riding on that bus?
Yeah.
In the end, the suspect jumped out of the bus and was hit by a car.
Did he die?
Probably...
I didn't have any time to watch what happened.
Raye...
Hmm?
Do you really think that was an accident?
What do you mean?
Well, you were on that bus because you were investigating someone, weren't you?
The criminal probably died.
Doesn't that mean...
Hey...
You were indeed once an excellent FBI agent.
But now you're just my fiancée.
You're no longer an agent.
Don't say anything about the Kira case.
Don't get involved or take risks.
That's what we agreed on
when I brought you with me here so we could meet your parents.
I understand, Raye.
It's just a force of habit. Sorry.
No... I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it.
Once we start a family,
you'll be so busy that you'll forget that you were an agent.
You won't have time for that habit to pop up.
But first, help me think of something that will make your father like me more.
Oh...
Are you going to write down the name of the agent now?
No.
I'm going to write his name a week from today.
If he died soon after I met him, I might look suspicious.
It would be better to do it
once they've investigated more people involved with the police.
For now, I'll use some more prison inmates to play with L.
L.
There is another dying message left by a victim.
Please send an image to me.
Shi    ni    gami
Shinigami...
"L, did you know?
Shi       ni    gami
Shinigami."
Does he want to say that Shinigami exist?
Watari.
Tell the police to keep watch on the prison.
There may be someone else who will leave a message.
I understand.
There sure are a lot of humans.
Are you going to do it here?
I'll show you what I've learned from
all of the investigations and experiments I've done these past few days.
Experiments?
Yes. I've been testing different killing methods on the criminals in this area.
First, I write the cause of death and the circumstances in the Death Note.
Then when I write a name in afterwards, it becomes true.
That's something even I didn't know.
He's here.
Right on time.
Mr. Raye Penber.
I'll kill you if you turn around.
I am Kira.
If you turn around or put your hand in your pocket,
I will kill you on the spot.
I-It couldn't be...
But this voice... I've heard it somewhere.
I shall first prove to you that I am Kira.
I'll kill the man with the glasses
working at the coffee shop you are looking at.
Th-That's impossible.
Don't do it...
I had no choice.
I thought that if I didn't kill at least one person, you wouldn't believe me.
That man has been repeatedly accused of sexual assault,
but the police have never convicted him because of a lack of evidence.
He was a menace and deserved to be punished.
You may already have heard from L,
that I cannot kill someone unless I know their face.
I could kill everyone you see here.
If you have any requests, I'll do it.
D-Don't do it.
I believe that you're Kira.
You of course care about your loved ones more than you do the people here, right?
Consider them to be hostages.
Y-You know about her?!
That's right.
I've investigated you.
I shall kill everyone,
including your family, if you don't do exactly as I say.
You too, of course.
I-I understand.
What do you want me to do?
You have a computer with you, don't you?
Is there a file on the agents who've come to Japan?
My laptop is for work.
I always carry it around with me.
But those files aren't in it.
Then take this envelope.
First, take out the transceiver
and put on the earphone.
A transceiver...
It's almost like a toy.
But this won't leave a transmission record anywhere
and we can converse at close distances even underground.
He's thought this out.
Please take the Yamanote Line.
It doesn't matter if you take the inner circle or outer circle.
I shall be observing you from a close distance.
Even when you're on the train, look forward. Keep your eyes focused on one spot.
Don't forget, I can kill at any time.
Once you're on, sit in the corner closest to the door.
If it's taken, wait until it's free.
First, I must ask you something.
If your answer differs significantly from what I expect,
I will kill your girlfriend.
Of the FBI agents who have come to Japan,
how many are there and how are they organized?
Please answer into the transceiver.
I-I've heard it's four teams
and a total of twelve people.
Next, take out what's in the envelope.
Huh?!
What is this?
Of those investigators,
write the name of the agent who is directly in charge of you all
in the space at the top.
What is the meaning of this?
What is he planning?
But I have to do as he says.
He shouldn't be able to kill with just names alone.
Next, open your laptop.
You should be receiving a file from your superior soon.
A file of all the names and faces of the FBI agents who came to Japan.
Wh-What's going on?
Now, like you just did,
take a good look at each agent's face as you write their names on the envelope.
I don't understand it.
What is Kira trying to do?
What is he doing?
Looks like you're finished.
Now put the transceiver and envelope with the names on it
back into their original envelope and put them on the rack.
Now put your hands on your lap and continue riding the train without making a move for about thirty minutes.
When you are sure that nobody has noticed that you have forgotten the envelope,
get off of the train.
Why?
Why can't I remember that voice?
Kira...
Who are you?
Yagami Light...
Farewell, Raye Penber.
Raye Penber was writing those names on pages taken from the Death Note.
He unwittingly killed all of his coworkers.
Penber's directions were to die after sending the file to all of the agents.
The rest of the agents all died of heart attacks after the file was received.
L.
We have a call from the FBI Director.
It's me.
I've just got word from Japan that all of our agents have died.
They all died of heart attacks.
I can only think that Kira killed them.
L, I'm very sorry,
but the FBI will call off our investigation in Japan.
It's from Chief Yagami.
L. I have just talked with the FBI Director.
According to him,
you were investigating everyone here who is involved with the task force.
Yes.
What is the meaning of this?
Do you mean to say that you suspect us?
I decided that it was necessary to learn Kira's identity.
I cannot condone this.
I cannot believe that you
would spy on your comrades.
L, how can we trust you?
Besides that, Kira killed those FBI agents, didn't he?
Even if they're not criminals,
he'll kill anyone who stands in his way!
Kira is really just a murderer!
Another victim has left a message.
L,
do you know? Shinigami...
love apples.
Damn you, Kira!
Raye... died.
No...
He was killed by Kira.
What? A family meeting?
Even if I kept it secret, you'd find out sooner or later.
I'll tell you now.
I am currently in charge of conducting the Kira investigation.
Is that so?
Dad, you sure are amazing.
That isn't what I wanted to say.
Hm?
Yesterday,
twelve FBI agents who were sent to Japan to find Kira
all died.
Does that mean that they were killed by Kira?
What?!
It means that Kira might kill
anyone who tries to catch him.
It's a cold and ruthless crime—
the most horrific we've ever seen.
Many of my officers have quit.
D-Dad, you should quit too!
I don't want you to die!
That's right.
You should place your life before your job.
No. I will not remove myself from this case.
I will not yield to evil.
Dad...
Dear...
Dad, that's admirable.
I'm proud of you.
If something ever happens to you, I'll see to it
that Kira gets executed.
Kira will probably kill all who oppose him,
even if they aren't criminals.
We may be killed by Kira.
Think of your lives, your families, and your friends.
If anyone wants to be dropped from this investigation, please resign.
If you resign, you will not be demoted.
I promise you.
I want those with the confidence to stay on the case to fight Kira,
even if going after him means sacrificing everything.
That is all.
Hey, what are you going to do?
"What" indeed...
Yeah, right, that's him.
I remember him because he said, "Get down."
But I don't really remember the other passengers.
Is that so?
I understand. Thank you very much.
If what I'm thinking is right,
Kira could have been among those passengers.
If so, I can find Kira along the path this bus takes.
Only five people, huh?
Six including myself.
No, I should say as many as five of you are willing to risk your lives.
I trust all of you who have a strong sense of justice.
Wait just a moment.
L says he trusts us,
but we don't trust L.
L,
we have decided to risk our lives to catch Kira.
You should know what we mean by that.
But you never show your face,
and you just boss us around.
We cannot work with someone like that!
L.
If you want to work with us
and catch Kira,
would it be possible for you to come here?
Earlier, I said that I trust you all.
Why does he suddenly want to work with us?
If he's solved numerous difficult cases by himself,
he should do the same this time, too.
And judging by the way that L has been conducting the investigation,
he'll probably send a double to meet us.
A double, huh?
It's possible...
I-I trust L.
I also think we need L's help in this case.
Me too.
L said from the beginning
that he needed the police's help in this case.
Perhaps you could think of it like this.
L was waiting for this to happen.
For what to happen?
There were people in the investigation who distrusted L from the beginning.
Then we had detectives continue to resign
and our confidential information was leaked.
You can't run an investigation unless you trust your partners.
In other words,
L was waiting for the task force to be whittled down to people he can trust
and who will face evil without fear.
Yes.
I'll resign rather than join up with L.
Don't worry.
I won't trail you and try to find L.
I trust L and will try to cooperate with him.
Me too.
I am currently in a room at the Teito Hotel.
I shall be switching hotels from now on every few days.
From now on, I want you to think of these rooms
as the de facto center of the investigation.
If you can agree to these terms,
I want you to split into two groups, separated by a thirty-minute interval,
and come here by twelve o'clock midnight.
Kira...
We're finally at an even distance
from finding each other.
Very well.
I'll make my first appearance in front of people as L.
If you manage to find this out,
you'll definitely close in on me.
Bring it on.
I've worked a lot during these past few days.
Think.
Was there something that I missed?
And what should I do from here?
The real battle starts now, L.
Please come in.
If this woman had spoken to the police before she met me...
It seems that a god other than a Shinigami...
is on my side.