I am L.
He's L?
He's different from what I imagined.
I am Detective Superintendent Yagami of the National Police Agency.
Uh, I'm Matsuda.
I'm Aizawa.
I'm Mogi.
I'm Ukita.
I'm sorry we're late.
These five are our current...
Bang!
What are you doing?!
If I were Kira, you would be dead, Mr. Yagami Soichiro.
You already know that all Kira needs is a face and a name, don't you?
Please don't give out your name so carelessly.
Let's value our lives.
I've heard about him needing a face,
but I haven't heard anything about him needing a name.
Criminals whose names were unknown or whose names were broadcast incorrectly were all spared.
It was discussed at task force headquarters.
Let's not stand around and chat.
Please come right this way.
Oh, right.
Please turn off all cell phones, laptops, and other electronic devices and place them on that table.
L, do you think that we'd make calls on our
cell phones and leak our information to the outside?
Just do as he says.
I know he's cautious,
but I still can't tell whether or not he trusts us.
No. I just can't stand it when people's cell phones go off when I'm talking.
Let me start by saying...
Please do not take any notes on anything we say at this headquarters.
Keep all of it in your head.
Please, sit wherever you like.
O-Okay.
Um, L...
When you refer to me from now on, I wish to be called "Ryuzaki," not L.
Just to be safe.
Oh, then, Ryuzaki...
If you know that a face and a name are needed,
then couldn't we cut down the number of victims by censoring crime reports?
If we were to do that, then ordinary people would be killed.
Ordinary people?
Why?
Kira is childish and hates to lose.
He's childish?
And he hates to lose?
Yes.
I'm also childish and hate to lose.
That's how I know.
Ryuzaki,
could you elaborate?
When I declared war against Kira on television...
Until then, we thought that Kira was only after criminals.
But he didn't hesitate to kill my double.
Also, as soon as I said he was hiding in the Kanto region,
as if to say, "So what if I am?"
he started drawing most of his victims from Japan.
He's met each of my challenges without flinching.
What do you think would happen...p
if we tried to use media restrictions to hide criminals from someone like this?
Well...
"If you won't give me your criminals,
then I'll kill those who've committed lighter crimes
or even the innocent!"
"The whole world is my hostage!"
"I'm not the evil one."
"Those who oppose me and hide evil-doers are!"
This is how Kira's mind works.
Speaking of the mass media,
let's think of ways we can use it to our advantage.
For example?
How about this?
"U.S. furious over deaths of FBI agents."
"Kira's antics have angered the whole world,
the leading nations send a total of 1,500 investigators into Japan."
It would be different from his recent experience with the FBI.
He would begin to see everyone as a threat.
When he's at his limit, it should cause some sort of response.
Th-That's interesting.
1,500 instead of the actual group of seven, huh?
And unlike those FBI agents,
they don't exist, so they can't be killed!
This could work!
Well then, I'll tell you my thoughts on the Kira case.
Kira works alone.
He was accessing inside information from the investigation before.
Why do you believe he's working alone?
Aizawa, wait.
Let's hear Ryuzaki's entire theory first.
Kira needs a name and a face to kill.
To a certain degree,
he can even control the victim's time of death and the actions the victim takes before his death.
With all of that in mind...
Please listen closely to the following.
On December 14th,
twelve FBI agents entered Japan.
On December 19th,
Kira began using prisoners to conduct tests concerning actions a victim can take before death.
In other words, during just this five-day period,
Kira became aware of the FBI's presence and felt threatened.
Because he didn't know their faces or names,
in order to eliminate all of the FBI agents,
he had to see how far he could control the deaths of his victims.
Finally, on December 27th...
After making sure the FBI agents received the file
with all the names and faces of the other agents,
I succeeded in killing all of them.
It is nearly impossible to figure out whose files Kira saw.
But...
I can't let anyone know that I came into contact with Raye Penber.
Huh? You're not using the Death Note today?
Are you studying for the entrance exams?
It's no use practicing for those at this point.
Oh? So what is it?
From December 19th through the 27th...
That's when I worked the most.
Within this time, twenty-three people died of heart attacks as we all know.
They were all wanted criminals, ex-convicts,
and people who were suspected of crimes.
People obviously different from those Kira usually targets.
Indeed.
It means that in order to kill the FBI agents,
he needed to control those with even lesser crimes.
He killed twenty-three people
so that we couldn't tell whom he used.
He actually probably only used a few.
He left eight days after the tests
to allow the FBI to gather information on other suspects.
He wanted to draw attention away from himself.
Thus, I suspect that Kira was one of the people
who was being investigated by
the FBI between the 14th and the 19th.
This is data from the FBI.
It contains other important information.
You can't take these out of this room, but—
Amazing!
This is amazing!
If we have this much information,
our small group can do more than enough on our own.
Let's split into two groups.
One will trace the FBI agents, and the other will research those who had heart attacks.
There are only a few people
who were able to get info from headquarters,
whom the FBI were investigating during their first five days!
Yeah.
Well, does anyone have any questions?
Well then, Ryuzaki,
I have a question.
You said earlier that you hate to lose.
But you've shown us your face.
Doesn't that mean that you've already lost to Kira?
That's right.
The fact that I've shown my face
and that I've sacrificed twelve FBI agents are both losses.
But I will win in the end.
This is the first time I've put my life on the line.
Let's show Kira that we're willing to risk our lives...
because justice will definitely prevail.
Th-That's right.
Justice will prevail!
Let's give it our best!
Let's do this, Ryuzaki!
When I first saw him, I was suspicious.
But there's no mistake. This man is L.
First off, in order to make sure that Kira is not among us,
I would like to talk to each of you individually.
Huh? Oh, yeah.
So he doesn't trust us?
It's understandable.
If Kira's been gathering information from headquarters from the beginning,
chances are high that he's here.
I get it!
Because we've stayed on the case, we've seen Ryuzaki's face.
Even this is a risk, huh?
Things have been going well so far.
If only I had one more thing...
Just one more decisive clue...
If there was just one thing I missed...
Just one piece of evidence that would come to light...
It could cost me my life.
Just one thing...
Have you finished studying?
Yeah.
It's all right.
There wasn't anything I missed.
My biggest gamble was the bus-jacking incident,
but it's impossible to connect it to Kira.
The police and L don't know
that Kira can kill people by means other than heart attacks.
But if anyone were to discover that fact,
it would be a huge problem for me.
What? Right now?
Dad's been pulling overnighters.
He needs clean clothes.
You've got to give this to him.
I promised I'd go to the first
New Year's Shrine Visit with my friends!
I'll go.
I could use a break.
How lucky!
Thank you, Light!
That means that you can spy on the Police Department.
I'll only be able to go as far as the receptionist's desk, though.
Oh? You're bringing a page?
An outing to kill?
Lately, I've been doing this when I go out.
Just in case.
That day...
Raye said that he was going to go to Shinjuku.
On that same day, there were
four heart attacks in the Shinjuku area.
And...
a bus-jacking...
It's not a coincidence.
Kira can...
kill by means other than heart attacks.
That's unusual for Dad.
I wonder if he's at an important meeting.
Please help me!
I must speak directly to someone from the task force.
I told you already.
There is no one at the Kira task force headquarters.
There's no one at headquarters?
Dad's phone is off.
What's going on?
Is there any way I can contact them?
It's something very important relating to the Kira investigation.
The Kira investigation?!
Well, I'll try to call their headquarters once more.
I'm Detective Superintendent Yagami Soichiro's son, Light.
I brought my father's change of clothes,
but it doesn't look like he's here. Could you hold on to these for him?
Sure. Light, I haven't seen you around in a while.
Oh, sorry. Uh...
Remember? We solved that insurance murder with your advice.
I was the receptionist then, too.
Really? I'm sorry.
I just write my name here, right?
Does this mean that you're going to help the Kira case, too?
Yes.
If all goes well, I may be able to beat L.
Beat L?
Nobody's at their headquarters.
Please trust me on this.
I'll be sure to give them your message.
That won't do.
It must be in person.
Excuse me...
My father is leading the Kira investigation.
Do you want to leave a message with me?
His cell phone is off,
so I can't tell him immediately.
A bunch of FBI agents were killed,
and a lot of detectives quit the case because they were afraid of Kira.
Light, you shouldn't be telling civilians that.
People are already talking about it.
Besides, this person is trustworthy.
I can tell by looking at her eyes.
She's a very wise and careful person.
You've heard about the FBI incident,
and you figured out that there's a problem within the Japanese police force itself.
That's why you want to speak directly to headquarters.
Did I get that right?
I'll probably get a call from my father
once he gets the message I left on his phone.
You can talk directly to him at that time.
Is it all right?
Of course.
I can't give you my father's cell phone number,
but you can use my phone.
Of course, it's no use if you don't trust both of us.
What's up with that cheery attitude?
I leave it to you.
You've managed to lead her along well, Light.
You're pretty brave...
to involve yourself in the Kira case.
Not at all.
You think that Kira is...
Uh, may I ask what your name is?
My name is Yagami Light.
Yagami as in "night god,"
and Light as in the character for "moon."
It's a strange name, isn't it?
I'm Maki Shoko.
Maki as in "space" and "tree,"
and Shoko for "shining child."
Ms. Maki, right?
Ms. Maki,
I think that Kira's powers
enable him to control his victims before he kills them.
I thought so too!
That's exactly what I was thinking!
Kira can control the actions of a person before death.
But that's not all.
If my analysis is correct,
Kira can also kill people by means other than heart attacks.
Who is this woman?
I don't think anyone's noticed yet.
But I think this is what's going to help us catch Kira.
I hadn't even thought about that.
But if that's the case,
Kira would make sure not to give his victims heart attacks when he's intent on hiding a murder.
Yes. Someone I know may have met Kira.
They've met Kira?!
Oh, sorry.
Meeting Kira is definitely something that the police would have a hard time believing.
Right. That's why I have to explain it in detail to someone from the task force headquarters.
But wouldn't it be better
if that person spoke to them instead?
That person is no longer alive.
He was one of the FBI agents who came to Japan.
An FBI agent who met Kira.
Could it be...
He was also my fiancé.
He said that he witnessed a bus-jacking incident.
He probably met Kira on that bus.
Raye Penber!
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I'm sorry your fiancé passed away.
So what makes you think he met Kira?
Eight days after the bus-jacking...
He died, along with the other FBI agents.
That bus-jacker robbed a bank two days earlier.
He died in an accident.
An unusual and rare set of events...
I think that Kira set up the bus-jacking to steal information from my fiancé
in order to kill the FBI agents who had come to Japan.
The bus-jacker died in an accident.
In other words, heart attacks aren't the only way that Kira can kill.
The bus-jacker didn't die of a heart attack.
So that's why you think that Kira can kill
by means other than heart attacks?
Yes.
I think that's a bit of a leap.
No, it's not.
I can't help but think that the bus-jacker was being controlled by Kira.
Why?
I've been wondering about the bus-jacking ever since my fiancé told me about it.
I asked him about it more when he was relaxed.
He didn't name names, but he did tell me this.
What did he say?
That he reluctantly showed his FBI ID to someone.
Because it was an investigation conducted in secret by the Japanese police,
he wasn't supposed to show his ID.
So whoever saw his ID was the one who let it slip that the FBI was in Japan.
She's right on the money!
So this would be the oversight that Light was worrying about!
I see.
It's a conclusion you came to
with your singular knowledge and your desire to avenge your fiancé.
You believe that Kira can murder his victims by means other than heart attacks.
Yes.
You have some amazing deductive skills,
but you can't deny that
you have personal interests in this case. Your argument seems a bit forced.
But...
This theory is definitely worth investigating.
Your testimony will be very important to the case.
R-Right.
If what you said is correct,
Kira will be caught soon.
Because...
Kira was the one your fiancé showed his ID to on that bus.
Yes.
That was close.
If this woman had spoken to the police before she met me...
But...
It seems that a god other than a Shinigami...
is on my side.
I want to see how this woman dies,
but I can't be caught following her.
Now...
hurry to your death.