I-I can't believe my well-behaved son is looking at a magazine like that!
Light, dinner time!
I'll solve equations with my right hand...
and write names with my left.
I'll take a potato chip...
and eat it!
The witness to my alibi is L himself.
Are you sure, Ryuk?
Yeah. Nobody's following you.
G-Give it to me quickly.
My withdrawal symptoms...
You're not just saying that so I'll give you an apple, right?
Hey, hey!
I've flown around and checked
a hundred-meter radius around you.
I'm sure.
But there was the news report about Interpol dispatching 1,500 investigators.
It's a bluff, of course.
You said it yourself.
If it were real, they would sneak in and investigate secretly.
All right, Ryuk.
I'll buy you an apple.
All right!
Thank you very much.
Light! Quickly, quickly.
You really are a slave driver.
You had me search for cameras
and made me give up eating apples in the house.
Be sure to eat the core as well.
In the end, I'll really write your name
in my Death Note, and kill ya!
Is this any time to be laughing?
That's right.
, There's just one thing left to top everything off.
Ryuzaki...
Yes?
About the purse-snatcher and embezzler's heart attacks two days ago...
That happened before my family had any knowledge of it.
Have they been cleared?
I suppose you're right.
Even though Kira can control the time of death,
I don't think that there's any way he could set up
his victims without watching that broadcas—
Your son has come home again.
So, you're gonna shut up and act like you're studying again, huh?
I already have an idea of where all the cameras are.
But...
I was only able to kill
a purse-snatcher and an embezzler.
They've committed really minor crimes compared to those I've killed until now.
Are you going to watch TV?
I killed criminals whose names and faces were broadcast
when I didn't have access to TV or the Internet.
But there still is a chance that I'll be suspected
because only minor criminals die when I don't have any information.
In other words,
if I also kill minor criminals being broadcast when I watch TV,
I won't call attention to myself.
Also, when I go out,
regardless of the severity of the crime,
I should remember the names of criminals broadcast.
I'll kill them at random times
with the piece of the Death Note I left in my wallet.
Now my measures against the cameras are perfect.
During these past few days,
I have checked our tapes and video footage many times.
I've come to a decision.
Among the Kitamura and Yagami households...
no one is suspicious.
I shall remove the cameras and wiretaps.
So, in the end the culprit wasn't here, huh?
Don't lower your guard!
We're going to narrow down our possibilities once more.
Please don't get the wrong idea.
I just meant that there wasn't anyone suspicious from what I could see from our footage.
Huh?
Even if Kira is among them, he wouldn't give himself away.
No,
it means that he was killing criminals as usual, without showing it.
Then you believe that one of them might be Kira?
I'd say it's...
a five-percent chance.
Kira was still killing people
even while the surveillance cameras were in place.
I don't know how he did it,
but even if he is able to kill people by wishing death upon them...
If he were a normal person,
he would have behaved differently
or at least changed his facial expression when committing the murders.
Kira is not among them.
Most people would conclude that.
But... if Kira is one of them,
his psyche has reached a god-like level.
Judging sinners without changing his expression.
I want to believe that Kira doesn't really exist...
that this really is divine judgment.
But it's absurd to think that God would need
a person's face and name to kill.
But this isn't divine judgment by God.
It's the actions of someone childish who thinks he's God.
That's what this is.
The mass murderer known as Kira does exist.
And I will catch him.
But...
I don't think that Kira will expose himself
even if I keep these cameras in place.
What should I do?
It would be best to get him to tell me himself
that he's Kira, and have him show me how he kills.
But there's no way I can...
Hey, Light, the cameras really have been removed!
Every single one of them!
Light, are you listening?
Hey, Light.
Oh, I see. The wiretaps might still be here.
I'm no longer a suspect.
It's all happened as I'd planned.
But L will probably continue to chase Kira.
And if he's still using the Japanese police,
my father will be among those being used.
If that's the case...
I'll use my father to find out
L's identity so I can eliminate him.
If I just get rid of L,
Kira will be one step closer to becoming the god of the new world.
Light, hurry up.
Do your best!
Good luck, Light!
Really, you're making such a big fuss over this.
I'll be going.
It sure feels good, now that we know
there aren't any wiretaps.
Well, it's nice to know
that one cause of stress is gone before my test.
Once I start college,
I'll have more time to operate as Kira and search for L.
You there! The test will start in ten minutes! Hurry up!
I had planned to go in three minutes early because I didn't want to wait in the classroom.
I sure got here early.
That's some confidence you've got.
You may begin.
You there, number 162.
Sit in your seat properly!
There have been quite a lot of Shinigami looking real hard into the Human World lately.
What's with that?
It seems that Ryuk has turned into some human's pet.
Wh-What in the world is he thinking?
Really. He's a disgrace to all Shinigami.
No, I'm talking about the human who's keeping him.
Ryuk's probably not a very cute pet.
Well, yeah.
So what kind of human's keeping him?
Is it a woman? A man?
Who knows?
I'll go take a peek as well.
Oh well...
So you're a college student now, huh, Light?
My heart's filled with emotion.
Now for our freshman address.
And our freshman representative, Yagami Light.
Yes.
Oh, wow.
Likewise, freshman representative, Ryuga Hideki.
Oh! Got it...
Ryuga Hideki, the pop idol?!
Couldn't be... There's no way he's smart enough to enter To-Oh.
Ah... You're right. He doesn't even look anything like him.
I heard I was going to be giving the address with someone else,
but he's the last person I expected.
He's the guy who was sitting weird behind me
on the first day of the Exams.
He completely stood out from everyone else.
Life springs renewed in the breath of spring...
The person who scored highest on the test is supposed to do this, right?
This just means that there were two top scorers this year.
I heard they both had flawless scores in all subjects.
Seriously? I guess there really are people like that.
I definitely like the guy on the right!
What?! Kyoko, you're weird.
Most people would choose the one on the left.
But those two sure are different.
Yeah.
One looks like a brilliant genius from a sheltered family.
The other...
Life springs renewed in the breath of spring...
...seems wild or at least very weird.
Is that what people would call a genius?
He is giving the address for the To-Oh entrance ceremony while he's dressed like that.
He is either not taking this seriously, or an idiot.
Thank you very much. Ryuga Hideki.
Yagami...
You're the son of Yagami Soichiro, Detective Superintendent of the NPA.
You have a sense of justice which rivals that of your respect for your father.
Who is this guy?
You also aim to become a police official
and have helped the police to solve several cases in the past.
You're now showing great interest in the Kira case.
I have faith in your sense of justice and abilities,
and if you swear not to tell anyone,
I'll tell you something very important concerning the Kira case.
What is this, all of a sudden?
Should I just ignore him?
But what is this important information concerning the Kira case?
I won't tell anyone. What is it?
I'm L.
It...
It couldn't be!
What is he talking about?!
There's no way that L would say that he's L.
I thought he was a strange guy, but is he really that weird?
Th-This isn't good.
Don't be shocked.
If he really is L...
I have to act naturally,
how Yagami Soichiro's son, Light, would act.
If you truly are who you say you are,
I respect and admire you.
Thank you.
I revealed myself because I think
that you can be of help in solving the Kira case.
Yagami Light...
The probability that you are Kira is just under five percent.
But out of everyone we were watching, I sensed something from you.
You're inconceivably perfect.
And if you are Kira, there's nothing that could pressure you more than this.
If this guy really is L,
he's something else.
Indeed... if he really is L.
No, even if he isn't L...
I...
I can't do anything to him!
If what he's saying is true,
then he's probably already shown his face to my father.
If he dies as soon as he reveals his identity to me,
then suspicion will immediately fall onto me.
And he's using an obvious alias such as Ryuga Hideki.
If his name really isn't Ryuga Hideki
and I try to kill him by writing his name in the Death Note,
the pop idol Ryuga's face will pop up in my head whether I want it to or not,
and he may die instead.
But he won't die and will surmise that I'm Kira.
Is he really L?
Also, does he suspect that I'm Kira?
I don't know how much he knows, but I'm sure he suspects me.
There's no other reason for him
to tell Yagami Soichiro's son that he's L.
Does this mean that he's still focusing on the people
whom Raye Penber was investigating?
But why has L approached me directly?
Not now...
It's better to keep my mind blank.
I have to keep a straight face.
He's definitely checking to see whether I'm shocked now.
That was an interesting college entrance ceremony, Light.
Yagami.
Hey, Light, he's calling you.
It was nice meeting you.
No, the pleasure was all mine.
What an amazing car.
A limousine?
Well, I'll see you around campus.
Oh, yeah.
Where's that rich kid from?
And he's even at the top of the class? What a jerk.
Ah, welcome home, To-Oh University student!
Damn! He got me!
He got you?
Damn you, L! I've never been so humiliated in my life!
Say, why don't you just do
the Shinigami eye deal with me and kill him?
What good would that do if this is a trap?!
If he's not really L, then I might as well have "I'm Kira" written on my face!
S-Sorry...
There's a world of difference between Shinigami killing people and humans killing people.
I want to kill him no matter what it takes, but if I do, it'll be traced back to me.
The Death Note can only kill
a person whose name I write in it.
I cannot control someone to kill someone else.
The Death Note is a pain in the ass!
Light is usually calm, but he's fuming now.
He's pretty irritated.
At first, I thought that when I found out his name,
I'd have him get in an accident or commit suicide.
But it's no good unless I know a hundred percent that he's L.
No. Even if I do know it's him,
it may be too late.
No matter what the cause of death, if L dies, I'll be suspected.
I underestimated him.
Never in a thousand years would I have thought that L would come up to me and say, "I'm L."
He just has to tell all the suspects that he is L.
Even if he's his double,
this is a solid defense as well as an attack against Kira.
He beat me. It was a good move.
Ryuga will play dumb
and probably continue to approach me and manipulate me at the university.
This is great.
There's nothing to worry about.
This proves that they don't have anything on me.
It's a contest between L and me.
It's a game of wits!
On the surface, we'll be friendly acquaintances on campus.
In reality, we'll be investigating each other.
"Are you L?" or "Are you Kira?"
This is interesting, Ryuga.
If it's friendship you want from me,
you can have it in spades.
I'll make you trust me,
and once I've pulled everything out of you, I will kill you...
with my own hands!
Ryuga Hideki, L...
There's no way that he could profile me with this tennis game.
He has some other goal in mind.
But even if it's just tennis, I will win!