I'm surprised, Ryuga.
I never thought that you'd suddenly ask me
to play some tennis to get to know each other.
Is it a problem?
Not at all.
But you asked me already knowing my abilities?
It's all right, Yagami.
I was once the British Junior Champion.
If I ask him if he's British,
would he think that I'm trying to find out
more about him because I'm Kira?
Fine. I'll give it a try.
Ryuga, were you raised in Britain?
I lived in Britain for five years,
but don't worry.
There's nothing there that can reveal L's identity.
Oh, is that so?
Then the first to win a set of six games wins the game, okay?
All right.
This is just a friendly game of tennis.
This isn't a test to determine if Light is Kira.
But Kira hates to lose.
Fifteen, love.
Hey, Ryuga, you're serious right off the bat!
The person who makes the first move wins.
What do you mean that you can't say?
I'm very sorry.
Under L's orders, no one outside the task force can know.
Not even you, Deputy Director General.
Including what you're doing and where you're doing it, huh?
I'm very sorry.
Yagami...
It's been more than four months since this case has come to light.
People are saying that the police and L are incompetent.
With all due respect, Sir,
but can you really call the police competent for turning tail from Kira?
You should see how many people are left at task force headquarters.
If you're worried about what people are saying,
then try not to let them know that the bulk of the detectives have run away from Kira!
Excuse me.
Yagami.
What about L?
Can he be trusted?
I think he's far more capable than we are.
He's putting his life on the line right now.
Are they really amateurs?
Who are they?
They're Yagami Light and Ryuga Hideki.
The two who entered this year with top scores.
Don't worry, Yagami.
Kira hates to lose,
but most people don't like to lose. It's not just Kira.
Is getting worked up and going for the win something Kira would do?
Even so, if I lose on purpose,
he'll think that getting worked up and winning is like Kira,
so losing on purpose is also like Kira, right?
In the end, it's the same thing.
There's no way that he could profile me with this tennis game.
He has some other goal in mind.
But even if it's just tennis,
I will win!
See, you came in for the win.
Game count, four games all.
All of a sudden,
there's an umpire and a line judge.
Sir!
I thought I'd heard of Yagami Light somewhere, so I looked him up.
It seems he was the Junior High Champion
in 2002 and 2003.
During the Junior High third-year commendation ceremony,
he announced that he'd only play in junior high.
He hasn't played in any tournaments since.
Hey, hey!
So what about Ryuga?
He's holding his own against the Junior High Champion!
I can read your feelings, Yagami Light.
There's no way that this kind of tennis
can deepen our friendship.
We're going through the motions
just so we can say we're better friends.
By playing tennis with you,
you will think that I am preparing to take a step closer to you.
And then you're gonna try to get me to say something
that only Kira would know.
But you'll tell me you'll need to know if you can trust me first.
And you'll try to get me to give you details on the Kira case.
If I want to talk about the Kira case,
I'm going to have to ask him for proof
that he's currently in charge of the Kira case.
So the first thing you're going to want out of me is...
...proof that you really are L, from a third party.
In other words,
we'll go to task force headquarters!
In life, one cannot win just by playing defense.
To win, you need to attack!
Game set.
Won by Yagami.
Six games to four!
Wow!
As I expected of you.
I lost.
It's been a while since I've played seriously, Ryuga.
I'm thirsty.
And I have something I want to ask you,
so do you want to go get a drink afterwards?
I've lost the game,
so I'll tell you whatever I can.
But before that, I have something I must tell you.
What is it?
Yagami, I suspect that you're Kira.
If you still want to ask me, then ask away.
I'm Kira?
Well, even though I say I suspect you, it's only a one-percent possibility.
Leaving that aside,
once I'm sure that you aren't Kira,
and because you have sharp reasoning abilities,
I'd like for you to work with me on this investigation.
One percent, huh?
That's well-worded.
Even if he suspects me just a little,
it still means that it won't do any good
if I ask to meet someone from the task force.
Which means he beat me to the punch.
He got me.
This coffee shop is one of my favorites.
If we sit here, there's no chance of anyone overhearing us.
This is a nice spot you've shown me.
We don't have to worry about how we sit here either.
I have to sit like this.
If I sit normally,
my reasoning skills drop by forty percent.
So, what did you want to ask me?
Oh yeah.
That can wait until you're sure that I'm not Kira.
You can talk about whatever you want to.
Then excuse me,
but would you mind if I test your deductive skills?
Not at all.
That sounds fun.
Then first...
please take a look at this.
These three are pictures of notes that we believe were written
by criminals in prison right before they died,
while under Kira's control.
Please tell me what you think.
This is interesting.
Really, what a childish trick.
The print number is written on the back of these photographs.
If I paid no attention to this,
and correctly unscrambled the sentence the way Kira wrote it,
it'd be "L, do you know, Shinigami love apples."
There'd be a strong possibility that I'd be Kira.
But just because I solve this code
doesn't prove I'm Kira.
It would be amazing if Kira could not only inflict death on others,
but control his victims' actions as well.
And there's a message encoded here taunting you.
When we rearrange the messages and take a look at the top letters of each line,
they form another sentence.
Rearranging it into a message which makes sense would probably be...
"L, do you know? Shinigami love apples."
But there are print numbers on the back.
When we arrange them in that order,
we get, "L, do you know? Love Apples, Shinigami."
It doesn't make sense
and it's hard to think that Kira
would have wanted you to read it this way.
Incorrect.
There are actually four photographs.
When we add this one, this is what it reads,
"L, do you know? Shinigami who love apples
have red hands."
It's a fake.
This fourth picture is not a message I made a criminal write.
Is he stupid?
But even with the three photographs, my deduction was perfect, wasn't it?
It wasn't perfect.
The truth is that there are four of them.
If you'd figured out there was another, then yeah.
Yagami, even though you knew the message wasn't finished,
you decided that there were only three notes. You didn't guess that there was a fourth.
This is also true.
Damn him...
I see. He isn't just gauging my deductive abilities.
He's trying to get me to reveal myself.
If I latch onto this, I'll play right into his hands.
Hmm... I hadn't thought that far ahead.
Well, whatever the case, it's not a message that would lead to Kira.
Shinigami don't exist.
Let's say that you're in my shoes,
faced with someone who might be Kira,
how would you check if he was Kira?
I would try to have him say something
that wasn't broadcast to the public, that only Kira would know.
What you were doing just now.
That's amazing.
I've asked several detectives that same question,
but most of them needed a few minutes to answer.
You, on the other hand,
immediately thought of a scenario in which Kira is talking to the investigator.
Your deductive abilities are amazing.
The more impressive my answers,
the more suspicious I become, it seems.
Yes. By about three percent.
But in that respect,
it's made me more determined to work with you.
Even if you are Kira,
I would like for us to work together on this investigation.
Do you know why?
If I cooperate with you, the investigation will move forward,
and if I really am Kira, I might reveal myself.
In other words, you're killing two birds with one stone.
I think it's a great idea.
But aren't you getting the wrong idea, Ryuga?
I am interested in the Kira case
and conduct detective work as a hobby.
But I am not Kira, and I don't want him to kill me.
First of all, I have no proof that you aren't Kira, either.
It would be strange for just one of us to be investigated, right?
Neither of us have proof that we aren't Kira.
But, Ryuga, if you are L,
o I'm sure you can show me proof of that.
Like having someone in the task force, or my father,
tell me that you are really L in person.
If you can't, I won't investigate with you.
You talk a lot, don't you, Yagami Light?
Typical for someone who hates to lose.
Seven percent...
Could he really be...?
I never said that I wouldn't let you meet anyone from task force headquarters.
I am currently working with your father.
If I take you to headquarters, you'll help with the investigation.
Am I right?
What is he thinking?
Excuse me.
Oh, me too.
Yes?
Ryuzaki, something terrible has happened.
Light, your father has...
Yagami!
My father had a heart attack!
Well, see you tomorrow.
I'll bring your things that you need.
Light, I leave the rest to you.
Okay.
You're sure it's just fatigue, right?
Yeah. When I collapsed,
I thought it was Kira, but I'm all right.
I've been pushing myself a bit hard lately.
Especially since your son has been suspected of being Kira.
You told that to my father?
Yes.
I told him everything.
Even the fact that I'm L.
That's right. He's L.
We call him Ryuzaki so others can't find out,
but there's no mistaking it. He's L.
He's the real L.
My father is telling me so.
Probably the same L who has been ordering the police until now.
If I get rid of him and the investigative team...
No, it's probably not that simple.
There's no need to rush.
I'll have time to spy from here on.
At any rate, I have to be the Yagami Light
who is worried about his father.
So, Ryuzaki,
has talking with my son cleared away your suspicions?
I still suspect him, but only a little bit.
I'll explain once more.
Kira killed twelve FBI agents who were in Japan.
They were tracking those who were connected to the Japanese police.
One of them was Raye Penber.
There were many suspicious things surrounding his death.
And I was one of the people he was investigating.
It's no wonder I'm a suspect.
No, it's as Ryuga says.
There is no one else to suspect.
Your deductive ability is quite impressive.
It's always quick and accurate.
Ryuga, I'll cooperate with you on this investigation.
My father has vouched that you're L.
Also, I want to catch Kira and prove that I'm not him.
Light...
Soon, you're going to have to study to enter the police force.
It won't be too late to do this afterwards.
Dad, what are you talking about?
I don't know how many years that'll take.
I promised you, didn't I?
That if something happened to you,
I'd see to it that Kira gets executed.
There's no way that my son can be Kira.
It's hard to believe this is all an act.
No, if it's an act, it's too corny.
Light, listen to me.
Kira is evil.
That's the fact of the matter.
But recently, I've been thinking about it in this way:
the real evil is the power to kill people.
People who attain that kind of power are unlucky.
No matter how you use it,
nothing gained by killing people
can bring about true happiness.
It's as he says.
If Kira is an ordinary person who gained this power,
then he is a very unlucky person.
Ryuzaki,
I'm sorry for causing you trouble.
I'll try to recover quickly.
Excuse me...
Visiting hours are now over.
Ryuga.
Is there any way that I can get you
to believe that I'm not Kira?
If you aren't Kira,
then there isn't any need to do that.
Cut that out!
Think about how it feels to be accused of being Kira.
It feels horrible.
How about keeping watch over me
in a place without even TV for a month?
Would someone really go that far to clear their name?
That would be no good.
I can't do anything that would deprive you of basic human rights.
And furthermore, it's nonsensical
to take suggestions from the suspect.
I see.
It's all right.
We'll know in time if you aren't Kira.
Also, during that exchange with your father,
I thought that you might not be Kira.
Well then, take care of your father.
Oh, one more thing.
I said that I would cooperate with the investigation,
but I don't think I can do anything until my father is well again.
I understand.
Well then...
Ryuga Hideki...
Ryuzaki...
He's the L I've been fighting.
What is his real name?
Yagami Light,
are you not Kira?
Ryuk...
Hmm?
I never once felt unlucky
since I picked up this notebook and gained this power.
I'm wonderfully happy,
and I'll create a wonderful world.
I couldn't care less if finding the notebook's
made you happy or unlucky.
But...
It seems people who have Shinigami attached to them
experience nothing but misfortune.
Then I shall show you an exception to the rule.
I appreciate that.
What is it? Is this the only plan you can think of?!
You think that we'll get ratings
if we do any special program on Kira, don't you?
We've been getting ratings
because we cover stories that other stations don't!
Understand?
The problem is with the story.
Someone bring me a good story!
But the police are keeping quiet about this. It's hopeless.
Dumbass!
If we don't have any stories, just make something up!
Director Demegawa, a special delivery.
What is this?
Who is this from?
This is what I'm talking about.
This is what I want you to think of.
Wow, this is too good to be true.
"A message to the world from Kira."
"If you don't broadcast this, I'll kill you all, starting from your company's president."
Who wouldn't air this?
This is amazing if it's real.
I'm so happy, my heart's beating a mile a minute!
If I leave things the way they are,
L might be finished off within the next four days.
God really is on my side.
Only this time, it's not really God, but a Shinigami—
a God of Death.