Next, we have the Misora Naomi case.
Should we go ahead and open a criminal investigation?
We should investigate it separately from the Kira case.
We should avoid using photographs and only use police sketches.
But she's already been missing for four months.
She's probably dead by now.
If she's dead, it's odd that her body hasn't turned up yet.
If it does turn up, we might be able to find a clue.
Ryuzaki.
Take a look at Sakura TV.
Something terrible is happening.
In other words,
we are all Kira's hostages.
It is also our duty as news broadcasters to give you this announcement.
Please understand that this is not a hoax
and that we are not airing
these tapes solely for sensationalism.
Kira's hostages?
What is this?
Four days ago, our program director was sent these four tapes.
Beyond a shadow of a doubt,
they are from Kira.
Our ratings could go up sixty—no, seventy percent.
The first tape predicted the time of death of two suspected felons, yesterday.
As predicted, they died yesterday of heart attacks.
If this is true, it really is something that only Kira could do.
And Kira has instructed us to air
these two tapes today at exactly 5:59 p.m.
To prove that he is Kira, one tape predicts the killings,
and the other sends a message to the people of the world.
I-It's probably just another fake documentary, isn't it?
It couldn't be.
Who would make such a vicious fake?
Now, take a look.
I am Kira.
If this video was aired on April 18th, at exactly 5:59 p.m.,
the time now is 5:59:47...
48... 49.
Please change the channel to Taiyo TV.
The anchor, Hibima Kazuhiko,
will die of a heart attack at exactly six o'clock.
Wh-Whoa!
Change it!
It can't be!
How could he?!
Change the channel back.
Hibima continued to insist on the air that Kira is evil.
Bring one — no, two TVs here.
This is his punishment.
Understood.
There shall be another victim.
The target
is an NHN TV commentator
who has continued to condemn me
and is to appear live.
Kumaizumi Seiji.
Ryuzaki!
Change it to channel 24!
Change it back.
I trust you now believe that I'm Kira.
Kira said that he was going to send
a message to the people of the world.
Something terrible will happen if we don't stop this broadcast!
Get Sakura TV on the line!
It's no good.
No one I know at the station has their cell phones on.
The lines at the station are all busy!
Damn!
Ukita!
I'll go to the station and stop this at the source!
Everyone, please listen to me.
I don't want to kill the innocent.
I hate evil, and I love justice.
I consider the police as allies,
not as my enemies.
Damn you, Kira.
My intention is to create a world without evil.
If everyone cooperates, this will be simple.
If no one tries to catch me, the innocent will not die.
Damn!
Even if you don't agree with me,
keep your sentiments to yourself.
As long as you do not broadcast them, I won't kill you.
Please be patient.
I will create a better world for everyone.
I will change this tainted world
into a new one in which only kind people live.
Imagine it.
Together, the police and I will create...
Sachiko...
Dear, you'll ruin your health.
Please rest.
Sachiko,
I am the head of the Kira task force.
Damn! It's locked!
This is the police!
Open up!
You moron!
We interrupt this scheduled program
Hello?!
Damn, I'm not getting through!
We interrupt this scheduled program
to bring you live footage from the front of the Sakura TV studio.
Damn, I'm not getting through!
M-Mr. Aizawa!
Take a look!
Someone has collapsed!
We're in front of the Sakura TV studio!
U-Ukita!
D-Dammit!
It's Kira, isn't it?!
Mr. Aizawa.
Where are you going?
Where Ukita is, of course!
That wouldn't be good.
Please think about this calmly.
Are you telling me that we should just quietly watch TV here?!
If this is Kira's doing,
you'll just meet the same fate.
Kira shouldn't be able to kill without a name!
So how could this happen?!
Our aliases and fake police IDs are pointless!
You don't think Kira already knows our names?
That may be so.
If that's the case, it would be a lot easier to kill off all those who are investigating him before making a move.
I deduced that he needed a face and a name to kill.
But from what I just saw,
it's not entirely impossible
that he may only need a face to kill.
All I can say is that
Kira is within that television station
or is in a place where he can watch who enters the buildin—
If Kira is in that area,
isn't that more of a reason to go?!
He may have only placed surveillance cameras in the area.
If we go there unprepared,
we're as good as dead.
You said that you were risking your life to catch Kira, didn't you?!
Risking my life
and having a death wish are worlds apart.
What?!
Please control yourself.
Mr. Ukita was killed.
If something were to happen to you as well...
I want the police to tell me
whether or not they will help me create a new world.
Please make an announcement
on the six-o'clock news in four days.
I have prepared a video
for whichever answer you choose.
Wh-What the hell is this?!
Hey!
What do you think you're doing?!
Where is the studio that's airing the Kira video?!
This just in!
A vehicle has just crashed into the Sakura TV studio!
That's one way to get into the building without being seen.
But who would...
This is the police!
Stop this program!
Wh-What's going on?!
Stop the Kira tape right now!
W-Wait a second, Detective!
If we stop this, we'll be killed by Kira.
Shut up!
If you hand them over, you won't be killed now!
Wh-What do you think you're doing?!
Are you out of your mind?!
All of this is happening because you're treating Kira like some kind of celebrity.
Don't you think it serves you right?
Hand over all of the copies of your tapes!
Don't try anything funny!
I-I got it!
I'll hand 'em over!
So please stop waving that gun around!
You've got a crazy look in your eyes!
At last, police cars have arrived
in front of the Sakura TV building!
We aren't alone in this.
There are still people within the police
who will stand up against Kira.
Mr. Aizawa.
You know Deputy Director Kitamura's cell phone number, don't you?
Aizawa, I told you not to call me.
This is L.
I want you to do something for me.
Watch the news. You will see the police officers who are fighting hard to bring Kira to justice.
If you don't take control of them as their superior,
we'll have a tragedy on our hands.
But we are to stay out of this case.
Two of the police officers who rushed forward have collapsed!
W-We're going to retreat!
I understand, L.
Please advise me on how I should lead them.
It's from Detective Superintendent Yagami.
Call him back, and give the phone to me.
Quickly, get me Ryuzaki!
It's me.
Mr. Yagami, so that was you in that police van.
Yeah, I just couldn't take it anymore.
I've confiscated all the tapes.
I'll bring them to you.
How are you doing?
I'm more than fine.
I've never felt better.
So what should I do?
I think exiting out the front would be dangerous,
but maybe I'll be all right in that van.
Wait just a moment.
Deputy Director Kitamura,
Chief Yagami is the one who crashed into the building.
Are you prepared?
As you requested.
Mr. Yagami, wait five minutes,
and then use the front entrance.
Use the front entrance?
Listen up! Don't leave any gaps!
Conceal yourselves!
Kira is not in the television station.
He's outside!
Thank you.
I'll drive myself.
I understand.
Listen up!
There is a good chance that Kira is in the area!
Be sure to remain hidden while you're searching the place carefully!
The police have
turned down Kira's calls
and have shown that they are ready to fight!
I will gather up the courage to say this:
This is right!
This is the right thing to do!
This is the right stance that a country under rule of law should take!
My name is Tanakabara Koki.
This has been NHN's Golden News anchor,
Tanakabara Koki!
Chief!
Chief Yagami!
Ryuzaki,
I'm sorry for acting on my own.
My emotions had clouded my judgment.
Not at all.
The tapes and envelopes that Kira sent are all in here.
Thank you very much.
P-Please allow me to rest for a moment.
Mr. Yagami...
This won't be in vain.
The postmark is from Osaka.
But Kira can control his victims before they die.
He could've had it delivered
from Osaka without going there himself.
Mr. Aizawa.
Could you take this to the lab?
I have a lot of contacts in the lab.
I'll be sure to check this out thoroughly.
Please do.
I shall check the contents of the duplicate tapes.
Ryuzaki, what's on them?
They're very interesting tapes.
If the police had said yes and cooperated with Kira,
tape number three was to be aired.
Otherwise, number four was to be aired.
Tape three details the conditions for cooperation.
Basically, to broadcast more criminals.
Especially those who had hurt people,
or criminals who had abused those weaker than they are,
regardless of how severe their crimes were.
And Kira would be the judge, jury, and executioner in all of this.
Furthermore, as proof that the police are cooperating,
he said that he wanted the top brass from the NPA and L
to appear on TV and announce that they will cooperate with him.
In other words, have the top brass and me show our faces
so that if we raise any suspicion,
he can kill us.
What if we had answered no?
Basically the same thing, just expressed differently.
Mr. Yagami, our answer is no, of course.
Please allow Sakura TV to air the fourth video.
I think it is unfortunate that your answer is no.
The police have answered that they still wish to fight me.
So I will first take the life of the director general of the NPA.
Or, I may take the life of L,
who is leading the investigation.
The director general or L.
Whom will you hand out as a sacrificial lamb for not cooperating to create a peaceful world?
Please decide in four days.
God really is on my side.
Only this time, it's not really God,
but a Shinigami — a God of Death.
So it seems.
Another Shinigami has come to the human world.
And another Shinigami's Death Note
has fallen into the hands of someone who agrees with Kira.
This guy probably also has the Shinigami eyes.
Which means this Kira's killing abilities are far greater than mine.
If I leave things the way they are,
L might be finished off within the next four days.
However,
I can't forgive the impostor for dragging down
Kira's image with these dirty tactics.
If the impostor slips up and is caught,
the existence of the Death Note could be discovered.
I can't let him run wild for too long.
What I need most now
is to cooperate with the investigation
and to figure out both L's and the Fake Kira's moves.
Ryuzaki,
it's as you thought.
Leaders of several countries have convened
and they want the real L to appear on TV.
That would be the most right and reasonable choice.
Well, we still have three days,
so let's think of a measure to prevent all that.
It would annoy me
if I were killed by someone
who had jumped on Kira's bandwagon.
Huh?!
What do you mean, Ryuzaki?
There is a high possibility that this Kira is a fake.
No,
we should call him the Second Kira.
The Second Kira?!
Why do you think there is a second Kira?
Please explain it to us.
First of all, there are the predicted victims.
They were used to convince
the TV station employees that he's Kira.
Those two victims were featured only
in women's magazines and on daytime talk shows.
The real Kira has no need to prove himself
with such insignificant people.
But in the Second Kira's view,
he couldn't use a criminal that
the real Kira might kill before his prediction.
Hmm... Ryuzaki.
What are the chances that there is a second Kira?
This time it's more than a seventy-percent chance.
I don't like the way he does things.
It's not like Kira.
It's not like Kira?
Kira has always avoided innocent victims,
aside from those who have tried to catch him.
If we catch one Kira,
I think we'll get a hint as to how we can catch the other.
Mr. Yagami.
May I ask your son to cooperate in this investigation?
Does that mean he's no longer a suspect?
No, I can't say that he's been cleared,
but I could use his deductive skills.
So that's what it means.
If my son wants to cooperate with you,
I have no reason to stop you.
Thank you. However,
please keep it a secret that this current Kira might be a fake.
Please make it seem as if we're chasing the same Kira.
Hey, Misa,
I gave you a Death Note,
so why don't you use it more for yourself?
I am using it for myself.
I believe in what Kira is doing.
I want to know what kind of person Kira is.
I want to meet and talk to him.
I sent those videos to the television station especially for that.
I made sure Kira would take notice.
I bet that got Kira's attention.
I'm sure of it.
That's a dangerous game.
You might be killed.
Do you realize this?
It's all right.
I'm sure that Kira is kind to those with pure hearts.
In any case,
I'm stronger because I have the eyes!
I need to find out about the Fake Kira
before anyone else at task force headquarters does.
What kind of person are you,
Fake Kira?