Light, Ryuzaki says he wants you to help with the investigation.
If you're interested, come immediately.
Okay, Dad.
I was trying to find a way to get involved in the investigation.
I never thought L himself would ask me.
Now I can get inside information about the investigation
and about the Fake Kira.
I need to find out about the Fake Kira
before anyone else at task force headquarters does.
Thank you, Yagami.
Not at all.
Ryuga, we both want to catch Kira.
Please call me Ryuzaki here.
I'm Matsui.
I'm Aihara.
And I'm Asahi.
I see.
Well, would it be all right if I'm Asahi Light?
Please do.
I will call you Light here.
Now to business.
Take a look at our current information on Kira.
I also want you to examine this video,
which was sent to the television station, but was never released to the public.
Taking any material from this room
or taking notes is forbidden.
I understand.
We shall now begin.
Light...
We're going to hide the possibility that there is a second Kira,
and ask Yagami Light to investigate with us.
B-But wouldn't that make it difficult for Light to help with the investigation?
That's right.
Why do you want him to work with us anyway?
We're only going to hide that from him
until we have him watch this tape and ask him for his impression of it.
There's something amazing about Light's deductive skills.
When he sees this,
he may even deduce that there is a second Kira.
But the only basis for a second Kira
is your explanation that the victims
of those killings had committed minor crimes
that never would have been punished by Kira.
That's not all.
The Kira that we've presumed until now
needed a face and a name to kill.
But judging from the fact that Mr. Ukita was killed as soon as he arrived at the television station
and considering how Kira practically told me that he could kill me if I just appeared on TV...
That means the Second Kira
can kill by just seeing someone's face.
So, I'll ask Light to look at
the investigative facts and the video.
If he suggests that there may be a second Kira,
then he's almost completely cleared.
What do you mean, Ryuzaki?
If he's Kira, he'll want to kill me,
the one in charge of the investigation.
At this rate, if I go along with the Second Kira's demands
and appear three days later on TV, I will die.
I don't think that Kira would miss an easy chance to kill me.
So what you're saying is that if my son doesn't deduce that there is a second Kira,
you'll continue to suspect him?
No. In that case, it will remain below a five-percent chance.
And we'll tell him that we are investigating
the possibility of a second Kira and have him assist us.
After seeing that, I trust you now believe that I am Kira.
On the given day and time...
Could the reason I feel so disgusted when I watch this
be that I'm the real Kira?
This is more than just about tarnishing Kira's reputation.
So why...
Why isn't anyone giving me
any explanation about this video?
That's a bit odd.
Well, whatever the case,
I won't say anything careless about this video.
If I leave the situation alone, L will die.
What do you think, Light?
Did you get something from it?
Damn him!
There may be more than one person who has Kira's power.
K-Kira's power?!
What do you mean, Light?!
There is a good chance that this is not the Kira we know.
Up to now, Kira's never used suspects like these for his announced killings.
Furthermore, if Kira needs a face and a name to kill,
isn't it strange that he was able
to kill the detective and the officers
who happened to rush to the television-station building?
I-It's the same.
It's exactly the same deduction that
L — I mean, Ryuzaki, made.
G-Good job, Light.
You should be cleared now.
That's right, Light.
I also think we are looking at a second Kira.
I thought so.
So you knew, Ryuga—
I mean, Ryuzaki?
Did you test me, knowing that?
I didn't test you.
It's not convincing if I'm the only one who
argues that there is a second Kira.
With you coming to the same conclusion as I did,
my theory becomes more believable.
You've been of great assistance to me, Light.
Thank you so much.
So it's decided.
We first have to stop the Second Kira.
He obviously sympathizes with Kira,
and is not very bright.
I think he'll obey the real Kira.
So if we make a fake message from the real Kira, there is a good chance that we can stop him.
Great minds think alike, Ryuzaki.
I also thought that would be the best idea.
Light,
I would like you to play the part of the real Kira.
M-Me?
Yes.
With your intellect, you should be able to do it.
At any rate, we don't have any time to waste.
Could you script a message
from Kira to air on tonight's news?
Damn him...
He planned from the beginning to bring me here to play this role.
Ryuzaki, is this all right?
I think I've portrayed Kira convincingly.
I think this is very good,
though if we don't remove the part which says,
"You're free to kill L,"
I'll die.
Well, when pretending to be Kira,
I thought that he would demand that you be killed.
It's just a bit of a joke.
You can change that to whatever you like.
I will.
Mr. Aihara,
the script is ready, I leave it to you.
All right.
And now a shocking development.
In response to the video that was sent and aired on Sakura TV a few days ago,
another person claiming to be the real Kira has appeared.
He has ordered several television stations to air his message.
The police department has authorized us to broadcast this video.
Is this the real Kira?
Is this another Kira?
First, please take a look at the video.
I am Kira.
I did it!
Kira responded!
I am the true Kira.
The Kira who was shown on Sakura TV
is a fake.
I'm being lenient to the impostor
because I know he was only trying to help me.
However, killing the innocent is against my beliefs.
If the impostor truly sympathizes with me
and wants to help my cause,
I ask that he refrain from killing aimlessly, and accept my basic principles.
If you ignore this warning and continue to be reckless...
All right! The video, the video!
What are you planning to do?
I'm going to reply to him, of course.
Ryuzaki,
it's a reply from the Second Kira.
What?
It's here!
I will bring the entire envelope there,
but I shall play a copy on the computer.
Mr. Kira, thank you for your reply.
I will do as you say.
Wow!
We did it.
"I will do as you say," huh?
I don't know if I can use him.
If he really knows Kira's feelings,
he would force L to appear on TV, and kill him.
Don't fall for something like this.
Dammit!
I want to meet you.
I don't think you have the eyes,
but I won't try to kill you.
Please don't worry.
I-Is he stupid?
He talked about the Shinigami eyes
on a tape that the whole world will see?
He just said that he didn't have "the eyes," didn't he?
What could that mean?
Who knows?
Please tell me how I can meet you
without the police finding out.
When we meet, we can confirm our identities by showing our Shinigami to each other.
Shinigami?!
He's no good.
I have to do something about this guy quickly, or else...
What is it?!
R-Ryuzaki!
Are you all right?!
Sh—
Shinigami?!
Are we supposed to accept
the existence of something like that?!
Shinigami?
Are we supposed to accept
the existence of something like that?
I-Impossible...
There's no such thing...
That's right, Ryuzaki.
Shinigami don't exist.
Kira had those criminals in prison
write something about Shinigami.
So shouldn't we assume
that this is the same Kira?
It's the same person, so they say the same things.
That can't be, Dad.
If this is the same Kira from before,
he wouldn't have replied to our video.
There is no way that the real Kira would go through the trouble of getting L to appear on TV,
only to stop trying to kill him.
Then maybe the real Kira and the Second Kira
have already established a connection,
and decided to use the word "Shinigami" to throw off the investigation.
That's not possible.
It's as Light says.
If the two Kiras were connected,
I don't think that he would stop trying to kill me.
The Second Kira is acting
independent of the first.
He wants to meet the real Kira.
That's right.
He's acting out of interest in Kira.
"Shinigami" probably refers to their killing power.
"We can confirm our identities by showing our Shinigami to each other," probably means
"We can confirm our identities
by showing each other our killing power."
That's right.
The word "Shinigami" is a word that has
some meaning between Kira and the Second Kira.
We should try to get him to tell us what it means.
So are you going to respond
and force him to be more direct?
If we don't ask him properly,
he may realize that we know nothing,
and that we're not Kira.
No, I shall leave the rest to Kira and the Second Kira.
Leave it to them?
The Second Kira has received a message from Kira
and is now content about the current situation.
He thinks that he has Kira's attention.
And he also used a word that only the two of them would understand.
This reply will air today on Sakura TV's six o'clock news.
Of course, Kira should be watching the exchange
between our made-up Kira and the Second Kira.
From Kira's viewpoint,
he'll want to prevent the Second Kira
from coming into direct contact with the police.
Maybe this time,
the real Kira will feel pressured to respond.
And if Kira doesn't?
Yes, I thought of what we could do with the Second Kira in that case.
But if he reveals more information
that Kira doesn't want the police to know
and makes Kira more nervous and furious
in order to pressure Kira into meeting him...
That would be interesting.
If Kira gets scared
and sends a reply in order to avoid that... That would be even more interesting.
In which case,
we might be able to obtain some physical evidence from Kira himself.
In the meantime,
let us pursue the Second Kira.
That's good!
Just like that!
That was great, just great, Misa.
That was wonderful!
I'm worn out...
Modeling sure uses a lot of energy!
Hey, Rem.
Hm?
Can I ask you something?
What is it?
Shinigami always have to have a Death Note.
So to give one to a human to play with,
the Shinigami needs to have two Death Notes.
That means that Ryuk, who gave the extra Death Note to Kira, was able to trick the Shinigami King, right?
Right.
Then you too?
No. The Shinigami King isn't easy to fool.
Then how?
I'm one of the few in the Shinigami Realm
who know how to kill a Shinigami.
Let's leave it at that.
Then you killed a Shinigami and gave his notebook to me.
No.
I didn't kill him.
I just happened to be around
when a Shinigami died.
So, tell me how to kill a Shinigami.
Don't tell anyone, okay?
The way to kill a Shinigami
is to make them fall in love with a human.
What a beautiful way to kill.
There once was a Shinigami who used to watch a certain girl.
His name was Gelus.
Gelus was always looking at that girl,
from the Shinigami Realm.
It's today, isn't it?
The end of her life.
She looks so healthy.
I wonder why today?
Why...
today?
I wanted to know how she was going to die too,
and decided to watch with him.
The girl was walking alone at night on a street.
And then...
Suddenly from an alley, a man appeared
and confessed his love for the girl.
I love you more than anyone else in the world!
I'm always watching you!
I want to protect you forever!
It was a man she didn't know.
She turned him down, of course.
Then...
I'll kill you...
Then kill myself!
H-Hey.
Stop!
Gelus did something that a Shinigami should never do.
Gelus saved the girl
by using his Death Note.
But that was not good.
Shinigami shorten human lives.
They exist only to take lives.
At that moment,
Gelus became something which was neither sand nor rust,
and died.
Only his Death Note remained.
Then Gelus' remaining life
was transferred to the girl whose life he saved.
Does that mean that if he hadn't fallen in love
with that girl, he wouldn't have died?
That's right.
So...
It was a Shinigami named Gelus who saved me that day.
Yes.
Gelus was in love with you.
So that notebook is yours.
Yeah...
I see.
In order to kill a Shinigami, you need him
to fall in love with a human and save that person.
What about you, Rem?
Are you in love with me?
Give it up.
You can't kill me.
Oh, you figured it out?
But now I have something I can tell Kira.
I wonder if he knows?
How to kill a Shinigami?
I asked him on TV,
"Please tell me how I can meet you,"
but he hasn't replied.
Maybe I'll go and tell him something again.
This isn't good.
I can't leave the Second Kira alone like this.
If the Second Kira makes a fatal slip-up
and is caught by the police,
there is a chance that the police will find out about the Death Note.
Welcome.
A strawberry sundae please.
Certainly.
So what should I do?
How can I contact the Second Kira without L noticing?
Thank you for waiting.
I want to meet Kira soon!
But at any rate,
what kind of a person are you, Fake Kira?
What kind of a person are you, Kira?
May 22nd: my friend and I showed off our notebooks in Aoyama.
If the Fake Kira is caught,
I'll have to obtain his notebook.
In the worst-case scenario, I may have to kill everyone there.