I understand.
I can't be your boyfriend, but I can act like I am.
Thank you...
I'll try hard to make you love me.
I'll have her meet L to find out his name
and eliminate the entire task force headquarters.
I'll kill her afterwards.
That's right.
She's the only person who knows Kira's identity.
I can't let her live for long.
So you'll just act like my boyfriend, huh?
That's good enough to start with.
So then,
could you show me your Shinigami?
I suppose it's necessary to make her trust me.
Yeah. All right.
Could you turn around?
Okay.
You can face me now.
Hi!
Wow!
He's a completely different type of Shinigami from Rem, isn't he?
I already know your name, Ryuk.
Pleased to meet you!
Yeah, pleased to meet you.
Oh yeah, Light, do you know?
How to kill a Shinigami?
You're already calling me by my first name?
Then could I call you "Knight" instead?
Because you're like my knight in shining armor!
Light is fine.
Are you planning to check all the videos of Aoyama on the 22nd by yourself?
Yes. It is very likely that Kira and the Second Kira made contact with each other there on that day.
I want to check them all.
Also, Mr. Yagami...
Yes?
I would like Mr. Mogi to keep watch over Light's activities.
Light's activities?
In the event that Light is Kira,
the Second Kira might try to contact him.
I understand.
So when does Ryuzaki sleep?
I saw him sleeping in that exact same position the other day.
No, I'm serious...
So when a Shinigami has feelings for a certain person,
and kills someone in order to extend that person's life,
the Shinigami dies, huh?
Yes.
I can't imagine there's a Shinigami who would do that.
That's right.
It doesn't seem like the kind of thing that you would do.
By the way,
from where have you been sending your tapes to the television stations?
Um... The first time was Osaka.
Then it was Tokyo.
This other time was from Nagano.
I used the Bullet Train so my location couldn't be pinpointed.
So you still have videotapes and envelopes with your friend's fingerprints on them, right?
Yeah.
Then you should dispose of everything used to create the videos.
But only after sending one last video from yet another location tomorrow.
You should say:
"I will stop trying to meet Kira."
"I'd like to thank the police for their advice."
"But I'm going to help Kira erase evil from the world."
"I'm going to cooperate with him and get his acceptance."
"I will begin by punishing criminals whom Kira hasn't punished yet."
Also...
"I plan to make this world
a better place by sharing this power
among those who are worthy."
Share the power?
It's a line to throw off the investigation.
There are already two people with this power.
It's not too far of a stretch that there may be more.
And if they believe that they'll multiply, it'll create a panic.
Can you do it?
You don't have to ask.
Just tell me to do it.
I'll do whatever you say.
Also, one more important thing.
Okay!
If you're caught by the police...
If you're arrested as a suspect,
don't say anything about us or the notebook.
There's no proof against you as long as they don't get a hold of the notebook and verify it.
Can you promise me that much?
I promise!
So then, we're officially boyfriend and girlfriend, right?
Well, I guess so.
Now for my conditions.
Go on a date with me at least once a week.
She really doesn't understand.
That's impossible.
Wh-Why?
It doesn't seem like you'll understand unless I spell it out for you.
L already suspects that I'm Kira.
What?
L's pretty amazing...
Everyone's saying that he doesn't understand or that he's stupid.
So he's actually figured out that much.
But thanks to that,
I've also been able to get close to L.
Huh? L and Kira are in contact with each other?
You're both amazing.
It's making me kind of excited.
Even if I'm Kira,
L thinks he's safe as long as he hides his name.
He came out and told me he was L in order to directly investigate me.
But he's only positive because there isn't anyone else who could possibly be Kira.
And if I play my cards right, he'll trust me
and we'll investigate together.
So all you have to do is take me to where L is, right?
It's not that simple.
It was difficult enough for me to get close to him.
Besides,
if suddenly someone close to me steps into the picture,
and the actions of Kira and the Second Kira change,
that person will be suspected of being the Second Kira.
In addition, I'll end up casting more suspicion on myself.
It would be bad if we get together,
and he makes the connection that we're intimate.
Do you understand?
Kind of...
So does that mean we can't go on dates?
We can't meet in public because
you're afraid that he'll suspect you more?
No.
We should take some time to think of a plan
so that you can see L
without letting him know you're around.
Yeah.
I'll need you in order to eliminate L.
I want to be able to keep in direct contact with you.
Thank goodness.
So...
In order to make sure that our meetings don't stand out,
I'm going to see other girls.
Huh? What do you mean by that?
You're going to date other girls?
Well, pretty much.
I don't want you to!
If I see you with another girl,
I'll kill her.
Scary...
Listen, Misa sweetie...
Sweetie, huh?
This isn't a game.
We're both risking our lives to change the world, aren't we?
Yeah, but...
I love you... more than I love the world.
What are you talking about?
I thought your feelings towards me were those of just a Kira admirer.
It's only the first time we've met.
Haven't you ever experienced love at first sight?
Never.
Well, yes, I wanted to meet Kira
out of gratitude and approval, not out of love.
But when I first laid eyes on you, I...
What's with this girl?
You're popular as always.
Then if you love me, you'll obey me.
You told me before that you didn't mind being used
and just earlier, you insisted that you'd do as I say, right?
But I won't allow you to date other girls.
Those are two very different things.
I have both notebooks.
If you won't obey, I'll kill you.
I won't let you do that,
Yagami Light.
If you try to kill her,
I'll write your name in my notebook,
and kill you.
I can see her lifespan.
If she dies before that date,
I'll assume that you killed her.
If you used your notebook to save her,
wouldn't you die?
That's right! Then you'll die!
That's true.
But I couldn't care less.
Is this Shinigami serious?
Then that means, from now on...
Light?
What is it, Mom?
It's already 11:30.
It's not nice to have a girl stay out so late.
Yeah, you're right.
We lost track of time.
Sorry, Mrs. Yagami.
I'm sorry for staying so late.
Light, see you later.
Yeah.
Light, walk her to the station.
It won't be good to walk outside with her now.
Oh!
It's all right!
Good night!
She's cute.
Oh yeah. I was a bit worried at first, but she sure is cute.
I like her!
That Shinigami is going to kill me if I kill the girl?
Does that mean I have to deal with her until she dies?
Not only that,
but I'm forced to protect her
so she doesn't get caught by the police.
Thanks to you, Light really became my knight.
So it seems.
But don't kill him for real, okay?
In order to kill a Shinigami,
that Shinigami has to use a Death Note
to save the life of a human
with whom it has fallen in love.
I can't kill Rem
by using a Death Note to control someone to attack Misa.
If Misa's put in danger,
I'll be suspected first and be killed.
Right now, she's an even bigger nuisance than L is.
Sh-She...
She does something visible like this?
What'll happen if it's discovered that I met with someone like this?
Damn! She's in the way no matter you slice it.
What should I do?
No, besides that,
I should think of a way to use Misa's eyes to kill L.
If I just eliminate L...
Good morning, Light!
Good morning.
Mom, Sayu,
could you keep Misa a secret from Dad?
All right.
I also want you to keep your lips sealed, not just from Dad,
but from everyone.
She's actually an up-and-coming model,
so it would be problematic if people found out about us.
What? Really?!
No wonder I thought she was cute!
Just what I'd expect for your girlfriend!
I'll keep it a secret... for 5,000 yen.
Silly...
On page 246...
Misa's final message will arrive today.
Instead of going to the television station,
it should be routed to task force headquarters.
I have to go to headquarters in order to see L's reaction.
Yagami... Yagami...
You told me that you'd go out with me, right?
Yeah, I did.
That's why I'm sitting next to you at this lecture.
Okay.
But you don't seem happy at all.
You've been completely inattentive to me.
That's not true at all.
I was just thinking about how we're going to be the talk of the town.
To think that I'm going out with Takada, the famous Miss To-oh University...
It's obvious, you truly are beautiful.
Please don't think about such things.
I don't like being called Miss Whatever.
Yeah. You're right.
What's with this woman?
She actually likes it.
Let's just take things at our own pace, Takada.
Okay.
Good evening.
Light,
good timing.
A video message from the Second Kira just arrived.
Another one?
That's fast.
Yes.
I think this is the last one.
Well, take a look at this.
I will not contact Kira.
I'd like to thank the police for their advice.
But I'm going to help Kira erase evil from the world,
and gain his approval.
I will begin by punishing criminals whom Kira hasn't punished yet.
Also, I will share this power among those who are worthy
and make this world a better place.
Watching this
makes me suspect that Kira and the Second Kira have joined forces.
How so?
Didn't you sense it?
I thought you would get the same impression.
First of all, his attitude towards meeting Kira completely changed.
Also, he now says that he wants to punish criminals
whom Kira didn't punish, in order to gain his approval.
Why didn't he do this before?
He probably never thought that far,
so it's likely that he's working with Kira and was told to say that.
He was also ordered to hide the fact
that they're working together.
I see.
That probably means that Kira isn't thinking about his actions very much.
Indeed.
Did Kira encounter something he couldn't overcome?
He probably was trying to scare us
by making it obvious that he'd recruited the Second Kira.
Their union is really threatening.
But...
this lessens the suspicion I had of Light.
What do you mean, Ryuzaki?
If Light were Kira,
then he wouldn't have sent in a video like this.
He would've tried to threaten me, L, into appearing on television again.
Maintaining the lie that they aren't working together,
he would've placed all the responsibility on the Second Kira.
This is what he'd have him say:
"I stopped because Kira told me to,
but I don't think that warning would come from the real Kira."
"Kira would be happy if L died."
"There's no way he'd stop me."
Ryuzaki...
Yes?
If I were Kira,
I would never do that.
Why?
If you really are L,
then I know your character.
No matter how you were threatened,
you wouldn't be caught dead appearing on TV.
You wouldn't want to die in someone else's place.
You'd think of some way to escape.
You figured it out.
Light,
even hypothetically,
stop saying, "If I were Kira...".
I don't like hearing it.
Oh, sorry, Dad.
But I want to tell Ryuzaki what I think.
I have to pose the scenario hypothetically
in order to solve this case quickly and to clear my name.
Besides, I can talk in that way
precisely because I'm not Kira.
You're right.
You aren't Kira.
No, it would be a problem if you were Kira.
Because you're...
my first friend ever.
Yeah. You're a friend I have much in common with.
Thank you.
I've been lonely since you've been taking breaks from school.
I'd like to play tennis with you again.
Yes. By all means.
Friends?
Friends, huh?
Aren't you glad, Light?
That damned Ryuzaki...
He immediately noticed the connection between Kira and the Second Kira.
I've got to eliminate him quickly.
Oh really?
This makes it all the more dangerous for me to see Misa.
Light!
I just couldn't wait two weeks!
I was just about to go to your house!
This is the first time I've really wanted to hit a woman.
I-I just wanted to see you so badly...
Well...
Come over to my house.
Okay!
Another girl?
Welcome, Misa!
I saw you in a whole bunch of magazines!
Welcome.
Sorry for the intrusion.
Mom, please get some tea.
Rem.
You're Misa's ally, aren't you?
Yeah.
I've watched her many times from the Shinigami Realm.
I've developed a bit of affection for her.
Affection, even though you're a Shinigami?
You don't seem to like that
I said I'd kill you if you tried to kill her.
Does this mean that if Misa's happy,
you'll feel fine?
Well, you could say that.
I just can't bear to see her unhappy.
Misa is...
madly in love with me.
Light...
Misa.
Yes?
Would seeing me happy
make you happy?
Yes.
Then could you ask Rem
to kill L?
Rem wants you to be happy.
If L catches one of us,
we'll both be unhappy.
A Shinigami can't tell a person's name to someone who has a notebook,
but there's no restriction against Rem killing anyone.
Yeah.
If you kill L,
I think I'll be able to love Misa more and I would be grateful to you.
Above all, it'll make us both happy.
Rem...
I want Light to love me.
Light and I will be grateful.
That would be my happiness.
Fine.
Fine, Yagami Light.
I despise you.
Even if this ends up lengthening your lifespan,
I won't die.
I'll kill L for you.
L is a human who means nothing to me.
All right!
Thank you, Rem!
That's my Rem!
L will die...
this easily?
That's right.
Since Ryuga's revealed that he's L, I must kill him.
This is all a wager now.
Tomorrow will be L's—
no,
Ryuzaki and Ryuga's date of death!