Because you're...
my first friend ever.
Misa.
Yes?
Then could you ask Rem
to kill L?
Rem...
I want Light to love me.
That would be my happiness.
Fine.
I'll kill L for you.
L will die...
this easily?
So when should I kill him?
If you take me to wherever he is, I can kill him immediately.
It should be done as soon as possible.
Tomorrow if you can.
But it's still too soon to make a decision now.
I'll give you an answer after I think
of a way to kill him tonight.
All right.
Listen, no matter what, don't kill him until I give the order.
No matter what!
All right.
I promise.
Only about L, though.
Misa, give me your cell phone number.
It's about time!
Give me yours, too!
No, I can't give you mine.
Why not?! We're lovers!
I told you, I'm under surveillance by the police.
The police these days can listen in on specific phone conversations.
In that case, here!
I'll give you one of my own cell phones.
I ended up with three after using them for different things.
That's a good idea.
Using your phone would probably be all right.
All right!
I'll give you a love call every day and text you all the time!
No, I'll keep it off.
I'll be the only one making calls,
and you'll be on a need-to-know basis.
What? No way...
When are you going to call?
Probably tomorrow.
I'll call even if I'm not going to execute L.
What? Tomorrow?
It doesn't sound like something a lover would call about,
but we can talk about love afterwards.
Well, Misa,
go home for today.
What? Why?
It's only seven o'clock.
The time for lovers has just begun, hasn't it?
We can go get dinner, look at the night sky,
and after that, the main event!
Misa.
Okay?
Go home for today.
Okay...
Also, when you're talking outside with Rem,
whisper, and make sure that no one's around.
That's what Ryuk and I do.
All right...
Sorry for the intrusion...
Misa, come again tomorrow!
That kiss was so sudden, it surprised me.
I need to keep Misa madly in love with me.
Oh?
Besides that, I need to decide if I should kill L tomorrow.
L hasn't made himself public yet,
so if Ryuga dies, I have to prepare
for people to be more suspicious of me.
I see.
I thought you were hesitating
because he said that you were his friend.
His friend?
I was just giving him what he wanted.
From the beginning, I've said that if it's friendship he wants,
then I'll give it.
Ryuga is Yagami Light's superficial friend.
But L is Kira's enemy.
That's right.
L is my enemy.
Since Ryuga's revealed that he's L, I must kill him.
If I kill L with an accident,
there won't be many who would suspect that I'm Kira.
Even if someone does suspect, there's no proof.
I can only speculate what will be done after L dies.
This is all a wager now.
Tomorrow will be L's—
no, Ryuzaki Ryuga's date of death.
Hair.
Snack crumbs.
Mr. Yagami.
If I die within the next few days, your son is Kira.
Another hair.
What did you just say?!
Yeah. What are you talking about?!
I'll make sure that you have ready access to Watari,
I'm counting on you.
Ryuzaki!
You said he was almost entirely cleared, but I want the truth.
How likely is it that he's Kira?!
Even I don't know how I truly feel.
This has never happened before.
If Kira and the Second Kira are working together,
I'm in big trouble.
So I might not be analyzing the situation calmly.
I might be considering him a suspect just because there's nobody else.
Despite that,
if I'm killed now,
please assume that your son is Kira.
I have no choice but to make a sneak attack.
This is all a wager now.
That's not true.
I just know how to swim with the tide.
What's wrong?
Oh, Yagami!
Hello.
Takada, I want to talk to him for a bit.
Could we continue this later?
Oh, yes...
Was that okay?
More importantly, didn't you say that you were afraid to appear in front of people?
Are you all right out here?
I realized that as long as you're not Kira, it's okay.
You're the only one on the outside who knows I'm L,
so I've told everyone at headquarters that if I die in the next few days
to assume that you're Kira.
Damn him...
You told me that you've been lonely because I've been taking breaks from school,
so I came out for a change of pace.
As long as I don't die, college is a fun place.
Yeah. When you're not here,
it's so boring because there's no one who can match my level of conversation.
So that explains why you're with the "brilliant" Takada.
Well, something like that.
Is it really all right to kill him today?
No... As soon as I decided I should kill him,
he suddenly appears to distract me
from my decision to prevent me from killing him.
I'm playing into his hands.
Shall we have some cake in the cafeteria?
Sure. My next lecture was canceled.
That's good.
I wonder if they have shortcake?
Well... who knows.
Light!
There you are!
I came because I had a photo shoot nearby!
Misa! You idiot...
Is he a friend of yours?
He's so unique and cool.
No... I've won!
Misa can see Ryuga's real name!
I'm Light's girlfriend, Amane Misa. Pleased to meet you.
I'm Ryuga Hideki.
Huh? Ryuga Hideki?
Yeah, he has the same first name and last name as that idol.
Isn't that funny?
But it's different from the name I'm seeing...
Ryuga,
coming out this time has backfired on you!
Why's he chuckling?
Has he noticed?
But if he's guessed that she's the Second Kira,
there's no way he would be chuckling...
Yagami...
I'm envious.
I've been a huge fan of yours
since the August issue of "Eighteen."
Really?! I'm so happy!
Hey, that girl is Misa-Misa, isn't she?!
You're right!
It is Misa-Misa!
Misa-Misa?!
For real?!
Figures I'd be discovered with all these young people around.
I see you every month.
Keep up the good work.
Yeah. Thank you.
I'll do my best!
What's going on?
Hey! Who touched my butt?!
How disgraceful!
I can't forgive anyone who would take advantage of this situation.
I'll find the culprit.
Ryuga! You're so funny!
I wanna cop a feel, too.
As if!
At any rate, I want to ask Misa
what L's name is as soon as possible,
but these people are in the way.
Misa!
It's time!
Are you planning to be late again?!
Oh, sorry, Yoshi.
Let's go!
Oh, yeah.
That's good.
Once Misa's out of here,
I just have to give her a call and ask her for L's name.
See you after work, Light!
Now then, shall we get going, Yagami?
Yeah.
Sorry, could you go on ahead?
I need to use the restroom.
I see. Well then...
It's over.
It's been fun, L.
I'm glad that I could discover your name and kill you myself.
Yes?
Hello?
What do you mean, "Hello"?
Oh, someone must have dropped their cell phone during all that commotion earlier.
Bastard...
He must have...
Hello?
Yeah. That's Misa's cell phone,
so I'll return it to her.
I see.
I understand.
Ryuga...
You probably think you've won,
but Misa has another phone.
If I call that one...
Oh...
This time it's my cell phone.
Yes?
Yes. I see.
We did it.
I understand.
This may be good news and bad news to you,
but Amane Misa has just been taken into custody under suspicion of being the Second Kira.
When in the world did he find out about Misa?!
I never thought he'd catch her this quickly.
When the Second Kira sent
the video tapes from Amane's room,
they left a great deal of evidence, such as hairs and clothing fibers,
stuck to the masking tape used to seal the envelopes.
There will probably be a riot if we charge her
with being the Second Kira, so we're telling the public
that she's voluntarily coming with us
because her manager is suspected of drug possession.
The truth will probably never go public.
I was careless.
That video...
I should've destroyed all the evidence.
In the end, Ryuga chose to protect himself by being with me instead of hiding.
He confronted the heart of the matter.
This wager is my...
My...
No!
Not yet...
The challenge is just beginning, L.
Watari, has she said anything?
No, nothing yet.
Get me a visual of her.
Are you sure?
Yes, quickly.
R-Ryuzaki!
What's the meaning of this?!
I've apprehended her as the Second Kira.
This, at the very least, is necessary.
Indeed, there was enough evidence in Amane's room
to mark her as the Second Kira, but...
Yes. There's no mistake.
Now all we have to do
is make her tell us whether she knows Kira, and if so, whether she knows who he is,
and how she kills.
Watari, take the proper precautions, but do whatever needs to be done
to get her to confess.
Yes.
Also, Mr. Yagami,
I'm probably going to bring in Light to testify, as the prime suspect.
Please be prepared.
Ryuzaki, Amane's talking.
Give me visuals and sound! Quickly!
Finally after three days, huh?!
I can't take it anymore...
Kill me.
Hurry up and kill me!
I guess it was too much for a young girl.
She must be at her limit.
Amane Misa, can you hear me?
I can hear you.
Please kill me now...
Is this because you admit to being the Second Kira?
No! I don't know anything about the Second Kira.
I can't take this anymore...
I'd rather die...
Now, hurry! Kill me!
You should be able to kill me immediately, right?!
Misa, do you mean...
Yes, kill me.
You want me to kill you?
Yes... Kill me...
I can't take it anymore...
Kill me...
If I kill you, I'll kill Yagami Light.
This is all his...
No!
No... Kill me!
Misa, you want so badly... to die for him?
That's enough!
If you won't kill me...!
This isn't good!
Watari, don't let her bite her tongue!
Could it be that these are just actions controlled by Kira before death?
Oh, Rem.
What's the matter?
Yagami Light,
I offered to help Misa escape, but she refused.
She probably thought it would get you in trouble,
since the police think that she has special powers.
And when she was at her wit's end,
she started to ask me to kill her.
This is all because she wants you to love her.
No matter how much she asked, I couldn't kill her.
I couldn't bear watching her.
There was only one way to save her from that suffering.
Forfeiting ownership of the Death Note.
That's right.
If she forfeits ownership of the Death Note,
all memories related to the Death Note will disappear.
All memories of murders she committed with her notebook,
along with the fact that you are Kira, will disappear.
Misa will not reveal your secret.
Also, Misa will no longer be able to see Ryuk or me.
Misa...
You will forget everything about Shinigami.
It's all right.
The human you love is Yagami Light.
Those emotions will remain.
So, Misa, forfeit ownership of the notebook
and leave everything to Yagami Light.
Misa no longer owns the Death Note.
You did well, Rem.
I was beginning to think that was the only way.
If her memories of the Death Note are erased,
then it's not impossible to release Misa.
Yagami Light, I knew this was the method you would have desired the most,
and that's why I proposed it to Misa.
If you don't save Misa,
I'll kill you.
I understand, Rem.
I think I have a good idea of what L's next move is.
I have an idea.
This is good-bye, Ryuk.
What?
Yeah,
I know I probably look pretty bad in here.
But this useless pride...
I'll just have to...
get rid of it.