I relinquish ownership of this notebook.
Take care of Misa.
Mister Stalker...
Hey, Mister Stalker, where are you?
Let's stop playing this game...
Stalker? What does this mean?
Her attitude completely changed all of a sudden.
Just as I expected.
As long as I have Ryuk's notebook, even if I throw away Rem's notebook,
my memory of Rem doesn't disappear.
But, Rem,
all of this is happening to me because you brought
another notebook to the Human World.
You really sure about this, Light?
Yeah.
I never thought that the notebook I gave you
would end up buried in the ground.
Listen, Ryuk,
I'm just hiding it in the ground.
I won't get rid of it
until the next time I say, "Get rid of it."
When I say it, regardless of the context it's in,
it means, "I want to get rid of the notebook."
Got it.
Mister Stalker, this is illegal. Stop it.
Please, Mister Stalker!
She's been acting like this ever since
she passed out and regained consciousness.
Honestly. Does she think she can play dumb like this?
Okay, I know.
Could you at least take off my blindfold?
I really want to see what you look like!
Mr. Matsuda, give Mr. Mogi a call.
Huh?
Oh...
Here.
Mr. Mogi, when you apprehended Amane Misa,
you told her that we suspect she's the Second Kira, didn't you?
Yes. I did as you told me.
I covered her eyes and mouth from behind and told her,
"You're going to come with me
on suspicion of being the Second Kira."
She didn't seem to be struggling even when I put handcuffs and the eye mask on her.
She seemed to have given up.
I'll give you an autograph or shake your hand.
That's it!
I'll give you a kiss on the cheek!
Please! I won't run away!
We'd made so much progress with her.
Why is she suddenly talking about a stalker?
Amane Misa.
What, Mister Stalker?
Are you planning to release me?
You were quiet before you fell asleep.
You asked us to kill you.
Are you trying to give us trouble now?
What are you talking about?
You're the one who knocked me out and brought me here, aren't you?
So what?
Do you want to "investigate me" or something like that?
Do you know why I'm detaining you here?
Why? Because I'm an idol?
You're the first stalker who's ever gone this far.
Hey! Amane, quit wasting our time!
I'm afraid!
What is this?
I can't stand it anymore!
Let me go! Let me go!
Oh yeah...
I have to go to the restroom again.
I need to go to the restroom!
It's been only four minutes since you last went.
Please hold it in.
What's with that?!
That's the only way you'll untie me!
You can watch me pee again.
Isn't it fun? You pervert!
I'm... a pervert?
Amane, let's seriously talk more about what happened before you went to sleep.
Do you know Yagami Light?
Why did you approach him?
Huh? There's no way I wouldn't know my own boyfriend...
She was so tight-lipped about it earlier,
but now she nonchalantly says that he's her boyfriend?
What's going on?
It's from Light.
Turn off the visuals and sound.
Yes.
Yes... Yes, I understand.
We're in the K., room 2801.
My son's coming here?
Ryuzaki, I told you over the phone,
but I think I may be Kira.
Th-That's impossible!
What are you talking about, Light?!
What's wrong?!
Tell me!
There's no proof that Yagami Light is Kira,
but for him to say that he may be Kira?
It's an act.
It's not that you may be Kira, but that you are Kira.
What in the world are you trying to do?
Dad, if Ryuzaki is L,
I wouldn't be exaggerating if I said that he's the world's best detective.
L has decided that I am Kira.
Therefore, I must be Kira.
Wh-What are you talking about, Light?!
I'm the one whom Raye Penber, the FBI agent, was investigating in Japan when he died.
I'm the one who went to Aoyama on May 22nd.
Also, I'm the first person
whom the alleged Second Kira, Misa,
approached in the Kanto region.
It's all me.
If I were in L's shoes, even I would say that I'm Kira.
See... I may be Kira.
I just might not know it.
Light...
I see.
You aren't conscious of it, huh?
I'm not sure of anything anymore...
Even if I have no memory,
there could be another me who's killing people as I sleep.
That's impossible.
What do you mean, Ryuzaki?
Actually, there was a time when I put surveillance cameras
in your room for five consecutive days.
Cameras?
Yes. You slept normally at night.
Broadcasted criminals whom you didn't know about were dying.
But I decided that, even if you were Kira,
you wouldn't give yourself away on camera.
I won't give myself away, huh?
That may be true.
Well, up to a certain point,
I believe that some major criminals should die.
I think that anyone who has
such thoughts could become Kira.
Light! I believe the same thing!
I've thought it would be better if quite a few people were dead.
But, even so, we can't really kill people, right?
Besides, criminals were dying
while you had no knowledge of them.
The surveillance cameras proved that!
N-No...
We were short of investigators then
and we only watched him when he was at home.
It's also not as if we were watching him
every hour during those five days.
There may have been a way for him
to kill while he wasn't at home.
Did you purposefully come out
in order for this to happen, Yagami Light?
But if we restrain you for a long period like Amane,
and criminals who appear
before the public still continue to die,
Yagami Light is no longer Kira at that point?
Is this what you're trying to do?
I kind of dislike the direction
this conversation is heading in, but...
Fine.
Fully restrain Yagami Light and confine him in a cell.
Wh-What are you...?!
Y-You're going to detain Light?
We should do this now.
You won't be able to go anywhere where my eyes can't see you.
Th-This is crazy!
There's no way that my son is Kira!
My son wouldn't...
It's fine, Dad.
Light...
I can't help you catch Kira
if I keep worrying that I may be your man.
In exchange,
until you decide that I'm not Kira or you agree that I'm not Kira,
don't let me free no matter what I say
or whatever condition I'm in.
Understood.
Mr. Yagami, could you come up with an excuse
for Light's absence for your family?
No, please do it now.
I-I'm not too sure I can on such short notice...
But why does my son have to be thrown into a prison?!
You're being stubborn, Dad.
I can't be fully satisfied with myself unless I do this.
Are you serious, Light?
Yeah. By taking away my freedom,
I'll be able to defeat the fear of Kira that lies within me.
Mr. Aizawa, please take care of this.
As you wish.
All that's left is to get rid the notebook.
Does this mean I won't be able to eat apples again?
Ryuzaki...
Please remove me from the investigation.
Chief!
We're holding my son as a suspect in this case...
I shouldn't be here.
Regardless of whether we should investigate him,
when we were talking about confining him,
I let my personal feelings get in the way.
That's true.
Personal feelings shouldn't be involved.
A-And if my son really is Kira...
I don't know what kind of actions I may take.
Yes. I can imagine that you
p would kill your son and then kill yourself.
I agree that we shouldn't have you here.
Ryuzaki!
Could you confine me as well?
I'm calm now,
but I don't know what I'll do when my feelings for my son...
I thought you might say something like that,
so I had Watari make arrangements.
However, even though I'm confining you,
please keep your cell phone on as usual.
Maintain regular contact with your family
and people from the outside.
We won't tell Light about this.
If Light calls you,
talk to him as if you're right here, inside headquarters.
Also, we will keep you posted
on the details of the investigation.
Is that okay?
I am indebted to you, Ryuzaki.
Mister Stalker, I want to take a bath.
You know where I live, don't you?
Bring me a change of clothes...
The situation has gotten even more bizarre.
I feel so sorry for the Chief.
Ryuzaki, what's happening?
Have any new criminals been broadcast
whom Kira would target in the last couple of days?
And if so, have they been killed by Kira?
Quite a few criminals have been broadcast,
but since you've been detained, none of them have been killed.
No one's been killed? Really?
Yes.
I see.
Maybe I really am Kira.
Oh man, I wanna eat an apple...
What's going on?
I thought that the murders would continue
even with Yagami Light confined,
but in reality, they completely stopped.
It seemed like Yagami Light wanted to be confined,
but this would mean that Yagami Light is Kira.
Now the question is whether he was conscious of being Kira.
If he is Kira,
does he think he can get away with saying
that he wasn't conscious of what he was doing?
It's not like Yagami Light.
No, it's not like Kira.
I can't take it, Light.
If I don't eat an apple soon...
Anyway, I just have to get through it...
even if there's nothing to do.
Mister Stalker, your video won't sell if I'm just sitting.
Mr. Yagami looks even worse than Light or Misa.
Of course.
It's been five days since Light's been imprisoned.
During that time, not a single criminal who's been broadcast has died.
In times like this, I suppose it's harder
for the parents than the suspects themselves.
Especially since now, it's almost definite that Light is Kira.
Mr. Yagami.
What is it?
Good news?!
Bad news?!
Uh, no...
Try not to work yourself up too much.
You won't accomplish anything by mulling over things.
The outcome will remain the same.
Perhaps you should rest...
in a more comfortable place.
Out of the question!
There's no place anywhere
that would be relaxing in this situation!
In the state I'm in now, this is the best place for me.
No matter what the result,
I will leave with my son!
I understand.
Light, it's only been one week, but you're looking worn out.
Are you all right?
Now that I've come this far,
I think it's about time.
Yeah, I know I probably look pretty bad in here.
But this useless pride...
I'll just have to...
get rid of it.
All right.
Got it.
See you later.
What am I doing here?
Ryuzaki...
I know I agreed to be detained and chose to do this.
But now I just clearly realized
that doing this is meaningless!
It's because I'm not Kira!
Get me out of here quickly!
I can't do that.
We promised that no matter what you said,
I wouldn't let you out until we decided on whether or not you were Kira.
There was something wrong with me then!
Do you really think that Kira would be able to operate
without being conscious of it?
I don't remember committing Kira's crimes, so I'm not him!
I also don't believe that Kira has been acting
without self-awareness all this time.
But if you are him, then everything adds up.
As soon as you were detained, murders by Kira stopped.
All right, Ryuzaki, hear me out!
I am not lying...
I'm not Kira!
I can only think that I've been framed!
What's wrong with you, Yagami Light?
What you're saying doesn't make sense.
But for some reason, it feels like it's the truth.
Hurry and get me out of here.
We're wasting time!
No. I can't let you out.
Damn... How did this happen?
What's going on?
This isn't like Light.
He's taking back what he said earlier.
It makes no sense.
We can't release him now that the murders have stopped.
Even I know that.
Well, whatever anyone says,
can't we just decide that Yagami Light is Kira,
and that the case is closed?
What's going on?
Two weeks worth of criminals
were murdered all at once yesterday!
Yeah.
Kira is back.
Have you told the Chief?
No, not yet.
Chief, Kira has started killing again!
What?!
Kira was just resting.
He's started punishing criminals again.
I-Is that true, Matsuda?!
Th-Then my son...
I shouldn't be happy that the murders have occurred,
but now, suspicion of my son will be—
No, knowing Ryuzaki, he's not completely cleared just yet.
Well then...
He's in the grey.
Did you hear that, Chief?!
Yeah, he was pretty much guilty up to now.
Thank goodness.
It's probably a grey that's one shade closer to being clear.
Then I'll tell Light, too.
Matsuda!
I mean, Mr. Matsuda.
Please stop.
Matsuda?
Don't tell Light.
Wh-Why not?
Light.
What is it, Ryuzaki?
It's already been over two weeks. There haven't been any new killings.
Won't you just give up and confess that you're Kira?
Don't play dumb, Ryuzaki.
You're wrong.
I can understand how you deduced
from the investigation that I'm Kira. But it's a trap.
I'm not Kira!
Zoom in or something and look at my eyes!
Are these the eyes of someone who's lying?
Amane, you're really sure that you don't know who Kira is, aren't you?
Huh? That again?
That's what I want to know!
Kira is a champion of justice who punished the burglar who killed my parents.
I can't make sense of anything that's happening.
Th-That's crazy!
Wait, Dad!
If we die here,
we'll never find out the truth!
You trust L more than you trust me?
Dad!