Use it like that to kill the criminals who are broadcast.
Then you can use the notebook however you want.
Those are the conditions.
If everything goes according to Yagami Light's plans,
this is sure to save Misa.
This is a good deal for both of us, isn't it?
Or I guess as you would say, it's good business.
Mr. Yagami, are you all right?
There's no reason for you to stay there like that.
It's been over a month since
Kira started to kill criminals again.
I am sure that my son isn't Kira.
Now, all that's left is for you to be sure.
I get out when my son does.
The Chief sure is stubborn.
Light, are you all right?
Yeah. I'm all right.
But, Ryuzaki, criminals
have stopped dying since I've been confined.
I think it's highly likely that Kira
is someone who knows about my situation.
The logical conclusio—
No, criminals are not dying because you are Kira.
No! I'm not Kira.
How many times must I say it?
Kira should know that the killings have begun again.
It doesn't seem like he knows.
This is cruel, Ryuzaki.
You still haven't told Light
that criminals are being killed again.
Amane.
Yes?
I know you're tired, but are you all right?
Are you stupid?
There'd be something wrong with me if I were all right after all this time.
Yes, that's true.
Let me go...
I want to see Light.
See Light...
It seems like all three of them are at their limit.
Ryuzaki, why are you still confining Light?
Let him go already!
If you do, the Chief will come out too.
Criminals are still being killed even though
Misa and Light aren't able to obtain any information.
We know at least that much.
No.
All we know is that Amane harbors
an unnaturally strong love for Yagami Light.
Ryuzaki, sorry, but I think that you're doing this
because you don't want to admit that you were wrong about Light.
I thought you might think that.
As Light said,
Kira killed Lind L. Tailor and the FBI agents.
If Kira could kill under surveillance and without obtaining information,
then he wouldn't have needed to kill Tailor and the FBI agents!
No matter how hard we investigate, he can't be traced.
Kira doesn't kill without a reason.
You even said so yourself.
I see.
If he could kill in these circumstances,
he shouldn't have had a problem with leaving those FBI agents alone.
It's already been fifty days.
There's no reason to be doing this.
Besides that, we should be thinking of ways to catch the real Kira.
I understand.
Mr. Yagami.
What is it?
Will you return to task force headquarters?
I want you to hear my hypothesis on what's happening.
But first, I want to talk to you as Light's father.
All right.
I never thought that you would be an old man, Mister Stalker.
I'm not a stalker.
I'm a detective.
A detective?!
I remember now!
I was told that I was being arrested for being the Second Kira or something.
That was for real?
It couldn't be.
There's no way the police
would tie me up in such a fetish-like way.
Anyways, isn't it strange that my hands and feet
are restrained even though you're going to let me go?
Be quiet.
Light!
Misa?
I was dying to see you!
Dad, what's going on?
Huh? Dad?
Oh, no! I called your dad a stalker and other rude things like that...
Pleased to meet you. My name is Amane Misa.
I'm currently going out with Light...
I leave it to you, Chief.
What's wrong?
Hurry up and get in.
We're finally cleared and are free to go, right?
No.
You two are now
being taken to your execution.
I volunteered to escort you to the execution site,
secretly built in an underground facility.
Our execution?
What?!
What are you talking about, Dad?
This is a joke, isn't it?
L has decided that Yagami Light is Kira
and Amane Misa is the Second Kira.
He decided that if you were executed,
the killings would stop.
Haven't the killings stopped?
No, they're still continuing.
Continuing?
That's not what he told me...
L was trying to get a confession out of you.
That's not the problem here.
L's suggestion that the killings
would stop if you two were eliminated
was immediately accepted by all the top officials
of the UN and the Japanese government.
Kira will be erased,
hidden from the public.
Th-That's crazy.
Wait, Dad, I'm not Kira!
That's right.
What are you thinking?!
He's your own son!
This is not my decision.
It's L's.
He has solved many difficult cases
in the past and has a perfect track record.
Dad...
You trust L more than you trust me?
L says that if the killings don't stop,
then he'll take responsibility and end his own life.
L, what are you thinking?
I understand that all of the physical evidence
points to this conclusion.
But this is wrong!
Why did L come to this conclusion?
Something's strange.
This isn't like L at all.
L's always used hard evidence in all of his cases.
Is he planning to end it like this?!
We're almost there.
Where are we?
Why did you bring us out to the middle of nowhere?
What are you going to do?
Are you going to let us go?
Nobody will see us here.
I decided to bring you here instead of the execution site.
Light,
I'm going to kill you here and then kill myself.
Wh-What are you talking about, Dad?!
Stop it already! You're crazy!
Th-That's crazy!
Kill your child and then yourself?
If you want to die, then why don't you just die by yourself?!
If you do this, then you'll be no different from Kira!
No, I'm different from Kira.
I have a responsibility as a parent and as the Detective Superintendent!
Dad, Misa's right!
If we die here, we'll never find out the truth!
It would be better if we ran away!
It's too late, Light.
Either way, you'll be executed.
At least this way, it'll be by my own hand.
Stop, Dad!
I'm not Kira!
If I die here, we all fall into Kira's trap!
Don't you see?!
Amane, I'm going to die here with my son.
I have no reason to kill you.
The police will probably find this car soon.
You'll be executed at the original site.
Light...
From one murderer to another, I'll see you in hell!
Dad!
Stop!
Light...
From one murderer to another, I'll see you in hell!
Dad!
A blank?
Thank goodness...
What are you doing, Dad?
Forgive me, you two.
This was the only way to free you from confinement.
But please understand...
I did this because I believe that you aren't Kira.
Were you watching, Ryuzaki?
I did as you said,
and as you can see, I'm still alive.
Yes, it was a convincing performance.
If Amane were the Second Kira,
who can kill just by knowing a person's face,
then she would have killed you before you fired.
Also, if Light were Kira,
the Kira I know would even kill his parents if he was in trouble.
In Light's case, I cannot deny the possibility that
he may have discovered it was all an act halfway through.
But as I promised, I will end their confinement.
Also as promised,
even though she insists
that those tapes were just occult videos,
I have physical evidence and a confession
that she sent the Kira videos.
So Amane Misa will remain under surveillance until Kira is caught and his case is resolved.
What's with that?
Do you still suspect me?
Well, you get to return to your everyday life.
If you're not guilty,
you can think of the surveillance as police protection.
I see.
Since I'm not the Second Kira,
I should think of it like I have some bodyguards.
Also, Light, as promised...
I will arrange things so that
you and I will be together 24 hours a day,
working on the investigation.
All right, Ryuzaki.
Let's catch Kira together.
Yes. I'm looking forward to working with you.
Is this really necessary, Ryuzaki?
I'm not doing this because I want to.
Huh? Is this what you meant by
being together with him 24 hours a day?
It's kinda gross for two men to be like that.
Ryuzaki, is that what you're into?
I told you, I'm not doing this because I want to.
But Light belongs to me...
If you're together with him 24 hours a day, then when will I get to go on dates with him?
Dates will be with the three of us.
Huh? Are you telling me we have to kiss in front of you?
I'm not telling you to do anything.
But I will be watching.
What's with that?
You really are a pervert, aren't you?
Light, please silence Misa.
Misa, don't be selfish.
You were definitely the one who sent the tapes.
Just be grateful that you're allowed as much freedom as this.
Huh? What are you talking about?
I'm your girlfriend, right?
Don't you trust your own lover?
G-Girlfriend?
You said you fell in love with me at first sight,
and now you're always forcing yourself on me.
S-So then you took advantage of that fact and kissed me?
You jerk!
About this "love at first sight" thing...
It happened in Aoyama on May 22nd, didn't it, Misa?
Yes.
Why did you go to Aoyama on that day?
What did you wear?
I told you, I just happened to go there. How many times have I told you?
I don't really remember how I felt that day or what I wore!
Is it so wrong for me to be hanging out
in Aoyama without a reason?
So when you came back from Aoyama,
you were in love with Light and knew his name.
Yes.
You don't even know how you knew his name.
Yes. That's right.
Then, how would you feel if Light were Kira?
Huh? If Light were Kira?
That's right.
That would be wonderful!
I've always been grateful to Kira
for punishing the man who murdered my parents.
If Light were Kira, I'd love him more,
though I love him so much already!
We're talking about Kira, here.
You'd love him even more?
Don't you feel afraid at all?
That's supposing if Light is Kira, right?
He's not scary at all.
I'm one of those people who accept Kira.
I'd think of ways I could help him.
You'd probably get in his way rather than help him.
According to this, there's no mistake
that you're the Second Kira.
But it's so clear-cut that I don't want to believe it.
Don't believe it, because I'm not Kira!
Anyway, you'll remain under surveillance.
When you go out, contact us using this room's extension.
From now on for private and work-related affairs,
Mr. Matsuda will accompany you as your manager, Matsui.
I've already paid off your agency to agree to this.
Hey there, I'm Matsui.
I haven't told them he's from the police, so be sure not to give yourself away.
This old man's gonna be my manager? How awful...
N-No way!
What's wrong with me, Misa-Misa?
Cut it out with all this dating, kissing, and Misa-Misa talk!
This is the Kira case!
Take it seriously!
S-Sorry.
No, I'm sorry.
I know we're serious,
but, Amane, go to your room now.
What?
No questions, c'mon.
Light! Let's go on a date, even if it's the three of us!
Light, are you serious about her?
No, as I said earlier, it's one-sided.
Then could you act as if you're serious?
I'm sure that Amane's connected
to the Second Kira from the video incident.
And also from the way she loves you...
Are you asking me to become intimate with her
so I can find out information about the Second Kira?
Yes. I think you can do it.
And we could get clues to solve this case from Amane.
This is why I released both of you.
Ryuzaki...
Even if it's for the Kira case,
I would never use a woman's feelings like that.
I'm sorry, you need to understand.
To me, taking advantage of another person's feelings
is unforgivable, and is the most despicable thing a person can do.
There's something wrong.
I can only assume that his personality has changed.
Is this really an act?
At this rate, it sounds as if Kira was not only controlling Amane,
but Yagami Light as well.
What's wrong, Ryuzaki?
Nothing. You're right.
But it would be helpful if you could make sure
she doesn't leak any information about the investigation.
Ryuzaki, this system of moving to a new hotel every few days...
Can't we change it?
Yes. I've also been thinking about that.
That's why...
construction started immediately after
my first meeting with Mr. Yagami and the others,
when we decided to investigate together.
It will be completed in just a few more days.
This is it.
It has twenty-three floors above ground and two below.
It's built so you can't see them from the outside,
but there are two helicopters on the roof.
What?!
Incredible...
I would like all of you to spend as much time there as possible.
Even if the number of investigators increases
on this case, we can accommodate about sixty people.
Misa shouldn't have any complaints if we give her her own floor.
This is really amazing...
To go to these lengths...
By the way, Ryuzaki, where's the money
to pay for this coming from?
As you can see, I want to solve this case, no matter what.
That's what it means.
No, you dodged the question.
Yeah, that's right.
The mass murders are bad enough,
but I can't forgive the one
who put my dad and me through all of this.
I'll do whatever it takes to solve this.
Well, if you'll "do whatever it takes,"
then become intimate with Misa and investig—
I can't do that.
It goes against my honor.
I see. That's too bad.
It's nothing.
I just feel very motivated.
Ryuzaki, Chief Yagami, Light,
let's all try to catch Kira, no matter what!
Yeah.
Excuse me... I wasn't included.
It seems we're all here.
Well then, let's begin our meeting.
To further the growth of the Yotsuba Group,
and for our company to become the biggest business in the world...
Whom shall we kill?
It's tough to kill someone every week.
This may be irrelevant,
but why has Kira begun killing like this?
Takahashi, haven't you already noticed?
Huh?
This is the most advantageous course of action for Kira.
Advantageous?
The fact that Kira began a killing service is advantageous, Higuchi?
I think you should keep quiet.
You might be killed if you're too stupid.
The eight of us here are still young,
but we're all aiming to land in the CEO's chair.
And since we started these meetings,
our salaries have been raised well
above the other employees'.
It's kind of odd that Kira would back a company.
No matter how I think about it,
one of us has to be Kira.
So, back to business. Does anyone have a proposal?
Whom should we have Kira kill to further our interests?
Humans...
are disgusting creatures.
No, you're not.
The way you talk...
It's as if you won't be satisfied unless I'm Kira.
Stop messing around, Ryuzaki!