Oh yeah! I gotta take off this belt.
Huh? Again?
He'll just have to get used to our security system.
Enough!
How's this?!
Good morning!
What happened to your forehead?
Oh, this?
Well, I got into a fight with my wife and...
My kid is still small, so it looks like I'll be commuting.
Yeah.
You should live at home.
What a waste...
These rooms are incredible.
You should move here with your whole family.
Don't lump me together with a carefree bachelor like you.
Where's Ryuzaki?
He's on a date.
The three of them are in Misa-Misa's room.
Surveillance cameras, huh?
Well, since we believe that Amane might be connected to the Second Kira,
I guess it's unavoidable.
And Matsuda, stop calling her Misa-Misa!
Oh, okay.
Hey... This doesn't feel like a date.
Just act like I'm not here.
Anyway, are you going to eat that slice of cake?
Sweets are fattening, so I try not to eat them too much.
If you use your head, you can still eat sweets without gaining weight.
Hey! You're making fun of me again!
How about I give you my slice
and you leave me alone with Light?
Even if I leave you two alone,
I'll be watching you on the surveillance cameras.
It's the same thing.
You pervert!
Will you stop doing these sick things?
Call me whatever you like.
Don't mind if I do.
Fine! I'll just close the curtains and turn off the lights.
We also have infrared cameras.
Changing the subject...
Despite moving into fully equipped headquarters,
you don't seem very enthusiastic, Ryuzaki.
Enthusiasm, huh?
I don't have any.
Actually, I'm kind of depressed.
Depressed?
Yeah...
All this time, I thought that you were Kira.
I'm just shocked that my deduction was wrong.
But I'm still suspicious of you.
Hence the reason for these...
Kira can control people's actions.
In other words, Kira was controlling you to make me suspect that you were Kira.
You and Misa were both controlled by Kira.
When I think about that, everything matches up.
By that reasoning,
Misa and I were controlled,
but doesn't that still mean that we're Kira?
Yes, I don't think I'm wrong about that.
You're both Kira.
I think that when you were confined, you were Kira.
And while you were confined, criminals stopped dying.
You were Kira until then, so it works out.
But after two weeks,
criminals began dying again.
Based on that evidence,
I think Kira's power can pass from person to person.
That's an interesting idea.
But if that's the case, then catching Kira will be no small feat.
Yeah. That's why I'm at a loss.
Even if we catch those under Kira's control,
Kira's powers will be passed on to others and the former will have no memory of their actions.
Which means that it's useless to catch anyone.
But that's not set in stone, is it?
Cheer up.
Cheer up?
I can't.
In fact, it's better if we don't try so hard.
Our lives will be in danger if we desperately chase him.
Don't you think so?
Ryuzaki...
That hurt.
Stop messing around.
You don't feel like doing anything
just because your deduction about me being Kira was wrong?
I may have phrased that poorly.
I meant that making the first move might work against us, so we shouldn't try.
There's no way we can catch him if we don't give chase!
Do you know how many innocent people
you've involved in this case?!
Besides that, you're the one who confined Misa and me!
I know that.
But whatever the reason...
An eye for an eye.
It's not that my deduction was wrong.
"Yagami Light is Kira"
and "Amane Misa is the Second Kira."
The fact is, the case isn't going to be solved as simply as that.
That's why I'm a bit depressed.
I'm human.
Am I not allowed to feel like that?
No, you're not.
The way you talk...
It's as if you won't be satisfied unless I'm Kira.
I won't be satisfied unless you're Kira?
That may be true...
I just realized...
I wanted you to be Kira.
An eye for an eye.
I'll have you know I'm pretty strong.
L-Let's call the room and stop them!
Yes?
Please listen, Ryuzaki.
Misa-Misa is ranked first
in Eighteen Magazine's reader popularity poll!
Yes, I see.
That means she'll be starring as the heroine in the next film by the director, Nishinaka!
What's wrong?
Matsuda's acting stupid again.
Well, Matsuda is a natural at that.
I can hear you...
Ryuzaki, I know you're not feeling up to it,
but come over here for a second.
Take a good look at this.
Isn't it unbalanced?
All three of them were prominent Japanese businessmen.
They all died of heart attacks.
As a result, Yotsuba's stock prices rose and those of other companies dropped.
In other words, they're deaths that are in Yotsuba's favor.
Checking back, there have been as many as thirteen such cases in the past three months.
What do you think?
I can only conclude that Kira is supporting Yotsuba.
Yes... But if that's true,
then punishing criminals is not this Kira's true intent.
Yeah.
He's punishing criminals as a front
and killing people for the benefit of his company.
What do you think?
Do you feel a little more enthusiastic now?
It's amusing how well this has gone, without anyone suspecting us.
Yotsuba's benefits and stock prices
have been increasing slowly but steadily.
Indeed.
It's all proceeding according to our calculations.
I'm just worried about one thing.
Why did the three people we decided to kill last week
die of heart attacks?
Wasn't one of them supposed to die from an accident?
That was probably because
we chose the accident to occur on the Coastal Bay Route.
At the appointed time, he wasn't at his home,
but had snuck off to Italy with a woman.
In other words,
if the request is impossible...
...Kira kills the person by heart attack.
It's like I told you last week.
If you request only accidental deaths and death by disease,
they're finished in a natural way in the shortest amount of time.
Anyway,
the police should be too busy investigating the deaths of criminals.
If someone could trace the deaths of those others back to us,
he would be a god.
Besides, we've already taken precautions.
Chief! Oh, you too, Mogi! Great job!
This is amazing!
With Light's help, the theory that Kira is involved with the Yotsuba Group has become stronger.
Yotsuba?
Y-Yes...
That's probably the case, Matsuda.
Eh?
We just heard from the Director
that Kira has offered bribes to politicians.
Kira said...
As long as the police don't chase him,
he won't lay a hand on any politician.
The police caved in to Kira.
What?!
Mogi has already made up his mind, but...
Aizawa, Matsuda...
If you really still want to pursue Kira,
then turn in your letters of resignation to the NPA with Mogi and me.
We cannot pursue Kira anymore unless you quit the police force.
Wh-What do you mean?!
It's simple.
We were told that we would be fired if we were to pursue Kira with L.
S-So then, Chief, you really...
In a few hours, I'm no longer going to be your chief.
But you all have your own lives.
Please think long and hard before you make your decision.
You're right.
That's doubly true for those
who are married and have children.
I think you all should remain police officers.
I was alone to begin with,
and I'm grateful to all of you for sticking with me this far.
But I can do this by myself.
I'll be sure to visit you all at the police department
and bring you Kira's head as a gift.
Ryuzaki,
as long as I'm here, you won't be alone.
You have my promise!
That's right.
I'll have Light working with me until I catch Kira.
But everyone else should remain police officers.
But you told us that you needed the help of the police in this case.
That's because the police as an organization didn't bow to Kira, and hoped to arrest him.
I don't really think the help of two or three
civilians who quit the police force
can really count as the police.
Also, the police have decided
that they don't want to catch Kira,
so that's enough.
I-It's true that since we wouldn't be police officers anymore,
we wouldn't be of much help.
But what about our feelings?
We put our lives on the line to catch Kira.
We at least have the right to decide
whether we stay here or remain police officers!
I suppose you're right.
Then decide which you want to do.
B-But, Chief,
if you quit the police force, you'll be unemployed.
Suppose we do catch Kira,
what would you do afterwards?
Afterwards, huh?
I haven't thought about it,
but after we catch Kira...
I guess I'll be on the job hunt again.
I've decided!
I'm also going to quit the police and chase Kira!
I still have to do my job as Misa-Misa's manager!
Besides, if I remained a police officer, I'd feel like a loser...
Watch what you say, Matsuda.
How about if I remained a police officer and helped you in my spare time?
That's no good.
If you remain a police officer, please don't come back here.
I won't leak information.
I won't give you any information.
As detectives, you are free to chase Kira.
But I don't think it's right to give up your livelihoods and harm your families just to chase Kira.
It's as Ryuzaki says.
No one will blame you if you quit now.
That's right.
But, Chief,
you have a family too.
Our situations are different.
Th-That's not fair.
I want to stay here, too.
I was prepared to die at any time.
And if I quit here, how will I face Ukita?
Damn! Why can't a detective working for the police chase Kira?!
Ryuzaki.
In case anything happened to a member of the task force,
even if they were fired, you entrusted me to make preparations
so that financial support would be offered to their families,
and they would never be in need for the rest of their lives.
Why aren't you telling them that?
Watch your mouth, Watari.
I'm sorry.
Oh, so our livelihoods were secured?
Aren't you glad, Aizawa?!
Ryuzaki...
Were you watching to see if I would quit the police to join you?
I-It's not like that, Aizawa.
Ryuzaki just hates to say things like that to himself.
Th-That's right.
No.
I was testing you.
I was watching to see which you would choose.
Ryuzaki...
Fine then!
I'll quit and remain a police officer!
Aizawa!
I couldn't make a decision quickly like you all did,
and I was leaning towards staying a police officer.
Don't be so stubborn.
No! I quit!
It's become clear to me once more!
I hate Ryuzaki!
I hate the way Ryuzaki does everything!
But I like people like you.
I also just can't stand
how he can say things like that so shamelessly!
I quit!
Thanks for all your hard work.
I found another.
The branch manager of Yotsuba's biggest rival bank
died on September 7th when he slipped on the steps of his home.
September 7th was a Friday.
I checked once more and discovered that the deaths
that are beneficial to Yotsuba are concentrated around the weekend.
Huh? Really?!
At first, the times of death were random.
But gradually, they became concentrated
around Friday nights through Saturday afternoons.
It's amazing you noticed that, Chief!
I told you, I'm no longer the Chief.
No, you'll always be the Chief to me!
This should be some sort of hint, Dad.
I haven't lost to you and Ryuzaki yet.
I don't want to be dead weight.
Dead weight?
Is Kira someone from Yotsuba?
Or is Kira using Yotsuba?
I haven't figured that out yet,
but let's investigate this with the assumption that this is Kira's doing.
Let's thoroughly investigate Yotsuba!
I've compiled a list of all domestic employees in the Yotsuba Group.
Thank you very much.
300,000, huh?
I'm surprised you compiled the list so quickly...
That's amazing, Mr. Mogi.
Mr. Mogi's been amazing from the beginning.
R-Ryuzaki!
Is there anything I can do
besides being a manager?
You want to be useful?
Yes!
Then could you get me another cup of coffee?
What?
And for our guests over there.
Who are they?
And since when have they been here?
They're our new members.
I'm Aiber. A con-man. Pleased to meet you.
Wedy. I'm a thief by trade.
A con-man and a thief?
Yes.
Aiber has excellent social skills.
He's a con-man who can cozy up to our target.
We'll use him for infiltrative investigations.
Wedy is a thief who can crack any lock, safe, or security system.
As proof, she entered without any of us noticing.
W-We're going to be working together with criminals?
They're criminals,
but not the type who will surface and be killed by Kira.
Think of them as pros of the underworld.
I see. If we want to investigate Yotsuba,
we need people like them.
Let's all work together and give it our best!
Yeah!
Uh, right.
Huh?
It's Daddy.
What?
Daddy!
Yumi...
Eriko...
What are you doing here?
At least tell me if you're coming home.
I haven't bought enough for your dinner.
I'll give you half of my croquette!
Sorry...
I haven't had a break for quite a while now, so I got some time off.
Huh? Is a "time off" a break?
Yeah. That's what it is.
All right!
From now on, I can have a break every week.
So I can take you to this park.
No, the zoo...
or even the amusement park...
What's wrong?
Mama...
Papa is crying.
Secret meetings?
It sounds like they have one every Friday night.
Bingo!
I'm on it today!