Matsuda! This isn't child's play.
Don't joke around.
Okay...
This is the Kira case!
Take it seriously!
S-Sorry.
Matsuda!
I mean, Mr. Matsuda.
Please stop.
Matsuda?
I don't want to be dead weight.
R-Ryuzaki!
Is there anything I can do
besides being a manager?
Then could you get me another cup of coffee?
What?
I too ... want to play a bigger role in this!
I love you.
So please...
don't say you're going home.
Stay by my side forever.
Oh, Director, I have a boyfriend. Can we cut the love scenes please?
What?
W-Wait just a second!
Where is this coming from?!
Can't we fake a kiss?
What?
We can't make a movie like that!
No means no!
Yotsuba Group's main Tokyo branch...
Today is Friday.
Deaths that benefit Yotsuba
are concentrated around the weekend.
I don't want to be dead weight.
Mr. Mogi's been amazing from the beginning.
Matsuda! This isn't child's play!
Take it seriously!
Matsuda is a natural at that.
Then could you get me another cup of coffee?
Matsuda!
Matsu!
Hey, Matsu!
He went somewhere.
Huh?!
Anyway...
Please check this list.
Understood.
Would I punish evil-doers if I could kill
by seeing a person's face and name?
Indeed, there are people whom the world can do without.
But I don't think that I would become a killer
just to change the world.
I'm thinking too hard about this.
How could someone murder so many people and not remem—
What's wrong?
You're staring at me...
You're annoyed that I'm the only one with cake, aren't you?
No, that's not it.
Here.
I'm not envious of you.
Ryuzaki.
What is it, Watari?
Detective Eraldo Coil has been asked to uncover L's identity.
Isn't Eraldo Coil the man
who's the next greatest detective after L?
Who in the world would send such a request?
The person who requested it is the V.P. of the Rights and Planning Department
of Yotsuba Group's main Tokyo branch, Kida Masahiko.
So it was Yotsuba!
Yotsuba is linked to Kira.
If they want L's identity,
then that means they probably want to kill him.
That's not good.
We're already shorthanded,
and now we have to worry about Coil too?
It's all right.
The detective known as Eraldo Coil is me.
Three of the world's greatest detectives,
L, Coil, and Deneuve
are all me.
Those who try to find me usually fall for this.
I'll give you this strawberry, so please keep it a secret.
Just what I'd expect of you, Ryuzaki.
Maybe I should leave while I still have the chance.
No, then this would be pointless.
Should I wait until everyone's gone and search the offices?
No, if I were caught doing that...
Perhaps I'd better leave.
Not that again.
I'm beat.
But it's good that it's before the weekend.
We don't know how long our secret meetings will last.
If it were on a Monday,
I'd feel depressed about coming to the office.
Secret meetings?
Bingo!
The nineteenth floor!
I came this far!
So I'm going to do this!
Okay. I just have to get close to him, right?
Leave it to me.
And I just have to breach
the surveillance cameras and security system
at Yotsuba's main Tokyo branch, where this guy works, right?
Yes.
It is safe to assume that Kira and Yotsuba are connected.
We're going to check Yotsuba
to see who and how many have the power.
It is important that we gain a clear understanding quickly.
We must not allow anyone from Yotsuba figure out that we are investigating them.
If someone notices, please assume
that we'll no longer be able to catch Kira.
Damn. I can't hear them clearly.
If I only could hear just one tidbit...
Or rather, he's in the way.
Let's kill him and split up his stocks.
I just heard them say "kill"!
Kira sure is varied.
Kira?!
There it is! Kira!
There it is! What?!
"Let's have Kira kill him?" I heard it!
They really are working with Kira.
I did it!
I hit the jackpot!
Who are you?!
Please be sure not to act out of panic or haste.
And don't take matters into your own hands.
Ryuzaki.
What is it, Watari?
Matsuda has sent an emergency signal from his belt.
From where?
Well...
It seems it's coming from within Yotsuba's main Tokyo office.
My name is Matsui Taro.
An agent with Yoshida Productions!
How would you like to use
our top multi-talented star, Amane Misa,
as the new spokeswoman
for your company and for your commercials?!
Forget about everything I just said.
We'll need to rethink our strategy.
Matsuda, you idiot!
Yoshida Productions...
Matsui Taro...
He doesn't have anything suspicious.
And he doesn't seem to be a corporate spy.
Yes, um...
Please take Misa-Misa into consideration.
These two are only lookouts.
The rest of them must be talking about how to dispose of me.
I'm a goner.
I wonder if they received my emergency signal.
Besides, will Ryuzaki even attempt to save me?
What's gonna happen to me?
You can answer it.
Don't say that you're here.
Hold it away from your ear
so we can listen.
O-Okay.
Hello?
Yo! Matsui!
Ryuzaki!
It's me, Asahi.
It's been a while.
Oh, Asahi, it sure has.
You don't sound like you're out.
You home already?
Y-Yeah.
Are you by yourself?
Yeah, I'm by myself.
What's up?
Amane Misa is somewhere else.
Matsuda is alone.
Wanna go out drinking?
What? Now?
Sorry, I'll pass!
What?
Don't tell me your wallet's in trouble again?
In trouble?
Yeah, I'm totally broke.
That should be a given.
Matsuda's totally in trouble.
Oh well.
I'll take you out some other time. See ya later.
So then, how about Misa-Misa?
I think she'd be great for your company.
If you're pitching someone,
shouldn't you have brought them with you?
Are you really a manager?
Well, right now she's filming a movie nearby.
I'll call her here once she's finished.
Please make her the spokeswoman of your company!
I'd better keep stalling.
Misa's phone is on voicemail.
I left her a message to call us.
What are you going to do, Ryuzaki?
What indeed.
If Matsuda dies, that would justify the suspicion against Yotsuba.
Let's just watch how this all plays out.
What shall we do?
The question is whether or not he heard us.
There is a possibility.
We've got to kill him.
But did he really come to pitch us a talent?
Could he be a police officer?
He can't be.
The Japanese police have completely withdrawn from the Kira case.
It doesn't matter who he is.
We have to kill him.
It might be good to have her as the face of our company.
Right? Her shoot will finish soon,
so please remain patient.
I'm tired.
A message from Light!
Light (Knight)
Call History
He really worries about me if I'm late.
Misa...
Light! Sorry I've been working so much.
I'll be finished soon.
Misa, you're not with Matsuda, are you?
He's horrible!
He just abandoned me here.
Oh, I've got a call on my work phone.
It's from Matsu.
Misa got a call from Matsuda.
Tell Misa to let us listen in as well.
Misa-Misa, when you're finished filming, come to Yotsuba's main Tokyo offices.
You may be able to appear in Yotsuba's commercials.
I'm negotiating with them right now.
What? Really?
That's amazing, Matsu!
So that's what you've been up to!
I'll do my best!
Yeah. It's a short trip by taxi.
Yagami, we may be able to save Matsuda.
But we need Misa's help.
I'm sure she'll listen to you.
I'm Misa-Misa!
Going nude is off-limits,
but swimsuits and lingerie are A-okay!
Pleased to meet you!
Hmm... She's really cute in person.
That's not the problem right now, wouldn't you agree?
Matsu, since this is for Yotsuba,
I got the green light from the offices to have a special reception.
A special reception?
Good evening!
Pleased to meet you!
We'll be entertaining you with all the girls from the agency tonight!
Hey, don't you think this is heading in a weird direction?
It can't be helped.
Right now, we can't leave that manager alone.
Anyway, I'm just going to enjoy myself.
Ryuzaki and the others can see us from here.
I may be saved...
Yes, please drink! Drink!
This is Heaven on Earth.
Misa's pretty good.
Now then...
I need to go to the restroom.
Ryuzaki, are you watching?
Yes.
Um, sorry, I...
Never mind that already.
Okay.
The eight who came were having a meeting
to determine whom they would get Kira to kill for them.
I heard it clearly.
It's definitely them.
It's probably true.
But if you did overhear them,
then they should be trying to kill you.
Figures.
Is there anything I can do?
Luckily, you're still alive, so we may be able to save you.
But for that to happen,
you must die before they kill you.
What?
I want you to listen to me very closely.
You can't mean...
That's impossible!
Isn't that so?
In other words...
No, there are some women
I've broken up with whom I still think about.
Our company is still expanding.
What's going on?!
Man... I am so wasted.
It feels good!
Hey, is everyone having fun?
That's no good.
You should be enjoying yourselves!
Now, everyone...
The thing you've been waiting for!
Showtime with Matsui Taro!
Hey, what are you doing?
What?!
Go for it, Mr. Matsui!
There we go...
Hey, you're drunk!
That's dangerous.
It's all right...
I always do this.
Come down from there!
Come down!
That's dangerous, you idiot!
It's all right...
He fell!
This isn't good...
Oh no!
I heard a loud thud and came out to see what happened! How horrible!
Man, this role sucks.
Someone call 911! Call 911!
Everyone, leave this to us and go home.
What? But...
It's all right.
But please consider me for the commercial.
Hurry.
It'd be bad if the press were to see us here.
Yeah.
What's going on?!
Did someone jump?!
Well, it's good that we saw him die right before our eyes.
Keep quiet!
I know we're shorthanded, but I don't like doing this.
Matsuda, you idiot.
Amane Misa's manager dies.
Yes?
You're the V.P. of the Rights and Planning Department
at the Yotsuba Group's main Tokyo branch,
Kida Masahiko, aren't you?
Yes, that's right.
Who's calling?
My name is Eraldo Coil.
I'd like to discuss my terms with you.
A two-million-dollar advance
and eight million upon completion?
Are you out of your mind?
And even if we don't commission him,
we have to pay him two million to keep him silent.
Hush money, huh?
We should assume that Coil knows quite a bit already.
That's pretty bad.
I want out of these meetings!
I don't know who Kira is,
but I don't want to get wrapped up in this
and get myself arrested!
Hatori...
You're going to die tomorrow.
Wait! I was just joking!
I'll do this!
I'll stay and do it properly!
So what are we going to do?
Coil is willing to accept our job despite what he knows.
He'll become partners with us as long as we pay him.
That's what it means.
We need to have someone as skilled as Coil on our side.
That's right.
Pay him, no matter the cost.
Yeah, pay him!
All right, we'll contract Coil.
No objections?
No objections.
L, are you listening?
I'm so disappointed.
The security level here is terrible.
They only have a contract with a security company.
There weren't even any wiretap detectors.
I-It's been one week since I sneaked in.
Things seem to be moving very smoothly.
We're almost there.
One of these people...
is Kira.
Now then, let's commence our regular meeting.
There only appears to be seven of them instead of eight.
Ryuzaki!
Even after I catch the current Kira,
do you think that I could become Kira, a murderer?
Do I look like that kind of person?!