Let's begin our meeting.
Only seven of the eight are present.
That means that...
They probably killed one of them.
To further the growth of the Yotsuba Group,
whom should we kill?
See? It's like I said.
This is bad.
If this keeps up...
Before that, we have several topics which we should discuss.
The first is Hatori's death.
That couldn't be helped.
To be honest, I'm relieved that he's dead.
Kira has clearly shown what'll happen
to whoever tries to leave these meetings.
Yeah...
I think we all know what Hatori's death means.
Take it to heart.
Next, Eraldo Coil's report...
One of their partners just died. Is that it?!
Five million dollars just for this report, huh?
He hasn't found anything important about L, like his face and name.
Is this Coil really of any use?
Well, wait.
At the end of this report,
Coil warns us that we shouldn't take L's existence lightly.
It reads, "If you continue with your current pace of killing,
for Yotsuba's benefit, every week on Fridays and Saturdays,
L could possibly connect you to Kira."
It's impressive that Coil has figured out what we've been doing.
At any rate, we should stop killing on every weekend.
Th-This is amazing.
It's like they're confessing.
Yeah.
As long as we have this video,
we could probably arrest all seven of them.
This is definitely bad...
Kira isn't very flexible either.
It would be nice if he killed at various times during the week.
The fact that Coil noticed this makes it dangerous
to continue killing at our current pace.
From now on, we should be even more careful
and make sure nobody ever notices.
Now, on to the main topic.
Whom shall we kill?
We must stop E.L.F. Insurance from expanding their business into the Japanese market.
Yotsuba and many other companies' clients will be swept away.
Agreed.
So, is it all right for these people
from E.L.F. to die by accidental deaths?
No objections.
What is this?
They're so nonchalant.
Another person is protesting
Yotsuba's plans for the resort development.
His name is Zenzai Santaro,
a member of the Kugisawa Group.
Zenzai suffers from high blood pressure.
Therefore, it is possible to have him die of a stroke at a designated time.
Is this all right?
No objections.
Kira... death by accident... death by disease...
designated times of death.
It's as we thought.
There's no mistaking it.
No. Unfortunately,
we can only say that after those people they named die.
As long as we continue to monitor what these seven say at their meetings,
their actions, and whether the people they name die,
we'll definitely catch Kira.
Ryuzaki!
What is it?
Both of you in unison...
I can't go along with your idea!
It's wrong!
Here it comes...
You seem to plan on catching Kira
by allowing these seven to continue to kill,
but I can't let them!
That's right. It's clear as day
that these seven are committing murder!
Can't we prove it's them from Matsuda's testimony and this footage?
This is problematic.
If we catch them now,
everything we've done will have been in vain.
So the E.L.F. will be three weeks later.
We'll ask Kira to have Zenzai killed this weekend.
How about it?
No objections.
If it's this weekend, there's not much time left!
Light, you know the cell phone numbers of those seven, right?
Yeah.
Any one of them will do.
I'm going to call one of those seven and stop the killing!
Please wait.
If we do that just three days
after Aiber's made contact with them, we'll arouse suspicion that our investigation is catching up to them.
It's also highly likely
that we won't be able to figure out who Kira is.
We've come this far, but we'd have to go back to square one.
In order to catch Kira,
we need proof.
Ryuzaki.
If Kira is among these seven,
isn't it fair to assume that if we call one of them,
there's a one-in-seven chance that that person is Kira?
At most, I would think there's two of them.
So it's two out of seven...
If we're prepared to let them know
that the investigation is catching up to them,
then let's risk it on those odds.
I'm going to borrow the name "L," Ryuzaki.
From the looks of it,
the one who seems the least likely to be Kira and who carries some weight on the board is...
Ooi!
Namikawa.
If you're going to make a call, use this phone.
It can't be traced or tapped.
I really think it would be faster if we killed
the executives of our rival companies one by one.
That would be going a bit far.
Let's kill them and split their stocks.
You're the V.P. of Yotsuba Group's Sales Department One,
Namikawa Reiji, aren't you?
Yes. What about it?
Listen and respond as you see fit.
I am L.
I have cameras and wiretaps planted in that meeting room
and I'm recording footage of your entire meeting.
The opening topic was Hatori's death.
Now, you're debating whom to kill.
Isn't that right?
He's been watching everything.
If you aren't Kira,
or if you aren't someone who can contact Kira directly,
then let's make a deal.
A deal?!
Delay the death of E.L.F.'s president and Mr. Zenzai one month.
This shouldn't be difficult for you.
If we want to randomize the deaths, we should just throw darts at a calendar.
Yes, I see...
Yes... Go on...
If you do this,
and cooperate with us from now on,
your crime – no,
everyone other than Kira
will not be charged under the belief that they were threatened by Kira into participating in the meetings.
Ah... I see...
My only option is join L.
No, I'll be killed if Kira finds out that I've sided with L.
What should I do?
If you reveal this conversation, it'll cause a panic.
There would be no advantage for you.
Everyone would be caught.
But my goal is to go one on one against Kira.
Listen...
If L wins against Kira, you'll be acquitted.
If Kira wins against me,
you'll carry on with your luxurious life.
Or you can remain a spectator
and go along with either side.
Whoever wins, L or Kira, it's no loss to you.
However, it would be a loss to you
if you were caught right now.
He already knows the answer I would have given.
That's all.
Okay. On Monday...
What's wrong, Namikawa?
Who was it?
Nothing, a subordinate of mine
messed up and I'll have to fix it on Monday.
Sorry for interrupting.
Let's get back on topic.
Regarding when we should kill those E.L.F. guys and Zenzai...
How about this?
We give Coil one month to discover L's identity.
If he fails,
we'll be forced to kill them at various dates.
Next, we'll give him another month and repeat the process.
Once we've dealt with L,
we'll go back to two or three people a week.
In other words, we should make dealing with L our first priority.
I see...
Indeed. If we kill L, we'll be unobstructed.
Until then, we should be careful.
Yeah. It sounds good to me.
Well, we've got to be extremely careful.
Then we'll give Coil one month.
No objections.
L, you're probably satisfied with this.
But we'll still hold these meetings every week.
That's all for now.
It went well.
Yeah...
You really are amazing.
Not only did you delay the killing,
but we may be able to get information from Namikawa.
Furthermore, it looked like something I would do.
You thought of it faster than I did.
At this rate...
If I die,
it's quite possible you would be capable
of succeeding the title of L.
Why are you talking about such morbid things?
We have a month to figure out Kira's identity
and gather evidence against him.
The challenge is just beginning.
Yes...
But you're the one who first noticed Yotsuba.
You may be more capable than I am.
You might be able to do it.
If I die...
would you take over for me as L?
If I die, would you take over for me?
As L.
If this is all an act and he is Kira, he's sure to say yes.
What are you talking about, Ryuzaki?
As long as we're handcuffed, won't we die togethe—
I see...
Ryuzaki...
Sorry, but I'm going to tell everyone what you were thinking.
Ryuzaki thinks that if I'm Kira,
either I'm just pretending I'm not him and putting on an act,
or Kira's power has passed to someone else
and I have no memory that I was Kira.
Those two possibilities.
If it's the first...
If I'm putting on an act, these handcuffs will never come off.
No, even if it were the other possibility, he probably wouldn't take them off.
Ryuzaki thinks that I'm Kira.
Even if that power has been passed to someone else,
he assumes that I would've planned things to have it return to me.
In other words, he doesn't think I was being controlled.
I passed the power on
and planned for it to come back to me once I've been cleared.
Amazing...
It's like you've read my mind.
Ryuzaki's line of reasoning is
"Light will become Kira once he steals L's position."
Correct.
To acquire the position of L
and be able to freely control the police,
while being Kira in secret...
That would be the ultimate.
I could do that...
No, I would do it.
That's what you meant, didn't you?
Yes.
But what about now?
You should know by now that I'm probably not acting.
If you were acting and trying to steal my position,
there's no way that you'd reveal your plan in front of everyone.
Is that what you mean?
Ryuzaki...
Even after I catch the current Kira, do you really think
that I'd become Kira, a murderer?
Do I look like that kind of person?
I think so.
You look it.
A-Again?
Okay! Once is enough!
Let's just leave it as a draw!
I-I guess so.
At any rate, we have to catch the Kira before us.
As long as I'm handcuffed,
you shouldn't have any complaints.
I suppose so.
We only have a month.
Ryuzaki...
Yes?
If we can use that meeting as evidence against those seven,
won't the murders of criminals stop?
Not again...
Unfortunately, they won't.
They won't?
We're not sure if Kira is among those seven.
If they only have a connection to him,
Kira will simply kill them.
We have to be absolutely sure that Kira is among them,
or there's no point in catching them now.
Even if he is among them,
it's difficult to determine who's Kira right now.
I think it's still too early.
B-But, if you can't say that he's definitely among the seven,
there's still a chance
that the killings will stop if we arrest them.
It's like my dad says.
There's a chance.
Uh...
On second thought, I think I'll go after Kira by myself.
You can use these headquarters,
as will I.
You can do things your way
and arrest them if you wish.
I shall investigate as I wish in my own way.
We'll only get into arguments otherwise.
Let's split, and act separately.
In other words, you only want to figure out who Kira is, huh?
Yes. This case will never be solved if we don't capture him.
I won't say that stopping the deaths of people before us is pointless.
But if we don't find the truth,
Kira will appear again and the number of victims will pile up in the end.
That's why...
I think it's more important to figure out who Kira is.
I'm opposed to arresting those seven.
If you want to do that, then you take responsibility for it.
I will pursue Kira by myself.
We only have one month.
I wonder who will catch him first.
Ryuzaki...
Where are you going?
Amane's room.
Sorry, Light, I know you're on your father's side.
But I can't remove these handcuffs,
so you're going to have to come with me.
Light! Was today a day we could go on a date?
Along with Mr. Ryuzaki...
Misa...
Do you love Light?
Huh?
Y-Yes... very much...
But you also worship Kira.
Yes...
So...
Whom would you pick, Light or Kira?
Huh?
Light, of course.
I'm grateful to Kira and wanted to meet him, but that's not love. Light wins by a landslide.
Light wants to catch Kira.
Isn't that right, Light?
Yeah. Of course.
He wants to catch him.
Now what'll you do?
If Light wants to catch him, then I want Light to catch him.
So would you want to help Light
by working with him on the investigation?
R-Ryuzaki!
Yeah! I'll do anything for Light!
Wait a second.
What are you thinking of doing?
Aiber will pose as Eraldo Coil
and tell those seven that he learned Amane Misa might be able to identify L.
And that L brought her in for questioning
because he suspected that she was the Second Kira.
Well, that's true.
If they know that Amane Misa might know L,
they'll have her appear in their commercials
and ask her about various things.
Since Mr. Matsuda's screw up,
there were talks about using her in their commercials.
Go on.
That's no good.
Why?
Because it would subject you to danger.
Huh? You're worried about me?
All right!
But this is nothing if it's for you.
Listen, Misa,
if they know that you might know who L is,
we don't know what means they'll use to get that information out of you.
It's all right.
I won't say anything under any kind of torture.
Yes. That's true...
Besides, Kira can control his victim's actions before death.
There is a good chance that he might try to get her to talk, and kill her.
No, if he kills L, then he won't have any use for her
and Kira would kill Misa to keep her silent.
I wouldn't like that...
Light.
If we win, Misa won't die.
Besides,
as long as we're handcuffed, we share the same fate.
If I die, you'll die too.
In that case, Misa is the one who would grieve the most.
It's either we both die,
or we catch Kira.
Now which will it be?
Catch Kira!
I wouldn't be able to live in a world without Light.
Yes, that's correct.
Hey, Ryuzaki, that's messed up.
Desperate times call for desperate measures.
Besides, Amane Misa's...
bravery and love for you...
have no equal.
R-Ryuzaki...
I think I've misunderstood you all this time.
I called you a pervert and stuff.
You really do understand me!
Yes. Misa is the perfect, most worthy woman for Light.
Yay!
Thank you, Ryuzaki.
I could fall in love with you, you know.
Uh... That's a little...
How about being friends, Ryuzaki?
Sure.
I've made another friend.
Yeah. All of Light's friends are my friends.
Let's all be friends!
And I won't ever betray any of my friends.
With our powers combined, let's arrest Kira!
No, but...
Yagami is taking a different investigative approach
from us and will be working with his father and the others.
You and I will be together, Misa.
Huh? What's with that?
That's dirty, Ryuzaki.
Now my only choice is to join your investigatio—
No, that's quite all right.
What are you talking about?
Light will be joining us!
No, it's not like that...
I'm opposed to this investigation.
It's too dangerous for you.
Light...
Thank you for thinking about me.
But let me do this.
I want to be of use to you.
Not only that, but I want you to love me even more.
Besides that,
I would gladly die for you.
Arresting seven people in this situation is difficult.
Mogi, Matsuda, do you have any good ideas?
Well, I am an actress.
Director Nishinaka, Light, the others...
And now even the Shinigami's asking me to act!
This is a lot of work.
It looks like I might be in a big commercial.
I'm so popular!