Hey, I thought we were only supposed
to meet every other week.
It can't be helped.
Coil reported that Amane Misa might know L.
According to this, it means L questioned Amane.
This is the problem.
He says he's "deduced that Amane worships Kira."
"Furthermore, Yoshida Productions
is trying to promote Amane as the face of Yotsuba."
"I suggest that Yotsuba use Amane for its commercials
to extract information about L."
I cannot accept this idea.
Why not?
I think it's a great plan.
No, what Ooi is trying to say is...
It's ultimately Coil's job to reveal L's identity.
So it's illogical for him to leave this to us, isn't it?
Yeah. We contracted him to reveal L's identity.
Shouldn't we ask Coil about his stance?
That's right...
Mr. Kida, I thought we'd agreed you wouldn't contact me directly.
Is it an emergency?
I understand.
If that's the case, I have a good idea.
Even though the meeting's over, I still have to punish criminals when I get home.
It sure is tough being Kira...
But it's become interesting...
There's no doubt that Amane Misa is the Second Kira.
And L caught her at some point.
If he's letting her move about freely,
it means that she's forfeited ownership
and lost all her memories.
I can't leave her alone.
I'm going to make Amane Misa my wife.
Money, power, and a beautiful wife...
That's enough to make anyone green with envy!
Once we're married,
I'll take out a lot of life insurance on her.
Would she marry such a disgusting guy?
Rem, hide the notebook in the usual place.
Right now, this is the only thing I can do...
for Misa's sake.
All right! Let's take it from there.
Misa, you said that you came to Tokyo to meet Kira.
What?!
Hey!
Misa, please stop overacting.
It looks cheesy.
What? But that's what's called a realistic performance...
Just do it over...
Yes, yes, Great Director Ryuzaki...
If you don't take this seriously, I'll kick you.
M-Misa-Misa...
You're so tense.
You can just call me "Misa," Mochi.
I'm not suited for this.
But it's still part of the mission to catch Kira.
Misa-Misa!
What is it, Mochi?!
We have an interview with Yotsuba to see if they'll use you in their ads.
But it's also an infiltration.
I already know.
Of course, don't blow your cover either.
You're supposed to be a cheerful, energetic manager!
Yes, I'll give it my best!
All right!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Good morning!
I'm Misa-Misa's manager, Mochi, also known as Moji Kanichi.
Mr. Ooi, Mr. Shimura, nice to see you again!
I'm very pleased to meet you.
Good luck, Misa-Misa!
You're really nailing it, Mochi.
I'll be waiting to celebrate when they decide to put you in their commercials!
I'm not cut out for this, am I?
Well... This is our first time meeting, isn't it, Misa?
I'm John Wallace, the executive advisor
for the marketing department.
Pleased to meet you.
Pleased to meet you too.
This is a bit sudden, but I'll tell you honestly.
We're pretty much certain we're going to hire you.
But before we do, there's just one thing we have to clarify.
Yes?
We did a little background check on you...
A burglar killed your parents.
You worship Kira because he killed the man who murdered your family.
You said that you came to Tokyo to meet Kira.
Wh-Whom did you hear that from?
We can't tell you our source.
But this is reliable information.
It's written on your face.
Coil, I never thought you investigated that far.
Also...
You're still hiding something, aren't you?
Something that you don't want the world to know.
I have to sweat a lot and pause here.
L detained you.
Please tell us about what really happened.
It would be a problem if the face of Yotsuba were Kira.
Yes. Please tell us truthfully.
A-All right.
I'll tell you everything.
I was indeed detained.
I don't think it was L,
but he did ask me about Kira.
I'm not the Second Kira, though.
I'm here because he found out I have nothing to do with Kira.
Did you see who was detaining you?
I was blindfolded.
But you heard his voice, didn't you?
Only through a speaker, so...
Hey...
This is more like an interrogation than an interview.
How long do you plan on doing this?
I'm going to the restroom.
Indeed, it seems the interview has veered off track.
Excuse me...
May I also go to the restroom?
This is tiring...
But it's going well.
I have to keep it up.
Touching her with this piece of the notebook
won't return her memories.
But at least now, Misa can see me again.
Wh-What is this?!
A monster?
Misa, you're in a dangerous situation. The people from Yotsuba may kill you.
I came to tell you that.
Calm down and listen to me.
Calm down?
This monster looks like it's going to kill me!
I am your ally.
My...
ally?
I wonder if Misa-Misa is all right.
We should have at least wired her!
It is a different person, after all.
The Kira before and after I was detained...
are clearly different.
The current Kira is killing every criminal
as soon as they've had their crime broadcasted,
regardless of the situation.
The previous Kira would never punish
those who didn't have any intention to kill,
those who killed by accident,
or those with extenuating circumstances.
If I were Kira, that's what I would do.
The original Kira's criteria for killing
are disturbingly close to my own thoughts.
What am I thinking?
I'm not Kira.
There must be something wrong with me
if I'm comparing myself to Kira.
Yagami Light is Kira.
What is Light doing now?
What are you?
I know you're not a stalker,
but you don't look human at all.
Of course not.
I'm a Shinigami.
We once worked together.
I don't know what you're talking about.
You met me?
Light is Kira?
The Death Note...
If you write a person's name in it,
that person dies.
With that notebook,
Yagami Light punished criminals
and became known as Kira.
And you had the same—
no, greater power than Kira.
With that power, you managed to get close to Yagami Light.
Light is Kira... and I'm the Second Kira?
That's right...
No, more correctly, you were.
This should all be going according to Light's plan.
So Ryuzaki's right!
Misa,
do you still love Light more than anything?
Shinigami, you really are the real thing.
You know everything about me.
I'll believe everything you say.
Yes, I love him...
more than anything.
Besides, it's really awesome that Light and I were both Kira.
I believe you.
You haven't changed at all, Misa.
Those feelings towards Light
will probably never change, will they?
I now believe that you'll find happiness by staying with Light.
Thank you, Shinigami.
It's Rem.
The current Kira is a crooked and pathetic human.
You don't know what he'll do.
Be careful.
Be careful of the other Yotsuba men as well.
Trust Light and let him do whatever he feels necessary.
All right, I just have to act normal, right?
That's right.
When you go back to the interview,
you should be able to tell who Kira is.
Do not trust him.
Sorry I took so long in the restroom.
I fixed up my makeup!
Listen, when you return,
the man who's sitting in front of me is Kira.
Rem...
The person in front of Rem is Kira.
Higuchi is Kira.
That's horrible...
Misa-Misa sure is late...
They're back!
Hey!
I am so tired.
Hey...
How was it?
Yotsuba hired Misa to appear in their ads.
I see.
That's great.
Once I told them my cell phone number,
I was asked out by three of the seven.
What?
I just have to accept and investigate them, right?
It's exactly as planned.
No, the plan has been canceled.
Huh?
Why? It's been going so well!
You'll be in danger if we do this.
I won't stop you from appearing in any of their commercials,
but from now on, deny that you were suspected
of being the Second Kira and that you were detained by L.
Mogi will be your bodyguard,
and you will just be an entertainer.
If that's what you say, then that's what I'll do.
Well, I'm tired and tomorrow's shoot
is early in the morning, so I'm going to bed.
Thank you for worrying about me, Light,
but I've thought of a good plan.
I'm sure to be of help to you.
Light, want to come to bed with me?
What are you talking about, Misa?
I understand...
That's for after we catch Kira, isn't it?
You don't have to be shy, Light.
You do not have to be shy, Light.
I'm not being shy.
Why are you answering so seriously?
Cut!
That's good!
Good work!
Good work, Misa-Misa!
I can use the restroom in this hospital, right?
Yes!
Go right ahead!
_.Medical
College
Hospital
Then wait for me a moment.
Yes...
Good work, Misa.
Wow! Nori, you look good in that nurse outfit!
You think so?
To-Oh Women's Medical Center
It went well.
Whoa...
Just as I expected, an amazing car.
If you like it, I'll let you ride in it any time,
or I'll buy you one.
By the way, that nurse's outfit is pretty nice, Misa.
You like it?
You sure took your time.
Where's Misa?!
She's on a date.
Dammit!
Higuchi Kyosuke...
Misa, you're really my type.
He's the persistent dirty old man
who's been texting me ever since that party.
Hey, Higuchi! Quit hogging her!
It's horrible that this guy is Kira...
Misa, shall we get something to eat?
Don't take me anywhere weird, okay?
Well, even if you do try something,
it's all right because I can kill people.
What are you thinking, Misa?
Is this what Yagami Light wants you to do?
No, is Misa just saying that she wants me
to kill Higuchi if something happens?
That's a funny thing to say, Misa.
You can kill people?
It's true.
Because I'm...
the Second Kira.
I-It can't be...
Even if this girl was the Second Kira in the past,
she can't be right now.
She shouldn't have any memory of it.
What's going on?
Misa, you don't have to make up things like that to protect yourself.
I'm actually quite the gentleman.
Well, I don't really feel like proving
I'm the Second Kira to anyone other than Kira.
You'll only show Kira?
What do you mean?
It's my dream to become Kira's bride.
I know with all my heart that Kira needs me by his side.
If she's the Second Kira, then it's clear
from the Sakura TV incident that she has the Shinigami eyes.
If it's true,
I need her by my side, no matter what.
I'll test her.
Well then, I'm Kira,
so marry me, Misa!
Really?!
Yeah... I am.
Really.
What? Then prove it!
Let's show each other the proof!
That's impossible.
It would be risky to show how I kill.
You think so?
I would show someone if they might be Kira.
Nothing would happen if I didn't.
Then kill someone.
I may be Kira.
Fine. But I only kill bad people.
That's right.
A bad person, huh?
Kaneboshi Ginzo.
He's the president of a major consumer financing company.
He's a crook who's famous for his cruel collection methods.
Sometimes, he makes people pay
with their insurance money.
How about him?
Can you immediately check if he died?
I can tell if I make a phone call.
Then turn around for a moment.
Misa...
I have to kill Kaneboshi Ginzo, don't I?
Then Higuchi will trust you.
Fine.
Kaneboshi Ginzo
All right.
He should be dead now.
This is Higuchi from Yotsuba.
Sorry! Our president just collapsed and stopped breathing... Call back later!
See?
She killed a person whom I chose, right here...
It would've been impossible unless she had the powers!
It's decided!
Then if I'm Kira, you'll marry me, right?!
Wh-Why are you getting so serious all of a sudden?
Because I'm Kira.
Then prove it.
I can't kill until I go home.
You understand.
Yeah... then it's no good.
It might be a scheme to lure me into your house.
Oh, I know.
Then stop killing criminals.
If you're Kira, I'm sure you can do it.
Then begin killing when I tell you to.
Then I'll believe you.
Killing criminals
is something that only Kira could do.
I see.
That's a good idea.
All right.
I'm Kira, so in order to make you trust me,
I'm going to stop killing criminals starting now.
And when you know I'm Kira, we'll get married!
And there you have it!
Higuchi is Kira.
Now we know Kira's identity,
and the killings that have been bothering the Chief will stop!
You're awesome, Misa-Misa!
It's been three days since I stopped killing criminals.
That should be good enough.
Now if I marry the Second Kira, Amane Misa,
I'll have the Shinigami eyes.
And I'll control everything Yotsuba has!