And when you know I'm Kira, we'll get married!
And there you have it!
Higuchi is Kira.
If the killing of criminals stops,
then Higuchi probably has Kira's powers.
Still...
I knew that Amane would do anything for Yagami Light,
but I never thought she would go this far.
If the killing of criminals stops,
then it will become difficult to deduce the method of killing.
I have to think of a plan.
Misa,
how did you get Higuchi to say that?
Huh? He's head over heels in love with me.
I said I'd marry him if he was Kira.
And he thinks that I'm the Second Kira.
If I don't say this now,
I'll probably contradict myself later.
You idiot!
We told you to deny all of that.
B-But now we know that Higuchi is Kira,
so we can just catch him.
I suppose you could call this a victory, right, Matsuda?
In our current situation,
we still don't know how he kills his victims.
That's right.
Before we catch Higuchi,
I want to know how he kills people.
If criminals stop dying,
we won't be able to figure it out, right?
Right. Even if we're going to arrest Higuchi,
we'll do it when we're sure
that criminals have stopped dying.
Please let me think for a moment.
Wedy.
Yes.
What's the current situation?
It's going smoothly.
We should be able to track seventy percent
of the seven's actions with our cameras while they're in the building.
What about outside of the building?
That's impossible with just Watari and me.
How about just focusing only on Higuchi?
Higuchi?
I've only been inside five of their houses,
but Mido's, Namikawa's, and Higuchi's houses
have serious security systems.
Especially Higuchi's.
He's recently constructed an underground room
that blocks out electronic waves.
It took me two days to break in.
Higuchi is definitely suspicious.
Yeah.
All right.
In Higuchi's car rather than in his house, please install wire-taps, trackers, and cameras.
What? After doing this much?
Do you know how difficult it is to get inside someone's house?
Besides, how many cars do you think Higuchi has?
Six.
All right.
I just have to install them in all of his cars, right?
Please do.
Whoa... I would've been in trouble if he'd been wire-tapped earlier.
Yagami, sorry for coming back to this topic,
but I have to ask you again.
Ask me what?
Do you remember...
how you killed?
You're still accusing me of that?
I'm not Kira.
How many times do I—
Just answer the question.
Do you remember?
I don't.
Misa, what about you?
I don't remember, and I'm not Kira.
Yagami, please seriously analyze and deduce
what I'm going to say.
Your answer will determine if we can catch Kira.
Yagami Light was Kira.
And Kira's power passed on to someone else.
Right now, Yagami Light doesn't remember that he was Kira.
Give me your thoughts based on this premise.
Can you think about it in that way?
Yeah, I'll give it a shot.
Yagami Light was Kira.
And Kira's power passed to someone else.
Was it because Yagami Light wanted that to happen?
Or was there someone behind
Yagami Light who gave him Kira's power?
Did that person pass Yagami Light's power to someone else?
Under those circumstances,
it would be Yagami Light's choice.
Of course.
If there were someone who was moving that power from person to person
and didn't want the method of murder to be discovered,
it's strange that he took so long to move it from you to someone else.
If we acknowledge the existence of someone
watching down on us from above,
he would be impossible to catch.
I'd either be dead already,
or forever be dancing in the palm of his hand.
It's highly unlikely such a being exists.
Even if Light Yagami were Kira...
Kira's power can only move
by the will of the person who has it.
Yagami,
thanks to you, I feel ninety-nine percent better.
We shall create a situation in which Higuchi cannot pass his power on to anyone else,
and have him show us how he kills.
What are you going to do?
I'm going to trick Higuchi using Sakura TV.
A hidden-camera show?
What's that?
The Kira Special that Demegawa airs every week...
We'll take up a three-hour time slot
and right at the beginning,
we'll say that at the end of the program,
we're going to announce who Kira is.
Will he believe that?
It's Sakura TV, isn't it?
Besides, Higuchi might not watch that program.
We'll contact Namikawa
and have him call Higuchi and say, "This is bad. Turn on your TV."
When Higuchi realizes
that the person on TV knows his secret,
he'll believe us.
I see. So we're going to use Aiber.
He'll reveal that he was really a spy.
Not by a long shot.
We won't use Aiber.
The person who appears on that show
has to be someone whom Higuchi thinks he can kill.
In other words, someone whose name
he can easily look up.
Is there someone like that?
There's only Mr. Matsuda.
Matsu!
Matsuda, huh?
Higuchi probably thinks
that you were listening in on their meeting.
He'll believe that the manager
he thought was dead would rat him out.
That's right. I'll have Sakura TV prepare the screen and voice filter they always use for witnesses.
Higuchi would probably realize from the announcement and the silhouette that it's Matsui, the manager.
We'll have the station make a mistake
and accidentally flash the face
of the person behind the glass screen.
Wow! Sounds fun.
Until the show ends,
Kira's identity revealed at the end of this program!
we'll keep saying that we'll reveal the real name of H, who's Kira.
In this situation, Higuchi will have to discover his name as soon as possible.
We can anticipate Higuchi's actions.
And we'll be able to see how Kira kills.
After that, we'll apprehend him.
Right now, the only problem in this plan
is if Higuchi, like the Second Kira,
can kill by looking at someone's face,
Mr. Matsuda will die.
Since you're still alive
and he still wants Misa, that probably won't happen.
Well, this is a plan for when the criminals stop dying.
We'll have to watch for two or three days
to see whether that happens.
In that time, Mr. Matsuda must decide if he wants to do it.
I don't need two or three days.
Please let me do it.
What did you want to talk to me about in secret?
Namikawa,
who do you think Kira is?
Why do you want to know?
Besides, he could be either of you.
No, Shimura's not Kira.
He was just crying to me about how he
can't keep up with Kira's evil deeds anymore.
Shimura, if Mido were Kira, you would've been killed.
No, you and Mido would've been successful on your own.
You two wouldn't need to hold
those stupid meetings with eight people.
I know at least that much.
We're all cooperating because
we're afraid that Kira's going to kill us.
But if we continue,
the world will find out someday.
No, it won't end until that happens.
So, Shimura, let me ask you: who do you think is Kira?
Takahashi or Higuchi.
Takahashi is only there to make Kira look smarter.
He needs someone around
who's less sophisticated than he is.
It seems that everyone pretty much knows then.
It's probably Higuchi.
Yeah.
Higuchi is the one who lusts most for success and money.
The way he's always acting as if he's not interested in success
is proof of that.
Still, he's always making fun of people and doesn't know how to be a boss.
That's why he was demoted from being
the head of development to divisional head.
Was I the only one you called here?
I also called Ooi, but...
He said, "You can hold your silly secret meetings by yourself."
That sounds like the sort of impatient thing he'd say.
We know Kida isn't Kira because he provided the account to fund and commission Coil.
Namikawa, during the meeting after Hatori died,
you had a phone call.
Who was it from?
Shimura, you're really sharp.
Kira probably made you a member because he appreciates your caution.
It's Namikawa.
It's L.
Namikawa, are you by yourself?
No.
Then chime in as you see fit once again.
There's no need for that.
There's someone who got suspicious after you called me during the meeting.
Who called you, Namikawa?
L.
L, Mido and Shimura are here,
but I don't think they're Kira.
They seem to be sick of Kira.
Despite what they say, they choose to stand back and watch your face-off with Kira, just as I plan to.
That's fine.
Tonight, I'm going to catch Kira.
I want you to help me a little.
Higuchi's done, huh?
You knew?
It seems even L can be tricked.
Judging by your reaction,
now I'm absolutely sure it's Higuchi.
Namikawa is pretty good!
I was expecting that considering his looks.
No, Yagami just made a mistake.
We're going to make Higuchi move with a special on Kira
on Sakura TV which starts tonight at seven.
A few minutes into the program,
I want you to contact Higuchi and tell him to watch that show.
I won't do anything to the six of you.
If the others who aren't there — Kida, Takahashi, and Ooi —
try to do something, stop them.
Yes, all right.
So it really is Higuchi.
He'll probably be caught tonight.
It's been three days since I stopped killing criminals.
That should be good enough.
Now, If I marry the Second Kira, Amane,
I'll have the Shinigami eyes.
And I'll control everything Yotsuba has!
Higuchi, this is bad.
Turn on your TV to Sakura TV.
So one of these people is Kira, right?
Yes. I have a lot of proof.
What is this?
It's probably a hoax.
It is Sakura TV.
At the beginning of the program,
he said that he came across a meeting of eight people.
Someone who knows about the meetings?
Who is it?
Did someone betray us?
One of them was killed and now there are only seven left.
The victim was Mr. H.
H?
Hatori...
If he knows this much...
Is he one of the other six?
No, is he Coil?!
He was killed by Kira because he wanted to leave the meetings.
No. There'd be no benefit in it for him.
But there's no one else who knows about those meetings.
No, this guy is...!
I-It's him!
Misa's manager...
I think his name was Matsui!
How is he still alive?!
He thought he was going to be killed.
He took a chance, pretending to fall out of the condo
and escaping to a veranda on the floor below.
No. Just in case,
I went home and wrote his name in the notebook using his business card.
How is he still alive?
Was he a former entertainer
who became a manager under his stage name?
I don't know!
Furthermore, he says that he's continued to investigate Yotsuba
and has figured out who Kira is.
I'm contacting everyone right now.
All right. I'm going to hang up.
Are you all right from that mishap just now?
Shall we stop?
No, I'm well aware of the danger.
For justice, even if I'm killed,
I shall give it my best until the end!
That's more like it!
Don't make the Kira announcement until the end of the program.
I have to kill him.
If the Second Kira is Misa, she knows his face,
so she should know what his name is.
Here it is...
What is this?!
To be honest, I've been debating whether or not I should make this announcement.
But now that I'm here, I've decided it's my duty to reveal it.
This is no good.
The announcement will come soon.
I don't know when he's going reveal it.
Don't change your channel.
Cosme Misa.
Devilish charm...
and angelic glitter...
Misa's winning rouge...
Sent to you...
Mido, it's me.
Something bad is happening on Sakura TV.
Get your father in the House of Councilors.
Have the Ministry of Internal Affairs stop this program.
I'm watching, but that's impossible.
No one trusts this program anyway,
and we'd just look suspicious.
Besides, there's nothing to fear anymore.
That guy revealed his face.
We can confirm that it's Matsui Taro.
Namikawa is telling everyone to watch this show.
One of the seven of us is Kira.
So, Matsui Taro will die soon.
That's right!
I'm the only one who knows
that Matsui Taro is not his real name.
If I say that, then it'll reveal that I'm Kira.
Everyone! Kira's identity will become clear soon!
You're right. Talk to you later.
Stay with us!
Damn!
Ryuzaki.
Mogi, who's in front of Yoshida Productions, has received a call from Higuchi.
Yes. The next stage has come,
just as planned.
Moji, where's Misa?
Oh, Mr. Higuchi, a pleasure doing business with you.
Misa is taking a much-needed break right now.
She'll be back tomorrow... Yes.
I'm asking you, where is she?
Well, that's private information
that she doesn't want anyone to know.
I'm very sorry.
I can contact her tomorrow.
Damn... I know his face.
I could kill him at any time if I only knew his name!
Was her previous manager an ex-entertainer?
Pardon?
There was a guy by the name of Matsui Taro, right?
Oh, I came in as a replacement, so I don't know anything.
If that's the case, please contact someone at the office.
Oh, but everyone's gone to Okinawa.
Could you call our president?
Wow. It's going so precisely as planned that it's almost scary.
Don't be scared.
Rejoice, Yagami.
I shall broadcast Higuchi's call
to Yoshida Production's president.
This is Higuchi from Yotsuba.
Matsui Taro's not the real name of the guy
who was with you earlier, is it?
He's getting more and more direct.
Ah, he was using his manager's name.
Higuchi is an idiot.
It's proof that he's losing confidence.
I see.
So what's his real name?!
I believe it was Yamada—
no, Yamashita.
His first name...
I don't remember.
Don't fuck with me!
Remember the names of the people you hire!
What's with that tone?
I have his personal history back at the office.
Then go back there and tell me.
Give me a break!
I'm taking the first company vacation I've had in two years.
If you want to know that badly,
I'll tell you the security code for the office's door.
You can go right in and look around.
Personnel files are in the desk farthest back to the left.
They're alphabetized in the bottom drawer.
It's probably Yamashita.
If he's going to say it at the end of the program,
I still have two hours.
I wonder if he'll do it?
I've confirmed Higuchi.
He's only got a bag on him.
I'm going after him.
Everything's going according to plan, isn't it?
Yes.
I will kill him.
I've come this far.
I will not be stopped!
I'm going to have everything!
With this, I'm invincible!
Damn! I don't want to have to use this, but...!
Higuchi has a gun! The Chief's been shot!
This sounds kind of bad.
Higuchi! Hold it right there!
We'll get 100% ratings!
Give it up!
Think it over carefully.
We'll get 100% ratings!
I made it!