So one of these people is Kira, right?
Yes. I have a lot of proof.
The victim was Mr. H.
Kira's identity revealed at the end of this program!
If Higuchi, like the Second Kira,
can kill by looking at someone's face,
Mr. Matsuda will die.
I-It's him!
Don't fuck with me!
Remember the names of the people you hire!
I still have two hours.
I've confirmed Higuchi.
He's only got a bag on him.
I'm going after him.
I will kill him.
I'm going to have everything!
Cosme Misa.
Devilish charm...
and angelic glitter...
The commercial's going to end, Ryuzaki.
Misa's winning rouge...
Sent to you...
Is that so?
So I ended up drinking with the eight of them, including Kira.
That's amusing.
If I say too much,
the people who were there will know who Kira is,
so I can't say any more.
Yes. Let's save that revelation until the end.
Make speaker one Higuchi's car and speaker two Sakura TV.
Higuchi's watching TV in his car.
According to what you said earlier, you've met Kira?
Yes. But at that time, I didn't know who Kira was.
I think it takes a lot of courage to appear
even though he's seen your face.
Are you all right?
Yes. As I was investigating,
I discovered the two things that Kira needs in order to kill.
There are many rumors as to what they might be,
but I found out for sure.
A face and a name...
But Kira only knows one of those things about me.
He feels safe enough to step forward
just because I don't know his real name, huh?
Does that mean that there's nothing remaining
that connects him to his name?
If he already took his records into account,
is it pointless to go to Yoshida Productions?
Rem, what do you think?
What do I think? About what?
Rem?! Who's that?
He's in his car by himself.
I don't think that there's anyone else in that car.
He isn't using his cell phone either.
Could it be a radio or something?
No. There's no radio in that car.
Only our wire-taps, cameras, and tracking devices.
That's Wedy's job, so I'm sure.
Could it be that there won't be a record
on him even if I go to Yoshida Productions?!
Is he talking to himself?
There's no way I would know.
If he's smart, he would've destroyed everything
that connected him to his name before appearing on TV.
Also, don't you think that it's suspicious
for Yoshida Productions to just let me into their offices?
No, in this case, if there were a robbery,
the culprit would be me.
This sounds kind of bad...
It's all right. He'll go.
Even if he does have a record at Yoshida Productions,
what if it's filed under an alias?
Yes, there's a big possibility that he'd go that far.
It's probably Light and Misa's plan
to have Higuchi go to Yoshida Productions.
But if he knows that you're Kira,
then he'll end up announcing your name.
That is an inescapable fact.
All right, there's only an hour left until the announcement.
You have to go.
Whether or not there's an alias on his record,
there's no way that you'll be suspected if you kill him with the notebook.
Yeah. I know.
But just in case,
I should kill the people I called
from Yoshida Productions, Misa, and her manager.
What?! No way, he said he'll kill me!
It's all right.
He means after he's killed Mr. Matsuda.
There's no point for him to do that unless he's killed Mr. Matsuda.
That's true, but...
Think hard.
You only have to kill him.
If you kill the people whom you just called,
your call history will implicate you.
Oh yeah...
Rem, you sure are smart.
I'll kill them after I erase my call history.
But the telephone company will still have a record of it.
He can't be talking to himself.
Who's "Rem"?
Who is he talking to?
If he is talking to someone, it would have to be with...
a Shinigami.
Do you suppose?
Perhaps I should ask him...
How about returning ownership of the notebook to me?
No. I'll only meet a pathetic end if I do that.
He says he has proof.
If he were to highlight Yotsuba's growth,
no one would doubt him.
The person he says is Kira will be marked as Kira.
Even if he doesn't have concrete evidence,
my life will be over.
I won't be promoted.
I won't even be able to stay with Yotsuba.
We have structured this show
under the premise that Kira is watching.
Then I'll call out to Kira.
Kira, turn yourself in.
He acts like an idiot,
but earlier he escaped death by making it seem like he died.
I have to kill him.
He's arrived at Yoshida Productions.
It's about to begin.
To the left of the entrance...
In the desk farthest back...
In the bottom drawer...
Now, how are you going to kill?
Show me!
I'm ready to restrain Higuchi.
Just give me the order.
Got it.
It's no good!
He just made a note of his name and is leaving.
He's not going to kill him here?
Ryuzaki! Shall I restrain him?
I still don't know how he kills.
He might do something in his car.
Turn monitor one to Higuchi's car.
Higuchi is awfully calm despite wanting to kill Matsuda as soon as possible.
You're right.
If he needed a name, then he should've taken the personnel file with him.
But he just put it back in the drawer.
Thirty-six... Thirty-seven...
Thirty-eight... Thirty-nine...
Forty seconds.
Kira is a murderer,
so I cannot forgive him.
Damn! He won't die!
Wh-What's the meaning of this?!
He said, "He won't die!"
Did he just already try to kill?
Was writing his name all he had to do to kill?
What are you going to do?
Are you just going to keep watching him?
It seems like he can will a person to die with just their name.
What's going on?
I can't determine how he kills people.
But if I try to restrain him now and try to get him to confess...
There are only fifty minutes until the Kira announcement!
Damn! I don't have any time!
He's making a phone call.
Probably Misa again.
You're right!
Hey!
I know his face...
If I go back to the office, there should be surveillance camera footage of him sneaking in.
If I had the Shinigami eyes...
Half of my remaining life, huh?
But if he makes the announcement, my life is finished.
Well then, better to have a life that's short and sweet.
Rem. Let's make the deal.
Deal?
Who is this "Rem" he's been talking to all this time?
Could Kira's power be from heaven or something?
I don't want to think that's the case.
Then who's Rem?
A Shinigami?
At any rate, we should watch him.
It looks like we can still find out more.
We may be able to find out how he kills.
Now I'm unstoppable...
With this, my options are limitless.
I'm going after him!
Stop your car!
Pull over to the side of the road.
Pull over and stop!
This is bad.
Higuchi has been caught by a motorcycle policeman.
I'm going to pass him by.
I'll leave this to Aiber and the others.
You were speeding.
Show me your driver's license.
Yeah, all right.
All screens on Higuchi's car.
Where did I put my license?
I can't waste time sticking around here.
Hey!
Higuchi is escaping!
That bastard!
This is the highway patrol.
Th-The motorcycle cop just rear-ended a truck! It's a collision!
A collision?!
An accidental death?
This is bad.
Higuchi put his hand in his bag.
Did he do something then?
No, that aside,
how did he obtain the name of that motorcycle cop?
Could he have killed him
by looking at his face like the Second Kira?
Rem... Deal...
No...
If he could kill just by looking at someone's face,
he should have immediately killed Mr. Matsuda.
What's going on?
But...
Everyone! It's too dangerous to let Higuchi alone any longer.
We will proceed to capture him!
Higuchi, like the Second Kira,
is now able to kill just by looking at someone's face,
We will capture him with that in mind!
Watari,
connect me to the chief of the police department.
Yes.
This is L.
We have narrowed down Kira to a single person.
Currently, he's heading from Hibiya to Shibuya
on Highway Route One in a red sports car.
We shall capture him.
So please instruct all officers not to approach that car.
Dad, after the next commercial, start stage seven.
All right.
Demegawa, during the next commercial,
switch Matsuda and the emcee with mannequins.
We'll make it seem as if the broadcast is still continuing using the audio we've prepared.
We'll leave the cameras and everyone will withdraw.
Now then, Yagami, shall we go?
Yeah.
Sorry, Misa,
but I'm going to restrain you for a while.
What?! What's this?!
Stop kidding around!
I never knew you could pilot a helicopter, Ryuzaki.
It's intuition.
Higuchi isn't heading towards Sakura TV.
He's going the wrong way.
By his route, I'd say he's headed to Yotsuba's main offices.
That's incredible courage.
No, I just did what was appropriate.
If I go to the main offices
and find surveillance footage with him on it, I can kill him.
Wedy,
everything relating to Matsuda
at Yotsuba's main offices has been disposed of, right?
Yes. Is he headed there?
How convenient.
That'll give me time
to go ahead of him and wait with Mr. Yagami.
Damn! He's nowhere!
No, he's been erased from these videos.
Did he come and erase himself?
Or has someone betrayed me?
No, doing that wouldn't absolve them of their crimes.
At any rate, I don't have time.
I've gotta hurry!
The time for the announcement is approaching.
Yes. I feel like saying it already.
I understand your feelings,
but we'll have just one more commercial break right now.
Damn!
I'll just have to go to Sakura TV and kill him.
Dad,
Higuchi will arrive at Sakura TV soon.
He'll be there within fifteen minutes.
Are you all right?
I don't want my son to ask me if I'm all right.
I'm all right, Light.
Is there anything more you want to say before the announcement?
Well, I want everyone to think about Kira after he's caught.
Mr. Yagami, it's almost time.
Kira is definitely evil.
Yeah.
Here.
Aiber hates guns, so I'm the only one who's armed.
I'm no longer a police officer.
I'm not allowed to have this.
You're also not allowed to use this in Japan.
Stubborn as usual, aren't you?
I made it!
Why isn't anyone here?
Are they being careful
because they're broadcasting the truth?
Well, this'll be easier, since no one's here.
We've arrived at Sakura TV.
I'm getting into position.
Let's go, Aiber.
Okay, Mogi!
We're getting lots of phone calls and faxes
showing support for what you're doing here.
Even the studio is empty...
Still, I have to watch out for the television cameras.
I'm sorry, but due to the circumstances,
we must end this program here.
What?!
Mannequins!
No way!
Stop right there, Higuchi!
Don't move!
Give up.
Y-You must be making some kind of mistake.
I had something I wanted to talk to Mr. Demegawa about.
They're wearing helmets.
They've taken anti-Kira precautions...
In that case...
I'm from Yotsuba Group's development department.
I'll show you my card.
Chief!
Aiber!
Damn! I didn't want to have to use this, but...!
Higuchi has a gun!
The Chief has been shot.
Higuchi is making an escape!
I'm all right.
Sorry, Ryuzaki.
If we give chase immediately, we can still catch him.
Hurry!
This is bad.
He's escaped from Sakura TV!
We have no choice.
We shall proceed to capture him as well.
Watari, are you ready?
Ready.
Yagami...
Hold on to this for self-defense.
It's Kira we're after.
No. Those aren't allowed in Japan.
I'm sure your father said the same thing.
Yeah...
He's driving recklessly!
Don't lose sight of him!
Okay!
What was going on earlier?
It had to be a trap.
We now end our current broadcast to bring you the news.
The program ended, but I wasn't the one who ended it.
Damn... Who in the...
What's this?!
It was a trap after all.
Police cars with tinted windows?
The police have been taking anti-Kira measures.
What is this?
I told the police not to make any moves.
The only one who would do this is...
Yes, you're right.
Damn! If I go this way...
Stop right there!
Don't come any closer!
Don't you come near me!
It's over...
Yes. It is...
The human whose name is written in this notebook shall die.
This note will not take effect unless the writer
has the person's face in their mind when writing his/her name.
Therefore, people sharing
the same name will not be affected.