Ryuzaki, let me go.
Chief, I'll go too.
All right, but this is Kira.
Be careful when arresting him.
Don't let him see your face.
Watari,
if Higuchi makes even the slightest move...
Yes. I'll stop him without killing him.
Aizawa, do you have something to cover your face?
Yes.
Cover me.
Got it. Thank you very much, Chief!
Higuchi, put your hands up and get out of the car!
We've captured Higuchi!
Mr. Mogi, as planned, give Higuchi a headset.
Got it.
Higuchi,
how do you kill people?
Tell me!
I'll use whatever means necessary
to make you speak if you won't tell me.
The notebook.
Notebook?
You may not believe me,
but if I write the name of someone
whose face I know in that notebook, that person dies.
Notebook...
Mr. Yagami.
Yeah,
there's one in Higuchi's bag.
He's written names in it,
but it looks like any other notebook.
What's wrong, Mr. Yagami?
I-It's a monster!
Calm down.
You don't have a gun on you right now.
O-Oh yeah...
Are you all right, Chief?
M-Mogi, can't you see that?!
Chief, you're probably tired.
What's wrong, Mr. Mogi?!
Oh... Uh... I-It seems...
only people who've touched this notebook can see it.
This monster!
Bring the notebook to the helicopter.
Okay...
What in the world are you planning, Yagami Light?
When you take hold of the notebook once more,
all your memories
of when you had the Death Note will return.
But...
Ryuzaki, this is it.
That's a Shinigami, isn't it?
They really do exist...
Yagami Light, a notebook...
Show each other our notebooks in Aoyama...
Love at first sight...
Ryuzaki, let me see it too!
The Second Kira!
Two books!
There are more than two Notebooks in existence!
This isn't finished yet.
A Shinigami?
Write the name in the Death Note.
...and L.
...the god of the new world.
I'm L.
A-Are you all right?
Anyone would be surprised by that monster.
Ryuzaki.
What?
I'm going to try and match the names written in here
with the names of the victims.
Huh? Yes...
W-Well, of course.
I've won!
It's just as I planned.
I relinquish ownership of this notebook.
Now the ownership of the notebook has returned to you, Rem.
Am I right?
That's right. You're persistent!
Now give that notebook to Ryuk.
What?
Fine.
Now ownership of that notebook belongs to Ryuk.
Ryuk, drop that notebook
on the ground of the Human World again.
Huh? Well, okay.
Now ownership of this notebook belongs to me again.
Hold on, it's just gone around.
Nothing's changed.
Yeah, that may be true.
But there will come a time when this will be useful.
This notebook I first received...
I'm now going to return it to you, Ryuk.
Give it back to Rem.
Here.
Rem, give that to a person who has some status, a strong lust for power,
and who'll probably use the notebook solely for his own personal gain.
Misa will be released from her confinement if you do that.
If she's not released after several years, kill me.
How does that sound?
Yagami Light, what are you thinking?
This is to save Misa.
Trust me.
All right. If Misa will be saved, I'll do as you ask.
Later I'll make sure I'll be confined like Misa
and put under 24-hour surveillance.
While in confinement,
I will relinquish ownership of the notebook,
and lose all memory of the Death Note.
During that time, the killings of criminals will begin again.
If that continues,
Ryuzaki will have to release both of us sooner or later.
Since I've lost all my memory,
I'll probably try to catch Kira.
That's the kind of person I am.
And you'll try to catch the guy that Rem gives the notebook to
and steal the notebook before L gets to him.
That's right.
And at that time, I'll kill the owner of the notebook.
But there is one problem...
If you don't have ownership of the notebook,
your memory will only return
while you're touching the notebook.
Once you let go of it, your memory will disappear.
I'll kill Higuchi without letting go of this notebook!
If I do that, ownership will transfer back to me
and my memory won't disappear!
I have to pull here four times in less than a second.
All right...
I was wearing this watch.
Habits sure don't change.
Mr. Yagami, take Higuchi to the car.
Y-Yeah, all right.
This notebook...
What do you suppose we'll find
if we have it scientifically analyzed?
That's not like you.
That thing is beyond science.
That's true...
This is the longest forty seconds of my life.
Higuchi?!
Ryuzaki, Higuchi is...!
What's this?! What's going on?!
Hey, Higuchi!
Wh-What are you doing, Dad?!
If Higuchi dies now...
I-Impossible!
No, he's already...
Yeah, he's dead.
Ryuzaki...
you're next.
How to use...
The human whose name is written in this note...
shall die.
This note will not take effect unless the writer
has the person's face in their mind when writing his/her name.
Therefore, people sharing the same name will not be affected.
If the cause of death is written
within 40 seconds of writing the person's name,
it will happen.
If the cause of death is not specified,
the person will simply die of a heart attack.
After writing the cause of death,
details of the death should be written in the next 6 minutes and 40 seconds.
Additionally, instructions are on the back cover.
If you make this note unusable by tearing it up or burning it,
all the humans who have touched the note till then will die.
What?!
I-Is that true, Aizawa?!
Yeah, that's what's written.
That's right. With a rule like that,
my dad and the others won't try to dispose of it
No way! Why didn't you tell me before?
How was I supposed to know?!
That's right. With a rule like that,
my dad and the others won't try to dispose of it
and I won't lose my memory of this.
Rem, there's no way that the old man
will get mad at us if we write a fake rule here, will he?
No. There are no such rules against doing so.
Fine then.
Light, you owe me apples.
Man, I shouldn't have touched it
just because I wanted to see the Shinigami.
Then you'd be the only one who wouldn't know
what was going on in the investigation.
Would that be okay?
No, I want to work on the same terms as everyone else.
And...
this last sentence...
If the person using the note
fails to continuously write names of people to be killed
within 13 days of each other,
then the user...
will die.
What?
That means...
Light and Misa-Misa are completely cleared!
Yes, indeed...
Light and Amane were detained
for more than fifty days and are still under surveillance.
There's no way they'd still be alive if they're both Kira.
Aren't you glad, Chief?!
Yeah.
Rem...
You, the white-colored Shinigami.
R-Ryuzaki! That's rude!
Referring to her by her skin color...
Yes, it is...
There are other notebooks in the Human World, aren't there?
Who knows?
There may be. There may not be.
If there were other notebooks,
are all their rules the same?
It's useless, Ryuzaki...
You can't break this rule with Rem.
Yeah, they're the same.
There are many notebooks in the Shinigami Realm,
but their rules are all the same.
Even the rules for when humans obtain them.
Ryuzaki...
Light and Amane are cleared.
Their surveillance is over.
That's right. It's already clear.
You're right...
I understand.
I'm very sorry about everything that's happened until now.
Thank goodness...
Yeah.
But we still can't say that we've solved the case.
I want these handcuffs removed,
but can I continue to investigate here?
Yes...
Misa and I are now completely cleared.
He has to believe the fake rule that was written by a Shinigami
in the notebook of death.
With these fake rules
that I conjured up, Ryuzaki's lost his edge.
Listen, Ryuzaki...
In any world, rules are always created by those who are gods.
You will be beaten by the rule I have created,
and for the crime of defying the god of the new world,
you'll pay with your life.
Light!
Text me every day.
We're finally saying good-bye to Misa-Misa...
Hey, Matsuda, leave those two alone!
See you later, Misa-Misa!
Come on!
The surveillance cameras can't see my mouth at this angle.
Misa, I'm going to tell you about a certain place.
I want you to dig up something from there when no one is watching.
Light, your memory has returned!
It's all right. I'll do a good job!
Light, I remember.
I remember everything that happened
when I had this notebook.
You buried this notebook so I could remember.
Misa,
by the time you read this letter,
you should have remembered everything.
A letter from Light!
Do you remember my friend at To-oh University
who went by the name Ryuga Hideki?
I want you to write his name in the notebook,
and kill him.
Also, burn this letter,
hide a few pages of the notebook with you,
and bury the notebook.
When you meet me again,
casually touch me with a piece of the notebook.
If you do this, Amane Misa, I will...
..."love you for the rest of my life."!
love you for the rest of my life.
All right!
I see. This is Light's plan!
He wanted me to get this notebook, regain my memory...
and kill Ryuga Hideki... Ryuzaki.
One of Light's obstacles
will disappear and I'll be helpful to him!
It's no good, Light.
I can't remember his name.
I saw hundreds of names and life spans every day.
I can't remember at all!
I'm so stupid!
I'm finally able to come back!
Ryuk!
It's been a while! How are you?
Sorry, but...
Huh?
I'm male. You're making me shy.
Oh yeah...
Here.
Light told me to bring this.
Is it really that delicious?
Yeah.
Apples in the Human World are... what's the word, "juicy"?
At any rate, they're great.
Do you want to try it?
It's an apple from the Shinigami Realm.
It doesn't look very good.
Come on, just one bite.
Oh yeah, Ryuk...
Do the eye deal with me.
Sand!
A deal, huh?
You understand, don't you?
You've made a deal with Rem once before.
Do you really want to halve your life a second time?
Hmm... Well, I have to do this.
I've forgotten the name I had to remember.
Light will be angry with me if I don't take a look at it again.
Well, it's fine with me.
Oh, it's Misa-Misa.
The poor thing. We can't turn on our cell phones here,
so she has to come and visit you.
Light, go to her quickly.
You shouldn't make a woman wait.
Yeah.
Ryuk!
Why is he attached to Misa?
Misa's life has been halved once more!
It can't be... Did she do the eye deal with Ryuk?!
Light...
It's been a while, Ryuk.
L-Light, I'm sorry.
I don't remember Ryuga Hideki's real name.
I just can't remember.
I see.
That's too bad.
B-But I did the eye deal with Ryuk!
Everything is going as planned, huh?
Idiot! Your lifespan has been...
No, it's all right.
I want to help you.
Misa, right now, I want to live with you
for a long time in an ideal world.
That's how I feel.
Light, I'm so happy!
Misa...
Let's make a new world without crime...
a world with only kind people.
Let's!
Good-bye.