What seems to be the trouble, Ryuzaki?
What's wrong?
The corner of this page from this killer notebook is cut out.
Would someone still die if their name
was written on the part that has been cut out?
Who knows?
I haven't used it in that way, so I don't know.
Then do Shinigami only eat apples?
No.
But a Shinigami's organs are devolved—no, evolved,
so there's no need for us to eat.
Yagami...
You've finally been freed, but you never leave headquarters.
Even if Misa comes to visit,
you only chat with her for a few minutes.
You're free to go and have
a love life outside of here, you know.
We still haven't solved the Kira case.
I'm not in the mood for love.
Or are you trying to say that I'm a nuisance if I stay here?
No...
Right now, I'm in no position to be punishing criminals.
Misa,
punish them for me.
let's make a new world together.
What do you mean?
The murders of criminals have begun again?
There were sixteen just yesterday.
They were broadcast after Higuchi died.
That's thorough, huh?
I guess that means Higuchi wasn't necessarily Kira.
No, we're positive that Higuchi
was the one killing criminals until we caught him.
Then does that mean another Kira has appeared?
Why?!
Damn... Curse Kira...
Kira appears now...
What's going on?
Just what is going on?
There's only Misa.
This happened as soon as Misa was freed, didn't it?
Ryuzaki, you're still saying that?
Misa is not involved.
It happened as soon as Higuchi died.
You're right...
Well, if there is another notebook and someone is using it...
I'll catch him.
The Shinigami said it didn't know,
but if someone could kill by writing a name
on a clipping from the notebook...
It's not impossible...
But whoever writes a name in this notebook
has to write another name within thirteen days, or they'll die.
Yagami Light and Amane Misa are both alive.
Thirteen days...
This is the only...
Ryuzaki, even if we do catch the person who was writing in the notebook,
can we really convict and punish him as a serial killer?
Well, of course!
He wrote countless names knowing that people would die.
We should kill him if we don't want
the existence of the notebook to go public.
Killing him is harsh,
but I bet that's what our superiors would demand.
If he admits to killing with the notebook, he would receive the death penalty.
Or at least a life sentence.
Something like that.
What are you thinking, Yagami Light?
If Misa is caught, you'll also be...
So that's it!
That bastard!
Light Yagami is sure that I'll save Misa's life.
In order to save Misa in this situation,
I'll have to write Ryuzaki's real name in my notebook.
And if I kill Ryuzaki...
it'll definitely affect Misa's lifespan and I'll die as well.
Yagami Light is making everything go his way.
What are you going to do, Rem?
I know completely that despite
being a Shinigami, you care about Misa.
Misa's life has been halved. There's no way you'd abandon her.
Think about Misa's happiness.
What are you doing there, Ryuzaki?
What are you doing there, Ryuzaki?!
What are you up to, Ryuzaki?
Well, nothing in particular, but...
The sound of the bells...
Bells?
Yes.
The bells have been really noisy throughout the day.
I haven't heard anything.
Really?
They've been ringing all day
and I can't help but feel curious.
Do you suppose it's a church?
A wedding?
Or perhaps...
What are you talking about, Ryuzaki?
Don't say such silly things.
Let's go back.
I'm sorry.
Everything I say is complete nonsense,
so please don't believe any of it.
That's right, Ryuzaki.
Most of what you say is nonsense.
There would be no end if I took you seriously all the time.
I know that the best.
Yes, that's right, Light.
But...
it's true for both of us.
What do you mean?
Have you ever told the truth at any point in your life?
What are you talking about, Ryuzaki?
It's true that I lie once in a while.
But how many people live their entire lives
only telling the truth?
Humans aren't made perfectly.
Everyone lies.
Even so,
I've been careful not to tell lies that hurt others.
That's my answer.
I thought you'd say that.
Let's go back.
We're drenched.
Yeah.
Well, that was awful.
It's your fault.
You were standing in that rain.
You're right.
I'm sorry.
What are you doing, Ryuzaki?
I thought I'd help you,
since you're vigorously wiping yourself off.
You don't have to do that.
I can give you a massage as well.
It's the least I can do to atone.
I'm pretty good.
Do as you please.
All right.
Hey...
You'll get used to it.
You're still wet.
I'm sorry.
How sad...
What?
We'll soon part.
Yes.
All right. I'll come immediately.
Let's go, Light.
It seems it went well.
Oh, Ryuzaki! What is the meaning of this?!
I heard that you got approval from another country
to use the notebook for an execution!
Watari...
Good job.
Not at all.
Let's immediately
make arrangements to transport the notebook.
Yes.
Ryuzaki, what's the meaning of this?
It means that I'm going to try out the notebook for real.
That's pointless! We don't have to do that...
We already know that the power of the notebook is real, don't we?
Besides, who's going to write the name?
Once you write in the notebook, you have
to continue writing names every thirteen days!
The one who's going to write the name
is someone who'll be executed within thirteen days.
If he's still alive after thirteen days,
we've made a deal to commute his execution.
But we can't sacrifice people's lives—
Just a little more.
If we just clear this,
the case will be solved.
Wh-What's this?!
A blackout?!
Watari?
Data deletion?
What's the meaning of this?!
I told Watari to erase all information
in the event that something happened to him.
If something happened to him?
Could it be...
Where's the Shinigami?
Come to think of it, I don't see him.
He's nowhere!
What's the meaning of this?!
Everyone, the Shiniga—
Ryuzaki!
What's wrong?!
Hey! Ryuzaki!
What's wrong?! Get a hold of yourself!
Wh-What's this?!
What's going on?
Calm down, Light!
We're next!
Watari, Ryuzaki, we're next!
Damn!
Where are you, Shinigami?! Come out!
L-Light!
You must know something! Come out!
Let's search as well.
Y-Yeah...
Mogi, please stay with him.
Got it.
Everyone, come here.
Wh-What is this?
Sand?
What's going on?
Whatever it is...
Whatever happened...
I will avenge Ryuzaki.
Solving this case will be our gift...
for Watari and the other victims...
for all people.
Light...
That's right, Light.
Yeah, but we're going to be killed.
Isn't that what this means?
Matsuda, if you're scared of dying, leave the investigation.
Only people who have chosen to risk their lives should be here.
Oh... no. That's right,
b-but, Light, don't talk like Ryuzaki.
All those in my way have disappeared.
I'm the god of the new world.
Ryuzaki...
Watari...
Rem...
All those in my way have disappeared.
I'm...
the god of the new world.