Wh-What's this?!
Everyone, the Shiniga—
Try and kill me!
I told you that this is a live broadcast worldwide,
but this is only being broadcast in the Kanto region of Japan.
The first victim was the killer in Shinjuku.
Furthermore, his crime was only broadcast in Japan.
I have been able to deduce this much.
You are in Japan
and your first victim was your guinea pig.
Kira has found a way to obtain information from task force headquarters.
There are 141 people within the police force alone
who have access to classified information
on the Kira investigation.
But one of the 141 people
or someone close to them...
Kira is definitely among them!
On December 14th,
twelve FBI agents entered Japan.
December 19th...
Kira began using prisoners to conduct tests concerning actions a victim can take before death.
In order to eliminate all of the FBI agents,
he had to see how far
he could control the death of his victims.
Thus, I suspect that Kira was one of the people
who was being investigated
by the FBI between the 14th and the 19th.
Raye Penber's fiancée?
Misora Naomi...
So that's it...
She worked under me on that case and now she's in Japan.
She was with Penber.
She might have found a clue.
If that's the case, did Kira get to her first?
Everyone,
from now on, we'll focus our investigation on the people whom Raye Penber was investigating while in Japan.
Deputy Director General Kitamura and his family,
and Detective Superintendent Yagami and his family.
I also wish to place wiretaps and surveillance cameras in both households.
Ryuzaki, are you telling me that you suspect my son?
I suspect him.
I'm L.
Don't worry, Yagami.
Kira hates to lose,
but most people don't like to lose. It's not just Kira.
See, you came in for the win.
Yagami, I suspect that you're Kira.
I'm Kira?
Ryuga.
Is there any way that I can get you
to believe that I'm not Kira?
It's all right.
We'll know in time if you aren't Kira.
Four days ago, our program director was sent these four tapes.
Our audience rating could go up sixty—no, seventy percent.
One tape predicts the killings,
and the other sends a message to the people of the world.
I am Kira.
The anchor, Mr. Hibima Kazuhiko,
will die of a heart attack at exactly six o'clock.
Something terrible will happen if we don't stop this broadcast!
You moron!
Ukita!
Kira shouldn't be able to kill without a name!
But from what I just saw,
it's not entirely impossible
that he may only need a face to kill.
This is the police!
Stop this program!
There is a high possibility that this Kira is a fake.
No,
we should call him the Second Kira.
Mr. Yagami.
May I ask your son to cooperate in this investigation?
There is a good chance that this is not the Kira we've known until now.
It's exactly the same deduction that L — I mean, Ryuzaki, made.
When we meet,
we can confirm our identities
by showing our Shinigami to each other.
What is it?!
If there is a code that only people who have the so-called Shinigami power can understand,
I won't be able to decode it.
But we should thoroughly check out
the places listed in the diary.
Please be sure to keep a watchful eye on Light.
In the event that Light is Kira,
the Second Kira might try to contact him.
Also, Mr. Yagami...
I would like Mr. Mogi to keep watch over Light's activities.
Light! There you are!
I'm Light's girlfriend, Amane Misa.
Pleased to meet you.
I'm Ryuga Hideki.
Huh?
Ryuga Hideki?
This may be good news and bad news to you,
but Amane Misa has just been taken into custody under suspicion of being the Second Kira.
When the Second Kira sent
the video tapes from Amane's room,
they left a great deal of evidence, such as hairs and clothing fibers, stuck to the masking tape used to seal the envelopes.
R-Ryuzaki!
What's the meaning of this?!
Now, hurry! Kill me!
You should be able to kill me immediately, right?!
Is this because you admit to being the Second Kira?
No! I don't know anything about the Second Kira...
Ryuzaki, I told you over the phone,
but I think I may be Kira.
But for him to say that he may be Kira?
It's an act.
It's not that you may be Kira, but that you are Kira.
Light, are you all right?
Yeah, I know I probably look pretty bad in here.
But this useless pride... I'll just have to...
get rid of it.
Ryuzaki!
I know I agreed to be detained
and chose to do this.
But now I just clearly realized...
I'm not Kira!
Get me out of here quickly!
What's going on? Two weeks worth of criminals
were murdered all at once yesterday!
I can't make sense of anything that's happening.
It seems like all three of them are at their limit.
Ryuzaki,
why are you still confining Light?
It's already been fifty days.
I'm going to kill you here and then kill myself.
Wh-What are you talking about, Dad?!
Stop it already! You're crazy!
Th-That's crazy!
It would be better if we ran away.
It's too late, Light.
Stop, Dad! I'm not Kira!
Light...
From one murderer to another, I'll see you in hell.
Dad!
Stop!
It was a convincing performance.
As I promised, I will end their confinement.
Also, Light, I will arrange things so that
you and I will be together 24 hours a day,
working on the investigation.
They're deaths that are in Yotsuba's favor.
Checking back,
there have been as many as thirteen such cases in the past three months.
Is Kira someone from Yotsuba?
Or is Kira using Yotsuba?
I haven't figured that out yet,
but let's investigate this with the assumption that this is Kira's doing.
Let's thoroughly investigate Yotsuba!
Please be sure not to act out of panic or haste.
And don't take matters into your own hands.
My name is Matsui Taro.
How would you like to use
Amane Misa in your commercials?!
Ryuzaki, are you watching?
The eight of them who came were having a meeting to determine whom to have Kira kill for them.
If Matsuda dies, that would justify the suspicion against Yotsuba.
Is there anything I can do to save myself?
Matsuda, you idiot.
Good luck, Misa-Misa!
I'll be waiting to celebrate when they decide
to put you in their commercials!
It's my dream to become Kira's bride.
Because I'm...
the Second Kira.
Well then, I'm Kira, so marry me, Misa!
And there you have it!
Higuchi is Kira!
What are you going to do?
I'm going to trick Higuchi using Sakura TV.
A hidden-camera show?
Higuchi, this is bad.
Turn on your TV.
So one of these people is Kira, right?
Yes. I have a lot of proof.
I-It's him!
How is he still alive?!
I've confirmed Higuchi.
I'm going after him.
I'm going after him!
Stop your car!
Pull over and stop!
Rem. Let's make the deal.
Deal?
You were speeding.
Show me your driver's license!
Yeah, all right.
Shiraba Yukito              Accident
Hey!
Higuchi is escaping!
This is the highway patrol.
Everyone!
It's too dangerous to let Higuchi alone any longer.
We will proceed to capture him.
Higuchi, like the Second Kira,
is now able to kill just by looking at someone's face,
We will capture him with that in mind!
Stop right there!
Don't you come near me!
Higuchi,
how do you kill people?
You may not believe me,
but if I write the name of someone whose face
I know in that notebook, that person dies.
Yeah, there's one in Higuchi's bag.
What's wrong, Mr. Yagami?
I-It's a monster!
That's a Shinigami...
There are more than two notebooks in existence!
This isn't finished yet.
How to use...
The human whose name is written in this note...
shall die.
And this last sentence...
If the person using the note
fails to continuously write names of people to be killed
within 13 days of each other, then the user will die.
Yagami Light and Amane Misa are alive.
Thirteen days...
This is the only...
The following is the record which contains everything
I have investigated on the Kira Incident.
The fact that now you are reading this message
means I am no longer alive at this moment.
I hereby leave this record as my firm achievement.
It's been ten days since Ryuzaki's secret funeral.
It looks like we aren't going to die.
We now know Watari's identity, but in the end,
we didn't find out anything about Ryuzaki.
It seems Watari was actually an amazing inventor.
He created orphanages worldwide with the fortune he made from several of his patents.
He's a hero! A hero!
But we can't continue investigating here
now that L and Watari are gone.
This is tough...
Yeah...
Light, how is it going?
I can remove the entire system here by tonight.
I don't feel good about it.
It feels like stealing.
I've created a voice like the one that Ryuzaki used.
We can act like he's still alive
and control the police as we've been doing.
But who will replace L?
Where will we do it?
What'll we do with the killer notebook?
What are you talking about, Light?!
The only one who can play the role of L is you!
If Ryuzaki was killed by Kira for challenging him,
I don't feel comfortable about it.
Besides that, it'll be tricking the people of the world.
I understand your feelings,
but you're the only one who can do this.
That's right.
Ryuzaki said it as well.
You'd be capable of succeeding L.
How facile...
It's no fun without Ryuzaki.
Yeah, all right. I'll do it.
But I won't do anything dangerous
like challenging Kira directly to gain clues, like Ryuzaki did.
Is that okay?
Yes.
That would be better and safer.
Ryuzaki may have been too confrontational.
In that case,
I can do about the same work with this computer and my own.
It's also possible to be L from my room at home.
I'll also be Watari.
But it would be difficult to do this with my mom and little sister around.
It would be good if I could rent a one-room apartment.
There's nothing suspicious about renting a room for my son to live on his own.
That's right. Then the place he'll be renting out will be task force headquarters.
Yes.
All that's left is what to do with the killer notebook.
There's no need to think too hard.
We'll just have one of the five of us,
whom we trust will never use the notebook, hide it somewhere where no one can get to it.
Chief, please do this!
We can count on you!
You're a pillar of justice!
Me, huh?
All right...
Let's avenge Ryuzaki!
Yeah.
Yes. Kira's still here.
Let's catch him!
Well then, let's have a party
to celebrate Light becoming the second L.
Quit fooling around, now's not the time.
Now, now...
Light!
It's our first date in a while.
Enjoy yourself a little more...
Misa...
Let's live together.
Huh?!
R-Really?!
Yeah. I've already rented a room.
All right! We're living together! Misa wins!
Misa wins?
You know, against Kiyomi and Mari and Yuri.
It's all right, Light.
You just used them to trick L, didn't you?
I understand.
You won't see them anymore, right?
Right...
Say...
Is your score finally settled with L?
Yeah.
Then I can't expect anything interesting anymore.
That's not true, Ryuk.
Hm?
From now on...
I'll show you the creation of a new world.
Oh?
Papa!
Papa!!
Yotsuba's reconstruction is just beginning.
Y-Yeah.
Let's do our best!
Hm?
H-Hey, Namikawa?
Huh?! I-Impossible!
In April, 2012, Yagami Light, age twenty-three, joins the National Police Agency.
In the summer of 2012,
Kira's judgments gain momentum.
The world screams in fear of Kira,
but privately it cheers for him.
Slowly but surely, their true thoughts arise,
and some countries even express their acceptance of Kira.
The world continues towards a dark era where Kira is the law.
What is it, Roger?
L is dead.
About L's death?
From whom?
From where?
A kidnapping?
Who kidnapped whom?
Are they joking?
But...
This strange feeling...
What is it?