What did you say, Roger?!
Say it again!
L is dead.
Dead?!
Why?
Did Kira kill him?
Is that it?
Probably...
He said that he would get Kira executed, and was killed!
Is that what you're saying?!
Mello...
If you can't beat the game...
If you can't solve the puzzle...
You're nothing but a loser.
Me or Near?
So which one of us did L...
Neither one of you yet...
He can't choose if he's dead.
Mello, Near...
How about the both of you work together?
Sure. Sounds good.
That's impossible, Roger.
You know that Near and I don't get along.
We've always competed against each other.
Always...
It's fine, Roger.
Near should succeed L.
Unlike me, Near will solve this unemotionally, like a puzzle.
I'm leaving...
this institution.
Mello!
I'm almost fifteen, anyway.
I'll live my life my own way.
A police officer who happened
to be nearby when Higuchi was arrested
heard that if you write the name of someone you know in the notebook, that person will die.
Are you saying that's what the notebook of death is?
Yes.
The Japanese police should have it right now.
Mr. President,
the current L is one whom the Japanese police
have created to avoid confusion.
L is dead.
Director Mason,
who is he?
Well...
He is, shall we say... L's true successor.
But...
it's impossible to censor the Internet
and the Kira case has slowed to a dead-end lately.
Maybe those who show people
they want killed on the Internet should be killed.
But Kira gets some of his information from the Internet, so he won't kill them.
Matsu, your idea is full of contradictions.
If only people wouldn't do bad things...
Or rather, the world's become a good place for the innocent.
I suppose there are people who might believe that.
Look who's talking.
No, soon everyone will think in that way.
Are you talking about that again?
Stop it...
Dear, Light.
I'm home...
Welcome back!
Welcome home, Sayu.
Light, Misa.
It's unusual for both of you to be here.
Welcome.
Pardon the intrusion.
Mr. Matsuda, wasn't it?
Oh, yes!
It's been a while.
Thank you for taking care of my father.
S-Sayu...
Y-You've grown into a beautiful woman.
When I last saw you, you were this tall.
Matsu's beet red!
Huh? No way...
There's no way I'm letting Sayu marry a detective.
Huh?
That's right.
I definitely don't want that.
What? No way!
I never even got to propose or even confess that I love her...
Mom and Dad.
Dad?!
Mo...
Well, I think you're wonderful.
What? R-Really, Sayu?
Yes. I might have considered going out with you if you were a little younger.
You've sure learned how to talk.
Really. She's more mature than Matsu.
But, Light, you haven't changed one bit
and you're as wonderful as when I first met you.
Light, you've already found a career,
so stop living together in secret and get married already.
That sounds good!
What an unfortunate and heartwarming family.
How interesting!
What is it, Aizawa?
Yes.
All right.
Matsuda, Light,
come with me.
A kidnapping?
Who kidnapped whom?
Director Takimura of the NPA.
I don't know by whom.
Damn! As if the current situation with the Kira case wasn't enough...
Are you sure?
I got the phone call at 6:12.
Forty-five minutes ago.
We determined it was from the director's cell phone.
Did the kidnappers make any demands?
Well...
They wanted to trade the director...
for the killer notebook.
Who? For what purpose?
Do you suppose it's Kira?
Well, if the existence of the Death Note were leaked,
countless people would want it.
Dad,
how much does the director know?
We tried to keep the knowledge of the notebook within our group.
That's right. I never discussed it with the director.
The existence of the Death Note...
Someone knows that the NPA has it,
and they've come to take it.
Notify every bureau of the NPA
only about the director's kidnapping.
Yes.
Is it a call from the culprit?!
No.
There's someone who wants to meet Director Takimura.
What?
I'm an agent with the FBI.
The name's John McEnroe.
Of course, this is an alias...
since what I am doing concerns Kira.
Please forgive me.
Kira...
The Director is out at the moment.
If it's all right, I'll listen to what you have to say.
Well, that's fine.
Excuse me for getting straight to the point,
but the Japanese police is unreliable.
In order to solve the Kira case,
we want you to hand over the notebook to our country.
So it was the FBI!
Where have you taken our director?!
Wh-What are you talking about?
Don't act like you don't know!
This is a brazen criminal offense!
What would we gain by hiding the director of Japan's NPA?
Then how do you know about the notebook?!
What's going on?
It seems that the director of the NPA has been kidnapped by someone.
By someone who wants the notebook...
Commander Rester.
Suggest to him that we'd like to help rescue the director and apprehend the culprit.
We'll take the notebook when we have the chance.
All right.
Can you hear me?
This is headquarters.
These are your orders.
Has he said anything?
The Japanese police have begun to wimp out on Kira.
It seems that the only ones who are working with L are Yagami Soichiro, Mogi Kanzo, and Matsuda Touta.
Isn't that right?
Yeah...
There was another named Ukita, but he died.
Even though you were the director of the NPA,
you didn't know about the notebook?
The Japanese police really suck.
The highest ranking of the three is Yagami,
who was the chief detective of the task force, right?
Y-Yeah...
I think there are two notebooks.
Kira has one.
The NPA has the other.
We'll take both.
There's no mistake if Mello says so.
Has he ever been wrong
since he joined us a year and a half ago?
But why is the guy who brought us
the head of a mafia boss whom Kira couldn't kill
so fixated on the notebook?
I don't just want the notebook.
I want to kill everyone who stands in my way,
and be number one!
By whatever means necessary,
before Near does...
B-Boss!
What is it? Be quiet.
Sorry. Eddie and I were just talking
and Takimura hanged himself with his necktie!
You idiot!
What good is a dead hostage?!
No, that's fine.
If Kira is responsible for this,
he can't touch us, since he doesn't know our names or faces.
Thus, he went after Takimura.
Which means...
Kira is someone who knows about this kidnapping.
What are you going to do, Mello?
Kidnap Yagami Soichiro's daughter,
Yagami Sayu, next.
We still don't have any leads
on the director or the kidnappers.
Aside from that, why haven't they said anything since they kidnapped him?
Light,
there's no mistake that the FBI agent
John McEnroe's real name
is really Larry Conners.
Is that so? Thank goodness.
He's a real agent.
The director of the FBI
also said that he would help us rescue Director Takimura.
I think we can trust him.
The director should already be dead.
Why aren't they saying anything?
Would they give up on the deal just because he died?
I didn't think we were dealing with such weaklings.
Dad...
No, everyone here should be careful.
The director may not know about the notebook,
but he knows who was working with L.
If that gets out,
there's a chance that they'll come after us.
Light!
I'll be a good girl tonight and go to sleep alone, okay?
Yeah, good night.
Good night!
Then I'll stay here.
We're not the only ones in danger.
Our families and...
The director's cell phone...
It's from the kidnappers!
Aizawa!
Yes, tracing!
This is Yagami.
Mr. Deputy Director?
About the trade of the director for the notebook...
It's canceled.
Takimura is dead.
What?!
Wh-Why you...
However, it's only canceled with respect to the director.
We'll now trade the notebook
for Yagami Sayu.
You're the deputy director of the NPA.
It would be ridiculous to expect you not to tell the police.
But I want you to move by yourself.
I'll kill your daughter if I see the police do anything big.
That's right...
As swiftly as we killed the director.
I'll send you a picture of Takimura's corpse.
Take a good look.
I'll contact you tomorrow.
H-Hey!
They got me.
They used the death of the director as an opportunity to get Sayu.
Light, things have gotten interesting again.
Sir...
Why would they go this far?
Damn!
Yes, yes.
Dear,
you never call from your work phone.
Huh? Sayu?
Who knows?
Come to think of it, she's late.
Sayu...
Dad, are you all right?
I think that it was Kira,
not the kidnappers, who killed the director.
Huh?
What?!
He probably doesn't want
the notebook to be passed to criminals.
Kira is acting as an icon of justice,
so he doesn't want the notebook to fall into criminal hands.
If Kira killed the director,
it's possible that he has methods
to obtain information within the police department.
It's best if we were the only ones to investigate.
Otherwise...
...Kira will kill the hostage again.
That's right.
Near.
The kidnapped director of the Japanese NPA was killed.
By whom?
By whom you ask?
By the kidnappers...
It would be interesting if it were Kira.
Indeed.
They can't get the notebook if their hostage is dead.
Also, if it were Kira,
I can narrow down the suspects.
By the way, Commander Rester...
Have you tracked his whereabouts?
Well,
we're certain that he left the institution
four years ago, as you said,
but we don't know anything else after that.
Then it's decided.
Mello, you always overlook the most important things
because you become too emotional.
Or maybe...
you're not involved in this case at all?
How could you leave your picture at the orphanage?
This is Yagami.
Your daughter has finally arrived here.
Here?
You have a pretty good idea of where this is, don't you?
We'll do the exchange here.
At any rate, bring the notebook
to Los Angeles by yourself in two days.
I won't do the exchange
unless I know that my daughter's safe.
Let me hear her voice!
All right. All right.
I'll send you another picture.
Sayu!
Sir,
we've narrowed them down to Fifth Street in Los Angeles.
The TV show on in the background
is definitely being broadcast right now.
They showed us that on purpose to let us know she's all right.
Th-Thank goodness...
At least she's alive...
I'm taking the notebook to Los Angeles.
As the deputy director of the NPA
and as Yagami Sayu's father!
I'll make all the decisions and take full responsibility!
Dad!
We have to devise a plan first.
That's right, Deputy Director.
But I have to be in Los Angeles within two days.
Time is not on our side.
So you're saying that it was Kira,
not the kidnappers, who killed Takimura?
I'm just saying that it's a possibility.
If so, it means Kira gained information
from the Japanese police.
Yes?
This is L.
It's L. The current one.
Director, I've heard what Agent John McEnroe—
no, what Larry Conners had to say from Deputy Director Yagami.
Will you help us with NPA Director Takimura's murder investigation?
Well...
Pass me the phone.
Nice to meet you, L Number Two.
Number Two?
What do you mean by that?
Who are you?
It's useless to try and hide it.
We are the SPK, a new organization
established to capture Kira without the help of L.
Seven of our top members know of L's death.
L's death?
From whom? From where?
And I am at the center of the SPK.
I guess I would be...
N.
N?
Is he joking?
But...
This strange feeling...
What is it?
Damn! What's going on?!
I checked the crew of today's flight ahead of time.
There wasn't anyone suspicious.
I can still make it.
At this rate,
is my only option to kill...
Sayu?