Nice to see you.
Thank you for taking care of my father.
S-Sayu...
Y-You've grown up...
This is Yagami.
Mr. Deputy Director?
About the trade between the chief and the notebook...
It's canceled.
What?!
We'll now trade the notebook
for Yagami Sayu.
At any rate, bring the notebook
to Los Angeles by yourself in two days.
Nice to meet you, L Number Two.
I am at the center of the SPK.
I guess I would be...
N.
N?
Is he joking?
But...
This strange feeling...
What is it?
N... He's similar to...
This feeling... He's like L...
I said I wouldn't rely on L.
That means that the CIA and the FBI rely on me rather than L
to make their decisions.
However, the murder of the Director
of the Japanese NPA is an unforgivable crime.
I think there is a possibility
that this case could lead to the arrest of Kira.
So I will lend you my full support.
Lead to the arrest of Kira?
Just who does he think he is?
This confidence...
What's wrong, L?
Nothing.
Actually, after the director was murdered,
Deputy Director Yagami's daughter was kidnapped by someone
whom we believe to be the same person who killed the director.
They contacted us to make a deal in Los Angeles.
A deal? In exchange for the notebook, right?
That's right.
I understand. I'll gather as many investigators as I can
in Los Angeles without telling them the details.
And I'll use a satellite to monitor the L.A. area.
No...
I'll let you have total authority on this, L.
Thank goodness.
We make the decisions.
But what was that about
the Americans not trusting L anymore?
Near, are you sure about leaving this to a fake L
who hasn't succeeded in catching Kira?
So much the better.
It means that there's a chance we can take advantage of him.
Of course, people's lives are our first priority.
But as the SPK, our goal is simply
to get the notebook and capture Kira.
Light...
I don't care if it costs me my life.
Just save Sayu...
please...
Don't be foolish.
You may be satisfied with that,
but do you know how painful it would be
for everyone you'd leave behind?!
You cannot die in front of Sayu.
You may lose contact with me.
So if you ever come across a situation
where you have to make a decision by yourself,
do whatever you need to do
to make sure that both you and Sayu live.
Promise me that.
Light...
What? No way!
I can really go with you?!
Yeah. I may need your eyes this time.
All right! Thank you!
I have to start packing immediately!
Hmm... I can't decide...
Say, Light... Which do you like?
If things take a turn for the worse,
I'll have to kill Sayu.
Dad...
I'll go on ahead to Los Angeles and make preparations.
Mr. Ide and the rest of you, please come after us.
We'll take different planes.
So just in case, Mr. Aizawa will follow
my father and ride the same plane as him.
All right.
As a disguise, I'll cut my hair.
I'm counting on all of you.
Mr. Yagami.
Who are you?
Are you one of the kidnappers?
You will take flight SE333.
I have your ticket.
Hurry. It's Gate 18.
A-All right.
A man has intercepted him at Narita!
Should I arrest him?
Mr. Aizawa, calm down.
It won't do us any good if you arrest him right now.
At any rate, don't lose sight of him.
Oh no!
The Deputy Director got on a different flight
with that man than the one he was supposed to catch.
This is an emergency.
I'm going to get on as a police officer...
Calm down, Mr. Aizawa.
If you do that, it will be as bad as if you were discovered.
Do you know where it's going?
Uh... Oh...
It's also going to Los Angeles.
Impossible, they even have a plane?
This is bad...
Flight SE333, Flight SE333, can you hear me?!
You are off course!
This is Flight SE333.
I can hear you.
We are not off course.
I changed course.
What are you talking about?
What's wrong? Are you joking?
This is not a hijacking.
We're just going to take a little detour
and drop off a passenger.
You can track me by radar.
But if you do anything to interfere,
I will not hesitate to crash this plane and take all the passengers with me.
Light... I mean, L.
The plane has gone
on a different course than to Los Angeles.
Someone's going to be dropped off somewhere.
It's probably the Deputy Director.
Damn! What's going on?!
I checked the flight crew ahead of time.
There wasn't anyone suspicious.
The pilot is a veteran of over fifteen years.
There's no problem with the co-pilot, either.
So the enemy is powerful enough
to control even normal people like them.
Damn. I've got no choice.
Director, this is L. Get me N.
Yes.
N, I think you know the situation.
Can you notify the airlines, police, and military not to make a move yet?
What is L doing?
How unreliable...
All right, L.
We'll figure out where he'll land
and keep surveillance over the area by satellite.
If there's anything else we can do, please let me know.
Take this PDA...
Place the wireless earphone in your ear.
Yagami,
only you can hear my voice.
Listen closely.
I'm the one who kidnapped your daughter.
I have no interest in the lives of you or your daughter.
At this moment, the only thing I want is...
the notebook.
If you do as I say, I won't kill either of you.
I've even arranged an exchange procedure
that you'll be satisfied with.
Do not fight me.
I am trading the killer notebook for my daughter's life,
with an unknown person.
When that time comes,
what should I do?
As a police officer...
As a human being...
As a parent...
L,
we have pinpointed where
they have landed with our satellite cameras.
I'll send you footage of what we are watching.
Dad...
What's going on?
How is he going to make the exchange there?
You see it, don't you, Yagami?
Enter from there.
Underground, huh?
This is interesting...
Damn. Underground, huh?
That means he predicted that there'd be satellite surveillance.
Now I can't watch him...
It's bulletproof glass.
You understand.
Up until a few years ago,
a certain syndicate used this place to make shady deals.
We've made some modifications.
Slide the notebook through here.
When you slide it in, I'll release this handle.
We'll step back and spin the glass door.
The notebook will be passed this way
and your daughter that way.
If you don't go through with the trade, I'll shoot your daughter from here.
L, do you have a plan?
Or do you really think it's all right to let the notebook fall
into the hands of someone you don't know?
Y462, begin.
Now open the notebook
and slide it into the slot in the glass door
to the left.
Damn. I'm being set back even further.
I've just arrived in L.A.
I'm not in any situation to be giving orders to the police agencies around the world as L.
At this rate, the notebook will...
Light, what's wrong?
Are you all right? You're pale...
Misa, shut up and just do as I say!
I want you to take more care than usual
in killing the criminals in Japan.
He's investigating Kira.
You know something bad will happen
if the punishing gets delayed, don't you?
O-Okay... But who's he?
Just do as I say!
You're just taking out your anger on her.
I can still make it.
At this rate, is my only option to kill Sayu?
Now then, I shall test the notebook.
Test?! You're going to kill someone?!
That's...
Hey, hey...
We can't trade without testing it out.
Do you want your daughter to die?
It's no good!
Only the police know about this case.
I can't blame Sayu's death on Kira.
What's wrong?! Are you all right, Miller?!
That's what you get when you steal and sell our drugs behind my back.
He was a worthless guy,
but this is the first time he's been useful.
Y462, the target is dead.
It seems the notebook is real.
Now let go.
We'll exchange it for your daughter.
Sayu... Dad...
Oh, they've been saved.
The perpetrator is headed for a helicopter.
We can assume that's his means of escape.
This means that the notebook was definitely exchanged.
I still don't know what I'm going to do afterwards.
Follow their helicopter the best you can until it lands.
Don't let it out of your satellite's view.
That's easier said than done.
All right. I'll try my best.
It's no good. We've been tricked, L.
A missile?!
Whoa!
That's one that can't be tracked by radar.
The notebook is on a missile?
The missile's been launched!
The helicopter or the missile?
Which one is the notebook on?
Boss, I'm sure you were watching.
I followed your orders to the letter.
Yeah, good job.
So now my past mistakes will be wiped clean, right?
Yeah. I'll wipe them clean all right...
Do it!
Near, the helicopter has...
I thought so...
This means that the notebook was definitely on the missile!
The missile can't be tracked!
I've completely lost sight of the target.
It won't be difficult to retrieve the missile
if it falls in an unpopulated area.
He should be getting his hands on the notebook right about now.
When he does, I have a good idea of what he'll do first.
L.
Yes?
They got us.
They got you?
Yes.
Most of the members of the SPK
have been killed.
L,
you helplessly handed over the notebook.
N,
are you saying that if you were in command,
you wouldn't have handed it over?
No, with that kind of preparation,
it would have been taken either way.
There's no point in our quarreling.
Let's help each other and tell each other what we know.
I have some idea of whom the culprit may be.
I think the person who is behind this
goes by the name Mello.
The name Mello?
I don't have his photograph, and I don't know his real name.
I only know that until four years ago,
he was at an orphanage
called Wammy's House in Winchester, England.
Wammy's House?
That was the institution Watari established.
I think that Mello is playing a game with me.
To see who can catch the last boss, Kira, the fastest...
Armo Justin...
It's Armonia Justin.
I went to the old man, the king, to report that I lost my notebook,
but when I described what it looked like,
he said that Ryuk said it was his and that he dropped it, and took it.
What should I do in this case?
In this case, you've got to get it back from Ryuk.
I thought so...
So I have to go...
to the Human World, huh?
Yeah, you have to go...
I see...
Please calm down and listen.
On November 10th, at 11:59 p.m.,
all the Mafia will die.
That moment will be your best chance
to retrieve the notebook.