You have to go outside and get some sunlight every so often.
What in the world...
should I do now?
Ryuk.
Shidou?
Why are you here?
Hey, don't follow me!
I want my notebook back.
Yeah, I figured it'd be that.
Well...
To be honest, things have become complicated
and I don't know where it is now.
That's so irresponsible.
You're still following me?
Give me back my notebook!
I don't know where it is!
If you want it back, go look for it.
Wammy's House wasn't simply an orphanage.
It was an institution for brilliant children
to raise them to become the Second L, L's successor.
L's successor...
The one who ranked at the top was a boy called Near.
Near... N, huh?
And the boy N mentioned, Mello,
was ranked next after Near.
Near is L's successor.
There's no mistake.
N is commanding the SPK.
No, Mello probably wanted to become L's successor.
If that's the case, Mello would probably want to use any means necessary to get the notebook before Near.
Near is convinced that Mello is involved.
He's certain that he is.
These are sketches of both of them.
There are no photographs of them.
L's successor...
I'm still...
fighting L.
At any rate, I have to figure out
where Mello and his Mafia associates are located.
I've already had Misa check a list of wanted Mafia members
At any rate, I have to figure out
where Mello and his Mafia associates are located.
I've already had Misa check a list of wanted Mafia members
with her Shinigami eyes.
Oh! There he is!
Someone whose lifespan I can't see!
Number 105!
He's listed as Jack Neylon,
but his real name is Kal Snydar!
With the Death Note, I made Snydar
send a letter to tell me where his hideout is.
It should be coming soon!
Light!
You've got a letter!
He's in Los Angeles!
I did it! I've completely surpassed both of them!
I'm definitely the strongest as long as I have the notebook and Misa's eyes!
Light, I've been a big help, haven't I?
Yeah.
I love you, Misa.
The only thing I have to do is see how far I can control people.
I'd like everyone to notice me
so I can talk to them.
The owner is Snydar.
I guess I have to make him touch the notebook.
Oh, well...
What?
The notebook moved on its own...
It's a notebook that can kill people.
I wouldn't be surprised if it were alive!
Whoa!
B-Boss! The guy with the dirty clothes...
Is he new?
I'm not a new guy.
I'm a Shinigami.
A Shinigami?
If you want others to see me,
you have to make them touch the notebook.
H-He says you'll be able to see him
if you touch the notebook...
Everyone, touch it!
There's nothing wrong with me!
Fine. Everyone...
Touch the notebook.
What's this?!
I couldn't see him before.
Boss, shall I kill him?!
It's no use. Humans cannot kill me.
It seems that this Shinigami's real, and it looks like he's telling the truth.
Ryuk.
Right now I'm going to relinquish ownership of this notebook.
Follow the person whom I give it to.
What? You're relinquishing your ownership?
Won't you lose your memory if you do that?
Misa, lend me your notebook.
If I do this, I won't lose my memory even if I relinquish my ownership.
I'll give you as many pages as you need.
From now on, you shall be Kira.
Can you handle that?
That's fine, but what are you going to do?
I'll explain that right now.
Mistakes will not be allowed.
Chocolate is good.
Hey! So is what you just said true?!
"If the person using the note
fails to continuously write names of people to be killed within 13 days of each other, then the user will die."
"If you make this note unusable by tearing it up or burning it,
all the humans who have touched the note till then will die."
These two rules were made up?!
Yeah. Those are definitely fake.
A Shinigami probably wrote that
as a joke before giving it to a human.
We can disprove the thirteen-day rule
by using a single person.
The question is whether this notebook has passed through the hands of Kira.
If it has, we'll know whether or not it's fake.
If we know,
we can use this rule.
The thirteen-day rule
can be proven in thirteen days.
Shidou, keep guard outside.
Huh?
You can't be seen by humans,
so at least you're useful for something.
Keep watch outside.
Got it?
What's with this guy?
He's terrifying for a human.
This is Yagami.
This is Kira.
What did you say?
Kira?
The notebook that the Japanese task force had in its possession
was stolen by criminals, wasn't it?
Kira...
Do you have any proof that you're Kira?!
Proof?
Now that the notebook has been passed,
there's no way I can prove that I'm Kira by predicting killings.
But soon you'll receive proof that I am Kira.
My notebook.
Wh-What is the meaning of this?
The notebook that I'm giving you
allows me to know a person's name by seeing their face.
Got that?
Calm down...
and listen to me...
On November 10th, at 11:59 p.m.,
every mafia member whom I have gathered information on
from the FBI and other organizations will die.
I've already written it in my notebook,
so it cannot be changed.
I also know their hideout.
I shall send that information along with the notebook.
In other words...
November 10th, 11:59 p.m...
This moment
is your best chance
to retrieve the notebook.
What should we do?
If the members of the mafia are going to die
on the day that Kira specified, there would be a chance.
I resent the idea of following Kira's plan, but it's a good plan.
That's right.
But...
it doesn't do us any good just by knowing
when the mafia are doing to die.
Mr. Ide, you know the answer.
We have the Shinigami follow us,
a-and we do the eye deal and kill them for sure.
I'll do the deal.
N-No way!
I'll do the bargain.
I handed over the notebook to begin with.
Because of that, I even thought of killing myself.
I'll use the notebook to kill the criminals,
and after thirteen days, I'll die too.
If Dad ever writes a name in the notebook...
When that happens...
Is everyone ready?
We're ready.
Then... Deputy Director Yagami...
Make the eye deal with the Shinigami.
Ryuk, please.
All right.
Deputy Director Yagami,
take a look at the photographs of the criminals I gave you.
Can you see their names and lifespans?
Yeah, I can.
Your signal to go is when their names disappear.
We're going in!
So Kira was involved after all...
I never thought he'd go this far.
My perfect plan is still...
Damn! What is Shidou doing?
Just be quiet and watch, Shidou!
You'll get your notebook as long as you don't interfere.
Roy! Skyer!
The notebook is under Rod!
Bring it up to the monitor room!
Don't move!
L, we've captured two of them.
We've also safely retrieved the notebook!
We're going back now!
No, not yet.
We still haven't found anyone who resembles Mello.
He's hiding somewhere in the building.
We've come this far. Exercise caution, and hunt him down.
Whoa!
What's was that?
An explosion?
Don't move.
I've just blown up the two entrances.
But that was only a warning.
Next, I'll blow up the entire building.
Follow my orders.
It's Mello!
Yagami again, huh?
Maybe I should have killed you back then?
I never thought I would be bargaining for the notebook with you again.
M-I-H-A-E-L...
K-E-E-H-L...
Your real name is Mihael Keehl.
Dammit! How?
I did it!
Give up, Mello.
I won't kill you if you surrender.
Wha—
Why are you being stupid?
Hurry and write his name in the notebook and kill him!
You'll die if I write your name in this notebook.
Throw away that switch and put your hands up!
Yagami...
Don't move!
I only have to write your last name!
It won't take a second.
You idiot... Just write it. Write it!
Sorry...
I really didn't want to kill you.
Yagami, you've...
never killed anyone before, have you?
Gun shots?!
What was that?!
Jose! Grab the notebook!
Damn... This guy...
He won't let go of the notebook!
Why, you!
Deputy Director!
This is it, Mello!
Hands in the air now!
Matsuda, are you okay?
I don't think so...
He seems okay.
L, I don't see any sign of Mello.
Wha—
Damn. He got away?!
That's why I told my dad to kill him quickly!
Dad... Dad!
Please, don't die!
Light...
Dad!
I'm so glad...
Yeah, I'm glad too, Dad.
Light...
I still have...
the Shinigami eyes.
According to that Shinigami, Ryuk,
I can't see the lifespans of those who own the notebook.
Light...
You aren't Kira...
I'm really...
glad...
Of course not.
You're still worried about that?
Dad, don't say anything unnecessary.
That's important, but there's something even more important right now.
He has to write Mello's name in the notebook.
S-Sorry...
In the end, I...
I couldn't kill him...
It might not be good to say that "it's not too late" now.
No, it depends on how I say it.
At a time like this, I can be distraught to a certain extent.
Dad! Write his name!
Write his name with the last ounce of your strength!
You can't just let him beat you!
Dad!
Light...
I'm sorry...
Dad!
Don't die! You idiot!
You're the Shinigami who came
to take back this notebook, aren't you?
Yes.
Even if it benefits the Kira investigation,
we only need one of these notebooks.
I'll return it to you.
People who use the notebook are cursed with misfortune, huh?
Well, it's not as if Soichiro actually used the notebook.
He died believing that his son isn't Kira.
So I guess he died a happy man.
If Kira is caught, he is evil.
If Kira rules the world, he is justice.
From now, the world will gradually lean in favor of Kira.
Kira will become justice.