Near, I think it's time you to tell us
your thoughts about this case.
The current Kira is foolish, and his exchange
with the Japanese task force was far too convenient.
Near, I think it's time you to tell us
your thoughts about this case.
The current Kira is foolish, and his exchange
with the Japanese task force was far too convenient.
Taking that into consideration,
Kira is probably conspiring with the Japanese task force.
Conspiring?
If that's the case, then Kira is...
the Second L.
I-It can't be!
Are you serious, Near?
Yes.
I'm only seven percent sure, though.
Commander Rester,
we have to make assumptions during investigations.
If we're wrong, we can just apologize.
There have been fewer crimes in Japan lately.
If you do something bad,
your name will be posted on the Internet
and Kira will kill you.
That's what my dad told me.
What's your name?
and Kira will kill you.
That's what my dad told me.
Come on, if you don't tell us your name, we can't file a report.
and Kira will kill you.
That's what my dad told me.
Come on, if you don't tell us your name, we can't file a report.
Give me a break!
Anything but my name!
I'm going to post your names on the Internet!
I will declare this right here!
Kira is justice!
It is absolutely true that I was appointed
by Kira as his spokesperson.
Some people may try to kill me because of this.
But!
I am prepared to risk my life to spread Kira's word around the world.
Kira's Kingdom, huh? What a horrible title.
The world's come to an end.
I am prepared to risk my life to spread Kira's word around the world.
Persecuting Kira is an unforgivable act
and should be considered a crime.
We should really kill this guy.
Persecuting Kira is an unforgivable act
and should be considered a crime.
If you see someone trying to find Kira, whether that person is a police officer,
We should really kill this guy.
a regular citizen, or a criminal, bring charges against them!
Oh, the president's press conference is about to begin.
What could it be about?
They said that it was an announcement to the world.
You're always watching TV, aren't you?
We, the United States of America...
Could it be?
accept Kira
and will do nothing to stand in his way.
This is insane!
I did it! The United States has bowed down to Kira.
Wh-What is he talking about?
Is he afraid of Kira?!
Mr. President, explain this!
When was this decided?!
Explain yourself!
Give us more details!
Are you saying that Kira is justice?!
Are you?!
Justice? I didn't say that.
But war no longer exists because of Kira.
Criminal organizations are in a state of ruin,
not only in the United States, but around the world.
Make no mistake.
Whoever defies Kira directly will be killed.
We know that Kira does not stand for justice,
but as a country, we will not take any actions to catch Kira.
That's the same thing! You idiot!
You just announced that you accepted Kira!
Please explain!
You're fleeing?!
Can you really call yourself the leader of our country?!
I don't believe it.
This is the U.S. we're talking about...
It's their president's word.
Uh... I'd like to ask a serious question.
What is it all of a sudden?
So you're saying that you aren't always serious?
In the depths of your heart, do you think that Kira is evil?
What?!
What do you mean, Matsuda?!
To tell the truth, I don't think he's completely evil.
You believe that Kira is justice?
I don't know.
But I think that Kira is fighting evil.
The world has definitely become
a good place for people who live honestly.
You're wrong, Matsuda.
They're afraid of the carnage.
It's not true peace.
I know. I know that!
But I understand the feelings of those who call Kira a savior!
I've always been
a weak person.
But I'm a detective.
I can't accept Kira.
I understand that and want to catch him as a part of my job.
Not being able to completely denounce him...
My head's probably messed up.
There's nothing wrong with you, Mr. Matsuda.
Light, you too?
What are you talking about?
Kira probably knows that what he's doing is evil.
He'll change the world even if he becomes a martyr.
That is the form of justice that Kira has chosen.
That's probably what Kira thinks.
We shouldn't argue over whether Kira is good or evil.
We just have to catch Kira.
If Kira is caught, he is evil.
If Kira rules the world, he is justice.
But the world is rapidly coming to Kira's side.
Soon Kira will be justice.
What'll happen to us?
We've been dissolved thanks to that chicken of a president.
No, not even a chicken.
He's lower than a maggot.
You've got to be kidding.
There's no way that accepting Kira can be good.
You're alive?
Near!
What should we do?
Let him in.
Welcome, Mello.
Throw down your gun!
Everyone, please put down your guns.
It is meaningless for us to shed blood here.
But Mello killed the others.
Don't make me repeat myself.
Our goal is to catch Kira.
Right now, killing Mello will not benefit us.
All right...
Have things gone as you planned, Near?
Yes. You've heard from Lidner, haven't you?
About the Second L...
I've pretty much figured out who Kira is
because of everything you've done.
Near!
I'm not your tool to solve your puzzles!
Mello, shoot me if you want.
Mello!
If you shoot Near, we'll have no choice but to shoot you.
What'll happen if you both die?
Only Kira will be happy.
That's true.
Near, I just came to retrieve the photograph you have of me.
Yes.
This is the photograph.
There's only one and there are no copies.
I've already dealt with everyone
who knows your face at Wammy's house, and elsewhere.
I can't guarantee it,
but it's safe to say you won't be killed by the notebook.
Is that all, Mello?
Near...
I have no intention of working with you.
I know.
But it'll upset me if I just take my picture and leave.
The killer notebook...
It's a Shinigami's notebook.
Whoever touches it can see a Shinigami.
That's crazy!
Who would believe that?!
I believe him.
What good would it be for Mello to tell a lie like that?
He would at least tell a better lie,
or something that has some truth to it.
Therefore, Shinigami really do exist.
The notebook I had was one that belonged to someone other than a Shinigami.
Also, there were fake rules within the rules written in it.
That's all I can tell you.
Near.
Mello.
Which of us is going to get Kira first?
The race is on.
Our destination is one in the same.
I'll be waiting for you.
Yes.
A fake rule...
Judging from previous events, there's no doubt that the notebook
can cause heart attacks and control its victims, to a degree.
As for burning or tearing the notebook...
The book still exists and there is no way to test it.
In that case...
The fake rule is the rule
that a person will die if he doesn't write a name within thirteen days.
Gevanni.
Get me L.
Yes.
It's from Near.
Yes?
L, we've caught Mello.
But he escaped.
However, we were able to interrogate him a little.
He didn't escape.
You let him escape.
Isn't that right?
No, he really did escape.
By the way, Mello said that there is
a Shinigami attached to the notebook.
Have you been able to confirm any such entity?
Yes. Shinigami do exist.
I kept it a secret because I didn't think that you'd believe me.
I'd like to talk to the Shinigami about some things.
I don't want to talk.
The thing that bothers me the most is the fact that
there is a fake rule among the rules
written within the notebook.
There's a fake?
Yes.
L, tell me what you think.
Which rule do you think is a fake?
By elimination, it would have to be the one
that requires the owner of the notebook
to write a name within thirteen days, or he'll die.
I thought you'd say that.
I think so too.
Shinigami. Was there a fake rule
among the rules written within the notebook?
No, there aren't any.
So there's a Shinigami there?
Yes.
I see...
I pretty much get the picture.
In other words,
Kira is there and he's making the Shinigami lie.
This guy's amazing.
He got it right.
Even if the Shinigami is lying, it doesn't mean anything.
No. It would mean that it was meaningless to detain Light.
If the rule that a person has to continue to write names is fake,
then it's meaningless that he spent more than thirteen days doing nothing.
B-But that's wrong!
There's no way that Light is Kira.
The Deputy Director confirmed that he didn't have a notebook, and passed away.
Well then, how about testing it in this way?
I will write Mello's name in the notebook.
When Mello dies, and if I die thirteen days later, Kira wins.
I don't mind.
Wh-What? So it's just a matter of winning or losing?
Even if testing the thirteen-day rule
benefits the Kira investigation,
there shouldn't be any drawbacks.
I shall put my life on the line.
If I reject this offer on my own, it'll give a bad impression.
Wait a moment.
We need to think about that suggestion.
Give me your honest opinion.
It's easy to say that we should honor human life
and we shouldn't do that,
but I was the one who was confined.
It's strange for me to be saying that.
This is awkward...
I want to see the Deputy Director avenged.
I think that Near should do it if he wants to.
I'm against it.
I don't believe that Kira is among us.
We shouldn't kill anyone with the notebook.
Yes. We should follow the Deputy Director's will.
I'm also against testing the notebook.
Near, we cannot allow you to test the notebook.
I thought you would say that...
And lastly, one more thing.
To the members of the Japanese task force:
was there ever a time that you thought your Second L was Kira?
If you've listened to the conversation and want to help my investigation,
call the number that I'm going to give you.
I'll answer.
There's no way that Light could be Kira.
No, I just don't want to think that.
But...
If the thirteen-day rule is fake,
it's true that we can't say that he's innocent.
Near... I have to kill him!
It's me.
This is Kira.
I-Is-Is this a prank?
I will read you a list of people whom I'm going to punish tomorrow.
Check it and make your decision.
Mr. President,
I am very grateful that you have sympathized with me.
But that isn't enough.
The SPK is trying to catch me.
I want you to stop them immediately, and disband them.
At the same time, I want you to use American police, the CIA, the FBI,
and all other intelligence agencies
to find out where the SPK members are hiding.
Let me know immediately.
I will tell you how to contact me.
Mr. President,
it is your choice whether or not you live a long life.
Don't forget that.
All right...
Demegawa! Please wait!
Why are you suddenly going to New York?
I'm going to crush an organization that's defying Kira.
It's going to be live!
This is an order from Kira.
I got a call from the President.
I don't even know what I'm saying anymore!
I don't care about anything!
I'll get 100%— no, 120% viewer ratings!
Come on, everyone!
The age of Kira is upon us!
The last L was suspicious of Light.
But I'll just be killed if he really is Kira
and I say that we should investigate him again.
The thirteen-day rule...
Aizawa.
I've known you for a long time.
I know what you're thinking.
You should do what you think is right.
I never trusted L to begin with.
I'm doing this because I want to work with you rather than with Light.
Ide...
I'll contact Near without letting Light know.
All right.
I'll make sure that no one knows what you're doing.
Light...
I want to believe...
that you're not Kira.
Big trouble! Demegawa's on TV and...
I, Demegawa, along with my comrades, have finally
pinpointed the location of and surrounded the hideout
of the evil organization that is trying to catch our god, Kira.
Right now, they appear to be hiding within this building!
Behold the power of the people!
The power of justice!
When Near escapes, I'll write his name in the notebook.
Light, I'm going to do my best!
Near, at this rate, we'll be dragged out...
L...
What's wrong, Near?
Is this a plan by Mello to finish off the SPK?
Or is the SPK is so poorly structured
that even the public was able to discover your location?
You and your lies...
I win, Near.
I can definitely use him.
He worships Kira from the bottom of his heart,
and he understands that by accepting the notebook, he was chosen.
There was nothing wrong with my choice.