The current Kira is foolish,
and his exchange with the
Japanese task force was far too convenient.
Kira is probably conspiring with the Japanese task force.
Conspiring?
If that's the case, then Kira is...
the Second L.
To the members of the Japanese Task force:
was there ever a time that you thought your Second L was Kira?
Near...
I have to kill him!
Big trouble!
Demegawa's on TV and...
I, Demegawa, along with my comrades, have finally
pinpointed the location of and surrounded the hideout
of the evil organization that is trying to catch our god, Kira.
Fellow Kira followers!
Do not rush in all at once.
The traitors may hide among you to escape.
I am Kira's voice.
Follow me and we will place them
in front of the cameras, and offer them to Kira!
I'm not going to miss them!
Near, you have to get out of there.
You have some nerve, saying that as Kira.
You're still saying that?
There are other organizations that are chasing Kira.
We get attacked as soon as I begin to suspect you.
The timing is too convenient.
Near, you've made some kind of mistake and are making too many assumptions.
Members of the task force:
Kira is probably among you.
Think carefully.
Light is Kira...
My suspicions are getting stronger again.
The previous L also thought that Light was Kira.
The first wave of twenty people will break the door and get inside! The second wave will stand by!
Get out of the way, dumbass!
We're the first wave!
What?! We're going first!
Near, we have to get away immediately.
Really, what stupid people.
I don't think it's strange that there are people who follow Kira.
They are people who hope
that Kira will bring justice to evildoers.
The people who are barging in here are different.
They really are stupid people.
Selfish people... who only want to have some fun.
I-I know that, but right now...
Let's use L's fortune and the anti-Kira people we hired.
But if we carry out that plan once...
Let's do it.
We should be prepared already.
It should be interesting.
M-Mo...
It's money!
I-It's money!
Money?
Wow! There's so much!
Amazing...
I wish I were there.
Matsuda...
Jeez. Humans sure are interesting.
Well, that can buy apples, so I kind of understand.
I grabbed these first!
Cut it out!
Out of the way!
Damn. Curse you, Near!
He plans to escape in this chaos!
But then he'll be caught on Demegawa's cameras...
P-Pilot! Go to the floor where the money is coming from!
Jeez! What is Deme doing?!
You can't buy love and peace with money!
A large flurry of money
is causing a panic in Lower Manhattan.
It's the police!
The police?!
As expected when faced with this chaos,
the police were called in.
This is bad... At this rate...
Let's go.
Right now, we can just walk out the entrance.
As expected, the police have to take action in a riot like this.
Damn... They were prepared for something like this.
They plan to come out among the police!
Telling Aizawa and the others
to watch over the police is like saying that I'm Kira!
The police have come out from the building.
Where is he?!
He should be among them...
Where?!
Dammit...
I wonder how much money that was...
Matsuda...
It was probably about ten million dollars...
How many apples is that?
Near!
Near?!
This is Near.
We've reestablished a connection, so I decided I should give you a call.
Near, you're safe.
Members of the task force:
I think it's about time that you have some certainty about who Kira is.
We were attacked at such a convenient time.
It's like saying that Kira is
in the Japanese task force headquarters.
With this in mind, you're no smarter than a preschooler
if you aren't suspicious of the Second L.
The number I gave the day before is working again,
so call any time you like.
Well, then... I'll be waiting.
He's pretty bold to be that sure of himself.
Everyone...
Help Near if you want to.
I'm not satisfied with this situation.
Ideally, we should cooperate with the SPK.
Near sure is tripping us up, isn't he?
When I think about Deputy Director Yagami,
I don't want to suspect Light.
But...
Dad?
Welcome back.
So you're home today.
Yeah... You're still awake?
I have tests coming up.
I see.
Don't push yourself too hard.
Okay.
You too.
It's not unusual for someone to want to contact Near.
The problem is after that.
If I'm late to act, something
I may not be able to fix may happen...
I'm left with no other choice!
It's an emergency order from Light.
Um... number three...
Huh?
No way...
Yes, this is Near.
This is Aizawa of the Japanese task force.
The time has finally come...
In order to keep me safe
and for me to become a normal wife...
This is what Light wants for me!
He wants me to be happy just as a woman should be.
Light, thank you!
I see. How fascinating.
So that L was detained for more than fifty days,
and there were two suspects
who were cleared due to the thirteen-day rule.
Of course, that alone doesn't mean that they're Kira.
So L just simply released them?
No, L had Deputy Director Yagami, who was Bureau Chief at the time,
put on an act.
He said that they both had been found
to be Kira and the Second Kira,
and were being taken to their execution.
Then the Deputy Director
pointed a gun at the suspects and said that he would kill Kira and then kill himself.
We rationalized if they were Kira,
they would kill the Deputy Director if pressed that far.
Kira is quite impressive.
He used his detainment to demonstrate his innocence.
Did the suspect volunteer himself to be detained?
Come to think of it, Light did volunteer to be detained.
If he did, then it's already decided.
So who is it?
Who were those two suspects?
I can't tell you that much.
I'm still a member of the Japanese task force
and am working under L.
I understand.
Thank you very much for your valuable information.
Especially the part about the Shinigami eyes that enable people to see other's names.
It will be helpful. Goodbye.
Is it all right, Near?
Shouldn't you have pressed a little more?
I think that his cooperation with us is fine at this rate.
Also, I discovered something very important.
Deputy Director Yagami and the person
who is suspected of being Kira are parent and child.
That's the only thing it could be.
It's the only reason he would say
that he would kill Kira and then kill himself.
Therefore,
the Second L, and the one whom I think is Kira, is...
Yagami Light.
Light.
Yes?
I'll tell you truthfully.
I contacted Near.
Don't worry about it.
I recommended it.
So what did you say?
No, I won't ask.
It was strange of me to ask about that.
I want to believe that you're not Kira.
Sorry for doing this again,
but I want to observe you until we catch Kira.
And Amane Misa as well.
I'm going to check your home right now.
There's a possibility that Amane has a notebook.
Hold on, Mr. Aizawa!
No, go right ahead.
You can prove to everyone
that I'm not sneaking around and contacting Misa.
Mogi...
I also want to make sure.
It would be best if Light weren't Kira,
but if Amane has any evidence linking her to Kira...
If so...
Oh! Mochi and Monchichi!
It's been a while.
Light hasn't come back because of the Kira investigation, so I've been so bored.
It's impossible for her to have the notebook
on her while dressed like that...
Misa, we were just told that there were explosives planted in L's home.
We think it's a prank,
but we'd still like to check the place out.
What?! Is Light okay?
I have to call him.
You can't.
Why not?
Light is all right.
There's something he has to do right now,
so he handed the investigation to us.
I-I guess so. Light loves me very much,
so he'd worry about me if he heard my voice.
Search as much as you like, Aizawa.
You won't find the notebook.
I don't want all this to ruin the mood we have here.
We're not a club.
You and Mogi should do as you see fit.
Oh, it's time for Kira's Kingdom.
Hello, Kira supporters.
I am Demegawa, Kira's voice.
Take a look.
Kira's Kingdom shares its name with this program.
Its construction is going smoothly with your support.
When it is completed, let's welcome Kira here!
Boy, that's in such bad taste...
Say, is everything all right?
Yeah, it must have been a prank.
But just in case, one of us is going to stay here to keep watch over you for the next few days.
Okay. Thank you.
Mogi, you can go back to headquarters.
I'll stay.
Huh? Why Monchichi instead of Mochi?
Don't you trust me?
That's not it. You're just not Monchichi
since you changed your haircut. It's not cute.
Mogi!
Yes. Sorry!
You stay here.
We have received over a million yen in donations
towards the completion of Kira's Kingdom!
It looks like a scam...
Yeah. It's no different from any other suspicious group.
It doesn't seem like Kira...
Demegawa... he's doing things on his own...
People will begin to drift away from Kira if he does this.
I no longer need Demegawa, but...
Oh, welcome back.
We didn't find a notebook in Light and Misa's home.
But...
I understand.
Keep watch over us until you're satisfied.
And now,
I shall introduce the Kira's Kingdom leaders whom I have chosen.
The first one is...
Delete.
With Kira, we will...
Please save me!
Delete.
Wh-What is this?
Why would Kira kill his supporters?
Do you suppose that he wanted
to stop them from going overboard?
That might be so.
But this is horrible.
What's the meaning of this?
There was no chance for Amane Misa,
or Light, to use the notebook.
Mikami... I can definitely use him!
It seems I chose correctly.
He knows Kira's beliefs, ideals,
and what Kira does and doesn't want.
He takes action without orders.
I made Misa relinquish ownership of the Death Note.
Misa has lost all memory of the Death Note,
and I've sent the Death Note to someone else.
Right now, she cannot answer any questions about it.
She's merely a plain woman.
The question is...
the next owner.
He talked to Kira through the television.
He worships Kira from the bottom of his heart,
and he understands that by accepting the notebook, he was chosen.
There was nothing wrong with my selection.
Mikami Teru...
He's worthy of becoming Kira's right hand.
Shinigami, thank you for coming.
Now I can punish evildoers with death.
God.
You are a woman whom the whole world pays attention to.
It must be fate for us to meet again like this.
I just want you to meet me and listen to what I have to say.
Somewhere... alone.