Delete.
The average Japanese adult would say that Mikami Teru
was a child with a strong sense of justice.
One who was able to distinguish right from wrong.
And compared to the average Japanese citizen,
Teru was also clearly more unfortunate.
He was a person who continually witnessed death.
Stop...
There is only good and evil in this world.
That is the first truth that I grasped from watching the world around me
ever since I was young.
All humans are split into two groups,
that of good and evil.
That held true even in a small world like elementary school.
As the class president,
no matter what lofty goals I tried to achieve,
there were always enemies.
Stop! Stop... Please.
Evil has to be confronted.
Get him good!
At times, it seemed as if justice had lost.
But I felt happy no matter what happened to me.
Thank you...
Those words from the victims
made me want to save them time and time again.
I didn't spare any effort for that.
In the end...
I was able to defend my sense of justice.
Just let him have it!
Come on, come on, come on...
But...
That was the case only within the world of children.
In middle school...
the more often I faced evil,
the more enemies I had to face.
Victims became participants.
Even observers
became influenced by evil and turned into enemies.
Justice must be served.
I must delete evil in order to do that.
The only one who understood me and was my ally
was my mother, who had raised me by herself.
No, it should've been my mother.
Teru, not everything in the world works the way you want it to.
Please stop.
There's no reason for you to be bullied.
There's no reason for you to be hurt like that.
You'll just look foolish.
Nothing will change, no matter how hard you try.
My mother was wrong. She wasn't virtuous.
She was a person who should not have existed.
Then a miracle happened.
The four enemies lost control of their car while joyriding without a license and died.
A bystander was killed.
That bystander was my mother.
The people I denied were deleted.
At first, I was scared.
I trembled from my heart.
However...
I was sure there were some people
who were happy due to this elimination.
The victims definitely were—
no, almost everyone in my class
must have been glad somewhere in their hearts.
I wasn't wrong.
There was a peaceful class.
There was definite retribution for evil deeds.
It is deserved and needed.
Evil must be deleted.
That's all. Is there anything wrong with this record?
No. Thank you very much.
My beliefs became stronger with my growth.
There will always be those who have no reason to exist—
no, whose very existence is a threat to others.
And the older they are, the less hope I have to reform them.
They can only be deleted.
Surprisingly...
Time and time again, whomever I decided
should be deleted was deleted.
Was this a coincidence? Was I special?
Such questions aren't important.
Evil must be punished by the heavens.
If it isn't, then someone
must mete out punishment to that evil.
That is why I became a prosecutor.
A prosecutor is the good that punishes evil.
That's what I thought.
That's when...
God came before me.
Everything that had been happening around me
until now was not mere coincidence.
It was divine justice.
God was watching me.
How I did not kneel down before the face of evil...
And He punished them for me.
When I realized that,
I went to the place where I could grab
God's attention the best I could.
And...
God accepted me.
Not only that, but He shared his power with me.
I must respond to this.
I'll figure out what Kira wants and do what Kira would do.
Delete.
Mikami killed Demegawa before I gave the order,
but now there's no one to be Kira's spokesperson to the world.
I can't do anything in this situation.
What are you going to do, Mikami?
Kira isn't saying anything.
I guess he's in a situation in which he can't move.
But this is an important time.
We need someone to spread Kira's thoughts.
Then I will...
Extra, extra! A new development!
Kira has chosen a spokesperson to take Demegawa's place.
Take a look!
This woman...
Takada Kiyomi!
Good evening.
This is Takada Kiyomi of News 6.
Starting today, it is my duty to spread the word of Kira
accurately and quickly.
NHN's star newscaster, huh?
Kira has good taste, choosing Takki.
There's no mistake.
This girl is from Light's college days.
You dealt with it quickly, Mikami.
But the fact that she and I had a relationship will soon be...
No, she's not a bad choice.
I wouldn't have thought of her because I know her.
Things may be getting easier.
The police are calling for civilians to evacuate.
I can definitely use him.
I want to contact him as quickly as possible, but...
Takada Kiyomi...
I spoke to her when we were on a debate show.
She was a shrewd host,
but her attitude changed as soon as Kira was brought up.
She has a uniquely rigid way of thinking.
She hates crimes and social evils.
I talked to her privately several times afterwards.
She clearly thinks like Kira.
She is the broadcaster
who is most worthy of being Kira's voice.
Takada Kiyomi...
It would be too suspicious
to choose an ex-girlfriend as a spokesperson.
There was no sign of Light sending any messages.
Am I reading too much into this?
Everyone.
About our investigation...
I think we should incorporate Takada Kiyomi from now on.
To be honest, I was quite friendly with her during my college days.
Oh?!
He said it himself?!
That means he has no intention of hiding that fact.
If Kira is giving her orders to read messages,
it might be our best option
to find a way to get Kira through her.
But Takki is probably being threatened by Kira.
She may be too scared to help us.
That's true...
That's all right.
I know her cell phone number.
She'll surely meet me if I ask her to.
That's some confidence.
So typical of you, Light.
But it'll probably be difficult to get her to help catch Kira.
I talked to her about many things during college.
She's quite...
the Kira-worshiper.
But we can use that to our advantage.
Right now, even the police say that they support Kira.
But actually they're doing nothing.
So I'll reveal that I've joined the police
and ask her what I can do to get instructions from Kira.
It wouldn't sound like a bad idea to a Kira-supporter like herself.
Will it go well?
I don't know. But it's worth trying.
I agree, we shouldn't ignore a lead that's in plain sight.
Then let's do this tonight, if possible.
Light!
I want to listen to your conversation with Takada.
Sure. I don't mind.
Actually, I want you to listen.
We don't know when she may give us a hint about Kira.
Y-Yeah...
Hello?
Miss Takada, it's Yagami.
Yagami?!
It's been a while. What is it?
Miss Takada...
There's something important I have to tell you.
Could you meet me?
I want to ask a favor of you.
A favor?
Yeah... It might be impossible,
since you're the woman the whole world's watching.
But I don't think you would
have called if that wasn't the case.
You're right...
Since we left college,
I've wanted to tell you, but I never had the chance to.
But since we've had the chance
to connect through our jobs as adults,
I can't help but feel that it's fate.
What's this job?
I'm with the police right now.
There's also something I really wanted to tell you in person.
Right now, the police won't do anything to betray Kira.
Fine. I may have to help you, depending on what you say.
Thank you. I just want you to meet me
and listen to what I have to say.
Somewhere... alone.
Okay. After tonight's broadcast is finished.
All right. I'll find a hotel room.
Is that all right?
Yagami, I thought you were living with Amane.
Are you still happy together?
Well, the truth is...
she doesn't have the brains to be my partner.
Mochi.
Yes?
Your cooking is good, and I appreciate that you'd do anything for me,
but it's been five days.
Yes.
Light doesn't know about this, does he?
I'm beginning to get a bad feeling about this.
Yes...
No matter how much Light trusts me,
wouldn't most people think that I might cheat on him?!
He'll definitely be jealous!
Near and the others told me
that this woman is the Second Kira.
But could this stupid woman really be?
Kira hasn't tried to contact me yet.
If Kira is in a situation in which he couldn't
contact me even if he wanted to,
he'll try to contact Takada first.
Good evening. This is the nine o'clock news.
Kira's words, which I am to tell you now, are to become the law of this world.
Kira will not forgive people
whose existence is deemed a threat.
Additionally, he will not tolerate people who live wastefully and do not use their abilities for the good of society.
Huh? Does that mean he'll kill lazy people?
You're kidding, right?!
You're overdoing it, Mikami.
No, it's too early.
I have to contact Mikami...
Matsuda, how is it?!
Yes, the sound and visuals are crystal clear.
No blind spots!
The nine o'clock news just ended.
See you again.
Light, I'll be heading back.
Okay.
I've wanted to see you...
Oh, excuse me. It's just...
Please have a seat.
It doesn't seem like it's been that long now that you're here.
What's wrong with Light?! He's silent.
He'll look suspicious if he doesn't say something quickly.
Ide, have you ever been in love?
What?
How is it?
The mood's good.
That's not what I meant.
Sorry.
Kira...
Mikami?!
She just said Kira!
Kira's contacting her directly?!
You should answer it.
O-Okay.
Hello?
No, I'm with a friend.
There's no one else.
If luck is on my side, I'll get on the phone.
Mikami, can you bring me luck?
We decided to meet unexpectedly.
Someone who could privately call on Kira's spokesperson.
Pass the phone over to your friend.
He wants me to give the phone to you.
It was right to choose you.
She's passed the phone to Light...
It's dangerous if it really is Kira!
Hello?
Who are you?
November 26th? Five pages?
What are you talking about?
God!
All right, Mikami.
How much have you figured out?
You can't move freely now.
Yes.
You're being watched right now.
Are you really Kira?!
Turn to Sakura TV!
Huh? Sakura TV?!
Sakura TV.
No matter what it takes, we're going to call back Kira!
He died!
This is bad! He's the real thing!
Mikami, you're better than I expected.
Yes...
Wh-What? Remove the wiretaps?!
We have no choice but to obey him.
What is the meaning of this?!
Now I can talk to you without constraints.
Huh?!
Listen, Kiyomi...
I'm Kira.
That's right. I'm Kira.
That's all.
Yagami is... Kira.
Listen. I won't allow you to ask Kiyomi
about who I am.
Yes. I leave the rest to you, God.
Understand?
I am Kira, and that man just now
is someone with whom I've shared Kira's power.
Y-You really are amazing.
You're the only man I've respected and admired my entire life.
For you to be Kira...
It's almost too good to be true!
With me,
you're going to become the goddess of the new world.
Yagami...
Light, are you all right?!
Yes. Things went well with Takada.
From now on, I'll be meeting with her
to find Kira.
Delete. Delete. Delete.
Come to think of it, since the beginning,
this has been a one-on-one battle against L.
Fine, Near. I'll come out if you're coming out.
I accept your challenge!