The Second L, and the one
whom I think is Kira, is Yagami Light.
Good evening.
This is Takada Kiyomi.
Kira's words, which I am about to tell you now,
are to become the law of this world.
About our investigation...
I think we should incorporate Takada Kiyomi from now on.
Sorry.
Kira...
Remove the wiretaps?
It can't be helped...
Listen, Kiyomi...
I'm Kira.
Yagami is... Kira.
All the pieces are set.
Now that things have gone this far,
it's my turn to head to Japan.
Commander Rester.
Yes.
Can you return to New York now?
Now?
I've decided to go to Japan.
Does that mean that I'll be standing by
in New York while you're gone?
No.
Then why do I have to return to New York?
I've never been on an airplane by myself.
I want you to return now, and come with me to Japan.
All right.
As we expected, Yoshida Productions and NHN jumped at the chance.
The Great Misa-Misa Comeback Plan!
It's difficult to enter NHN right now,
but this will allow us to do it without looking suspicious.
Yes. Mogi can go as her manager.
We definitely want someone who can freely enter NHN.
I'll also investigate through Takada.
This is Near. Give me L.
This is L. What do you want?
I'm going to arrest Kira,
and I'm here in Japan.
He's in Japan?
Why is he taking the time to tell me that?
L,
you've contacted Takada and are investigating Kira, right?
Yes. I'm investigating her myself.
I thought so.
Right now, it's a given that we must investigate
NHN's Takada Kiyomi if we want to find Kira.
So, tell Takada that
SPK members have entered Japan in order to arrest Kira.
Why?
In order to lure Kira out.
I also want you to add this:
there are only four members of the SPK, including myself.
Kira won't run away.
He'll definitely try to kill us.
We're...
going to use that to beat him at his own game.
Beat me at my own game, huh?
Fine, Near...
I'll accept your challenge!
I'm in Japan.
I'm also in Japan.
Then we may meet face-to-face soon.
You're right.
That will be something to look forward to.
Yes.
We'll bring this business with Kira to an end once and for all.
Definitely.
Come to think of it, since the beginning...
this has been a one-on-one battle against L.
Only now, it's shifted to someone who's influenced by L.
Fine, Near. I'll come out if you're coming out.
When we meet,
we'll see who's more prepared and who can surpass the other.
When that happens, the battle will end.
That's when I'll begin my reign at the top!
First, we have to figure out our current situation.
L is Light Yagami.
And Kira...
Let's assume that there is an L-Kira.
And there's another.
X-Kira. He holds the notebook and is using it.
Judging by X-Kira's killings,
he definitely has the Shinigami eyes.
L-Kira and X-Kira plan to communicate through Takada.
So I believe there are approximately two ways to win against Kira.
Our first option...
is to kill L-Kira and X-Kira and take the notebook.
But we will never resort to this method.
Why not?
That is not how we do things.
We?
That's right.
Killing people and getting ex post-facto justification
just by the fact that the killings have stopped...
That's not the way that L and I do things.
L wouldn't be able to rest.
There would be no meaning
to entrusting this case to his successors.
Takada, it's become well known that you receive an enormous amount of fan mail every day.
Yes. I've heard it's about an average of 200 letters a day.
200 letters a day... I'm kind of jealous.
I don't even have time to read them.
With just audio and no video, it's quite boring.
I think you should look through them
even if they're fan letters.
You're right.
Keep calm when you read the following note.
Make sure not to let the people listening to this conversation detect your surprise.
The SPK has started to move.
For your safety, you should not only accept messages,
but make demands to Kira as well.
Oh, Light has moved on to the main topic.
You shouldn't remain just a representative.
Why don't you reach out to Kira?
There's a different job that T must to do.
In order to create the perfect world for Kira,
I want you to punish as Kira.
It's all right.
You'll do it well...
If you do, you can give information to Kira
that you don't want the SPK to know.
All right. I'll do it.
We did it.
As I expected of Light. He's good.
Delete. Delete.
Delete.
Takada Kiyomi...
Yes?
Here's your message.
Send me a fan letter that I can tell is from you.
Place within it... five blank notebook pages.
Continue killing as usual until I receive them.
What about after you receive them?
Continue killing using a fake notebook.
A fake?
Yes.
Make a notebook that looks
as close to the original as possible,
and act as if you're killing using the fake.
I understand.
God, what are you doing?
No, there's no need to question Him.
God is absolute.
My job is to do as God wishes.
What is this show?
It's the program after Kira's Kingdom.
They're as unscrupulous as always.
Today, Miss Takada will introduce her four female bodyguards
who have passed a rigorous screening process.
The 22nd Karate Title Champion, Ooyama Tatsumi.
Former CIA agent Hal Lidner.
If there's an SPK member among these people,
it would have to be Hal Lidner.
Near is also trying to investigate Takada.
A phantom killer has stabbed six people
in Shinjuku's busy quarters.
Who would I choose to be X-Kira?
There has been another slaying.
There is nothing more important.
Children are to be taught about Kira's existence and teachings as mandatory education.
Takada was chosen because she is a Kira-worshiper.
X-Kira is someone who knows that Takada is a Kira-worshiper.
Someone who has a close, intimate relationship with Takada.
Kira will not forgive any small crime.
From now on,
assume that any living person is a target.
I'd like to hear Kira's voice and thoughts once more.
I think that following Kira's teachings exactly as ordered
is the quickest path to world peace.
Reconstruction of Japan
Thinking about the
21st-Century Discussion
I think it is of the utmost importance that young people do everything
in their power to contribute to society from now on.
If there are no orders or words from Kira,
21st-Century Discussion
Thinking about the
Reconstruction of Japan
If there are no orders or words from Kira,
we need to believe that it's all part of Kira's plan,
and make our own decisions and take action.
L-Kira is Yagami Light.
Kira's orders. Kira's Kingdom.
It was Mikami Teru's own decision to contact
Takada Kiyomi in order to stop Demegawa's rampage.
...spokesperson. Close since college. Coincidental past. Secret meetings.
...had notebook before our surveillance.
Everything seems to fit.
I've been saying...
Why aren't I the headlining performer?
You said that I was the highlight
of this year's East-West Song Festival.
No, the highlight is the highlight.
But the headlining act is usually a leading figure.
We should take precautions.
Takada Kiyomi...
She sure is stupid. She doesn't know
that Light is just using her for his investigation.
Don't say that.
You'll be killed if you do.
I know. That's why I whispered it.
Hey!
She snickered at me!
I'm going to kick her ass!
Don't!
What were you trying to do?
What was I doing?
What about you, lady?
Lidner, she's a good friend of mine.
Please don't be rough with her.
Understood, Miss Takada.
I'm very sorry.
M-Misa-Misa!
Are you all right?
That was so frustrating!
L, if Mr. Aizawa is there,
may I talk to him?
Near, this is Aizawa. What is it?
Do you videotape and wiretap L and Takada's meetings?
No, we only have wiretaps now.
I see. Only wiretaps now.
Thank you very much.
If it's only wiretaps,
then we can assume that L-Kira and X-Kira are contacting each other through Takada.
If that's the case, then Lidner is in increasing danger.
I know.
What's important is for L to turn his attention to Lidner and Takada.
We'll investigate Mikami while his attention is on them.
How are things, Gevanni?
About Mikami... It's strangely easy to shadow him.
He doesn't try to hide and has been living normally
in the same place for the past four years.
He's prosecuting people enthusiastically at his job.
I don't think that he can be X-Kira.
No. There is a high possibility that Mikami is X-Kira.
Please be careful.
Don't enter his room yet.
Just keep watch over him.
Got it.
Jeez. How many meetings do I have to attend with NHN?
And how many times have only I been told,
"Be careful about what you say"?
What's with that?
Yes. I'll ask her.
Misa-Misa. Takada is asking
if you would like to have dinner with her.
Huh?
That Kiyomi... What does she want?
That's fine.
The Song Festival emcee and the main headliner
should have dinner together at least once.
Tell her, "Okay."
Hello?
Miss Takada, she agreed.
Well, I'm looking forward to it.
Lidner, book a nice private room.
Also,
I would like you to attend as well.
Okay.
Miss Amane, I'm sorry for keeping you out so late.
It just had to be after News 9 finished.
I don't mind.
I'm a night owl anyway.
So what do you want?
It's hard for me to say if you ask,
but your boyfriend seems busy.
Do you still see him?
Why that... She knows that she can see him, but I can't.
She's such a...
I do. He's a lot more affectionate than he looks.
He clings onto me so much
as soon as he comes home every night!
I see. You're doing well.
Thank goodness.
Also, since you're the emcee,
I wanted to tell you this in advance:
I'm going to announce my engagement to him at the Music Festival.
Does he know?
Of course.
It's an engagement,
I can't do it by myself.
He promised me more than a month ago.
Don't you think it would make things more exciting
if I announced it at the Music Festival, Miss Emcee?
I guess so.
It would be great if you could.
What do you mean, "if I could"?!
You're not going to let me?
Or are you...
going to have Kira kill me?
Of course not.
Only Kira decides whom to punish.
I'm not involved.
I think of you as a friend.
Don't say such sad things.
I don't have any intention of killing anyone, no matter how horrible they may be.
Well, whatever.
I used to like Kira as well,
but Light's going to catch him soon enough.
When he's caught, nothing good will happen to him.
And you'll probably get...
executed.
Miss Takada!
Are you all right?
Listen, Kiyomi...
I'm Kira.
With me,
you're going to become the goddess of the new world.
Miss Amane.
Yes?
That was unpleasant.
Well, the same goes for you!
I should have waited to invite you to dinner
until after you had become more mature
and learned some manners.
Oh my...
I'm older than you are, little Kiyomi.
Besides, doesn't leaving the table
over something like this make you the more childish one?
Mochi!
Thanks for waiting! How are you?
A-Are you all right?
Of course. I won!
You won?
Yeah. It was a cinch!
About tonight's conversation between Takada and Amane...
I could only assume that they were fighting over
which one was Yagami Light's girlfriend.
Near...
All that I can say from this is...
Yagami Light is popular.
Takada and Amane adore Yagami Light.
Near, take this seriously!
It's a problem if they seriously like him.
They won't easily betray him.
They're at his beck and call.
Please stop!
What's up with that, lady?
You're wearing such a short skirt even though it's winter.
You were tempting me, weren't you?
S-Someone...
A cell phone?
Mikami has taken out a notebook.
Delete.
He's writing in it.
Could that be it?
Mikami's getting off.
Mikami is talking to himself!
He seems to have reacted to the scrap of paper at his feet.
He's entered the gym.
I'm sneaking into the locker room.
I've opened his bag lock!
I'm going to touch the notebook!