I'm going to announce my engagement to him at the Music Festival.
I used to like Kira as well,
but Light's going to catch him soon enough.
You'll probably get executed.
Send me a fan letter that I can tell is from you.
Place within it... five blank notebook pages.
Continue killing as usual until I receive them.
What about after you receive them?
Make a notebook that looks
as close to the original as possible,
and act as if you're killing using the fake.
What's up with that, lady?
You're wearing such a short skirt even though it's winter.
S-Someone...
Delete.
Mikami's getting off.
A man who was harassing a woman collapsed.
He was in the same train car as Mikami.
It happened a few seconds after Mikami
wrote something in a notebook.
It's probably...
Now we're sure.
Indeed.
First we've got to get as close as possible to Mikami.
But there's something we need to be careful of.
The Shinigami.
We must assume that if the Shinigami discovers that we're following him, he'll alert Mikami.
But the Shinigami can only be seen
by those who have touched the notebook.
Being careful of something you can't see is difficult.
Even if it's difficult, please do it.
I understand.
Light is going to meet Takada again in this room today.
As soon as they began their secret meeting,
Takada received a phone call from Kira
and the surveillance cameras were removed.
The first thought that hit me was that
they could communicate by writing messages.
It looks fine.
There's nothing in this room other than the wiretap on me.
Y-Yeah. All that's left is the bathroom.
Why does Light care so much about the cameras and wiretaps?
No, why is Kira allowing this secret meeting to go on?
It doesn't add up.
In the event that they are writing notes,
the only thing that I can do is...
Yagami, I talked to Amane yesterday, alone.
About what?
Light's in trouble now!
Matsuda, you seem kind of happy.
Amane said that she was going to announce
her engagement to you at the Music Festival.
Trouble, trouble! Big trouble!
Matsuda, shut up!
Well,
I just haven't been able to break it to her.
She's nothing to me already.
Misa, that moron.
That was unnecessary.
No, Takada as well.
Why are women so...
Already?
Is that true?
She was in charge of Kira's killing before T.
She gained Kira's power somehow
and discovered that I was Kira.
It couldn't be helped.
There would be no other reason
I would choose such an impulsive woman.
Amane was doing Kira's killings,
but right now it's me.
He had no choice with Amane,
but he chose me.
Takada, believe me.
You're the only one for me now.
"You're the only one for me now?"
That's so unlike you,
such a predictable line.
It's definitely unlike Light to give such a brutal excuse.
Those are my honest feelings.
So... Amane or Takada. Which one is it?
I wonder how many women you've said that to.
Well... He might be dating both.
Takada, do you really think I'm that kind of guy?
Two-timing? Do you think that's acceptable?!
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to...
Hey, I'm not the one...
Shut the hell up!
It depends on you from now on,
but I'll trust you.
However, I'll make things hell for you if you're lying.
I'll tell Kira.
Kira, huh?
I know that the world needs Kira right now.
But I've been thinking...
I wonder if I'll ever be together with you.
In other words, I hate Kira
because he chose you as his spokesperson.
It's fine if he kills criminals.
But we're not criminals.
We should have the right to be happy.
"Together, peacefully and happily."
"But that could only happen...
if Kira weren't around."
Yeah. If only Kira weren't around.
"Kira...
should be arrested."
Huh?
You're right.
Kira needs to be arrested
in order for us to be happy.
T-Takada,
are you serious?
Yes.
But I'll need your help for that. You'll be putting yourself in danger.
I'll be defying the police,
and you'll be going against Kira and the whole world.
Is that...
all right with you?
Th-That's one long pause.
It's fine.
"I'll help you if it means that
we can be happy together."
A big turn in our favor!
Just as I expected of Light!
He brought the conversation from two-timing with Misa-Misa to getting Takki to help him!
Mikami is talking to himself!
To himself?
Yes. He's too far away for me to record his voice,
but I've got visuals of his mouth!
This is footage of Mikami during his break at work.
Right here. He's saying something.
Show it once more to us in slow motion.
Shinigami, huh?
But...
He seems to have reacted to the scrap of paper at his feet.
He just gave a small sigh.
Here he talks a bit more.
I'll zoom in on his mouth.
And that Shinigami
justgave me the notebook and has
not appeared before me since then.
"That Shinigami just handed me the notebook and has not
appeared before me since then."
Mikami was given the notebook by a Shinigami,
but the Shinigami hasn't been following him.
I see...
Then I guess that'll be it for today, Yagami.
Yeah.
It's finally over.
Today was really quite amazing.
It's tough to do this for several hours.
And yet you're still smiling.
Then I'll go to the hotel and checkout.
Thanks for your help!
Must be tough for Aizawa, making all
the reservations and checking out of the hotels.
It's gone...
The nail mark I left is gone!
Two of the four marks I left are gone.
The room is the way they left it.
The hotel staff hasn't come in yet.
So why is the notepad switched with a new one?
They've been passing notes!
Yes?
What?
You want to meet and talk to Near directly?
Mr. Aizawa, it's been a while.
And also, nice to meet you.
There's no point in saying that if I'm blindfolded.
He doesn't have any weapons or cameras on him.
Then you can take off the blindfold.
Near,
I believe you.
L and Takada have been meeting almost every night.
I know.
Then what about this?
There's no mistake that they've been passing notes!
Mr. Aizawa,
please don't do something unnecessary.
Something unnecessary?
Yes.
It's no longer a matter
of simply finding evidence against Kira.
We must hit Kira with complete defeat in order to stop him.
Mr. Aizawa, to put it bluntly,
you and the task force are no longer part of this battle.
But if you still want to capture Kira,
just keep an eye on him as you've been doing.
Just keep an eye on him?
Yes. But there is a purpose to watching over L.
And that's part of my plan.
I want you to cooperate that way.
In order to win against Kira
and to watch...
the end of Kira.
There's only a few minutes left of this year,
but it's been one full of breakthroughs for myself.
The East-West Music Festival will wrap this year up.
I'm Takada Kiyomi, your host.
Pleased to meet you.
The Music Festival is about to begin!
Matsuda, have you crosschecked Kira killings and the victims?
After our Misa-Misa's performance! She's this year's opening act!
Wh-What is it?
We're the SPK.
We want you to come with us.
I must apologize to everyone.
Unfortunately, this year's opener, Amane Misa, has not arrived yet.
What?
However,
unexpected things can happen at this Music Festival.
What's going on?
Mogi didn't tell me anything about this.
Go back to NHN immediately!
I'm already known as the queen of sudden cancellations!
Misa-Misa, please calm down.
Mochi, why?!
We need to do this to catch Kira.
That doesn't involve me!
If worse came to worst, I was prepared to pull a gun on you.
But I'm glad that you didn't resist, Mr. Mogi.
I probably would've resisted
if I hadn't listened to what Aizawa said.
But...
hearing about the notepad, there's no doubt that...
What's going on?
Near.
What is it, L?
Mogi and Amane Misa have gone missing.
Yes. I've taken them into my custody.
What?!
Why?
Just in case.
Near...
Kidnapping and confinement are crimes.
Release them immediately.
Well, Mr. Mogi and Amane agreed to cooperate.
I'll put them on the line.
Here you go.
Mogi, Misa, this is L.
Light!
It seems that Near is detaining you.
Is it true that you agreed to it?
Yes.
Mogi...
I was against it!
But Mochi said it would be better if I sat still.
He said that we would be killed otherwise.
I understand.
I guess it's fine if you both agreed.
For the time being, I'm excluding Amane,
who was suspected of being the Second Kira.
Yagami Light,
you know what this means.
No way!
You're planning to end this without Misa-Misa performing?!
Have Misa-Misa perform!
Looks like Lidner and the others succeeded.
It's past nine.
All right, now it's my turn.
The time that Mikami leaves work differs only slightly.
He leads a completely fixed life.
So he always goes to that gym every week on Monday and Thursday until 9:00 p.m.?
Yes. He's come at that time
for the past four years, ever since he joined.
He hasn't even skipped New Year's Day.
I became a member to confirm it.
Then can we assume that he's going this 31st?
Yes. He's someone who would go on New Year's Day.
He's sure to go on New Year's Eve too.
Gevanni.
Is it possible for you to touch
the notebook on the 31st at the gym?
Yes.
I've already checked the hotel's security.
There are no surveillance cameras in the locker room.
Then I leave it to you.
There's a possibility that I'll die
if there's a Shinigami with him, isn't there?
Indeed.
We need to confirm it.
That is why I'm asking you to do it.
Even if you don't see a Shinigami after touching it,
I want you to continue to watch him
for a while to see whether there is one with him.
I'll have Rester do it if you're too afraid.
No, I understand. I'll do it.
If a Shinigami is with him...
No, I'm already past the point of no return.
I have to touch it.
I have successfully touched the notebook!
I cannot confirm any Shinigami at this time.
Commander Rester, connect me to Mr. Mogi.
Mr. Mogi, according to the notebook's rules,
how long can a person be controlled before death?
Twenty-three days,
judging by the data from Yotsuba's experiments.
Are you sure?
Yes. I think that Yotsuba's killings have proven that.
Thank you very much.
Then it is possible that Gevanni is already being controlled,
and is being made to say that there is no Shinigami.
I'm going to confront L
if Gevanni is alive twenty-four days from now.
Takada, you had quite some trouble at the Music Festival, didn't you?
Yes. To think that Amane would go missing...
"Give T the order to tell you
once everything has been confirmed."
"Once you get the message,
send me a text message or something
that says you want to meet me quickly."
Taking pictures?
Yes.
I want to see how it's written.
Any patterns as to how it's being written,
if there are any quirks, and what kind of notebook it is...
I want to see everything in detail with my own eyes.
What do you think, Near?
Gevanni has done well.
The handwriting matches that
of Mikami's records he wrote as a prosecutor.
This is definitely Mikami's handwriting.
Yeah.
We can do this.
The escort team has been attacked?
Takada, are you all right?
Is it Near again?
No, this way of doing things...
It's Mello!