Near, it went well.
I did everything that you told me to do.
Okay.
"T"...
That is all I have to tell you today.
Very well.
I also have something I want to tell you.
Go ahead.
I've confirmed it.
Hm? A text message?
Ooh... It says "I want to see you."
I'm so envious!
I did it! That's the confirmation sign from Mikami.
I just have to wait for Near to ask to meet me.
Near, I've won!
I predicted from the very beginning how you would move.
This is Gevanni.
Near, I've checked the notebook.
For the past three days,
he's filled out one page a day every night past midnight
as he usually does. The victims match up.
There's been no change in Mikami's behavior.
I understand.
Then let's begin.
Oh, it's Near!
He called!
L.
What is it, Near?
I want to meet you.
What?
I must meet you to discuss the Kira case.
But don't you suspect me of being Kira?
You shouldn't want to meet me.
Well,
there is something that I cannot show you
unless I show my face.
Everything will be resolved once I do that.
Fine.
I want you to realize that you are wrong
about me as soon as possible.
The time has finally come for Near to prove that Light is Kira.
If Light is Kira, then for him to kill Near,
he has to...
Let's agree on some rules regarding our meeting.
Yes. Anything.
To start off,
all of our investigators must be present at the meeting.
In other words, everyone who is pursuing Kira will gather.
I understand. That's fine.
As I said before,
there are a total of four SPK members, including myself.
Mr. Mogi, who is here, will accompany us.
Amane will be released right before we meet. She will not be told where we'll be heading.
We shall meet you once you confirm that Amane has been released.
How about it?
What should we do?
Near, I understand.
We have five investigators, including myself.
No, Mogi is with you, so aside from me, there are three.
Very well.
Now about the location of the meeting...
Daikoku Wharf.
An abandoned warehouse
on the outskirts of the southeast side,
nicknamed the Yellow Box.
I've already purchased the lot if it is all right with you.
How about it, Yagami Light?
You should be able to put your plan into action here.
One more thing.
I want you to bring with you the notebook that you have at your headquarters.
Why the notebook?
A simple reason:
there's no one to guard the notebook
if everyone leaves.
I promise you that I will not try to steal it.
I won't even lay a finger on it.
I'll place my faith in you
if Mr. Aizawa can confirm
that it's the notebook from your headquarters.
All right.
Someone other than L will hold onto it
because I believe that L is Kira.
I understand. But I will decide who holds onto it. Is that all right?
Yes.
Then all that's left is the time and date.
The time and date... The question is what time.
Mikami kills right after midnight. In the morning,
he'll probably be receiving a notice of the people to kill.
Taking his movements into consideration...
In three days.
On the 28th. How about 1 p.m.?
One o'clock, huh?
Just as I expected.
Near is calculating Mikami's movements.
That's fine.
It doesn't matter what time it is.
Then three days from now at one o'clock.
Got it.
Near.
Yagami Light.
I know what your plan is!
I'm going to win!
Sorry, Miss Takada.
I'm a little busy today.
Busy? Does that mean that you can't stay until morning?
Yeah.
Sorry.
The police are going to have
their hands full for two to three days.
How unfortunate...
I've already given orders to Mikami and Takada.
This is the final order
to kill Near.
Protect Miss Takada!
It's a rebel!
Miss Takada, are you unhurt?
Yes.
He's getting away! Give chase!
Miss Takada, please get inside NHN quickly!
Don't!
If someone like that was just here,
it's too dangerous in or around NHN!
Mello!
At any rate, you should get away from here!
Miss Takada, please get on!
Quickly!
Miss Takada, it's all right.
Get on quickly and get out of here.
Okay...
Team A and Team B, follow Miss Takada by car.
The other teams go after the car that just sped off!
All right! We've confirmed her safety.
Get Miss Takada to car number seven.
I-It can't be!
He's taking Miss Takada?!
D-Dammit!
You idiot! Stop!
What if you hit Miss Takada?!
Wh-What are you doing?!
One of them is heavily armed.
Miss Takada's escort team and the police are hot on the trail.
Th-This is really bad!
Is it Near again?
Near, you promised that we'd meet three days from now.
What's the meaning of this?
No, this isn't his style. It's more like...
It's Near!
So it's the cars that got ahead of me, huh?
Just how many escorts does that Takada have?
Come on!
Since when were the Japanese allowed to carry such big guns?
I'm an accomplice in the kidnapping of Miss Takada.
Don't you want to question me?
You wouldn't shoot—
Idiot. He probably wouldn't have told us anything.
Death is the only way to pay for defying Kira.
This guy is...
the person whom Yagami warned me
to be most careful of: Mello.
Mihael Keehl...
Take off everything you're wearing and put it in there.
Quickly.
I'll give you a blanket.
L, the one who kidnapped Takada
was not me.
I see. If that's the case,
then it was Mello.
Indeed.
I'll tell you honestly.
The individual whom I had guard Takada
has confirmed that Mello was the one who abducted her.
I'm sorry this happened while we had an escort with her.
Near, can't you contact Mello?
No, it's impossible. I have a method,
but there is no way that Mello would respond in this situation.
Let me take off my underwear
after I wrap the blanket around me.
Fine.
The escort team was forced to shoot one of the perpetrators.
They are still tracking Miss Takada's whereabouts.
It's definitely no good, is it, Light?
Yeah.
Takada's cell phone is turned off.
I want to get in contact with Takada if at all possible,
but right now, all I can do is wait.
This is the only thing that can be done. If I don't do it...
We are still unable to identify
the man who was shot.
Matt,
I never thought you would be killed.
I'm sorry.
Light!
Impossible!
Everyone, be quiet.
Yes?
Yagami, I...
Miss Takada?!
Miss Takada, are you all right?!
The only reason that she'd call me
without notice in this situation
is because she escaped from Mello, or...
Yagami, save me!
It's all right.
Calm down and answer my questions.
All right.
First, your location.
Do you know where you are?
I don't know where I am.
I was put into a truck. It was locked from the outside.
We went on the freeway and I once saw a sign
that said we were heading to Nagano.
Right now, I'm inside a building.
Miss Takada, you're Kira's spokesperson.
Do you remember telling me
that there might be people who are after your life?
Yes, I remember.
We talked about what you would do in that situation.
Do you remember?
I remember.
I did as you said.
I did it.
She did it!
I didn't struggle even when I was stripped naked.
I did exactly as you said.
I made survival my first priority
and I did it.
Yagami, I did everything you told me to do.
Come quickly... Save me!
Miss Takada...
You know what to do afterwards, don't you?
Do as many killings as possible while I still can...
I-I know...
But Yagami...
You can do it, can't you?
I can...
Aizawa, Ide, let's go.
Okay.
Matsuda, take care of headquarters.
All right.
It's me...
Send me as many names as you can of those to be punished.
My email address is...
Yes. Yes, I understand.
The fact that she's called me like this
means that she's killed her kidnappers.
Then the only thing that's certain is that she's in a situation where she can't make any moves.
Nakajima, I'm heading to the crime scene for the case.
Okay.
We've discovered the location by tracing the call.
Head to Karuizawa by freeway.
Karuizawa, huh?
Damn. It'll take at least thirty minutes.
Please hurry.
It's Mello. We don't know what he'll do.
Yeah.
For God's sake... Aizawa and Ide are so stupid!
They both got into the front seats without a thought.
This is just too easy.
This scene... Mello!
What's going on?!
Takada Kiyomi, suicide.
January 26th, 2013,
2:32 p.m.
Burns to death by setting fire to everything around her,
including the things she wrote on.
It'll end now.
No,
today is just the beginning.
Kira's perfect world.
Everyone who knows about the notebook
shall die!