L,
I want to meet you.
Daikoku Wharf.
The Yellow Box.
On the 28th. How about 1 p.m.?
That's fine.
Take off everything you're wearing and put it in there.
I'll give you a blanket.
Miss Takada, are you all right?!
Yagami, I did everything you told me to do.
I made survival my first priority and I did it.
Come quickly... Save me!
Takada Kiyomi.
January 26th, 2013,
2:32 p.m.
Burns to death by setting fire to everything around her, including the things she wrote on.
We are sad to announce that the Special Police
has confirmed in their autopsy report
that one of the bodies recovered
at the crime scene was that of Takada Kiyomi.
A two-ton truck and a motorcycle were found in the burnt-down church.
Officials suspect a gasoline fire.
I'm wondering
who's going to be Kira's next spokesperson?
Kira's voice should continue to be broadcast to the world.
It is very unfortunate that Newscaster Takada passed away,
but I have to say that with that kind of carelessness, she lacked a full appreciation for her position as Kira's representative.
A woman is not suited for this role.
Kira, make me your representative.
No. Give the honor to Sakura TV once again!
This is horrible.
Yeah.
As soon as Takada was annnounced dead,
every station has been debating over who should be Kira's spokesman.
The killings last night were carried out.
This means that Takada and Mikami had cell phone contact.
There's nothing to worry about.
It's Near!
L.
Yes?
Sorry to interrupt,
but we're going to meet...
on the 28th at 1 p.m. Is that still all right?
Yes.
There's no change,
just as I thought.
There's no mistake.
So the day after tomorrow, the 28th.
Got it.
The day after tomorrow, huh?
Isn't it exciting?
Yeah, I don't know what Near wants to show us, but...
Matsuda, Ide,
we all might be killed tomorrow.
Do you understand?
Gevanni.
Yes.
Will you make it in time?
Yes. It's not a problem.
Commander Rester, Lidner, Gevanni,
let's do our best.
Good morning, everyone.
G-Good morning.
First,
we've released Amane.
Call her for confirmation.
I don't know why, but I'm in a deluxe suite at the Teito Hotel.
Probably as some sort of compensation...
It feels great!
I see. All right.
Please stay there for a little longer.
Okay!
Near, please get me Mogi.
In order to bring the notebook we have here,
we need PIN's from each of us.
All right. I'll connect you to him.
This is Mogi. The number is 62-324.
All that's left is my number.
The Killer Notebook.
How to use...
The human whose name is written in this notebook shall die.
This note will not take effect unless the writer has the person's face in their mind when writing his/her name.
Therefore, people sharing
the same name will not be affected.
If the cause of death is written
within 40 seconds of writing the person's name,
it will happen.
If the cause of death is not specified,
the person will simply die of a heart attack.
After writing the cause of death, details of the death should be written in the next 6 minutes and 40 seconds.
Near, I've got the notebook here.
I'll be bringing it with me.
Is it all right if Mr. Aizawa carries it, L?
Near,
my only concern is whether you think that Aizawa is best-suited for this task.
Thank you very much.
We'll see you there.
It's all going to end.
No, today is just the beginning.
Kira's perfect world...
Everyone who knows about the notebook...
shall die.
Near is inside. There's no mistake.
Well then, let's go.
Near, you're far inferior to L.
You have no right to wear a mask of L.
L, those four are the SPK.
Near is the one wearing the mask.
W-Wait, I have a problem with this.
I don't care whom he accuses of being Kira,
but that mask proves that he's trying to protect only himself.
This is just for insurance.
There is a chance that everyone's faces, excluding me, can be seen by Kira.
He may already have written down our names.
So for an hour—
no, for half an hour, I want to see
if anyone becomes controlled or dies.
Wh-What's with that?
He's waiting to see if we die?
He's right... It's not impossible if Light is Kira.
Especially now... We're expendable.
This is just a front to buy some time, Near.
I never thought it would be so hard to keep myself from laughing.
Near's probably waiting for him to come.
I've already predicted that.
Near!
It's been over thirty minutes.
Nothing's happened!
Of course. Kira isn't here.
Fine. Everyone seems safe.
I'll remove my mask.
What's wrong, Near?
Are you still waiting for something?
Waiting... That's right.
I am waiting
for the one person who will solve everything to arrive.
One more person who will solve everything?
He'll come soon.
That's what I'm waiting for.
This building is enclosed.
You can't see inside without opening that door.
He'll come through that door,
or peek through it.
Who's going to come?
The one who is currently killing in Kira's place: X-Kira.
He'll come with the notebook
and he'll see me and write my name.
No, he'll probably try to kill everyone here
who knows about the notebook.
This...
This makes no sense.
What are you talking about?!
Are you saying that some third party is going
to come strolling by with the notebook and kill us?!
So we should just be quiet and watch this happen?!
That's right. Please listen.
If someone comes through that door,
just let him in.
If the door opens slightly,
act as if you don't notice.
Th-That's crazy. That wouldn't...
He's already here.
God!
Delete.
Please do not move.
It's all right. You won't die.
Delete.
How can you be so sure, Near?!
I've tampered with the notebook.
Delete.
We took possession of the notebook and replaced its pages.
The person behind the door who is killing for Kira
Delete.
has been using exactly one page every day.
So I replaced the pages for today
and all subsequent days so no one will die.
Delete.
X-Kira, who's beyond that door,
will eventually look inside to see if we're dead.
We can catch him when he does.
The one whose name isn't written in the notebook is Kira.
Y-You're right...
The one whose name isn't written is Kira.
But...
Exactly as planned! Exactly as planned! Exactly as planned!
Tampering with the notebook...
I knew it all along.
Near, you've been completely defeated!
The notebook you tampered with
was the fake that I had Mikami prepare!
And now the one that Mikami is writing names in
is the real notebook that's been hidden!
I had Mikami make a fake notebook
and send Takada clippings from the real one.
In other words, Takada was the one who was really doing the killings.
I had Mikami write names in public numerous times in the fake notebook
so he would be noticed if he was being followed.
But even then, Takada was the one who was doing the killings.
That is how I made them believe
that the notebook that Mikami had was the real one.
Mikami's daily behavior can be called morbidly methodical.
He fills the notebook with names one page a day.
Near, you noticed that,
and thought of tampering with it.
In other words, you arranged it so that on the day of our meeting, the page would be on the right side.
You just had to change the pages for that day on.
If you did, no one would die from having their names written in the notebook.
That was your plan!
That's why the meeting date was unchanged.
But I knew you were going to tamper with the notebook,
so I had Mikami check the notebook every day.
I've confirmed it.
This match was settled at that point.
The notebook that Mikami brought today
was the real one I had him hide!
But, Near,
you had a chance.
You're soft.
You're nowhere as good as L was.
L would have noticed there was a possibility
that the notebook was fake,
and would have tested it.
You had the opportunity.
I'm completely disappointed in you.
This is no fun.
You tried to win too nobly.
Well, that's fine.
It's your fault. Everyone's going to die.
And I...
Kira will have a perfect victory.
To the person outside:
have you written the names down in the notebook?
God!
Yes, I've written them.
No, not yet. Don't laugh yet. Hold it in.
They're all going to die forty seconds after he's written everyone's names.
Thirty-five seconds...
I'll claim my victory after thirty-five seconds!
That's odd.
Why would he answer you calmly
when you asked him if he had written our names?
Who knows? Maybe he's honest?
No, he's confident?
Could it be that he's seen through your plan?
Huh? Then that means we're in big trouble!
Mikami Teru.
Come in if you'd like.
I know that you are doing the killings for Kira.
There shouldn't be anything to be afraid of if you've written our names.
Waltz right in.
Mikami Teru?
That's right.
Don't hide. Come in.
God!
Well done, Mikami!
How many seconds has it been since you wrote the first name?
Thirty...
Thirty-one... Thirty-two...
Thirty-three... Thirty-four...
Thirty-five... Thirty-six...
Thirty-seven...
Thirty-eight!
Thirty-nine!
Near, I win!
Forty!
That's right.
I'm Kira.