How many seconds has it been since you wrote the first name?
Thirty-five...
Thirty-six...
Thirty-seven...
Thirty-eight!
Thirty-nine!
Near, I win.
Forty!
We're not dead...
A minute's passed...
and we're not dead!
I've been telling you that nobody would die.
Wh-Why?
Why won't they die?!
G-God!
I did as you told me!
Rester, Gevanni, apprehend Mikami.
Gevanni, the notebook.
See for yourselves.
The first four names are unmistakably the real names of the SPK members.
And the only name not here is...
Yagami Light.
Mikami called you "God,"
and said that he did as you told him to.
This proves it.
It's a trap!
This is a trap!
Near set the whole thing up to frame me!
It's strange that no one's dead even after their names were written in the notebook.
That proves that this is a trap!
But I told you that nobody would die because I tampered with the notebook.
N-No...
No way!
Impossible!
This is a setup. I don't know that man.
Light, it's too late.
Near wins.
A second ago, you said "I win."
That's as good a confession as any.
Light...
Wh-Why?
S-Stop!
Yagami Light...
L...
Kira...
You lose.
You declared your victory a moment ago.
Truthfully, you might have won
and I might have lost.
We tampered with the fake notebook
as you expected us to.
But when I said that I had tampered with it,
I was referring to the real notebook as well.
We only switched a part of the fake notebook.
But as for the real one,
we switched the whole thing.
This is the real notebook.
I-Impossible!
We used the same pen as Mikami,
copied Mikami's handwriting perfectly,
and made the inside and outside look exactly the same.
Gevanni was able to do it in a single night.
Since I had already touched the real notebook,
I could see the Shinigami.
Shinigami, pleased to meet you. I'm Near.
Pleased to meet you. I'm Ryuk.
He can talk to Ryuk.
He can see him, so it must be real.
The edges of this page of the notebook are cut.
Would someone die if their name were written on this clipped portion?
Yeah, he would.
I thought so.
You probably found many ways to use this.
I wonder how many times you've killed
and deceived us with this.
Yagami Light.
You are Kira.
This has to be a trick.
Could Mikami have betrayed me?
You're mistaken.
This is happening thanks to Mello.
I'm sure you'll understand what I mean by that.
Mello?!
Take a good look at this.
Takada's name is in the notebook!
A plan to kill Takada
a minute after I did!
Could it be that Mikami did the same thing at that time?!
G-God, I thought that you were being watched and couldn't take action.
I thought it was my job
to take care of Takada in a situation like that...
You idiot!
I've been giving you orders not to make any unnecessary moves until today!
That's right. On the 26th,
right after Takada's kidnapping was broadcast,
Mikami went to the bank.
According to my findings,
Mikami goes to the bank every month on the 25th.
It is very odd for someone as methodical as Mikami to go there two days in a row.
I followed Mikami to a safe deposit box.
It was only at this time
that he became clearly concerned that someone was following him.
It was easy to open the safe.
Inside it,
the real notebook was there
and Takada's name was written in it.
Yagami Light,
you didn't notice that Mikami took the liberty and made a move
because you had just killed her with a clipping from the notebook.
This is when I noticed the possibility of a fake notebook
thanks to Mello, who had created this situation.
Mello may have known about it.
He said that it's straightforward
if we can get him to write in the notebook?
Yes...
I'm going to have to do it.
Mello knew.
He knew that alone, we aren't able to attain our goal to surpass L.
But together...
Together we can stand with L.
Together we can surpass L!
And right now, we are confronting Kira, who defeated L,
with solid evidence!
Try to talk your way out of this if you can.
That's right.
I'm Kira.
That's right. I'm Kira.
So what are you going to do?
Are you going to kill me here?
Listen...
I'm Kira.
And...
I'm the god of the new world.
Kira is the law of the world right now.
Kira is maintaining order.
I am already justice incarnate.
The human race and the world's only hope.
Are you going to kill me?
Is that really the right thing to do?
Since Kira appeared six years ago,
wars have stopped and global crime rates
have decreased by seventy percent.
But the world is still rotten!
There are still too many rotten people.
Someone has to do it.
When I first laid hands on the notebook,
I knew I had to do it!
No,
I was the only one who could do it!
I know that killing people is a crime.
But this is the only way to fix the world!
This is a duty given to me!
I'm the only one who can do this.
Could anyone else have done it?!
Could they have done this much?!
Could they have continued on?!
That's right.
The only one who can create the new world...
is me.
No.
You're just a murderer.
And this notebook is the worst murder weapon in history.
You've yielded to the power
of the Shinigami and the notebook.
You're no different from a crazy serial killer who has a god complex.
That's all you are.
Nothing more, nothing less.
They're all fools who don't understand.
Near.
The notebook you have right now,
and the notebook that Aizawa brought
from the Japanese Investigative Headquarters...
Are they real?
Is he bluffing now?
Only I know where the real notebook is.
If you're going to defeat Kira,
even if it's just to test the notebook that Aizawa's carrying...
you should write my name or Mikami's in it.
To see if the notebook is real...
or fake!
He's hidden a piece of the notebook!
Matsuda!
You imbecile!
Matsuda! Who do you think you're shooting at?!
Stop fucking around!
What was it all for?
What in the world did your Dad die for?
Dad? Oh, you mean Yagami Soichiro?!
That's right, Matsuda!
Overly earnest people with a strong sense of justice like him are always going to lose.
Are you okay with a world like that?!
Kill the others if you understand!
Shoot!
You let your father die...
How can you act as if it were nothing?!
He's writing with his blood!
I'm going to kill you!
We have to kill him!
Matsuda!
Damn...
What... is this?!
Mikami... What are you doing?!
Write!
You have... to kill them!
Near...
It's finally over, isn't it?
Yes.
What happened to Misa?!
What about Takada?!
S-Someone...
What in the world should I...
M-Mikami's...
Stop the bleeding!
No, but...
We can't do anything anymore...
Light!
Light! Wait!
Mr. Aizawa!
He probably doesn't have any more notebooks hidden.
He can't go very far with those wounds.
He'll stop on his own if we leave him alone.
Near, I'm not taking your orders.
All right. I'll leave it to you.
You lose, Light.
I told you when we first met
that I'd be the one writing your name
in my notebook when you die.
It's the agreement that's made between a Shinigami who brings a notebook to the Human World...
and the first human who picks up the notebook.
I don't know when you die if they'll put you in prison.
And it's too much of a pain to wait around.
It's all over.
You should die right here.
We've eased each other's boredom for quite a while.
It's been quite...
fun.