Okay.
Finally healed!
I was resting until my wounds healed,
but now I can fight like before.
I have to work hard for
Sheele and Bulat's sake!
Kill the Battle Fanatic
Someone, train with me.
Hey... Mine...
You've recovered. That's great.
What are you doing?
These guys were gung-ho about training,
so we're helping them out.
After putting it on...
I realized how much energy Incursio takes.
Train Daily
Bulat
I need to train my body, so I can wear it
for a prolonged time like Bro.
As of now,
I can barely use invisibility for a second.
I rarely see you drenched in sweat, Lubbock.
Well, there are only two
guys in our group now.
I figured I should start
putting in more effort...
Good job, sounding cool.
But you realize you've only done half
as many push-ups as Tatsumi.
That can't be helped.
Since Leone and I have a
major weight disparity.
You're all here.
Boss...
I'm going to Revolutionary Army headquarters
to deliver the Imperial Arms we
confiscated from the Three.
Alone?
That axe is ridiculously heavy, though.
Oh, I can handle this much.
Here.
It isn't possible to use as a weapon,
but transporting it isn't an issue.
The boss is amazing like the rest of you?
Obviously.
You know she was a general, right?
Akame, you're in charge while I'm gone.
Our plan of action is that
everyone does their best.
I understand the basics.
Just the basics?!
Don't worry, she'll take her role seriously.
The other reason I'm going to headquarters
is to recruit new members.
I hope they can spare some
talented individuals,
but I doubt there are any.
I'm sorry.
I was weak...
You fought the Three, who were
key figures in Esdeath's army,
considered among the capital's strongest.
You eliminated all of them.
Although Esdeath's strength is unmatched,
her army has clearly been weakened.
When the Revolution takes place,
you'll have helped mitigate a huge concern.
Not only did you save the lives
of the people on that ship,
you essentially saved thousands
in the Revolutionary Army
who would've had to have faced them.
You're strong, and you've done well.
Boss...
I didn't want to inflate your ego,
so I refrained from saying this.
But Bulat once told me...
Tatsumi's still green
But he'll undoubtedly become stronger.
As long as he trains rigorously,
he may just surpass me one day.
I look forward to seeing that.
Bro...
Be proud, Tatsumi.
Keep surviving.
And become the man Bulat
anticipated you could be.
That being said...
We're still short-handed.
And according to Leone,
Esdeath is organizing a special
force of Imperial Arms users.
I have to do something.
Liver, Nyau, Daidara...
You three lost.
Which means you were weak.
It's only natural that
the weak are eliminated.
My poor subordinates.
There's nothing else that can be done
other than avenge your deaths.
My new subordinates who use
Imperial Arms arrive today.
I've been told they have their quirks.
Perhaps I'll play around with them some.
Fish Market
My name is Wave.
As a true man of the sea,
I fought in the Imperial Navy.
I've been recruited to join the special
forces squad the capital's organized.
Basically, it's a promotion.
Since it's my first time in the big city,
I didn't want to look like a hick.
So I wore super cool
clothes to help me fit in.
Back home, everyone admired me!
And the assorted seafood my mother
made me bring as gifts
is all top-notch, so there's no oversight.
It will be rude if you don't
bring gifts! Take this!
However...
He's a hick.
He must be from the country...
Maybe I'm imagining things,
but I feel like people
are looking at me funny.
Did I do something rude?
A hillbilly.
Yeah, definitely from the country.
Well,
I'm a man who's fought pirates and
aquatic Danger Beasts!
Little things won't bother me!
All right.
My new teammates are in here?
First impressions are crucial.
I can't be intimidated by them, so let's go!
You can't let them bulldoze you.
Dive in head-first!
Good afternoon!
I've come from the Imperial Navy—
Pardon me!
Uh, so this must be the torturer's room.
Jeez...
It's correct.
Which means he's one of my teammates!
H-Hello.
For the time being, I'll just
try not to draw attention.
Hey, hey... What's with him?
He's been staring straight
at me the whole time!
This is bad.
Mom, I wanna go home!
It's a normal girl!
H-Hey!
I'm Wave, and—
You can't have any of these.
She's totally weird, too!
Sorry for bothering you.
Crap. What the hell?
Pardon me!
I'm Seryu Ubiquitous, of the imperial police.
And this is Coro.
Oh, this one seems normal enough!
Dr. Stylish, all is prepared now!
Caring about one's first impression...
That is indeed what I call "stylish,"
as a man with etiquette.
Another crazy one!
Oh, my.
I can tell by sight alone that
you're a country boy.
But you're pretty good looking!
I can polish you to be even better.
We'll get along well.
And he's into me.
Hello.
Seems I'm the last to arrive.
Hey.
Nice to meet you. I'm Wave.
I'm Run. It's a pleasure
to meet you, as well.
Finally! A normal person!
Um...
Everyone... I've made some tea.
I'm really sorry.
I was the first one here,
and I didn't say anything.
I'm what you call painfully shy...
So I was nervous.
But I probably have the most seniority...
I have to get it together!
Since we're all Imperial Arms users,
I'm sure we'll get along!
I'm Bols, of the Incineration Squad.
That isn't the look of someone who's shy...
The Incineration Squad...
The stylish squad that sets anything ablaze,
be it man or thing.
No wonder he looks like that.
He isn't my type.
Huh? Who are you?
What are you all doing here?
Hey, hey...
We were all told to assemble here.
Assassins are among the traitors.
Don't ever drop your guard!
This one has good reflexes.
For someone trying to attack from behind,
you're giving off too much presence.
Even if you're just messing around,
I can't hold back.
So that's the Imperial Arms Yatsufusa, eh?
What an impressive blade.
General Esdeath!
Ouch...
Even our boss is weird!
Did I surprise you earlier?
I figured a normal greeting would be boring.
I'm used to rough situations.
In fact, thank you for the lesson!
All right, then.
We have a party to attend,
after we meet with the emperor.
W-We're already meeting him?
For the first day, this is a pretty
fast-paced schedule.
I believe in getting annoying
things out of the way first.
But before that, Lady Esdeath...
What do we call ourselves?
We are a unique organization,
ordered to mercilessly hunt and
take down the atrocious traitors.
We are the special police force...
We are the Jaegers.
I'm really happy
we're serving my assorted
seafood as the main course...
But isn't it weird that
he's the one who can cook?
Wave,
the spinach should go in last.
If you put it in now,
it'll become too tender.
I, uh... Sorry.
By the way, I was relieved when I
learned that you're a kind person.
I'm not... a kind person...
General!
How have you been spending your time here?
Mostly hunting and torturing.
Or researching.
But at the moment...
I am interested in falling in love.
Love?
On another note,
I've been informed there
is a spare Imperial Arms.
Oh, uh... Yes.
The giant scissor-shaped Imperial Arms,
retrieved from evil, is at the main office.
But they have yet to find
someone suited to it.
If it stays like that, the
minister will take them.
That would be quite a waste.
Perhaps we should put on a show,
to help us identify one who's
capable of using them.
Oh.
Hey.
Yo.
Whoa!
This really does feel like a secret base!
Right?
It's my pride and joy!
But you didn't make it or anything, did you?
Hey, there!
Welcome to the secret base in the capital!
Sis, you're way too relaxed.
Well... Mine's face appeared
on the wanted signs,
so only we three can walk
freely in the capital.
Also, the city's been clamoring
about the special police force.
They call themselves the Jaegers.
Considering Esdeath is their leader,
that isn't surprising.
I get why it's a hot topic,
since she's such a dangerous person.
Tell me exactly how dangerous she is.
Let's see...
Let me give you an idea.
A few years ago,
a tribe in the southwestern region
rebelled against the imperial
capital's tyrannical rule.
The capital responded by dispatching a
special force to go enslave them.
The tribe had about ten thousand warriors,
and the capital sent one hundred and
twenty thousand soldiers.
Everyone felt the result would be obvious.
However...
The land itself and the obstacles
they faced were intense
for soldiers who lived comfortable
lives near the capital.
When faced with nature's brutality,
they were overwhelmed.
On top of that, the tribal
warriors attacked nightly.
The young but capable Generals Najenda and
General Esdeath,
you seem gloomier than usual.
Of course I am.
The minister's orders were to
end the rebellion swiftly
with our Imperial Arms.
Handling nature's fury, which was too
daunting for the special forces,
is part of warfare's true
thrill and pleasure.
And yet, we have these boring orders.
However, it's an order.
Whether it's facing a
beast or noxious insects,
or a plague or virus,
everything before me
will freeze.
Wh-What power...
Travel directly to enemy
headquarters to destroy them!
My attacks are as strong as a cannon!
Musket troops,
fire!
After annihilating the enemy,
it's time to enjoy ourselves.
Destroy this town to your hearts' content.
Are you watching?
Do you see your home being ravaged?
Damn you! Just kill us!
I am a woman of mercy.
Some things are worth pitying.
I'm going to let a few of you go.
Stop joking around!
If you don't kill us now, we'll certainly
come back and kill you—
Remember this.
It's only natural for the
weak to end up like this.
If that makes you angry, become stronger.
I can't be a part of this.
Even though the capital ordered
us to make an example of them...
I can't be among those
who enjoy this savagery.
So that's what happened.
After causing so much agony, letting them
live seems pretty wicked.
In fact, from the capital's prospective,
wouldn't that be like
adding fuel to the fire?
That's exactly what Esdeath wants.
She wants more rebellions.
So she can enjoy being in war
for as long as possible.
Unbelievable...
Jeez, she's dangerous!
I'm glad I decided not to mess
with her when I was alone.
I wonder how many hundreds of
thousands of kills it took
for her to gain that evil aura.
She must be a monster for you to
talk about it like that, Sis.
If you're so curious, you should
check her out yourself.
Esdeath is sponsoring a citywide
martial arts tournament.
The winner gets a cash reward.
Maybe you can earn some money
to send back to your hometown.
Say, Minister?
Why do you think General Esdeath
said she wants to fall in love?
When they reach a certain age,
everyone desires the opposite sex.
General Esdeath was
practically born to battle.
Until now, she's always chosen
war over anything else.
But it seems different
desires have blossomed.
I see.
I'd like to help her find someone suitable.
She is a person of great pride.
I'm sure she won't accept anyone
less than perfect for her.
But no man like this exists.
Above all, he must possess
the potential for a great future.
I would personally like to train him
into a highly ranked general.
Second, he must be fearless,
and able to hunt Danger Beasts.
Third, much like myself,
he must have been raised outside the capital.
"Fourth, since I will be controlling him,
he must be younger than I am."
"Fifth, it would be nice if he
has a pure, innocent smile."
Most would be disqualified
at the first requirement.
Being trained by her into a highly ranked
general is also problematic.
What do you think of them?
Since they're boring subjects, the
battle itself is boring, as well.
I guess it was asking too much to expect
one capable of using an Imperial Arms.
Oh, it seems they've chosen the winner.
The winner is Nobunaga,
the dry goods merchant!
I did it!
This next battle is the last match.
On the east side...
Kalbi the butcher!
And on the west side...
Tatsumi the blacksmith!
That's an interesting cover.
Does he know how to strike iron?
Not as well as I do.
But he's pretty skilled.
It looks like one of them
is still a young man.
You're quite small, aren't you?
Guess I'll be taking that prize money!
I may have been excommunicated,
but I'm still a ninth-level master at Koukenji.
This old guy...
He isn't just talking himself up.
He's definitely powerful.
I may have been intimidated in the past,
but I'm calm now, aren't I?
Compared to the Three, this is nothing.
Begin!
Have a full course of my explosive fist!
I don't even need Incursio for this guy.
Whoa!
Wow!
That young man is outstandingly talented.
Yeah.
That'll be all!
The winner is Tatsumi!
Everyone is cheering for me...
I did it!
We've found him.
A candidate for an Imperial
Arms user, I presume?
That, as well.
But also...
Commander?
She's coming to the ring herself?
Tatsumi... That's your name, right?
It's a nice name.
Th-Thanks.
So this is Esdeath,
the commander of the Three.
If she didn't exist, Bro would still...
Your win just now was magnificent.
I'd like to give you a reward.
Thank you very much.
Even though I'm taking it from the enemy,
money is money.
I'll gratefully accept it.
Huh?
From now on, you'll belong to me.
Wh-What?
It's too distracting out here.
Come to my palace.
W-Wait, hold on!
No, I won't wait.
What did she just do to me?
Let's talk in my room,
just the two of us.
Wh-What the hell is going on?!
Tatsumi's been taken by Esdeath?
Did she find out he was a Night Raid member?
I don't really know...
There's a fifty-fifty chance.
We watched them go to the palace, but...
What do we do, acting boss?
Tatsumi...
I won't die!
Don't say something stupid
like you'll rescue him, Akame.
For the time being,
let's move our base farther
into the mountains.
That's a good idea.
They might find this hideout.
So what do we do about Tatsumi?
It may be impossible to rescue him...
I'm aware of that.
We won't rush in without any means,
but Tatsumi is an important teammate!
We'll do what we can!
Kill the Temptation