I wanted
to spend more time with everyone.
I wanted to fight alongside everyone.
If only I...
If I were more...
Tatsumi, how long do you plan on sleeping?
A-Ah, right.
My bad.
I was sleeping like a log.
We're finally entering Kyoroch, the religious
organization's headquarters.
Pull yourself together.
I know!
As long as we can defeat
the evil that dwells here,
the Revolutionary Army can
make their move, right?
This isn't the time to be
distracted by memories.
We need to take down this empire,
which starves its people,
and sever the root of these tragedies.
Kill the Demon
Borick, advisor to the religious sect's founder,
the minister has ordered us,
the special police force,
otherwise known as the Jaegers, to protect you.
Well, well...
To think that General Esdeath,
strongest in the empire, would come...
I couldn't be more relieved.
There have been reports already that
Night Raid's infiltrating the area.
Until they're caught, we'll borrow a room.
Of course.
I doubt you'll be bored in my mansion.
I have no interest in such things.
However, I would like to meet the
ones who have been spying on us.
As expected, you noticed their presence.
What's with these guys?
The empire let me borrow them.
They are the ones who control the followers,
the very face of violence,
the Four Koukenji Rakshasa Demons.
Oh... I was wondering why I hadn't
seen them in the capital.
They've been here this whole time.
Now that you're here, General, these demons
don't have to be devoted to protecting me.
They can be used for offensives now.
Wait a second, please...
Fighting Night Raid without using
Imperial Arms is impossible—
There's no need to worry.
We've defeated Imperial Arms
users with our bare hands.
Just like this...
Even if the Imperial Arms
are considered powerful...
...ultimately, the ones who use
them are regular humans.
Which means there many ways
to defeat them, right?
The Four Rakshasa Demons are
executioners hired by the minister.
As you've seen, their skill is superb.
Exactly.
You can just relax and have some
wine in the mansion while we—
Regardless of your accomplishments,
you shouldn't lower your guard.
Ah, incredible...
As expected of General Esdeath.
I'm gonna fall for you.
He had us come here, even though his
important pawns are already here.
That minister must be pretty cautious
about this religious organization.
Kurome...
Kurome!
Damn it. If I had gotten here sooner...
Bols is gone, too.
Even though he has a wife and kid...
What am I supposed to say to them?
But you were blown away because
you were protecting Kurome.
The captain doesn't blame
anyone for this incident.
I understand how you feel,
but you must calm down.
Damn it... Damn it!
Damn it!
How's Kurome?
She's still sleeping.
The doctor said that if she's made
it this far, she'll be all right.
I see.
I dissected the assassin we retrieved,
but I couldn't find anything
to reveal her identity.
Most likely, an Imperial Arms user.
Probably a member of Night Raid.
Indeed.
Captain...
May I feed Coro the evil person's corpse?
Sure.
Whew!
K-Kurome?
Now that I've rested, I'm better.
I've recovered a whole lot.
Eh? You must be kidding.
You were hit in the vitals!
Captain...
Please allow me to continue working for you.
As you can see, I can fight.
Very well, then.
As long as you're accompanying
us, I'll have you do your best.
We leave for Kyoroch in thirty minutes.
Yes, ma'am!
Wave, is something the matter?
N-No, it's nothing...
Hey, are you okay?
You're probably not fully recovered yet.
You should withdraw from the front lines.
I-I'm okay.
What are you talking about?
I'm gonna talk to the captain,
and have you taken off this mission—
Kurome...
In this squad, if assassins are
considered unable to fight,
they're disposed of, to keep them quiet.
Huh? Disposed of?
If I'm kicked off the Jaegers, I'm...
It'll be okay.
If we tell the captain, she'll protect you.
That's no good.
I have to fight.
I refuse to be disposed of...
I wasn't born into this world for that!
If I'm going to die, I'll die fighting.
Just like our comrades.
Kurome...
I'm okay now, Wave.
I'm sorry for making you worry.
When my wounds heal,
I'll be completely fine.
Kurome...
It seems there aren't any wanted
posters this far from the capital.
The Jaegers may have distributed
some recently, though.
Don't let your guard down.
Hey, just as I was saying...
What are you even doing?
I understand what you mean, but...
Isn't being too paranoid dangerous?
The enemy can sense that kind of tension.
Let's be more casual.
Even though he was so upset
when Chelsea was killed,
he's staying calm and focusing on the mission.
Heh, so he's matured.
Well, I guess you have a point.
What is this?
It's delicious!
Isn't it?
You can't find this in the capital, right?
Now that I think about it,
people seem much livelier here.
It's probably thanks to underground
resources and religion.
Religion?
Apparently, it's very profitable.
Although most of the proceeds seem to
go directly into Minister Onest's hands.
I see... So they don't know they're being used.
Borick is oppressing everyone
who knows the truth.
They can't do anything about it.
That's why we have to breach the system.
Exactly.
Well, for now, we have to
survey the city a bit more.
Right, let's circle the
outer perimeter this time.
Good idea.
Let's leave the dangerous area
around the church to Lubba,
who volunteered so enthusiastically.
Jeez.
These streets are like a maze...
But since there are lots of people,
it's easy to slip into a crowd.
That's helpful.
Whoops.
Luckily neither my face nor my name is known.
So I'll gather as much information as possible,
and score some points with Najenda.
Good job, Lubba.
Hey, Sten...
Doesn't he kinda seem like
he's surveying the area?
My instincts are screaming that he's an enemy.
The way he walks is what gives it away.
That's the movement of someone
who's fought a few battles.
It seems that he's being careful,
but I can tell.
That settles it, then.
Let's kill him.
Wrong, Mez.
Let's call it "freeing his soul."
According to our research,
there may be an underground passage
beneath this graveyard,
leading from the church to Borick's mansion.
If we can find the entrance,
we could go straight to Borick's basement.
Finding it would be difficult.
After all, this area is pretty big.
There's also the possibility of a trap
inside the underground passage.
Thanks for your help.
Did you think you could hide,
sweet Akame?
Ibara...
You're here, in Kyoroch?
Then you remember me?
That makes me happy.
When we were on the Assassination Squad,
we couldn't talk to each other at all.
I expected my battle with
the Four Rakshasa Demons
to be the last fight during
the minister's assassination.
A bad girl who's betrayed the empire
deserves a spanking.
I'll bury you!
Go ahead and try.
We, the Four Rakshasa Demons,
have not only undergone intense training,
but we also grew up consuming
broth of the lake kraken
that lives behind our temple, in the mountains.
So we can control every part of our bodies!
Crap, they suddenly started attacking.
How did they see me?
Are you just gonna keep running, little boy?
What? You died already?
I barely felt you get hit.
Come on, old man...
Hurry up and get out of here.
The thread armor I wrapped my
body in absorbed his punch.
As for my pulse, I inserted Cross Tail into
my body, and blocked the blood vessels.
So we didn't even need to
worry about this small fry.
How boring.
Hurry up.
How long do I have to play dead?
Here you go, Sten.
There's another one coming your way.
She's also a rebel spy.
Is that the girl I was supposed to meet?
I'm sorry, but I can't save you...
As a spy, you should know
to prepare for the worst.
You must be another lost child,
wandering around in this world.
Huh?
I shall free your soul for you.
You should be happy.
H-Help me...
So I couldn't do it...
I couldn't just sit back and watch an ally die.
Earlier, you didn't have a pulse.
What an idiot.
You should have just continued playing dead.
Given my circumstances, I was trying
my best to avoid close combat.
However,
when it comes down to it,
I'll give it everything I've got.
Both of you, come at me!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
That's a pretty sinister blade.
Murasame... It suits you perfectly.
There, there, there!
How's that, sweet Akame?
I told you, we underwent intense training.
Here we go.
Imperial Arms confiscated.
What's with this blade?
Don't tell me... this was the plan...
To let go of your Imperial Arms?
You called Murasame "sinister."
I figured you wouldn't get along.
How dare you...
How dare you?!
The cursed blade didn't take a liking to you.
Perhaps you should be relieved, Ibara.
What a dangerous woman...
I might fall for you.
A surprise attack won't work, I see.
A member of the Jaegers?
Yes.
Akame, of Night Raid, infiltration confirmed.
My role is reconnaissance.
I was able to get a good
look at your Murasame.
The Four Rakshasa
Demons and the Jaegers...
I hope everyone's all right.
Now, come at me!
What do you mean by "come at me"?
You're the one that's attacking with those strings.
I figured that would be too obvious.
Would you like me to free your soul for you?
Koukenji
Hundred Fists!
I wasn't calling to you, old man.
Ah, you're rather skilled.
That thread is an Imperial Arms?
Which means you belong to Night Raid.
Then, this time, I'll split your skull,
and make sure to kill you.
Stop flirting with me like that, would you?
Assemble, my thread.
And enhance...
Centrifugal Force!
Doesn't that move have far too many gaps?
Not really.
Take this.
Hidden ability...
Wire Impact!
Feeble.
This is your hidden move?
Don't make me laugh.
R-Really?
But I've already accomplished my goal.
Look behind you.
The woman got away.
And I'm gone, too.
He was using flashy moves to draw
our attention from the woman.
We have no choice.
Even if it's only you, I'll free your soul.
Are you sure it's okay to charge me like that?
My thread is made from the fur of a mega-class
Danger Beast, which lives in the eastern clouds.
The fur that protects its vitals is especially tough.
Thread from those areas is particularly sharp,
sharp enough to earn the name
"Realm-Cutting Thread."
What?
It's my best thread.
Even you won't be able to cut it.
Final blow.
F-Feeble...
This body's been through the toughest training.
This wound can't possibly...
It doesn't matter how tough your body is.
From the moment Cross Tail pierced your body,
its thread headed straight for your heart.
There's no way to train your
heart to be invulnerable.
Wow, not bad.
You actually defeated Sten.
The minister is gonna be mad about this.
Well, you don't have to worry about that.
Sorry, but now that you've
seen my Imperial Arms,
I can't let you live.
Don't be sorry.
After all, we're assassins,
so it's to be expected.
What the hell is that liquid?
This is bad.
That liquid is weighing down my
thread, rendering it useless.
It isn't oil. More like my sweat.
The Four Rakshasa Demons are
experts in body-manipulation.
Now the thread used for your
defensive barrier is useless.
S-So fast...
C-Can't get up...
If I take another attack, I'll die for sure.
Take this!
Don't be so desperate.
It's embarrassing.
Damn, you're cute...
If we weren't enemies, I would've
definitely tried to seduce you.
I don't dislike guys like you, so I
probably would have let you.
However...
That'll have to wait for the next life.
Bye-bye.
I had some thread tied to those knives.
So when I reeled in my thread,
the knives came back, too.
Bye-bye.
I have to hurry and get outta here...
Man, what a waste.
This always happens to me!
Whew.
We've searched the area a few times,
but there are still many escape routes
and secret paths to investigate.
This area is way too big!
That's exactly why we're surveying it.
If I could just go shopping, I would
gladly survey the whole area.
Your shopping takes forever, so it's
annoying to accompany you.
Huh? It's normal.
A man who can't excuse a woman's shopping?
How shallow.
A woman who immediately labels
a man's observations shallow?
Now that's shallow.
I see how it is!
Let's see whose rank is higher, here and now.
You're so arrogant!
The fact that you think there should
be a ranking system is messed-up!
Please stop this unproductive fighting.
Huh?
Who are you?
My apologies for intruding
on your conversation.
I couldn't help but speak up.
Are you perhaps the founder...
...of the Path of Peace?
Yes.
Sometimes, I go around the outskirts of
town, to ensure everything is all right.
I can clearly see that you two are
bound by the red thread of fate.
So instead of fighting,
you should confess your love.
Huh?
If you became a couple, an occasional
squabble would be good for you.
Huh?
Huh?!
Why would I ever be with someone like him?
What about me? I'd never be
with someone like you!
I believe you two are meant for one another.
Congratulations.
You've been chosen as our lord's noble disciple.
I-Is that true?
To be able to witness our lord's miracles...
It's a dream come true.
However, there still seems to be
something wicked in your body,
which makes you unfit for the role.
N-No...
Remove your clothes.
I'll cleanse you with a special ritual.
Yes, Lord Borick.
I implore you...
Full control of the religious
organization will soon occur.
Till then, I'll make the most of it.
Lord Borick...
What is it?
I'm in the middle of an important ritual.
The Four Rakshasa Demons...
In conclusion, three were
taken out in one night.
We underestimated Night Raid.
In other words,
we, the Jaegers, are the only
ones that can bestow justice
upon those heinous people.
Najenda... You may have won
a few battles along the way,
but I'll trample every single
one of your allies here.
Kill the Fate