Even after thorough searching,
how are we still unable to find their hideout?
Well, Kyoroch is a pretty big place.
And people here are religious and peaceful,
so we can't easily force
them out into the open.
Here.
They're so cute...
These children have yet to be tainted by evil!
I see, so she has another side.
She's been tense for a while.
The captain told her to loosen up a bit.
Hold up, you're hanging out,
like you're one of us...
But are you?
Hmm, more like a helping hand?
And it's a chance for me to be ordered
around by General Esdeath.
What am I sensing?
It's the same feeling I got from Stylish.
Everyone, play fair, be decent,
and get along with one another.
Okay!
The joy of a child choosing the path of justice!
This morality, this justice...
I have to protect it.
And that's all the information from our spies.
Kill the Fate
We're executing our plans during the religious
organization's anniversary festival.
Ah, how flashy.
We'll slip into the festival crowds,
sneak into the palace,
and take down Borick.
It's finally time.
This will signal the Revolutionary Army to rise up.
Failure is not an option!
Everyone, it's time to eat.
Today, I gave it all I had.
I hope you're all prepared!
Yeah!
Salt ramen for Najenda. With al dente noodles
and umami from the chicken
and salt, I'm confident.
Whoa...
Strawberry parfait for Mine.
I've even added some secret ingredients.
Oh, my.
The super fresh pandalid shrimp
is for you, Lubbock.
Wow.
Oden with chilled, high-end,
local sake for Leone.
An assortment of all the meat
I could get, for Akame.
It's marinated in my special sauce.
Tatsumi said he'd be fine with anything,
so here's my ultra-special Susanoo lunch plate.
Huh?
This is a kid's plate.
I had Susanoo make all your favorites.
Eat your fill, so you can maintain your energy.
And you're all already eating...
It's good that you're full of energy.
Yum. It's so sweet.
Delicious.
Tatsumi, wanna try some?
Tatsumi, what do we do when
my sake cup is empty?
Okay, okay. I'll pour some more.
Good, good... That's a good boy, Tatsumi!
Huh? Done already?
The food was incredible, as always, Su.
Yeah... We couldn't live
without you anymore, Su.
That is nice to hear.
However, Tatsumi...
You left a grain of rice!
It's distracting me.
If he weren't this anal retentive,
he'd be perfect.
If Night Raid were to attack, it will be today.
That's obvious, right, Seryu?
Miss Suzuka, please do not let any rebels enter.
Right, right.
Oh?
That walk and that gleam in her eye...
Seems you couldn't conceal yourself completely.
Damn, they're already looking for us.
It doesn't seem like they'd
follow us all the way here.
But now we're farther from the city.
I wonder if that served as a diversion.
Now we just have to believe all the
other bosses will do their part.
I feel like my face is still a mess...
Did all that makeup come off?
It's off...
Why are you all bashful?
Don't tell me you took that whole
"red string of fate" thing seriously.
No way...
The fact you'd bring that up means you're
the one who took it seriously!
Huh? That's not funny.
And if the red string of fate were to tie us,
you should have helped when
that frog swallowed me.
When you're needed most, you're useless!
Shut up...
I was completely tied up, too!
That woman... She's from Night Raid.
And worse, the person next to her is Tatsumi.
He's been tainted by evil.
Coro, number nine!
City Justice Detector.
There are no civilians in the area.
Finally...
We meet again, Night Raid.
Coro and I will annihilate evil,
and bring down the hammer of justice!
Coro!
From the Judgement of the Ten Kings,
I’ll combine two, seven, and eight and
shoot them with this annihilation device.
Tatsumi has fallen to evil, even though
he was adored by our great captain.
And the little villain who took
both my arms that night...
Repent in the blazing fire!
It smells like gunpowder.
Justice...
Simultaneous Fire!
So, you're still alive.
What a stubborn evil!
What's with this reckless attack?
Hmm...
This must mean we were drawn out
to the city's edge on purpose.
How audacious.
There are more, Tatsumi.
They stopped.
Are we out of range?
I saw who it was.
It's Seryu Ubiquitous.
Seryu Ubiquitous...
Where did she shoot from?
The last member of the Four Rakshasa Demons!
I'm Suzuka.
But I guess there's no reason to introduce
myself to those about to perish...
I'll deal with this one!
Get out of here, Mine!
Don't be stupid.
After being mocked like that, I can't run.
Ah, Tatsumi!
I won't let you lay a finger on Mine.
I'm your opponent!
How cool...
And that's fine. I'll kill you first.
Tatsumi!
Idiot...
I'll leave her to you.
I'll take on Seryu.
I'll finish her off, and make my way to you!
Coro, number six!
What is that?
That's a weapon, too?
How dare you rebels disrupt the system?
One who doesn't fight for
justice cannot possibly win!
Heh, what a huge target!
You took down the strongest
weapon in one shot?
Well, then...
Coro, number one!
I've come to personally deliver
judgment, Night Raid.
Seryu Ubiquitous...
I'll have you eaten, just like your friends.
"Friends"?
That woman whose head was put on a stake
in Romary was your friend, right?
Coro ate the rest of her body.
Just like that woman in glasses.
They both ended up being snacks.
And you will, too.
You...
For someone who always talks about justice,
you blindly trusted Ogre and Stylish.
You couldn't see that they were evil.
And that twisted laugh of yours...
It's no different from those evil men.
You're broken.
I can kill you without hesitation.
I'll shoot you down, no matter what!
Feel better, now that you
let all that nonsense out?
Coro, number five.
And your arm!
You just gave Coro time to recover.
Evil sure is stupid.
Let's go, Coro!
What's with this power?
I've been waiting for this...
For this battle to really become two-against-one.
The greater a pinch I'm in,
the stronger my Pumpkin rifle is.
Coro, endure it.
There's no way she can keep
up this attack for long.
That's true.
But since we fought before,
I know where the weak spot is.
I won't need long.
Crap.
Coro, hidden ability.
I was waiting for that.
I already know all the moves
of your Imperial Arms!
Enma's Spear of Justice!
Her body is more troublesome than last time.
That artillery...
It's powerful, even though
it isn't an Imperial Arms.
You bitch!
As punishment, I'll beat you to death!
Because of the damage to my body...
Damn it. I couldn't finish her.
So this is the rumored shocking body, huh?
Your strike was too close.
You...
I was surprised to hear someone
defeated Ibara, let alone Mez.
But it seems that it wasn't you.
I can tell how inexperienced
you are in actual combat.
Still too weak...
I've had so many regrets...
So many!
Even if there is a strength differential,
I have to overcome it!
Are you done recovering, Coro?
Good.
We'll attack from both sides simultaneously.
Natala... Doya!
Hey, Su. How's it going?
Smoothly.
We're taking care of the enemies here, as ordered.
I don't have time to play with you.
Where's my big sis?
Before that, allow me to rip off your
left arm, like you did mine.
I'm still wounded from when
that woman tried to kill me.
Brace yourself!
Your opponent
is me.
Sorry for running late, Kurome.
Heh, you wanna get blown away by Su again?
Come at me, lowly assassins.
I won't allow you to hurt any more of my friends.
Grand Chariot!
G-General Esdeath...
What are the Jaegers doing?
Shut your mouth.
This is happening because you
underestimated Night Raid
and let the Four Rakshasa Demons play around.
P-Protect me.
That's an order from the minister—
Well, an order is an order.
I will protect you.
So don't step out of this room.
Y-Yes...
Hiding in the ruins won't do you any good.
Eventually, you'll run out of strength.
That's right, which is why I'm sorry,
but I'll be taking you down with brute force!
Rakshasa Demon...
Wait...
Th-This is too much.
I'll tear this place down
before you can escape.
This reminds me of when,
as a half foreigner,
I was discriminated against.
I would just stare up into the sky.
No one would help me.
And that's when I understood...
That only I could help myself.
And that all my misfortunes were necessary.
Because I'm going to change this unfair world.
Which is why...
There's no way I can die here!
Don't underestimate my Pumpkin!
Coro!
My Ten Kings are all out of ammo,
but I still have this.
Justice is served!
This is the moment.
Blow through!
Sh-She sliced through me.
Pumpkin runs on my emotional energy.
The more intense my emotions,
the stronger it makes me.
You made me snap.
So you lose.
Justice can't lose...
No matter what the circumstances, evil will perish.
Judgment of the Ten Kings: Final Move...
Chakravartin Furnace of Five Hells.
One minute left.
Don't tell me... A suicide bomb?
This is the ultimate evil-purging weapon
I received from the doctor.
So long as I have this in my head,
I can't lose.
You...
It's overheated... It's no use.
With those injuries, running is futile.
It's already decided that this
explosion will execute you.
Die in fear!
I see...
You can't regenerate anymore.
But we haven't finished purging all of the evil.
I don't want to...
In a place like this...
Crap... My leg...
You've got to be kidding.
I have to survive, no matter what,
and stand on the winning side.
And I was finally able to avenge those two...
Why are you appearing in my head?
You still need me to be reliable...
Damn it all!
I wasn't strong enough for Bro...
And I couldn't make it in time for Chelsea.
But this time, I won't let anyone die.
Tatsumi...
Seems you're okay.
But I did it.
You told me earlier, remember?
That when I'm needed most, I should help.
I did it.
How's that?
I was thinking of you.
You're making it sound like I owe you.
Even if you helped, it was at the last second.
But...
You really saved me.
Thank you.
S-Sure.
Borick...
Where did he go?
Borick already ran away.
Najenda...
He ignored your warning.
He's probably being finished
off by my subordinates.
Th-That was close.
Holimaca!
It was just a scratch.
A sneaky strategy like that...
You haven't changed.
That's right.
I know your strength better than anyone.
Which is why I wouldn't dream of a frontal assault.
Looks like we're done for now.
Yeah.
Hey, Tatsumi?
What?
After this battle's over, I want to
talk to you about something.
Can't you talk about it now?
Nope.
Huh?
I'm surprised at myself.
To think I'd become the type that wants
to survive for someone else...
Promise me.
That you'll survive, no matter what.
Of course I will.
Moving forward, we'll face even harsher battles.
But as long as I have these feelings...
I'll be able to fight with even
more than I have before.
Kill the Carnage