Why... Just to save me?
Don't be so self-absorbed.
We needed to stop the public execution
to protect the Revolutionary Army's morale.
Everyone went in prepared for this.
Even if that's the case...
Also,
we were able to eliminate Commander-in-Chief Budou,
who's been a problem for years.
All things considered, a notable military gain.
How can you say that?
Tatsumi,
it isn't like the boss isn't in pain, too.
She lost Susanoo.
Don't worry about that.
As an Imperial Arms,
he simply fulfilled his mission.
Su...
As the survivors, we carry the feelings
of those who've passed away on our shoulders.
They're heavy...
They are.
However, we can't just surrender
because we feel they're too much.
Akame...
If we throw in the towel,
the dead won't be able to rest in peace!
You're right.
This anguish... We have to end it.
My life was required to activate
Susanoo's trump card.
And yet, I'm still alive.
Susanoo, you took your own life to save mine.
You weren't a mere weapon.
You were my precious partner.
You told me that you wanted
to stand on the winning side,
and create a world without discrimination.
I'm going to fulfill that wish for you,
Mine...
Kill the Little Sister
Let go...
If you keep resisting, I'll have you arrested!
Don't make me laugh.
This kingdom's done for.
What did you say, you bastard?
Stop!
Damn it!
How long are we supposed to keep this up?
This kingdom will not last much longer.
Most of the civilians we're supposed to
protect side with the rebel army.
Are we, the Jaegers, really okay with this?!
Please calm down.
This chaos will, most likely,
continue past the revolution.
We will be needed then.
You talk as though you knew all this would happen.
It occurred faster than I'd predicted, though.
Huh?
I hoped for revolution,
and joined the Jaegers in order to change
this kingdom from the inside.
Change the kingdom?
This kingdom is rotten.
However, rebelling like those out
there would have been foolish.
That's why you joined Esdeath's special forces.
That's right.
She's quite the interesting specimen.
You're pretty odd.
I'm often told that.
Being here, I became so comfortable,
I nearly forgot my true objective.
And as for you, what will you do?
You don't have much time left.
Y-You knew about Kurome's condition?
Don't be so surprised.
Your attitude and behavior gave it away.
If you leave now, you won't have to worry
about capture or punishment.
You can be free.
Freedom...
That's right.
Freedom isn't what I desire.
There's only one thing I want...
This is, indeed, how a battle should be.
If you're discontent with your situation,
show me how strong you are by defeating me.
Say your prayers, Esdeath.
If we defeat you, this will all end!
An Imperial Arms user.
How interesting!
Is there no one who can overcome death?
Tatsumi survived.
He managed to escape
death in that dire situation.
As I thought, we are destined for each other.
Wait for me.
After I take care of the grunts,
I'll be coming for you.
Shisuikan and Bench Fortress have both fallen.
The capital's almost completely surrounded.
What is Esdeath doing?
If she's attacked on all sides,
even General Esdeath wouldn't be able to...
Your Excellency!
Because of me,
the kingdom is going to be destroyed...
Have I been wrong this whole time?
You haven't been wrong, Your Excellency.
O-Onest...
Not a single person is reliable.
Everyone is far too flustered.
I am painfully aware of how you
are feeling, Your Excellency.
The citizens are being foolish.
They don't understand what it's like
to protect an entire kingdom.
I can't believe my people would rebel.
What am I supposed to do?
Your Excellency, at times,
an emperor must be cruel.
Now is the time to demonstrate your authority.
It's time to prepare!
The emperor's true strength...
It's almost over for me.
So...
Let's settle this once and for all, Sis.
They say he was a Revolutionary Army spy.
Is this meant to be a warning?
How cruel...
It's a code.
A code?
It's for me.
What did you say?
"I will be waiting for you near
the Kadai Forest facility."
Don't be stupid... You know it's a trap!
At this point in time, there'd be
no reason to single me out.
This is personal.
Personal? Who?
Kurome wants to settle things for good.
Is it important that you two see this through?
Right now, many people are
pinning their hopes on us.
Despite that, is this something you must do?
It's especially because we're their last hope.
I have to respect Kurome's wishes.
Even if she's the enemy?
She's my sister.
I'm the only one who can understand and accept
her wishes.
I understand. I'm coming with you.
No, you're not.
Your strength will be
needed in the final battle.
You must fulfill your mission.
Then...
Promise that you'll come back alive.
Tatsumi...
You've always said those words to me.
Don't make me the only one to promise!
Okay.
It's a promise.
I knew you'd come, Sis.
Kurome...
Do you want any?
In the past, we were reunited in this place.
And this is also where you betrayed us.
I can't think of a place more
fitting for me to kill you.
It's nostalgic...
You've always protected me.
As children who had no relatives,
we didn't belong anywhere but here.
Raised as assassins for the empire,
we were tasked with upholding public order
by stopping any potential insurgency.
That's what we were told
and how we were raised.
We obeyed our orders,
killing those who'd wronged the empire.
Because we believed it was the right thing to do.
Sis!
Kurome...
Sis...
We were finally reunited after being
trained in separate divisions,
simply because we needed to
replace our fallen comrades.
After that, we were always together.
Almost as if we were reliving our childhood.
We were the best squad of assassins.
Some missions were painful.
But because we were together, we managed.
As long as I was with you, I was happy.
But you...
You betrayed the empire and joined Night Raid.
Why?
I tried to stop you.
After you left me, I was miserable.
I thought about you every day.
About how I was going to kill you.
If you kill me, will you find peace?
There is no peace.
I just want to be the one that
does it, so you'll belong to me.
Using your Imperial Arms takes an
enormous amount of energy.
It's agonizing, isn't it?
I'll help you feel better.
Let's kill each other,
Sis.
Kurome's Snacks
Kurome...
She went out, didn't she?
To sort everything out for herself.
Why would she do that
without letting any of us know?
Because if she'd told you,
you'd have stopped her.
Do you have any idea what location she'd choose?
A place that's special to them?
Why did you betray our squad?
We could've stayed together!
I started to realize that what we were doing
wasn't to keep the peace.
It was all a lie.
We were a special unit dedicated
to executing any orders from the capital.
If the current empire continues to exist,
the citizens are doomed to suffer.
That's why I tried to get you to escape with me.
There's no way I could simply escape.
I can't betray our comrades,
who gave their lives for the mission!
The people who run the empire are
the source of everyone's misery.
If eliminating them will help the citizens,
our comrades that passed would understand.
That's a convenient argument, Sis!
A Danger Beast?
The clash of our battle must've awakened him.
Kurome!
Natala!
How dare you do that to my friend?!
Doya!
Even Doya...
I'll never let you into my collection!
Are you all right, Kurome?
Sis...
Let's do it.
Eliminate!
As expected of you and me.
We always made the best team.
Isn't that right, Sis?
Come forth!
Random puppets won't do...
This is
the end!
I won't let you hurt Kurome.
Wave?
Night Raid, I am your opponent!
Tatsumi?
Get out of the way, Tatsumi!
Don't interrupt us!
Kurome, I can't just abandon my comrades.
This doesn't make me happy at all...
Kurome...
Tatsumi,
why did you come?
To make sure no one interferes with your duel.
Tatsumi, I don't have time to deal with—
I want to stop them, too.
But then they'll never overcome their past!
Is that the answer you've
gotten from Night Raid?
I can't allow this battle to occur!
Everyone has their own reasons.
Sometimes, you must settle it without others' help
or there's no way forward!
Their own reasons...
I...
Wave...
Thank you for coming.
I wish we could've been
closer in a different situation.
Kurome...
I need this to deal with my
regret from back then.
So I can finally move on.
Let's do this, Sis.
Kurome... My little sister...
That's right. I love you, Sis.
It couldn't be any other way?
I couldn't do anything for Kurome...
You came for her.
That's plenty.
Damn it.
Damn it...
Damn it!
Night Raid...
What are we fighting for?
If you can't answer that for yourself,
you've no business with a weapon.
Only those who've committed themselves
have the right to wield a sword.
Committed?
Committed to keep carrying on.
Akame!
I told you not to come.
Not to fight.
But I'm just here to pick up a wounded comrade.
I've lost a lot that's important to me.
But you...
You've borne more than I can
imagine on your shoulders,
this whole time.
Akame,
we're done losing things that are precious to us.
What impressive determination.
Your wisdom is a testament to your greatness.
Now is the time to unleash the capital's
supreme Imperial Arms.
You must show the foolish
rebels and foolish citizens
the emperor's true power.
I am the Emperor.
I must protect the kingdom with my power.
Kill the Emperor