Blood pressure, 120 over 80;
pulse, 92.
I will now remove the bullet.
I have removed the bullet.
The removal is complete.
It's a little early to be relieved;
we must still reinforce the walls
of the damaged blood vessel.
Huh? Uh-huh...
Get the proline ready.
Yes, sir.
Downfall
Blood pressure, 128 over 72;
pulse, 88.
Seems the anesthesia is still working.
Do your best...
Do your best to survive...
Oh... Dr. Boyer...
Looks like yours went well.
Yes. The surgery did...
The mayor died.
I-Is that so?
That's a shame...
Humph! You act as though
it's none of your concern.
Huh?!
You're the very one
who abandoned our team
just before surgery.
Oh... but, that child
was brought in before the mayor...
What does it matter, who was first?
The problem is, because you selfishly
pulled out of our team,
we were forced to try to fill
the vacuum you created!
B-But... Listen to me! I...
You upset the teamwork.
By order of the Director,
I instructed you
to perform the surgery...
on the mayor.
But you... You ignored me!
B-but, Chief, at that time...
The success of a surgery
depends upon trust
among the entire staff.
But you made a grand stand play!
I have already reported this
to the Director.
He greatly regrets this incident,
which has lowered
the prestige of this hospital.
Prepare yourself!
Uh, sir...
Please wait a minute!!
Dr. Tenma...
At present, that child's blood pressure
is 114 over 82; pulse, 84.
His vitals are very stable.
I see...
That's good...
Um... That operation...
It was wonderful.
Mayor Roddecker, who collapsed
while on holiday,
has passed away at the hospital.
Upon hearing this unexpected news,
people have been arriving
at the Mayor's office
with bouquets of flowers,
many reminiscing on
the life of the Mayor.
A press conference has just been held
at Eisler Memorial Hospital
where the Mayor was taken.
The cause of
Mayor Roddecker's death
was due to a cerebral infarction
stemming from
a severe emphraxis
of the inner carotid artery.
We did everything we could for him,
but it caused severe brain swelling,
which resulted in
this unfortunate outcome.
As for naming a successor,
a city official explained that
concrete steps will be taken
- as soon as possible.
- I've got to get some sleep.
In the case of the murder of
Mr. and Mrs. Liebert late last night...
Judging from the signs of
a search in the rooms,
police believe
this may have been a robbery...
or perhaps the act of
a political terrorist
against this couple
who had fled here from their country.
A two-pronged investigation
is under way.
Of this couple's twin children, the son,
who received a gunshot wound
to the head
underwent successful surgery, but...
has still to regain consciousness.
He is listed in critical condition.
Now, for the weather...
The whole country is
- in for clear weather...
- That boy...
I wonder what will happen to him.
I'm just like him...
Mr. Reinhardt in ICU
is complaining that
she just can't sleep...
Can't we give her something
to help her sleep?
Dr. Tenma, are you listening to me?
Huh?
O-Oh... in that case,
give her one Halcyon tablet.
That man! He's been unfocused
all day long.
Yo!
Dr. Becker!
Seems you've had a trying time.
Has the Director
handed down his judgment?
Huh?
I warned you, didn't I?
I told you the hospital
is ruled by politics.
If you played your cards right,
your future would have been
smooth sailing.
Well... I guess this means you and I
are in the same boat now.
Now, don't be so depressed.
You'll get a chance
to redeem your reputation.
Let's go have some drinks.
It'll cheer you up.
Uh, excuse me!
I still need to get a statement
from the girl twin...
I can't discuss that with you now,
Detective!
Huh?!
That girl is gone from her room!
What?!
That girl is always
slipping out of her room
and wandering through the hospital!
Huh?!
...me...
Kill...
Kill me...
And so...
Eisler Memorial Hospital has
proven to be
the nation's leading medical facility.
That is first and foremost,
the result of our being blessed with
such excellent personnel
such as you all.
I am sincerely grateful.
Yesterday...
unfortunately, the Mayor died
here in this hospital.
But, as always,
we had done our utmost to save him.
The public's evaluation of this hospital
has not changed one bit.
Let's have a round of applause
for Dr. Boyer and Dr. Eisen,
who strived to the end
to save the Mayor's life.
I looked at your paper.
I hope you will continue to
work on your research.
Director Heinemann!
Uh... I must apologize
for my actions...
Now, now... What's done is done.
Director?!
You did what you thought you should.
Let's leave it at that.
Director...
And now...
let's have a word from
the Head of Neurosurgery!
Pardon me... I'm being called up.
It's not you.
Huh?
Here's the newly appointed...
Dr. Boyer, please...
Please come this way.
Sir, what is the meaning of this?
If you wish to remain at this hospital,
you may do so,
but you'd better give up the idea of
rising any further as a doctor.
That would be impossible for
someone with a flawed character
such as yours.
I'll recognize your skill as a surgeon,
but that is all.
You should also give up any ideas of
presenting any papers
at future conferences.
B-But, sir... Please listen to me.
Even if you wish to move
to another hospital,
I have no intention of
writing you a recommendation.
This means it's no use for you
to have any ambition.
You may consider your path
to becoming
the doctor you envisioned closed.
Surgery requires teamwork.
Only with the help of each
and every one of you
can a life be saved.
Eva...
Eva, won't you talk to your father
for me?
I haven't done anything wrong!
I just operated on
an emergency case
in the order in which
he was brought in!
That's... your engagement ring.
You're such a fool...
Huh?
Eva!!
Why, Dr. Norden,
don't you look elegant?
As do you! You're more beautiful
than ever tonight, Eva.
What a laugh, isn't it?
After coming across
Director Heinemann's paper,
I came here to Germany,
and he made me what I am today...
Now that I think about it,
I suppose that paper
that I was so impressed by
was probably written for him
by someone somewhere...
I knew that he was using me...
but I believed,
when I reached a certain position,
I would be able to work on research
of my choice to my heart's content.
We are scholars, first and foremost.
Isn't that right?
That's not right! Saving people's lives
is what's most important to a doctor!!
After all, people's lives
aren't created equal.
You're wrong!
There is no distinction
between people's lives!
I am not wrong!
You say there's a flaw
in my character?
What about you?!
You call yourself a doctor;
but you're just money hungry!
That bastard... That bastard...
He's better off dead!
I have you to thank...
You opened my eyes, as a doctor...
You must do your best to live.
I threw everything away
in order to operate on you...
That's how far I went
in order to bring you back to life.
You know your name, don't you?
Your name is Anna Liebert,
isn't that right?
I told you, didn't I, Detective?
It's too soon.
Can't anything be done, Doctor?
After all, she saw her parents
shot to death before her very eyes.
She has no physical wounds,
but extreme trauma seems to have
brought on amnesia.
Could you please refrain from
trying to get a statement from her
for a while?
This is a difficult case, you see...
The victim was
an East German diplomat.
If we don't solve this quickly,
the BKA will come.
Those guys always come
and steal the thunder from
us state police!
I haven't got the time to take it slow.
Oh... What if we do this?
We let her see her brother.
She'll be relieved to see him
and her memory might return.
I cannot agree on such a gamble-
one suggested by an amateur, at that!
Besides, Dr. Tenma
will probably not permit it.
Tenma?
He's the doctor
in charge of her brother Johan.
Tsk... What the heck
am I supposed to do?!
Well, Dr. Tenma...
You seem to be in a daze.
You look awfully tired.
I've been so busy
with emergency surgeries.
They've been working you
to the bone...
ever since you were
demoted from Chief.
I don't mind.
It actually makes me feel better.
Hey, now... Are you all right?
I'm sorry, I've just been paged.
You're so tired,
but you still have work to do?
The more diligent you are,
the worse it'll be for you!
Look at this, Director Heinemann...
See all the gifts
and letters of encouragement.
There are mountains of them
in his sister's room, too.
After losing their parents
these two only have each other.
The mass media keeps reporting on
their heartbreaking plight,
and this is the result.
As far as this hospital is concerned,
they're nothing but an inconvenience;
what with no sign of anyone paying
their medical expenses.
Now, now...
So their story is a pitiful one-
that's just fine.
Huh?
That means this hospital is
garnering attention.
For that reason alone,
these kids are valuable...
Don't you see?
Uh, yes...
Why don't we do this?
We'll give the media
a photo of the siblings together.
Yes, the media keeps asking
for something like that.
Do it. It'll be a picture
of the orphaned siblings
trying their best to live
within the warmhearted care
of our hospital's staff.
But the boy's doctor says
it is still too early
to allow them to see each other.
Who's on his case?
It's Dr. Tenma.
Dismiss him.
What?
There is no need to give that man
a position that gets so much attention.
Take Dr. Tenma off the case.
Yes, sir!
This is a heartwarming gift
from the citizens.
Why don't you have one?
Thank you.
How do you feel, Mrs. Hankel?
Thanks to you, I feel quite well.
Your stitches will be removed soon,
so it won't be long
until you're released.
I'll be able to go home?
Yes, but as I said, you must rest.
Of course, I will.
Give Mrs. Hankel regular doses
of an anticonvulsant
and a hypotensive.
Wake up, Anna!
W-What are you doing?
Dr. Tenma!
They let her see her brother.
Then she gave a loud scream and...
Why did you bring them together?!
Dr. Tenma...
Take her back to her room, quickly!
Yes, sir!
Dr. Boyer, what is the meaning of this?
Why the camera?
Oh... We're going to give the media
a picture of the emotional meeting
of the two children.
Who allowed you to do such a thing?
I am the boy's doctor.
You have been dismissed
as Johan's doctor.
Wha?!
As of today, he is my patient.
I decided that it would be fine
to let them see each other.
Those children...
Don't make those children fodder
for the media!
We did it by order of the Director.
I think it would be best for you
not to fight it.
I'm the one who saved this boy!
I have a duty to protect him
until he is completely healed!
If that's the case,
take a look at the boy's reaction!
As soon as he saw his sister,
he extended his hand and cried tears.
He regained consciousness
and showed a normal reaction.
That means the surgery
was a great success.
Good job. Your work is done now.
Get back to where you belong.
Damn it...
Don't make me laugh!
Who cares what the Director says?
Who cares what the Chief says?
They're all money and power hungry!
Damn them!
I... I am not wrong...
I'm home, Father...
Father? Are you in your room?
Chief?
Are you still in a meeting at this hour?
Father, are you asleep?
I'm coming in.
That bastard... He's better off dead...
A Murder