Yes?
Sorry for calling on you so early.
I'm from the state police.
Are you Dr. Tenma?
What can I do for you?
Excuse me, but were you at home
all night?
No... I was out drinking
until it was nearly morning...
What about it?
The truth is,
Eisler Memorial Hospital's
Director Heinemann;
Chief of Surgery, Dr. Oppenheim,
and Dr. Boyer are dead.
In any case, no one except the police
are allowed at the scene of the crime!
A Murder
Even so, you are obstructing
the operations of the hospital.
The Press is not allowed
- inside the hospital!
- Please don't do anything
to excite the patients!
Was it an accident?
Or was it murder?
Three people died at the same time!
Of course it was murder!
Are you from the hospital?
Do you know anything
about this incident?
Out of my way!
Let me through!
Hey! No one is allowed in!
I'm Dr. Kenzo Tenma of this hospital!
Oh... go right ahead.
Hey! Don't push!
So, did you see anyone suspicious?
Wait a minute.
Now is not the time...
- Now is not the time...
- Dr. Tenma!
Dr. Tenma! The Director!
Doctor!
Everyone, calm down!
Are the emergencies taken care of?
W-Well, even at this time...
there's been no end
to the emergencies.
There are two patients
waiting to be operated on...
I understand. I'll help out!
Take care of the car accident victim
with the brain contusion.
I'll go to the X-ray Reading Room
to look at the x-rays first.
What about the other case?
A patient who collapsed due to a stroke.
Oh, Doctor, will you help us
in our investigation?
Now is not the time...
I know that,
but the initial investigation is vital!
Do you know of anyone with a grudge
against the director and the others?
A grudge?
You may consider your path
to becoming
the doctor you envisioned closed.
Huh? Do you know something?
Oh... No.
Dr. Tenma!
Trouble! Those kids...
The twin brother and sister...
We can't find them anywhere!
Is the sister's bed empty, too?
I looked!
But they're nowhere to be found...
What's going on?
What in the world has happened?
...compassionately extended
a helping hand.
We will surely praise his lifetime
of achievements through eternity.
Farewell Dr. Heinemann.
Rest in peace. Amen.
Father...
- Eva...
- Eva.
I know it's difficult,
but pull yourself together...
Let me go!
Give back my father!
Father!
It's just too much, Dr. Tenma.
Yeah...
Up until now, she lived an easy life
as the director's daughter...
Now suddenly,
she's just an ordinary person.
It must be a big shock...
How can you say that
at a time like this?
Oh, pardon me.
You're Dr. Tenma, aren't you?
I am Detective Visbaugh
of the Nordhein-Westfalen
Police Department.
Thank you for your efforts.
This was such a tragic incident...
Yes...
Let me introduce you. This is...
German Federal Criminal Police Office [BKA]
Inspector Lunge
I am Inspector Lunge of the BKA.
I've heard rumors that
you are a brilliant physician.
Not at all. I've still got
a long ways to go.
Um... Have you any idea
where the children are?
Never mind them.
We have determined what caused
the death of the director
and the other two.
We found a nitrate type poison
in their bodies.
Nitrates...
That means a muscular relaxant...
As expected of a doctor.
You are knowledgeable...
But how could something like that...
It was candy.
Candy?!
The same candy wrapper
was found beside each body,
and the same candy was found
in their stomachs.
By the way...
Would you have any idea
where the three of them
might get a hold of
something like that?
I don't know anything about that.
What about the search for the twins?
The BKA has
taken over the investigation.
Don't worry about it.
This incident may have started
when the parents of those twins
were shot and killed.
Their parents defected
from East Germany
and were killed by someone.
Then, the director and doctors
of the hospital
where the children were taken to
were killed.
There is also the possibility
that this is political terrorism.
Those children might be
holding a major clue.
Please.
Please find them.
We will do our best.
Then...
Before the incident, the Director
removed him from his position as Chief.
Furthermore, the Director's daughter
broke off her engagement to him...
But he was in a bar drinking
at the time of the incident.
He has an alibi...
Umm...
May I ask you something?
Why do you move
your hand like that?
Huh?
Oh, I'm typing.
What?
I'm inputting all the information into
the disk in my head.
When I press the key
to extract the information...
"Not at all. I still have
a long ways to go."
That's what Dr. Tenma bashfully said
when I called him brilliant.
The police? Do they suspect you
of doing something?
It's because there's enough evidence
for me to be a suspect.
Don't worry about it.
They were quite persistent
when they questioned me, too.
I'm exhausted...
When the dust from this thing settles,
I think I'll go back to Japan...
- What?
- I came to Germany to do research,
but due to the recent chain of events,
I feel like I've gone back to saving lives,
the true duty of a doctor.
Hey, don't be so depressing.
I'm tired...
I'm just so tired...
Your progress is favorable,
Mr. Buchner.
Thank you, Dr. Tenma.
Do you think I can work again?
Yes, of course.
My store will go under
if I'm not there.
But you mustn't overdo it.
I'll go have a drink there
after you're released.
I'll be there to make sure
you don't overdo things.
Dr. Tenma
Yes?
I heard that you were
leaving this hospital.
Is that true?
What?
Please don't quit.
There aren't any
good doctors like you.
Please don't say you're quitting.
Please.
Mr. Buchner...
Dr. Tenma, the Chairman
is asking for you.
The board is discussing who should
succeed to the empty posts.
Up until now, the Director's faction
has filled the major positions...
There will be a considerable
purging of personnel.
The rumor is Dr. Eckner
is being transferred
to a small hospital in Bavaria.
- Is that so...
- Umm, Dr. Tenma!
- Huh?
- No matter what the Chairman says,
please don't give up!
We're all behind you!
Please don't leave this hospital!
Huh?
I'll say it again.
I am performance oriented.
Dr. Tenma, you are appointed to
Chief of Surgery.
What a life...
I went against the orders
of the Director,
lost my position as Chief,
and my engagement to Eva
was dissolved.
As soon as I decide to work
as a simple doctor
without any hope of promotion...
Wh-What a life!
I'm sorry for calling you out.
I heard you've been appointed
Chief of Surgery. That's very good.
Thank you...
Kenzo... At my father's funeral,
you tried to comfort me, didn't you?
Oh... not really...
It made me happy...
A lot of things happened between us,
but I'd like to try again.
Kenzo!
Please! I was wrong!
I want to try again!
Kenzo...
Kenzo!
9 Years Later
The patient hospitalized
for a spinal cord tumor...
His paralysis has accelerated.
I understand.
I'll perform the operation.
If you will, Chief of Surgery.
Make the arrangements
for the operation.
Yes, sir!
Honestly, when will this flood recede?
Köln,
(Germany)
I thought the world would change
when the Berlin Wall came down
six years ago,
but nothing good has happened.
Even with the unification of Europe,
hopeless people from all over
come flowing in.
Yeah. There's been an increase in
unexplainable crimes.
Oops...
Inspector, we've arrived.
Both victims had their throats
slit open with a knife.
Their identities?
The Reichmanns of Stich Drive
They were murdered in their home.
We believe that they were
hidden in a closet,
and their bodies floated out
because of the flood.
A murder of a middle-aged couple.
There have been four incidents
in Germany
over the past two years.
All by the same method.
It's probably a robber who targets
rich middle-aged couples.
No, it's too soon
to call them robberies.
According to the data,
for some reason,
all of the couples
did not have children.
This couple certainly
did not have any children.
Don't you think there are
too many similarities
to call them robberies?
But money and goods have been
taken from all of the victims' homes...
All of them totaling very little.
It would make sense
if a single perpetrator did it.
Are you suggesting that
there wasn't a single perpetrator?
Two of the homes had
extremely strong locks and alarms.
But the perpetrator opened them
and entered very easily.
Also, all the couples did not seem to
fight back when they were killed
and the neighbors did not hear
any noise at the time of the incidents.
Don't you think they were
too skillfully done
for it to have been done by
a single individual?
Do you know this man?
No.
Adolph Junkers, 32 years old.
He has been convicted twice
for larceny.
His role was to open locks...
In other words, he's a lock picker.
He was seen near the scene
of three of the murders
of middle-aged couples.
Then did this man do it?
I can't say.
Well, that's the extent
of your work as state police.
Leave the rest to the BKA.
Uh... yeah...
Oh!
It didn't fly after all.
I've never flown a kite before.
It almost went up.
Well, how was the girl last night?
How was she?
She was a nice person.
Hey, hey, she's the daughter
of a director, you know.
Don't tell me you just had dinner
and saw her home.
Well, there was an emergency call
during dinner,
so I had to come back to the hospital.
What's that?! You'd better rethink that
all work and no play doctrine!
You're going to lose a great catch
and regret it some day!
Hey! Are you listening,
Chief of Surgery?!
A kite?
Good morning, Chief.
Is that yours, Karl?
My grandpa gave it to me,
but it just won't fly...
Could it be it's unbalanced?
Chief, can you fly a kite?
I did it often during my childhood in Japan.
Try holding it up high, Karl.
Like this?
That's right.
Now... will it work?
- Heave ho!
- There!
- There we go!
It's flying!
I did it!
Oh, my...
If I were in his shoes,
I'd have at least five lovers.
Honestly...
That's amazing, Dr. Tenma.
Get well quickly
and fly it yourself, Karl.
Yeah!
Today's surgery is
a parasellar meningioma extirpation.
We'll proceed with
a right pterional approach.
Yes!
Watch closely. Chief Tenma
will perform the surgery himself.
What a splendid operation.
He's hardly retracted the brain at all!
He truly is a surgical genius.
You residents should treat the brain
with tender care.
Always keep this in mind.
Huh?
This is terrible!
- Look at the blood!
- Ambulance! Call an ambulance!
I-I didn't do it!
It's not my fault.
This man ran into the street suddenly!
This is the patient?
Yes.
How is his condition?
Well, I can't say...
There's nothing more we can do...
He's a material witness
in a certain case.
His testimony alone
could solve a serial murder case.
We can't have him die.
But the patient is
in a very critical condition.
Nothing more can be done
at our hospital...
There's a terrific brain surgeon
at Eisler Memorial Hospital.
If he came...
Brain surgeon...
You mean Dr. Tenma...
Thank you for coming all this way,
Dr. Tenma.
How is the patient's condition?
He is in a coma.
And one of his pupils is dilated.
It's been a long time, Dr. Tenma.
Um... I'm sorry,
but who are you?
It's been nine years.
Not since the Director's funeral...
If I'm not mistaken,
you're with the BKA.
Inspector Lunge.
Please make this operation a success
for the sake of the BKA.
Huh?
The patient has to live.
He holds the key to solving a big case.
I don't operate
for the sake of the police.
I do it for the sake of the patient.
That's fine...
Well, I have an operation to perform...
I hear you've become
the Chief of Surgery, Dr. Tenma.
You've been very successful...
Is there a problem?
No. At your age,
it's quite an accomplishment.
Aren't you in line
to become the next Director?
No, that would be
a long way off for me.
About the murders
at the Eisler Memorial Hospital...
There is very little evidence.
The investigation
has been extremely difficult.
The only clue is the poisoned candy.
The methodology means
it is an intelligent crime.
An intelligent crime means
the victim and the assailant
have some sort of interests at stake
What are you trying to tell me?
No, excuse me. In this business,
I'm constantly thinking like this.
In any case, rest assured.
All the cases I've ever handled
have been solved.
Every single one.
I hope so.
We will perform a craniotomy
to remove the hematoma.
We must hurry. There is the danger
of the brain hernia worsening.
No matter how you look at it,
only one person greatly benefited from
the Eisler Memorial Hospital murders.
That is you, Dr. Tenma.
Thank you for taking the trouble
to come here.
Not at all. How has
the patient been doing?
He's conscious,
but his right pupil remains dilated...
And he has some paralysis
on the left side.
He's started rehab already, hasn't he?
The paralysis should go away.
He's recovering normally.
Also, the police will want to see him,
but please refuse for now.
But, that detective, Lunge,
is so persistent...
Right now, the patient's recovery
is most important.
How are you feeling, Mr. Junkers?
Mr. Junkers, do you recognize me?
Can you see this finger?
How about it? Can you answer me?
What's that?
The monster... is coming...
What's that, Mr. Junkers?
Coming? What's coming?
The monster is coming...
The monster... is coming...
The monster?!
Night of the Execution