Please tell me! Who are you?
And I'm not Anna!
I'm Nina!
No, when you were brought into
my hospital, your name was Anna.
And your brother's name was Johan.
My brother...
Johan...
Anna...
House of Tragedy
Mr. Fortner!!
Mr. Maurer!!
Mr. Maurer! Mr. Maurer!
Mr. Fortner! It's Tenma!
Anna... I mean,
I've brought Nina home safely!
Mr. Maurer!
I'll call the police from here.
It doesn't look like
the police ever came...
It can't be...
Live...
Please... Come back to life...
You must come back to life!!
Please...
I'm begging you...
Mr. Maurer...
Your favorite cigarettes...
Mr. Maurer!!
That day...
I killed him...
I... killed... him...
Kill me...
I killed him... I killed him...
- Nina.
- But that day, I killed my brother!!
I... I brought him back to life...
The phone line has been cut...
We've got to get
away from here quickly.
He'll come to take you away.
Is everything all right?
Huh?!
We're the police.
We received a call.
If you don't mind,
we'll have a look around inside.
What in the world?
This is terrible.
Are you two all right? Any injuries?
Thank heavens.
We'll have help soon.
They'll take care of the scene.
We'll hear your stories
down at headquarters.
Is she the victims' daughter?
Poor thing...
I see... So that means
you didn't see who did it?
To think something like that could
happen in such a peaceful town...
Where are you from? China?
No. I'm Japanese.
My name is Tenma.
Oh, you're Japanese...
What a terrible experience for you
in such a faraway land...
Steady... You're all right now...
Uh... Where are we headed?
The Police Department.
But the Heidelberg Police Department
is in the middle of town.
We're from Mannheim Precinct
in the next town.
I wonder why they're taking us
to the next precinct...
We'll be there in about 15 minutes.
Uh... I see...
He said they got a call...
They came because they got a call...
Who could have called them?
The phone line was dead...
This car came without sirens blaring...
Would the police whisk away
the people who discovered the bodies
without first securing the scene?
Still, those police IDs
looked authentic...
Blood!
No way...
It couldn't be that these men...
U-Um...
A-A roadblock?
Thank goodness...
We're searching for
a hit-and-run driver,
so we'd appreciate your help.
U-Um...
Huh?!
Well, if it isn't Detective Mesner
and Detective Muller.
Yes... See you're doing your job...
Are you on your way
back to headquarters?
Wow, you've got a new car.
- What's going on?
- How nice!
It'll be a junk heap in no time.
That's 'cause you don't take care of it.
Uh, excuse me!
Uh...
This girl says she doesn't feel well.
Can we go out and get some air?
Oh...
Oh, go ahead.
Did those two do something?
No, nothing like that.
What's going on?
Are they really detectives?
But what about that blood?
Whose call did they receive?
They didn't even turn on their siren...
What should we do? What?
Is everything all right, Dr. Tenma?
How?
How did you know?
I gave you my name,
but I didn't tell you that I was a doctor!
How did you know that?!
There was a grocery story nearby.
I even found some clothes.
There's bread, sausage and cheese.
I even had them pour
some coffee into this thermos...
You may not have any appetite,
but you've got to eat.
Anyway, you'd better change
your clothes. You're freezing.
There were lots of dead people...
My brother and I walked among them,
just the two of us.
It was like... we were the only people
left in the world.
Where was that?
Can't you remember?
We crossed the border...
A man and and his wife cheered us up.
They were so kind to us...
Then my brother said that
he had a good plan.
Not long after that...
The man and his wife died...
I don't know why,
but everyone who's ever
been nice to us... all die...
But one day, I discovered
the reason why... That rainy day...
You're talking about
Mr. and Mrs. Liebert, aren't you?
My brother shot them...
My brother killed them...
He's killed them all up till now...
That's why I took the gun...
I aimed it at my brother...
That's when he said...
He laughed as he said,
"After you shoot me,
throw the gun outside...
Be sure you shoot me in the head."
I shot him like he said...
I aimed for his head...
Why did you save him?
If you hadn't saved him,
my mom and dad
wouldn't have been killed.
Why did you save him?
Don't move from this place.
I'll go to the police...
But if the detectives last night
were the real thing, that means that
someone in the police department
is on Johan's side...
But we can't just stay here like this...
Now, listen, Nina...
Johan is trying to take you away.
I want you to hide
if someone comes looking.
You have to eat,
drink some hot coffee,
then sleep for a while...
That's how people go on living.
You're alive...
You must think about the future.
Your future...
Don't you have any leads?
Heidelberg Police Department
Is there any connection to the string
of killings of middle-age couples
throughout Germany?
As I said, we are putting all of
our resources into this case,
but I am not free to
disclose any details.
We have found that
Mr. and Mrs. Fortner have a daughter.
Where is she?
That is under investigation as well.
Why was that newspaper reporter,
Maurer, with them?
Who was that Japanese guy
who is said to have been with him?
Japanese? He sounds suspicious!
Was that murder at Heidelberg Castle,
that occurred at nearly the same time,
the work of the same killer?!
Heidelberg Castle...?!
So he was killed, as well?
Just a minute...
Anyway, we will keep you
abreast of the happenings!
Excuse me... Please let me through.
There's not enough for an article!!
U-Um...
Oh! I appreciate the help offered
by the Mannheim police,
Detectives Mesner and Muller.
Just give us our orders.
We'll do all we can to help.
How are the investigations
coming along?
We can talk about it inside...
They're real...
Those guys are really
with the police...
What should I do?!
The Heidelberg Post!
What? I can't hear you!
The editing room is in chaos!
- Huh?
- At any rate,
- Who are you?
- we have to find that Japanese guy
who was with Maurer!
He knows something!
Please quiet down! I'm on the phone!
Hello?!
I will bring an important witness
to your office at 5:00.
You must not let the police know.
Is that true?!
This isn't a hoax, is it?!
Hello!
If I can't trust the police,
there's only the paper...
that can... keep Nina safe...
Mr. Maurer...
You shouldn't be in here
without permission.
Besides, you're here from
the federal police to investigate
the killings of the middle-age couples,
aren't you?
We only have files on
the killing at the castle here...
Inspector Lunge.
Sorry... Something was bothering me.
The case you're looking at and
this one happened at the same time.
It couldn't be the same perpetrator.
I see.
This guy... It looks like there are signs
that his hands had been tied.
Did you find rope or anything nearby?
No... It had been removed
by the time the victim was found.
I... see...
There are four possible routes
of escape from the scene...
He had to consider whether
he'd be hidden from sight,
how crowded the area was
where he'd come out,
and the locations of the lights.
Found it...
Nina, it's me... It's Tenma.
Nina! You needn't hide anymore.
Nina!
Don't tell me...
Nina! Nina!
Where are you? Nina!! Nina!!
Nina... Was she taken away?
I shouldn't have left her alone.
Dr. Tenma, it wasn't your fault.
You just did what you
had to do as a doctor...
It wasn't your fault.
Please eat the sandwiches
and get some rest.
I want you to survive,
and save as many people as you can.
Nina Fortner.
Nina... What do you intend to do?
Do you intend to try to
kill him again?!
I brought him back to life...
That monster... I...
Pursued