Well, well... you've found
some wonderful property.
It's a convenient twenty-minute drive
from the center of Berlin;
Former
(East Berlin)
in a well-located
and nice neighborhood.
It's rare to find this sort of property
on the former East side.
Umm...
Wasn't this the residence
of Mr. Liebert,
the consultant to the former
East German Trade Commission?
Huh?
What? You just came
to investigate Mr. Liebert?
Is that all?! You're not a customer?
Sorry... There was something
I just had to find out.
I wouldn't know anything about
an official who died ten years ago!
The Lieberts adopted twins
while they were here.
I told you, I don't know anything...
What about the landlord?
Can you introduce me to him?
Listen... most of the land in
the former East side is the property
of Jewish capitalists who escaped
from the Nazi regime.
The eastern government was paying
foreign countries and capitalists
from the west side
and borrowing land.
The landlord for this property
is overseas...
Besides, my company is
a west-side real estate company
that prospered after
the destruction of the Wall.
I don't know anything about the past.
Now, get out.
I'm going to lock the gate...
Isn't there anyone who knows
about ten years ago...
someone who
remembers Mr. Liebert?
As I told you, this is a residential area
for ex-government officials.
Most fled after the Wall came down.
Especially from the officials from
the Ministry of the Interior...
Oh! Come to think of it...
An ex-official of the former East German
Department of Commerce
lives ten houses away from here...
Yes, Mr. Liebert. He didn't have to
take such a risk, only to die.
If only he had waited
just a little longer,
until East Germany collapsed...
It makes you wonder why
he went to a free country...
Just to be killed of all things...
Did Mr. Liebert have twins?
Twins?
Oh, I remember!
Those twins that Mr. Liebert adopted
from the orphanage!
Orphanage?!
They were such cute kids...
Mr. Liebert always wanted children.
W-Where is that orphanage?!
Umm... I think it was...
Hmm... 511?
Yes, that's right,
I think it was 511 Kinderheim...
511... Kinderheim?
511 Kinderheim
The site of this orphanage will soon
be turned into a supermarket.
I'm relieved that this creepy building
is finally going to be destroyed.
Excuse me, do you know anyone
from this orphanage?
Someone from here?
There isn't anyone.
I don't want to talk about it.
It's so creepy.
B-But...
If you really want to find out,
there's Hartmann over on 47th St.,
who worked at the old
Ministry of Health and Welfare.
Hey there... Do you know someone
named Hartmann who lives around here?
What's wrong?
You're injured... Let me take a look.
It's all right. Don't be afraid.
Let me take a look.
You've injured a healing wound...
It's festering.
Suck it up!
This will sting a little,
but this will help you get better.
All right, that's good...
Don't trip!
You'll get hurt again!
Hartmann...
I became the foster parent to all those
kids after the fall of East Germany.
Foster parent?
Yes, I took care of them until they
were adopted or went off on their own.
The president of
an accessories company
adopted the kid in the middle.
The kid to the left
is in the military right now.
I'm even taking care of one right now.
It must be hard work.
I wouldn't call it work.
I worked for many years,
dealing with orphans,
as the district official for
the Ministry of Health and Welfare.
I opposed the way that the government
was treating them at the time.
After the fall of socialism, I wanted to
help the children in my own way.
I'm poor and things
haven't gone my way...
but, still, it's much better than
the orphanages that they were in.
511 Kinderheim was
a special orphanage
that was run by both
the Ministry of Health and Welfare
and the Ministry of the Interior.
Well, all orphanages in East Germany
were more or less like that,
but special orphanages
were the worst of them all...
It wasn't just an institution
for children with nowhere to go...
It was a gathering for
the children of criminals,
captured political offenders,
and the children of those
suspected of being rebels and spies.
That's why it was expected that
they would be discriminated against
and treated inhumanely...
The children there couldn't do
anything about their situation...
It was a clash between socialism
and totalitarianism...
The government told the public that
the orphans would be reeducated
and turned into model socialists.
But in reality,
they were treated like criminals.
The directors and instructors
were horrible...
The worst ones would confiscate
packages sent to the children
and sell them.
Who were the real criminals?
Fear and violence ruled
the special orphanages.
No person would grow up
normal there.
Then that incident happened...
Incident?
What happened at that orphanage?
You said that you wanted to
ask me about the twins, didn't you?
Do you know something about them?!
I don't know much about the sister
because she was left at an orphanage
in a different district.
But I do know about
the brother, Johan.
Johan! Yes, I want to
know about Johan!
It was... It was top secret.
The East German government
placed a strict gag order on it.
Well, it was a long time ago...
I think it's all right to talk about it...
What is this incident?!
What did... What did Johan do?
A revolt...
I'm home...
Dieter, we have a guest.
Come and greet him.
Oh!
Dieter, what's with your attitude?
Aren't you going to greet him?
I-It's okay. We already met
in front of the house.
Right?
Oh... I'd like to hear the rest.
No...
Not in front of the child.
Oh... you're right.
It's already late so we should
meet another day.
Dieter!
Would you care to
have dinner with us?
S-Sure.
Mr. Tenma, you say that
you're a freelance journalist.
Does that mean that you're going to
write an article about the things
that you've investigated?
Y-Yes, that's right.
Then, this is one thing
I want you to emphasize...
The development of a child
all depends on the adult
that raises him.
We must lead children
in the right direction.
That's when children can
have pleasant dreams.
Dreams, huh-?
Dieter, what dreams do you have?
A soccer ball...
Huh...?
I want a soccer ball!
I see...
Thank you for dinner.
I'd like to continue where we left off
another time.
Sorry we couldn't
finish our conversation.
I'll come again.
Perhaps I can come tomorrow.
Dieter...
Umm... Excuse me.
Can I come in?
Mr. Hartmann!
It's Tenma.
Mr. Hartmann! Mr. Hartmann!
What happened, Mr. Hartmann!
Mr. Hartmann...
M-Mr. Tenma...
Dieter!
What happened?
He fell.
He was standing on the chair and...
Oh, Dieter.
Ow... ow, it hurts...
Where does it hurt, Dieter?
It hurts...
Mr. Hartmann, call an ambulance!
O-Okay.
Dieter, let me take a look.
What are all these scars?!
Is this it?
Does it hurt here?
Two ribs are broken...
And his clavicle is dislocated.
How did he get this injury
from falling off a chair?
The ambulance will be here soon,
so it's all right.
O-Okay...
But what are all these injuries?
I told you that it's all right...
So you can leave.
But...
The way you touch those injuries...
It's as if you're a doctor...
Oh... well...
Tenma...
I thought I heard
that name somewhere.
You're a doctor, aren't you?
You're the one wanted for murder...
This injury...
Where are all these injuries
on his body from?
Nevermind that... Shouldn't you
be running away, Mr. Tenma?
I called the police
along with the ambulance...
Mr. Hartmann! I'm asking you
how Dieter got all these injuries!
It shouldn't matter
to someone like you,
who's wanted for murder.
It's just as I expected from a fugitive.
You're very short-tempered.
You did it, didn't you?!
Did it? Did what?
You were abusing Dieter.
Abusing?
Don't say such ill willed things
about me.
Right, Dieter?
What do you plan to do?
I'm going to take him to the hospital.
First murder, and now kidnapping?
Don't move!
You'll be caught even if you do that.
It's all right, Dieter! I'm going to
get you to a hospital!
I'm afraid of the hospital...
There's nothing to be afraid of!
The doctors will get you better.
Mr. Hartmann always
makes me better...
You're covered in injuries...
You've never been to a hospital?!
I'm afraid... Right now,
the world is full of bad things.
That's why I have to be strong!
Strong...
Did Mr. Hartmann tell you that?
The world is dark...
The future is dark...
That's not true!
It's a big lie that the world is dark!
Really?!
Yes, it's true.
Oh, I forgot.
Here... A soccer ball.
Wow!
Tomorrow will be... a good day.
Sorry for coming at this hour.
It's all right... But we're crowded with
emergency cases at the moment.
It might take a while
until we can see him.
Could you do something about that?
- There was a very big accident.
- The bus driver died instantly.
We need to ask the truck driver about
the circumstances of the accident.
He broke both his legs,
but he can still talk, can't he?
We have to treat him first.
Question him later.
- Then, we'll be waiting here.
- U-Umm...
I'll be back in two hours.
Huh?
Please take care of that boy.
Also, please don't let anyone
leave with him other than myself.
U-Umm...
Is the accident site cleaned up?
No, it's still backed up...
Now then...
What should I do now?
First, what to do with Dieter?
Even if I go to the police...
I can't go with him.
I don't know much about
Johan's sister because
she was left at an orphanage
in a different district.
A different orphanage...
That's it.
There's a child that you
want me to take in?
So, who are you? Why are you
coming here at this hour?
I know it's an unreasonable request,
but this kid...
I know that the kid is being abused.
But if I don't know who you are...
Umm... Well...
I can't take in a child from
someone so suspicious.
U-Umm... could this be the orphanage
that took care of Anna Liebert?
Anna Liebert?
You know Anna Liebert?
S-So Anna was here?
Yes. How nostalgic...
How is Anna doing? Is she well?
Y-Yes.
Right now, she's going
to Heidelberg University...
I see. She's doing well!
Anna was a nice girl...
I knew she was adopted by
Mr. Liebert of the Trade Commission
along with her twin brother.
Umm...
What was his name?
Johan.
Yes, Johan, Johan.
They were very close,
but I felt sorry for them
when they were placed
in separate orphanages.
Those two were really alone
before they came here.
When they were taken into custody
near the border of Czechoslovakia,
they were holding hands
as they walked.
They both were shivering in the cold.
At first, Mr. Liebert only
wanted to adopt Johan.
But Johan wouldn't go
without his sister...
Thankfully, Anna got to be happy.
I heard that the conditions
of the orphanages
of the east side were horrible.
We're not like 511 Kinderheim.
Huh?
Inge, the bathroom isn't that way.
Okay? See?
Mommy...
It's all right. It's all right...
There's nothing to be afraid of.
Now... you can go to the bathroom
by yourself, can't you?
Those kids really did not know
a parent's love.
You only need love in order to
develop as a person.
As you say, the orphanages of
the east side were quite horrible.
Even this place was once referred to
as Orphanage 47.
But we did what we could
so we wouldn't be controlled
by the government,
even just a little
in order to avoid becoming
like 511 Kinderheim.
It was a special orphanage
run by both
the Ministry of Health and Welfare
and the Ministry of the Interior.
Do you know what that means?
No...
The real state of affairs
was being managed by
the Ministry of the Interior.
That place was... East Germany's
experimental laboratory...
A Little Experiment