Those two were really alone
before they came here...
When they were taken into custody
near the border of Czechoslovakia,
they were holding hands
as they walked.
They both were shivering in the cold...
I heard that the conditions of the
orphanages in the east side were horrible...
We're not like 511 Kinderheim.
Huh...?
Inge, the bathroom isn't that way...
Okay? See?
Mommy...
It's all right. It's all right...
There's nothing to be afraid of.
Now... you can go to the bathroom
by yourself, can't you?
Those kids really did not know
a parent's love.
You only need love in order to
develop as a person...
As you say, the orphanages
of the east side were quite horrible.
Even this place was once referred to
as Orphanage 47.
But we did what we could so
we wouldn't be controlled
by the government,
even just a little,
in order to avoid
becoming like 511 Kinderheim.
It was a special orphanage
run by both
the Ministry of Health and Welfare
and the Ministry of the Interior.
But you know what that means?
No...
The real state of affairs
were being managed by
the Ministry of the Interior.
That place was... Old East Germany's
experimental laboratory...
A Little Experiment
Experimental laboratory?!
They were running a project
that would turn the children
into perfect soldiers...
Psychological reconstruction...
Research on modifying humans...
They made the orphans
join factions and
observed as they fought each other...
It was an experiment to create cold,
merciless humans...
Can you imagine what these children
would be like when they grew up?
But right now, there's no way to prove
that was happening...
All the data was burned
right before the Wall came down...
The people from
the Ministry of the Interior
who were involved with
the Project escaped.
But I heard there is one person
who was able to gloss his record
and remain in this country...
He was the person
who was overseeing
the devilish project
that was 511 Kinderheim.
He was actually
a pediatric psychiatrist
affiliated with
the Ministry of the Interior...
Officially, he was a district official from
the Ministry of Health and Welfare...
District official from
the Ministry of Health and Welfare?
Inge, are you done
using the bathroom?
- Yeah.
- Sweet dreams. Now then...
Good night...
Good night.
But all of that was covered up
by that incident...
That... incident?
What happened at 511 Kinderheim?!
It seems like I've talked
a little too much...
It made me remember
such awful things.
Please! Please tell me what
happened there!
Where's my soccer ball?
Huh?
Where's my...
Where's my soccer ball?
Oh...
Here you go.
It's right here.
But hold off on soccer
until your wounds have healed.
That man said he was going to come
to pick you up soon, so rest until then.
I don't know what really happened...
The East German government at
the time placed a strict gag order on it.
It all began with the mysterious death
of the director of 511 Kinderheim.
Soon after, there was
a power struggle among
the instructors over
the director's position...
The orphanage was
thrown into anarchy...
The children's internal strife
couldn't be controlled...
It's amazing that Johan
made it out of there.
And?! What happened to
511 Kinderheim?!
Everyone died...
Wha...?
All the members of the orphanage,
including the instructors
killed each other off in there.
It's a big lie that the world is dark.
Tomorrow will be a good day.
Dieter.
You're going home.
Say...
Mr. Hartmann, aren't we going home?
No... let's take a detour...
I-I don't want to go there...
No! No!
Dieter...
Dieter, you're a good boy, aren't you?
What?!
I told you not to hand over Dieter
until I returned!
B-But...
That person
was that child's foster parent...
He was also quite the gentleman...
Much more of a gentleman
than you are.
Uhh...
Well...
But that man...
Besides, that boy
wanted to go with him.
Dieter!
Dieter?
They haven't returned?
Hartmann's study?
It seems that they were
taken at different times,
but were all taken at the same place.
Where is this place?
Johan...
Who's the man in the photo with him?
I see... All the photographs
were taken at 511 Kinderheim...
About ten years ago up until now...
All the members of the orphanage,
including the instructors,
killed each other off in there.
Dieter...
Could it be...?!
Dieter!
Dieter, hold on! I'm coming!
It seems that this boy can't see it...
Hartmann!
This boy can't see what Johan saw
from here back then...
It's no good... It's no good again...
This boy isn't Johan either.
Everyone... Everyone died...
Ten years ago...
The instructors and the orphans...
All fifty of them died...
Johan... watched it...
He watched it from here.
Johan... just watched it.
I asked Johan...
"What...
What did you do?"
He replied...
"I just dropped
a piece of oil-soaked cloth
in into the fire like this..."
What do you think?
Do you know what this means?
"Hatred is created
when people gather.
I just poured a little oil on it..."
That's what he said.
A boy, just 10 years old.
And he pulled it off!
He had fifty people kill each other
without moving a finger.
Your...
Your experiments turned him into
that kind of person!
We did?
No...
Not at all...
Huh?
511 Kinderheim was indeed
an experimental ground.
It was a project to raise orphans
to become perfect soldiers.
Thinking back on it now,
it was such a small experiment...
And what about Johan?
Him, a soldier?
Not at all...
He was a born leader!
He was someone who was
meant to stand at the top.
There's no way we could create
such a work of art!
He was superhuman
from the beginning...
He was a monstrous being!
He foretold that everyone would
end up hating and killing each other.
What do you think Johan's goal was?
He said...
"To be the last person remaining
in this world..."
Dieter... The future is dark...
You've got to become even just
a little more like Johan...
But...
Why is it no good?
Why can't you be like Johan?!
Stop, Hartmann!
I'll shoot you if you
harm him any more!
Get out!
This is our problem.
Get out.
Dieter!
Come down from there!
Dr. Tenma!
You want to know about Johan,
don't you?
What are you going to do
once you do?
I think it's impossible to
find and kill him.
Fine...
I'll tell you one piece of information.
In exchange, once you hear it,
leave us alone.
Look for General Wolf. He's the one
who first discovered Johan's skill.
He should be alive somewhere.
Is he the man from the photograph
in your study?
Is he the man in the photograph
with Johan?
He's the one who brought Johan to us.
He should know something.
Now... get going.
Dieter!
Decide for yourself if you're
coming down from there!
There's nothing to worry about!
I'll shoot Hartmann if he puts
his finger on the rifle's trigger!
Dieter!
Decide for yourself!
Make your own decision!
There's no way you'd leave me,
would you... Dieter?
Because you're my child...
That's how it is, Dr. Tenma.
Now leave.
Dieter...
That's right... it's all right...
That's good... Slowly... Slowly...
Dieter... come back.
My dear Dieter...
Dieter!
Do you think that you can live
without me, Dieter?!
Stop, Hartmann! If you move,
I'll shoot!
I love you!
Dieter!
The world is dark!
Tomorrow is dark!
Tenma told me that tomorrow
will be a good day.
Dieter!
Be strong!
Don't be afraid!
Dieter!
Dieter...
Now did you get that?
Get on the bus here and get off
at Keunen Street...
The orphanage is right there.
Give this to Elna Tyce...
She's an instructor there.
She looks scary,
but she's a very nice lady.
Take care...
I can't stay in this town.
We part ways here.
A bus will come
in two or three minutes...
See you later.
Good luck with soccer.
No, you can't come with me...
Here.
Dieter.
I'm telling you that you
can't come with me!
You can't... come with me...
Petra and Schumann