The extremists are going to start a fire in that town!
That Turkish woman was killed.
We will soon arrive at the place Johan told us about.
I don't know what will happen. I'll assume
you know how to use that gun.
Take me to Frankfurt... to Calvin Street.
Aren't you going to go kill Johan?
I'll do that later. Now hurry!
General Wolf will be disappointed... After he
commissioned you to eliminate Johan...
Commissioned?
I won't take orders from anyone.
I'll kill Johan of my own free will.
Now go to Calvin Street!
Reunion
I've received word that the preparations for
starting the fire have been completed.
Good work.
Make sure to mark this rebirth of our master
race with a spectacular display.
Yes, sir!
Well, what should we do with them?
There are people like them even in the master race.
This one's a thief, and the kid was trying
to tell the Turks about our plans.
They're both scum.
We must purify them.
That's just how I feel.
This place is going to burn anyway,
so they can burn along with it.
Come on, don't cry...
Mama will be home.
Ayse.
Ay-
So you're alive.
Why are you here?
Dieter told me where it was.
Dieter?
So you're the Tenma he was talking about, huh?
Has Dieter come here?
No.
He's not here?
More importantly, where's Ayse?
This is Ayse's son.
I have to give him back to his mother.
Huh?
Don't tell me...
I don't believe it!
What's going to happen to this baby?
What's going to happen to him if he
loses his mother at an age like this?
From now on, no more people will be sacrificed.
Let me see this town's representatives.
What do you think?
They're going to start a fire, huh?
So what? All year round, there are rumors
about the extremists' plans for a fire.
This Japanese guy... His life is in danger, but he just
shows up at our place. Seems pretty suspicious to me.
You people! Ayse died for this!
She was killed because she was going to warn us!
I wonder if that's really true.
Ayse is a prostitute, just like you.
She was doing business in an area with a lot of
Germans and disappeared. That happens a lot.
It's a disgrace to all Turks.
Yeah, who knows who that kid's father is?
That's what it takes to survive here. You all know this.
If you want to survive, listen to what I'm saying.
I've had enough! Do what you want!
I hope you all burn!
Wait a second there...
You want us to form a group of vigilantes?
Let's try doing what he says.
Dennis!
Are you going to listen to what this
suspicious Japanese guy is saying?
He is suspicious,
but there are some Japanese
people you should believe...
like General Nogi.
General Nogi...?
Haven't you heard of him?
He was a Japanese man who saved the Turkish Navy when it was in the Pacific.
Gather all the men in the town.
It looks delicious.
We're having a special dinner tonight too, it seems.
Hold up. You shouldn't eat so quickly.
If you do, our dinner will end before show time.
The main dish should come at the climax of the show.
We can enjoy it while drinking the Chateau
Latour '76 I've been saving for this evening.
We will tickle our taste buds with my
favorite, raw halibut with caviar...
And eventually...
Look!
The first fire has appeared.
That's still just an appetizer, though.
When is the main dish?
Didn't I tell you not to rush?
You have to save the taste and enjoy the show...
Hmm?
Where is the main dish?
If that fire is an appetizer,
where will the fire that you call the "main dish" start?
Fire!
Bring water!
It won't be enough for a fire like that!
Don't have everyone go.
People with free hands, come with me.
As I thought, the fire was started upwind.
That means that this area is
in danger, too. Let's split up!
Oh, another wonderful guest has arrived.
Don't move!
I will shoot.
Put that dangerous thing away.
Enjoy yourself.
It's a pity, but your appetizers are being put out.
Well, they are only appetizers, after all.
This was your favorite food, right?
Too bad.
Why don't you just enjoy yourself?
This is a party to call your brother, Johan.
Johan wouldn't want this.
How do you know that?
I saw it.
I went to the place he mentioned in his message.
He didn't want this.
What did you see?
He...
He didn't wish for anything!
I-I get it.
Relax... Calm down.
You killed Ayse.
I won't let you do any more horrible things!
Where is the "main dish"?
Where are you going to start the fire?
Damn it! They started fires in places that
are difficult for fire trucks to access.
Carry the injured. I'll be there in a second.
Tenma.
Did you find Dieter?
Someone said they saw a boy like
him at the park during the day.
Dieter...
Are you sure you don't want us to follow her?
Yes. Let's continue with dinner.
She certainly is Johan's little sister.
Huh?
Her eyes... I could see that she really was going to kill me.
Because of that, I was just about to tell her the
truth about where the main dish will be.
Shall I bring you the rest of your dinner?
No. I need some new underwear first.
Huh?
She is a frightening girl.
Hold on! I'll put out the flames.
You're quite the trooper, little boy.
You're safe now.
I don't know who you are, but thanks.
How did you end up like this?
That is...
It's this kid's fault.
We were almost done for!
Well, I'm off.
They aren't going to stop at
just this simple little plan.
I used to live here when I was a
kid, so I know this place well.
If I were to start a fire, I wouldn't do it here.
This was just a decoy.
It seems that we managed to put out
three fires that were upwind.
We owe you our thanks, Mr. Tenma. Right, everyone?
Yeah, thanks to you, we avoided a catastrophe.
First, we have to treat the injured.
I won't let there be any more sacrifices.
I just won't!
What do you mean a decoy?
The direction of the wind will change.
Right about now, the wind stops, and then, all of the
sudden, the breeze from the river starts to blow.
The wind has stopped.
Well now... it's finally time for the main dish.
All right. It shouldn't give you any problems now.
Thank you, Doctor. Let's have a drink.
What are you saying? You should rest if you're injured.
Don't be so strict.
That's right. Thanks to you, we stopped
the fires before they got out of hand.
The extremists must have been frustrated
since their fires were put out.
They should never have underestimated us Turks.
Is there any other place where the wounded are staying?
A mosque by the river.
Hey, Dr. Tenma. Take a break already. Have a drink!
I have to treat the wounded first.
If all the fires so far have just been a distraction, then,
where are they going to set the next fire?
Leave me alone!
I don't care what happens to this place.
I have something to attend to.
Wait!
I'm begging you! Tell me!
Where would you set the fire?
I told you!
The river breeze will begin to blow.
If they set fire to the factories by the
river, no one could stop them.
There are some chemicals left there.
It's finally time...
It's time for the main dish.
Fill me up with satisfaction!
It's all going as planned.
The party for the master race begins now.
Little boy... Why did you follow me?
We have to put out that fire.
I promised Tenma.
Tenma...
This is the warehouse, right here.
Good. Maybe they haven't noticed this place.
Are these all chemicals?
If all of these chemicals catch fire, the
entire city is doomed.
All right, I'll guard this area.
I absolutely won't let them start a fire here.
Are you okay?
I slipped.
What is this?
It's gasoline.
Someone's... here.
Don't worry. I can walk by myself.
Let me take a look at you at the shelter.
Thanks. I got a sprain when I was
carrying some important tools.
As long as I have this rug, I don't need this town!
800,000 marks... No, 1,000,000 marks!
Heckel!
What happened to Dieter?
Well, that is...
I'm asking you where Dieter went!
If you're looking for him, why don't you
try looking around the riverside factory?
Factory?
The river breeze will start to blow soon.
If the chemicals there were ignited,
this town would be done for.
See? This wind!
Tell everyone in the shelter to get away from the river!
Hurry!
Let's go, Heckel!
Who's there?
Don't move!
It's you. So you're Johan's sister.
Throw away the lighter!
If I use this lighter, the gasoline will
make this place go up in flames.
I'll shoot you in the head before you can do that.
If I cut your cranial nerves, I can
stop you from moving!
Will you be able to hit them?
I had six months of training.
I have a 100% chance of hitting them from this range.
Your threats won't work on me.
This is the party for the master race...
a party to call Johan!
Johan doesn't want that!
It is true that Johan came to Frankfurt,
but he killed one of your leaders
and his men, and then he left.
He left a message afterwards.
Message?
He's not the type of person you think he is.
He's something more complicated than that.
What are you trying to say?
He's something more frightening than that.
He's suffering in an abyss of sadness.
I don't know about this... I don't like
messing with this organization...
Where is the warehouse?
Hey, hey. I've done enough.
I'll take my leave right now.
What are you saying?
Are you just going to let Dieter die?
Where's the warehouse?!
I'll tell. I'll tell already!
You said your friend is named Tenma, right?
I also know someone called Tenma.
Really? Is he a brave person?
Yes, but he told me never to hold a gun.
He thought that you shouldn't kill.
You mustn't ever kill.
No matter how evil they are?
That's right. Never do what I'm about to do.
Close your eyes! Don't look!
Don't shoot!
Tenma!
Heckel, put out the fire!
The rug! Hurry up!
Stop, idiot!
My million...
Nina...
Tenma.
Crap! It's the cops!
Run! Leave this man to me.
There's a boat in the river.
Hurry up and get out of here, Tenma!
My main dish... has gotten cold.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Could you give me the details at the station?
Just a second. I'll be right back.
Hey, you!
Tenma!
Nina!
Nina, promise me something.
Don't shoot.
You must never shoot anyone!
I saw it... I saw Johan's message.
I saw it, too. I'm going there.
That day, ten years ago, when I shot Johan...
I finally understand why he
told me to aim at his head.
Johan... isn't one person.
There are two Johans!
So... Dr. Tenma...
It wasn't your fault.
I have to... I have to aim at
Johan's head once again.
Hey, why are we stopping here?
Let's hurry up and go!
Geez. My life sucks.
I'm hungry, and I have no money.
If only I had that rug...
Huh? What's this?
This is...
"Help me! The monster inside
me is about to explode."
Johan has...
two personalities!
Five Sugars