Let's not take a side trip here!
Let's just hurry and go!
Geez. My life sucks.
I'm hungry, and I have no money.
If only I had that rug...
Dammit!
Huh?
What's this?
Th-This is...
"Help me! The monster inside
me is about to explode."
Johan has...
two personalities!
Five Sugars
So you're saying that when
you got to the warehouse,
the Asian and the arsonist
had already fought,
and when the Asian man saw
you, he fled from the scene.
Is that right, Ms. Anna Liebert?
Yes.
The suspect is an extremist, and he turned
himself in while mentioning something
about "a flame for a race's festival."
Your background checks out,
so we're done for today.
So I can go home now?
Yes.
One more thing. Didn't people
call that man Dr. Tenma?
Do you know anything about him?
No, I don't.
What do you think?
Wearing those clothes? It makes
me think she's a hooker...
Not her.
I meant Dr. Tenma.
That's what the people from the Turkish
quarter called that Asian man!
When we told them that he was a
murder suspect, though,
they all clammed up and
said they didn't know him.
I came to back you up.
Mr. Rosso.
You're safe, Anna. I was worried!
You just disappeared all of a sudden.
You changed clothes?
These clothes suit you much better.
Those clothes didn't fit you at all.
You must be hungry. Eat up!
Aren't you going to eat, Mr. Rosso?
I ate before I came.
I'll be happy with just some coffee.
Come on, eat!
I will. Thanks for the food.
What is it?
You always put in five spoonfuls of sugar.
Of course! Unsweetened
coffee isn't good at all.
You finally laughed.
Huh?
You had such a gloomy face for
coming in for a job interview.
Is it so strange to use so much sugar?
What was it...? Anna...
Anna Liebert.
Umm...
Of course I'll hire you.
Naturally, if I have a beautiful girl like you working
for me, my restaurant will be a huge success.
However...
However...?
You should smile more.
You're wasting your beauty.
Thank you. I'll work my hardest!
You don't have to strain yourself.
It's just a countryside Italian restaurant.
You'll see how busy it gets.
Come here, Anna.
Yes, sir.
I'll put the food out here.
You take it to the customers.
The dirty dishes go on the
right side of the counter.
The wine's over here, and the
glasses are on this shelf.
I'll also put the wine on top of the counter.
The tickets with the orders will be here.
The wine is on top of the counter..
The glasses are here...
This is the water.
Yes, sir.
Good afternoon!
Welcome.
I'm hungry...
Nice to meet you. I'm Anna.
"Nice to meet you"?
Don't tell me you're a waitress here!
What do you mean by that?
There's no doubt about it... Anna
is a waitress for this restaurant.
I'm looking forward to serving here.
Is this for real?
Anna, I'll have some carbonara.
Anna, I'll have a Bolognese.
Anna, can you come here and get me some water?
I'll be there in a second.
We have carbonara and a Bolognese.
Got it.
Thanks for waiting.
Thank you.
One vongole, one rigatoni!!
Coming.
Where did you catch a cute one like her?
"Catch"? Don't bad-mouth people.
Anna, I'll take you to a nicer place
than this. Are you free tonight?
I won't let you off easy if you
touch my serving girl!
That crybaby Rosso is using
some pretty tough words.
That guy cried when he was watching a movie at my house.
Shut up...
Another squid ink risotto.
They're playing "Summertime."
Huh?
They're playing "Summertime" at
the Masterpiece Theater. Look.
It must be great. Frankfurt has a
lot of movie theaters.
It was on TV before.
I cried so much.
Have you seen it?
No.
I see.
This movie is set in Venice.
Venice is a port city in Italy. It's
been called the water capital.
Wow!
It was originally built on a lagoon,
so a canal ran throughout the city.
I'd like to show you Venice some time.
Have you been there?
Yes.
On top of that, the music in
the movie is pretty good.
You've probably heard the
main theme for the movie.
What kind of song was it?
Let's see...
If we hurry, we could see it.
We could still get in.
Yes...
But...
I see. If we go now, it'll be
late by the time we get out.
Yeah.
I'm back.
Welcome back.
Ahh. I'll do it.
Don't worry about it.
I'm sorry for leaving every afternoon.
It's okay. I'm free this time of day anyway.
I don't mean to pry, but...
Where do you go every day?
You don't have to answer. It's your business
where you go when you're not working.
I have marksmanship training.
Marksmanship?
Yes, from a man named Wenkel.
Oh, you go to Wenkel's place.
He's a good guy.
Have you ever fired a gun before, Mr. Rosso?
Guns are terrible.
Just seeing one makes me tremble all over.
Here you go. Enjoy.
Thank you.
I wonder how it is this time.
Why don't you try it, then?
What can you taste in it?
Garlic, olive oil, and parsley.
The flavors of everything else you put
in there disappeared, didn't they?
Yes.
Then it's not a real pasta dish.
This is hard.
Everything is training.
Mr. Rosso, the bath is free.
Good night.
I couldn't believe that there was such
a movie when I was young...
Mr. Rosso, you always cry
when you watch movies.
When I was young, even if I wanted to see
them, I never had time to watch movies.
I should have eaten a lot of good things then,
but I can't remember the taste
of anything from that time.
I didn't even know the taste of sugar.
The taste of sugar?
You know about me, don't you?
After you left here, I did a little
background check on you.
Nina Fortner.
Her parents were murdered. Current
whereabouts unknown.
What did you want from me?
Did you want a job, or did you want
me to tell you something?
I wanted you to tell me something.
How did you know about me?
There was a law professor at
the university where I studied.
The Ristorante Nino Case, The Sacco Milano
Case, The Sabatini Bombing...
You were an important reference for three murder
cases where the modus operandi were different.
They all resulted in a ruling of no prosecution
due to the lack of evidence.
That professor had an interesting theory, though.
He said that you were,
without a doubt, a professional assassin.
On top of that, you were top-class.
How many people do you think I killed?
The truth is that I don't remember myself.
When I was a kid, before I knew it,
I was a member of the organization.
Theft, blackmail, anything you could think of...
In the end, I became an assassin.
I was able to eat well, thanks to the rewards.
I never asked why.
It was my job.
That day was the same.
Just as usual.
It was at a café in broad daylight.
I was lining up my shot on someone, not knowing
or caring what number target he was.
That person was drinking coffee.
He was beginning to add sugar to it.
One spoonful.
Two spoonfuls.
Three spoonfuls.
Four spoonfuls.
When he added the fifth spoonful of sugar, the taste
of the coffee I drink all the time spread in my mouth.
That someone began to drink it happily.
That's when I put down my gun.
That was it. That's what made me stop killing people.
Why didn't you ask me how to kill
people for these last six months?
I...
I thought that I shouldn't get you involved.
Do you have to go?
Goodbye.
Thank you, Mr. Rosso.
Killing people is easy...
if you can forget the taste of sugar.
Monster's Abyss