I got divorced three years ago.
No, it's more like my wife ran away from me.
I wish I'd paid more attention to her.
She left me because I paid more attention to this thing.
This is what she said to me:
"You're just a collector who peeks into people's hearts."
Doctor.
You've got problems.
You might be right.
My talent for fishing around in the abyss of
people's hearts also carries a high risk
of sinking into that abyss myself.
Your fourth victim was an 18-year-old girl...
Do you remember the sexual arousal
you felt when you chopped her up?
Doctor.
Ask me about the twelfth murder.
Hanna Kempf of Krupp-Haus.
Fifty-two years old.
When I did that, I...
No, you don't have to tell
me about that incident.
I'm sure I'll want to ask
about it sometime in the future,
but for now, I'd like to ask
about the first eleven incidents,
okay?
Tell me, is the peak of your sexual arousal
usually before or after you kill someone?
As you can see there, his victims are limited to
missing school girls from the ages of 16 to 18.
Monster's Abyss
His crimes should obviously be
classified as sexual murders.
He confessed to a twelfth murder, though.
The victim of this murder was a 52-year-old
woman named Kempf, and on top of
that, there was no evidence of sex.
He claims that he did this at the request of
a friend,  and our investigation is in a
state of confusion due to his claim.
Huh?
Who is it?
Who's there?
It's me, Rudy.
Tenma!
You surprised me.
Sorry, this was the only way I could reach you.
You know why.
Yes, I've heard.
Do you think I'm a serial killer?
I don't know.
I've just heard rumors in the papers, on the
news, and from old college colleagues.
What did you come here to ask me?
It's not that we're good friends, especially since...
you've had nothing but contempt for me.
That's what I feel when I look into your eyes.
I feel that you despised me.
Oh, I see.
You want me to give back that money I borrowed.
Is it money?
No, it's not that.
I've heard that you're one of
the top criminal psychologists.
I have something I want you to take a look at.
"Look at me! Look at me!"
"The monster inside me has
grown so big, Doctor Tenma!"
"Help me! The monster inside me is about to explode!"
What is this?
I see.
This Johan is the real killer of the director.
He killed the foster parents that took care of him, left
you those messages, and once again disappeared.
I have to find him as soon as possible.
And with that, prove your
innocence as soon as possible.
Twenty years ago, there was a kid at a famous
medical school who didn't rest until
he became the top of his class.
When a Japanese student came to that school,
his situation changed completely.
He was sociable and popular with everyone.
On top of that, his grades were excellent.
The student who was at the top of the class
was displaced during the midterm exam.
He worked his hardest for the finals so that
he could become the top student again.
He had done perfectly in
all of his classes until then,
but the last test was his worst subject:
Introduction to Medical Law.
If he did poorly on that test, all his hard
work would have been for nothing.
That man played his last card.
It was the only way he could get the high score.
However...
However, the Japanese man didn't tell anyone.
The result was that the man took back
his position as the top student.
So do you have any ideas
about those two messages?
Is your theory that of multiple personalities?
You're trying to say that one personality is a
murderer, and the other personality
is trying to stop those murders.
There are, of course, examples of serial killers
leaving messages like this behind,
but there's also the possibility that they're using
this to escape from being guilty of their actions.
Seeing through that is where we
psychoanalysts show our skill.
Many people think that all serial killers are
introverts, but they are sadly mistaken.
Some of them are intelligent,
sociable, and very persuasive.
They're all big fat liars.
Are you saying that he's just playing with me?
Hold on. You shouldn't rush to conclusions.
Will you tell me more about Johan, first?
The truth is that I got divorced three years ago.
No, it's more like my wife ran away from me.
Thank you, Rudy.
That was a fascinating conversation, Tenma.
I'd really like to research this in further detail.
Get in touch with me in a week.
What do you think of him?
I understand him.
Oh? In what way?
The monster he was talking about...
I see.
So there's a monster.
Of course, they exist... inside of you,
inside of him, even inside of me!
Stop it.
Stop your academic nonsense.
What do you mean?
I'm saying that monsters really exist in this world.
What's with your eyes?
Don't look at me with those eyes!
I hate being looked down on.
What are you doing?
We're done here.
Are you scared?
Are you scared? Huh?!
There are much more frightening things in this world.
I'll let you know something good.
Thank you for your cooperation.
So he's definitely going to see you again?
He will.
When he does, I'll contact you at once.
However...
However...?
After you arrest him, I'd like you
to let me use him for research.
He's a fascinating criminal,
that Dr. Tenma.
I'll let you know something good.
Go to the Kempf Mansion,
to the basement storage room.
You'll understand when you get there.
The proof that monsters exist is there.
Hello?
Hey, Tenma.
I'd love to see you.
Got it.
I'll be waiting!
Inspector Kohl.
I've gotten in touch with Tenma.
8:00 P.M. in Oder Park, in front of the fountain.
Goodbye.
I'm currently following the route of entry
that Jurgens used to commit his crime.
According to his confession, he snuck in through
this storage room and spent a few hours here.
When she came home, he snuck up to the
second-floor bedroom and killed her.
There's nothing unusual here... just pictures.
A lot of them.
They have Mrs. Kempf in them.
A doll.
I don't see anything out of the ordinary.
There's no proof that there's a monster
like Jurgens said there was.
It seems that Jurgens committed this murder
to throw the investigators off his trail.
He claimed that he killed at
the request of his friend.
He called that friend a "monster."
When I was a kid, my mother
would always punish me.
There was a large doll that
she loved very much.
It was a female doll with long hair.
When I was beaten, I pleaded
with the doll to help me,
but it would only look at me and grin.
There were just a lot of
photos in that storage room.
No matter where I looked, it was just
my mother, my mother, my mother...
always watching over me.
What does this mean?
Is it that?
Is it that Jurgens changed this storage room
to look like the room from his childhood?
This is Jurgens as a child.
This can't be. He couldn't have
known Mrs. Kempf as a child.
What's with this photo?
Jurgens' face as a child was put on top.
This one, too. This... this too!
And this one, too!
Mrs. Kempf was not supposed to have had any children.
Then this boy is...
Who are you?
The proof that monsters exist is there.
I just did everything exactly as the
letters from my friend told me.
Your friend?
One day, I got a letter in a
blank envelope with no address.
He knew about me.
He wrote to me in an overly familiar
way, and at first I was angry.
After that, I got a letter every week.
He was a letter demon.
But then the letters didn't come as quickly.
Gradually, I started enjoying receiving them.
Those letters were fun.
I thought that he might really be my friend.
Then one day, he called me with that letter.
"Go look at the basement in that mansion..."
The storage room in the basement
of Mrs. Kempf's mansion...?
How did he know?
How did he know about my childhood?
I was totally confused, there
in the basement storage room.
What's going on?
Is Mrs. Kempf my mother?
When I came to my senses, I went up
to the second floor and killed her.
He was a letter demon.
Did that "friend" send letters to Mrs. Kempf, too?
This one...
And this one!
"Look at me! Look at me!"
"The monster inside me has grown so big!"
"Help! The monster inside me
is about to explode!"
These are the messages that Johan left me.
They're the same.
The friend and Johan are real...?
He's still not here?
It's past eight o'clock.
Inspector Kohl, look there.
He's here.
He's an Asian man with long hair.
I'm sorry for bothering you
at such a busy time, Rudy.
I analyzed what you'd said.
I thought you made it up.
"Johan doesn't exist."
"He's just something you made up."
Hear me out, Rudy. I...
I'm currently researching a
serial killer named Jurgens.
There's only one incident where the modus
operandi is different from the others.
No, listen to what I have to say.
That's all for today. Come again!
The carnival is over.
Tell all the groups, "When I give the
signal, move in and capture him."
Sir.
Don't forget to listen to their conversation.
Tenma, you looked down on me, didn't you?
Ever since you saw me cheating, you've
always looked down on me.
Didn't you?
Inspector Kohl.
This is bad.
Tenma and the doctor are
walking towards the west exit.
They'll get lost in the crowd leaving the carnival.
I deserve all the scorn you can give me.
Rudy, more importantly, right now...
Do you remember?
I used that hidden paper to cheat on the exam.
Just like this.
"Run! You're surrounded by the police!"
Don't look, just walk.
Is the doctor being threatened?
The crowd is too loud. I can't hear anything.
Jurgens said that he killed
at the request of his friend.
This is...
This was in Mrs. Kempf's storage room.
Mrs. Kempf didn't have any children.
The Johan you spoke of and Jurgens'
friend are probably one in the same.
They're outside the west gate.
Should we stop them?
Wait! Tenma might have a gun!
Mrs. Kempf had letters that had the same
messages as the letters he left you.
Johan was feeding off of her, and when
her use had run out, he disposed of her.
It might have been to eliminate his past, just as you said.
You're innocent.
Maybe I can't tell you anything more than that,
but from what I've analyzed, I can tell you this:
I don't know how, but
Johan can sniff out the killers.
On top of that, he can
isolate them and control them.
I can't find the case where Johan had killed
his foster parents after adolescence.
It's probably because he thought that foster
parents weren't necessary anymore.
I can think of something else.
Johan found his ideal family and joined it.
Why is he trying to erase his past, though?
Does he have some reason for doing that?
Is he joining his family for some reason?
If so, for what reason?
Now, we've made it to the bus terminal.
Get ready. Find out which bus he gets on.
Surround the terminal with the squad cars.
Get ready for pursuit!
Yes, sir.
I've already got you a ticket.
Tenma...
There are still ways to
prove that you're innocent.
I'll help you.
I'm not chasing after Johan to clear my name.
Thank you, Rudy.
Tenma, don't tell me...
You're going to... to Johan...
Oh, yes. I never looked down on you.
It's true.
You looked like an interesting fellow,
but I never had a chance to meet you.
But now we're finally friends, aren't we?
You saw me cheat, though.
You lifted your head and looked my way.
I was cheating, too.
What did you say?
Five buses left at the same time?
Tenma...
Journey to Freiham