Hey, hey, move it! Don't
disturb the investigation.
What happened?
Tell us how you're handling the investigation.
Is this murder the work of the serial killer?
The victims, the Jopps, don't
have children, do they?
No matter how you look at it, the scene
looks just like one of the serial killings
of middle-aged married couples that
are happening all across Germany.
No comment.
We've heard that a special agent from the
confederate detective agency is coming.
Is this proof that this is one
of the serial murders?
No comment.
It'd be faster to just ask the confederate
detective agency itself.
Leave it to me!
I'll get you your story.
Be sure to leave a lot of space for me.
Thanks.
Excuse me.
I'm Mr. Kipper for Hamburg Talk.
You're the investigator from the
confederate detective agency.
Could I get a statement?
Is this incident related to
those serial murders?
Mr. Kipper from Hamburg Talk, I'll
say something special, just for you.
You're absolutely correct.
This murder was done by the killer
of those middle-aged couples.
I knew it! The suspect is the
Japanese doctor, then.
I saw the report.
It looks exactly like the serial killings.
I've got my scoop!
Thanks!
Wait a second.
Yes?
Hamburg Talk is pretty influential
around here, isn't it?
So your article will spread to other
papers across the country, right?
Of course. Thank you for your cooperation.
Lunge's Trap
I am the killer.
I've become the killer.
Should I knock?
Yes. It would be best not to alarm them.
What a courteous old couple.
I've been invited into the
living room without hesitation.
They don't suspect a thing.
The husband's seat.
Of course, I sit on the couch for guests.
A few minutes later, the husband
dies on the floor over there,
but I haven't started to
make any movements yet.
Where is the wife?
Right, she isn't in the living room yet.
She is making tea in the kitchen.
Before the tea is prepared, the wife is killed,
which means that I have to take action soon.
I take out my knife, and while the
husband is still confused, I stab him.
I miss.
The husband runs while holding
his wound with his left hand.
The next attack is aimed at
the husband's right shoulder.
Another clumsy miss.
What an amateur I am!
The husband cries out for his wife,
but the wife can't hear
him from the kitchen.
Her hearing has been getting worse.
Yes. I know that.
Scream if you want!
I can take care of your wife
easily after I've killed you.
I've caught up to you.
The husband's left handprint.
I catch up to the husband
at this sideboard.
This is the final blow!
No, I don't deliver the final blow here.
I am five meters from
where the husband died.
Why?
Why didn't I deliver the final blow here?
Is this the man who killed the Jopps?
No, it's not that simple.
I'm just asking the people of the neighborhood.
If he shows up, treat him naturally.
Then contact me as soon as possible.
That's all.
You won't be in danger.
I guarantee it.
It's hard to believe something so horrible
happened in a neighborhood like this one.
Yeah. The Jopps were such kind people.
Whenever I called out to her in the morning,
she'd always respond cheerfully.
You called out to her?
Her hearing has been going bad
for about a year now, hasn't it?
Is that true?
It's written in her doctor's reports.
She shouldn't have been
able to hear you say hello.
She must have sensed me
some other way and responded.
So the people of the neighborhood
didn't know about her hearing?
Probably not.
This is quite the company.
It's extraordinary to have come this
far at such a young age, Mr. Giebel.
Nah. The makers we sign contracts
with just have pretty good cars.
You have my deepest condolences
for losing your uncle and aunt.
Yeah. I didn't have any other
relatives besides them.
Since your aunt and uncle were childless,
they must have been quite fond of you.
Yes, as if I were their own.
Can you catch the killer?
Yes, I have a good hunch.
Is it that Japanese doctor?
You know the details well.
Of course... There were other
cases similar to this one.
How much did you inherit?
Huh?
The Jopps were very wealthy.
Does that have anything
to do with the incident?
You're the only one who
would inherit the money.
Isn't that correct?
What are you saying?
It's not the right time to
be talking about that.
Even if companies seem to be spectacularly
successful on the surface, there are
often poor managers underneath.
There are many cases like that.
What the hell are you getting at?
Are you accusing me of killing
them for the inheritance?
Don't worry. You have a perfect alibi.
You took your secretary and subordinates
out to eat. There are witnesses.
Wh-What are you saying?
You're not the killer. That's right, isn't it?
Inspector Lunge!
Oh, you.
What's happening?
What are you talking about?
Don't play dumb with me.
These last few days,
I checked up on that nephew.
At first glance, his company looks quite good,
but behind it all, their stockbrokers mess
up, and their financial state is horrible.
And you've been thoroughly scouring that company.
What's the truth?
Do you really see this case as
part of the serial murders?
Everyone is printing our exclusive scoop.
If there's no relationship between this murder and the
previous ones, it'll be a terrible miscommunication.
It's just as you said.
It's the work of a copycat.
He made it look like one of
the serial murders.
I knew it! I have to change the story.
No, just leave it as it is.
You're going to write the story stating that
the murder is one of the serial murders.
This isn't a joke. Why should
I print false information?
Just do it.
I-I'm a journalist. You can't
pressure me into doing things.
You said your name was Kipper, right?
Didn't you find her to be a fascinating woman...
even though you have such a caring family...
a wonderful wife and daughter?
I guess such a fascinating woman would make
you want to be unfaithful, though...
If you do as I say this time... no,
if you keep on doing it...
If you do it, he'll come back.
I'm expecting good things from you.
Coming.
I have a favor to ask.
I see. They were a wonderful couple.
Yes.
Umm, did they have any foster children?
No.
Was there a child who was staying
there for only a little while?
No.
They loved their nephew very much, though.
Oh, how would you like another cup of tea?
No, I'm fine.
Don't hold back.
There's no doubt.
It's the man in the photo.
He's in my house now.
I see.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Inspector Lunge.
You have a visitor.
Who is it?
The nephew of the Jopps.
You must think I'm the killer.
Isn't that right?
I killed them for the inheritance...
That's what you think, right?
It is true that I have quite a few debts now,
and the money they left me
would definitely save me...
But I'm not that type of person!
Is that all?
"Is that all?"
You treat me like a murderer
and then say, "Is that all?"
I have somewhere I must go.
Wait right there.
I want you to take back what you said.
The police have called off the
people following you.
The police here are treating you as innocent.
Just leave it as it is.
Then who do you think the killer is?
The killer?
I couldn't care less.
As long as I can catch that one man...
The bloodstains over there mean...
He made a mistake.
So you don't think this murder's
perpetrator was the Japanese doctor?
Let's see...
It's a copycat of the couples' serial murders.
What are you saying?
There's something in this case that
was missing in other cases.
The killer catches up to the victim here,
but not here.
He delivers the final blow all the way over there.
Why? Why did he hesitate?
It's different.
There's a feeling.
A feeling?
At the scene of the crimes
of the man I've been chasing,
there have been valuables stolen to make it seem
like a robbery, but there's no feeling at all.
When I went to the site of the crime this
time, however, there was a feeling.
He paused when he saw his and
his victim's faces in the mirror.
Well, don't worry.
The police here are brainless.
This is the doing of a copycat who
made it look like Johan's work.
How long will this continue?
How long?
It's been a while...
We finally meet, Dr. Tenma.
I've been looking for you for so long...
So very long...
I wanted to talk with you.
You can't run away.
Let's talk.
How long are you going to keep
doing this, Dr. Tenma?
I'll end it here.
As long as I get rid of you...
Move!
I killed the Jopps... Forgive me!
I have no interest in you.
You're in my way.
Dammit!
What's this wound?
At this rate, he'll die from blood loss.
Who did this to Inspector Lunge?
I have no choice but to leave him
in front of a hospital and run.
Damn!
Are you awake?
Where are the keys to the handcuffs?
Don't bother looking for your gun.
I have it.
Tell me where the keys are.
I can't help you like this.
I've looked at your wound.
The wound, fortunately, did not
reach your abdominal cavity.
However, if I don't stop
the bleeding, you'll die.
Confess, Dr. Tenma.
What?
The three murders at Eisler Memorial Hospital, the
serial killings of couples over the last three years...
Confess to them.
You really will die!
It was all "Johan's" work.
You were searching for the real killer, "Johan."
Johan doesn't exist.
You are Johan, Dr. Tenma.
Confess.
There wasn't much I could find
in this old warehouse,
but I found materials for emergency treatment.
All that's left is my hands.
If only my hands were free, I could save you.
When you're Dr. Tenma, you're
an exceptional surgeon.
That face of yours doesn't have
one speck of wickedness.
How many people have you
killed with those hands?
You're mistaken.
When do you change into "Johan"?
When do you change into that killing machine?
You're mistaken.
I don't make mistakes.
The drop in blood pressure is making you
waver in and out of consciousness.
Your crime scenes...
You shouldn't talk anymore.
At your crime scenes, there's no feeling.
Don't talk.
You lose your emotions when you hold the lives
of people in your hands every day, Dr. Tenma.
It's there. That calmness is
always at the crime scene.
Total calmness.
You're mistaken.
Whenever I was performing surgery,
I prayed I wouldn't make a mistake.
I prayed that it would go well.
I worried that there'd be problems.
The truth is that I was
scared out of my mind.
People's lives are in my hands.
In my hands...
There's no way I could be calm!
Don't... move.
I'll save you.
I'll shoot...
I'll stop the bleeding. Where is the key?
Is it in your pants pocket?
I'll... shoot...
I'm so relieved!
Are you feeling well?
You're complexion looks better now
than when you're working.
I'm sorry to have worried you.
The emergency treatment was perfect.
That's what the doctors said.
If it hadn't have been done
so well, you'd be dead.
Tenma... saved my life.
That's what happened, right?
Well, Tenma might have gotten away,
but... Giebel confessed to the murder of the Jopps.
Good work, Lunge.
Thank you.
What do you think?
Tenma saved his life.
It might be hard for
him to arrest Tenma now.
We should take Lunge off of the Tenma case.
We're sorry that Inspector Lunge
caused you so much trouble.
He wasn't trouble at all.
He's very nice to be around.
He said he's in a hurry and would like to
get done with rehab as soon as possible.
He's already squeezing the ball
and walking around the halls...
He's having fun!
Fun?
Yes.
He says it quite often.
He says that he's never
had so much fun before.
Now what did he say the killer's name was...?
That's right, Tenma.
"Chasing after a criminal like Tenma
is the most fun I can have."
Eva's Confession