Oh, Corinna.
Why was your letter so short?
Just like Eupolis who practiced, practiced,
and practiced astrology,
my heart is troubled by you.
Idas's gold faded, and Galonus the carpenter...
That's enough.
There's no need for you to read any further.
What's wrong?
That's enough.
Go home.
I'm sorry. Did I do anything to upset you?
People who can't pronounce Latin correctly
have no right to read a book to me.
I'm sorry.
I'll try harder in the future.
I'm telling you to leave.
Thursday's Boy
Munich University
Friedrich Emmanuel School
You really got scolded
harshly at the mansion.
Cheer up.
Business management major, Karl Neuman.
How do you know about me?
What's your name?
I'm Lotte Frank,
a cultural anthropology major.
Are you also reading
books to him as a part-time job?
No, I just take care of the place.
Only male students read to him.
You're the person who
reads to him on Tuesdays.
On other days, he has other students come and
read to him since his eyesight has worsened.
What do you think of him?
That mysterious millionaire,
Hans George Schubert.
I... I don't know.
I just thought that the wage he was paying for the
part-time job was pretty good, so I jumped at it.
Have you heard the numerous
rumors about him?
They say there's a phone line in the mansion where he can
manipulate the German stock market any way he wishes.
They call him the Howard Hughes of Bayern.
He has no family and no acquaintances, but his
fortune just keeps growing and growing.
What do you think he
does with all that money?
I don't know.
There's an even bigger mystery than that!
He is also called the Vampire of Bayern.
Vampire?!
When the clock strikes two in the morning, he gets
in a car that looks like a Hearse and goes to town.
It looks just like a scene
from a gothic horror movie.
He was probably just going out for a stroll.
I'm going to confirm for myself whether
or not it was just an ordinary stroll.
Confirm for yourself? What are you saying?
It's for my research paper.
"Mental Activity of Medieval and Current
Day Financial Figures in Bayern."
He's a great sample for sure.
So you investigated me in the same manner.
I only looked up your name and major.
You shouldn't worry about his yelling at you.
He says cruel things to all the students.
I'm used to getting yelled at and beaten up.
Used to...?
A lot happened with my foster parents.
You aren't from one of the
local high schools, are you?
So you did  investigate me.
I see. You don't have any parents.
The truth is I was hoping to meet my real
mother in Munich, so I transferred here.
So your mother is in Munich?
Have you seen her?
No. I don't care anymore.
Huh? Why?
You're finally close to her.
You probably know her name, right?
Yeah.
What is it?
I told you, it doesn't matter anymore.
Tell me!
I'm interested now.
I'll figure it out eventually anyway.
Margot...
Margot Langer.
If you know that much,
it shouldn't be hard to find her.
Go see her. She'll be happy.
I told you, it doesn't matter.
Margot Langer... Margot Langer...
No way!
The galloping of the chestnut-colored horse was like
lightning striking the ground and large waves crashing.
I can't take it.
I only love beautiful things.
I can't listen to that anymore.
Why didn't you tell me?
I looked up your mother.
What can I say?
It's okay. Just drop it.
Karl, isn't there anything
I can do to help you?
Thanks, but don't worry about me.
Karl...
Lotte, you said that you wanted to see
what Hans Schubert does at night.
Can I come with you?
Of course. If you come with me,
I'll feel a lot better.
It's true!
This is my first big scoop.
Really?
It's perfectly clear that one of the men who founded
this school in 1502, Bishop Gropius, wrote this.
The most important part is this line here.
"In the second-to-last larger year,
the Thursday Boy will come to this land,
and the books shall be engulfed in flames,
and the whole world will
be wrapped in sorrow."
So what does that mean?
Will you ever get it?
This... "In the second-to-last larger year"...
It's 1996! So it's this year.
Why?
The "larger year" means leap years.
The only leap years left in this
century are this year and 2000.
"The Thursday Boy will come to this land,
and the books shall be engulfed in flame."
"The books of this land in flames"
means that this school will burn.
Then who is this "Thursday Boy"?
Thursday is "Donnerstag."
The origin of that is "Donner."
In other words, "thunder."
It must be the lightning god!
What a whopper!
This is no time to be laughing.
This will be the hit story of the next issue.
We won't have a problem writing this,
but who's going to believe it?
Who'd believe that a god of destruction
would come to this school?
Screw the "Vampire of Bayern"!
Is this the truth behind
the mysterious night out?
What a let down!
Shh! Here he comes.
How ridiculous.
I'm going home.
Take care.
Huh?
I'm going to go take a look.
Go where?
Let's give up already.
This isn't the place for a girl.
Go home.
"I only love beautiful things."
I want to know.
I want to know how low a man he really is.
It's open.
If you're looking for a girl,
this is the wrong place.
I retired a long time ago.
Who are you?
You should introduce yourself first
before you ask someone's name.
I'm Margot Langer.
You look like college students.
Yes. We work part time for Mr. Hans Schubert.
What do you want with me?
Why does Hans Schubert come here?
"He comes for pleasure."
That's what I'd like to say, but it seems that his
thing down there doesn't work anymore.
He comes to give me money.
Huh?
Naturally. When I came to him and told him
who I was, he cried and apologized to me.
He left me with a child and threw
me away like trash.
Karl, don't tell me... that you're
Hans Schubert's child?!
But...
You're lying.
You're not Margot Langer.
That's right. It was in the paper
a year ago. "Former..."
"Former Prostitute Margot Langer
Murdered -- Killer Unknown."
His mother is already dead.
You're using the name of Margot Langer
to swindle Hans Schubert out of money.
He knows it, too.
He gives me money, even though he knows
I'm not the real Margot Langer.
He knows that giving all his money away
won't bring the real Margot Langer back.
It's his way of paying for his sins.
With money! Money! Money!
A man who has lived only for money can't
think of anything other than money.
It might sound a bit arrogant, but
people aren't all that different.
There's a method where introducing yourself
as his son gets you a piece of that dying
man's ridiculously large fortune.
What are you trying to say?
I might be a liar, but...
you know what I'm talking about.
There's another one.
Another boy who calls himself his son.
He came here with the same story.
No way.
You don't mean...
It can't be. He's lying.
I don't know who's telling a lie.
You both look like imposters to me.
Who is he?
He's the same as you.
You take turns reading to him
on different days, don't you?
That boy is also one of them.
He is the "Thursday Boy."
Why didn't you tell her that
you were the real one?
I've been sent to live with
many foster parents.
There were good ones and bad ones,
but the ones I have now
really take care of me.
I feel that I could never thank them enough.
But I've always felt that I
needed to meet my real parents.
I wanted to know how low
my real father was...
so that I could love my
current parents with all my heart.
That was it.
Have you ever seen the "Thursday Boy"?
I have Thursdays off, so...
Once I went to get something
I had left behind, though.
Did you see him?
What did he look like?
He was blonde and had a handsome face...
Monday
Who is he?
Who is the "Thursday Boy"?
There's a boy here pretending to be me.
Got it? Listen to what Momma
has to say to you.
Take this money and get on the fifth train line.
Get off at the eighth station. A lady
named Marta will be there.
What about you?
I told you that I can't go with you.
Are the police chasing you?
I want to be with you.
If you stay with me, you'll be put
into an orphanage.
If you stay here, people will call
you the son of a whore.
So hurry.
My father is Hans George Schubert.
Who did you hear that from?
Mrs. Bella from across the street said so.
He's rich, isn't he?
She said that I was abandoned by my father.
You weren't abandoned.
Then I'll go see him.
You can't now.
Then when?
When you grow up.
If you want to see him, see him then.
But you mustn't want anything from him.
You must not hate him if
he treats you coldly.
Why?
Because I don't hate him.
Take this.
Your father gave you this
when you were born.
Karl!
I figured it out!
I figured out who the "Thursday Boy" is.
His name is Edmund Fahren.
He's a philosophical literature major.
He reads books to Mr. Schubert
as a part-time job on Thursdays.
Edmund Fahren.
This is it.
The lecture just ended for this classroom.
Excuse me.
We'd like to see Edmund Fahren.
Is Edmund here?
Edmund? He didn't come today.
That's what they say.
Really...
It's too bad.
But it's only a matter of time.
We'll catch that imposter.
You're the one who should
inherit Schubert's fortune.
That's not true.
Huh?
I don't care about the inheritance.
But...
I don't care how much money
he cons out of him.
I just...
You just...
I just can't forgive Edmund Fahren for
calling himself my mother's son.
Tuesday
The petals of your silk flower
petals flutter in the wind,
and a mocking bird sang in my heart.
You haven't said anything today,
Mr. Schubert.
Why didn't you quit after I
yelled at you so much?
Was the money that good?
That's not it...
No, it's not that.
Can you talk about anything but money?
Just as you said.
Where are your parents?
I have foster parents.
I see.
Forgive me for asking, but do you
want to meet your real parents?
The truth is...
It seems the boy who appeared
this time is the real thing.
He doesn't want money.
He?
Sorry. I was talking to myself.
You can go home.
I forgot to mention...
Your Latin's gotten better.
Thank you.
Wednesday
It seems like Edmund Fahren
is absent again today.
He must have caught a cold.
Either way, tomorrow is Thursday.
He'll show up for his job
with Mr. Schubert.
I see. He'll show his true
colors in front of Mr. Schubert.
We'll get him... We'll get him good!
Thursday
He hasn't shown up. It's been an hour!
If he caught a cold,
he might be staying home.
Hey, do you want to give
him a surprise visit?
You went so far as to look
up his address already?
204, 204, 204.
This is it.
Well, go on.
Friday
How horrible.
Everyone's talking about Edmund Fahren.
They can't believe he committed suicide.
His last testament is in the
school paper, right?
"I can't pretend any longer."
He's talking about...
Yeah, after pretending to be Schubert's son and becoming
close to him, he was consumed by pangs of guilt.
If he was going to be troubled so much that he would
kill himself, he shouldn't have done it in the first place.
Lotte.
Yesterday was quite a ruckus, wasn't it?
Yes, it was. We were questioned
by the police all day.
My reading was called off today.
Mr. Schubert was very troubled by the news.
Karl, I'll introduce you.
This is the Friday reader.
Nice to meet you.
Hi. I'm Karl Neuman,
a business management major.
I'm a law major, Johan Liebert.
The Secret Woods