Here, here!
Wait!
Double Ranger Kick!
Hey! That's not fair...
You should fall down if you get kicked.
The evil emperor who plots world conquest...
cannot be defeated that easily!
You know that at the end of those TV
shows the bad guys always lose.
Is your world conquest coming along smoothly?
Johan...
He won't go down, no matter what!
But you know, the hard part comes
after you conquer the world.
What kind of world do you plan to build?
I don't know anything about that.
I guess I'll leave it messed up.
What?
It sounds more fun if you're
just going to mess it all up.
I'm quitting the Rainbow Rangers
and joining the Evil Organization.
Shall we all head back?
Okay.
Let's head back now.
Don't forget anything.
Okay!
Just One Case
It's gotten warmer lately.
You're right.
How's Rosemary?
She didn't catch a cold this
winter, did she?
Yes, she did. She was running around
with her friends outside.
She always did get a bad
fever every winter.
Yes, it was around this time...
We took her to the doctor in
the middle of the night.
You carry around an album of her pictures?
Yeah...
She must have grown so much.
Since she's still growing, I wonder if her face has
changed in the little while that I've not seen her.
But I have confidence that,
no matter how old Rosemary gets,
I'll be able to recognize her instantly.
Oh, yes.
When the time comes,
please show this to her.
It contains copies of the report
and newspaper clippings...
from when I shot the young boy, the
perpetrator of the serial killing.
I'm not telling you to explain
things clearly to her.
It's a fact that I killed a person.
I'm not trying to defend myself.
I just want her to know the truth.
I understand.
I wonder... when I can see her again.
I'll ask her again...
whether or not she wants to see her father.
R-Really?
I'll be waiting for your call.
I'm home every night by nine o'clock.
Richard...
You've really returned to how you used to be.
What?
Those youthful eyes that you had when
you were a rookie detective...
Yes, much like the time when we first met.
Is that so?
So how about it?
Offenbach
Hesse
There are benefits if you sign up now.
The thing is, we're already signed up
with another insurance company.
I'm begging you here, Mr. Liebert.
The insurance we have now is enough.
We don't have the extra money to
pay for more insurance.
We got our insurance right when
we moved here four years ago.
Four years ago?
Where did you live before coming here?
In Brunt치l, near Mannheim.
Brunt치l? That's a nice area.
Were you born there?
Yes, we lived there up until we moved here.
By the way, ma'am, do you have any kids?
Yes. My son is currently at the
University of Munich.
Oh? He's a college student?
If that's the case,
then I have the perfect policy for
a young man like him.
Please listen to what I'm offering.
Is this your son?
He looks like he was a cute one.
What is his name?
Johan.
Would you like some tea?
Oh no, please don't bother.
Ever since he went to the
University of Munich,
we've only gotten a call from
him once in a while.
Boys are like that.
Sad, huh?
I went there, Dr. Reichwein.
Yes, to Johan's family.
Well, it was a family just like any other,
with absolutely nothing out of the ordinary.
So what do you think, Richard?
Well, from my analysis as an ex-detective,
the more ordinary something seems,
the more suspect it is.
I see.
In any case, I'll continue investigating
Johan's surroundings.
Something...
There's got to be something.
At the gymnasium that Johan
attended, he had a reputation...
of being a good student with
good grades and conduct.
But I have confidence that...
no matter how old Rosemary gets,
I'll be able to recognize her instantly.
I can't imagine how that baby's face
can become Johan's adult face.
Brunt치l City Hall
This is the birth certificate.
Thank you.
Johan Wilhelm Liebert.
Born on February 9th, 1976.
He was indeed born in this city.
There's absolutely nothing out of the ordinary...
Mr. Hertz!
How many times do I have to tell you?
There's no smoking in the City Hall!
Don't be like that... Go get me an ashtray.
No way!
You remember that there was a
fire here four years ago, right?
All the paperwork was destroyed.
It was a big mess.
Did you guys redo all the
paperwork back then?
Y-Yes...
The paperwork was redone according
to individual request,
but since this is such a small city, most
of the paperwork was restored.
Ah, thanks for coming, Dr. Gillen.
It's been a while, Dr. Reichwein.
Dr. Tenma went to you and told you he
was looking for a man named Johan?
Yes.
There was no basis for his story.
But if this person was indeed the
friend who led the serial killer...
Peter Jurgens, whom I was researching, astray,
then it would be a breakthrough for all the cases.
I'm counting on you, Dr. Gillen.
Yes, I'll get permission to see
Jurgens as soon as possible.
Depending on how he reacts to this photo,
we might be able to prove
Dr. Tenma's innocence.
He died?
Yes.
The real Johan, who was born in
Brunt치l, died when he was two.
So you're saying that the Liebert couple
used the fire as an opportunity...
to reissue documents that said
that he was still alive?
Probably.
Then the person who's called
Johan Liebert is...
Who the hell is he?
In any case,
as I told you before, I gave
Johan's photo to Dr. Gillen.
Hopefully an answer will come out of that.
How about some food?
Sorry, but I have to get back.
What? You've been running around all
day and you still have work to do?
No, that's not it.
It's just that I may get a phone call.
I may be able to see my daughter.
Oh?
I'll be fine.
The important thing is to move forward, right?
Excellent, you've made a full recovery.
Yes! Hello?
Dad? It's me...
Rosemary...
Yes, I'm fine.
Yes...
Meet?
We can meet... anytime you want.
Mr. Richard?
It's Johan.
It's about this young boy, Jurgens.
Do you recognize him?
Might you have met him before?
I don't know him.
You mentioned that your friend, Johan,
never met you personally,
but only wrote you letters.
Johan knew you pretty well, though.
Could I borrow a pen?
What?
Sorry, but I'm not allowed to
hand you anything.
A pen, please.
The park.
What?
At the park,
the day after I killed somebody...
"Let's stop this."
"Let's stop right here."
I thought that as I went to the park.
He had a lot of children with him.
Could you wait a minute?
I forgot to start the tape.
Can you start from the beginning again?
"You should come, too."
Huh?
"You should..."
W-What is it?
We met at Mr. Schubert's, right?
I'm Johan Liebert.
I called you many times,
but you never picked up.
That's why I came to see you.
Hello?
Dr. Gillen?
How did it go when you showed
the photo to Jurgens?
He died?
Yes, he just died in the hospital.
Due to the police questioning, I
can't leave the hospital either.
Because of my negligence,
I gave him a pen, and...
an important witness has...
However, Dr. Reichwein,
his suicide was no doubt a
reaction to Johan's picture.
As soon as the questioning ends,
I'll head over there.
Understood.
I'll contact Richard right away.
Richard...
A research paper for your university?
Yeah.
I'm researching the UN Convention
of 1989 on the Rights of the Child.
Would you like a drink, Mr. Richard?
No thanks, I'm fine.
I see that you've stopped drinking.
That's right...
It's because you were drunk when
you executed that young boy.
Am I mistaken?
N-No...
Although I was drunk at the time,
I did something inexcusable.
That's what I'd like to ask you about...
The young boy you killed,
Stephan Joss, seventeen years old...
What crime did he commit?
A young boy, eh?
That seventeen-year-old "young boy"
committed such horrible crimes...
Nine rape-homicides and two homicides!
And that's why you executed him.
It wasn't an execution!
Oh, I'm sorry.
Incidentally, you know that under Article 40 of
the UN Convention on the Rights of the Child,
a child is "innocent until proven guilty," right?
Yes, I do know that.
I was once with the Juvenile Division, too.
I see.
Then you know that under Article 37, a person
under eighteen cannot be executed...
or sentenced to life in prison for
crimes that they've committed.
Most of the Convention consists of basic rights
that are granted to all in this country,
be it a child or an adult.
My shooting him was not an execution.
It was a mistake caused by alcohol.
I know I did something inexcusable.
And I'm now being sanctioned by society...
Okay, okay, please wait a minute.
I wanted to meet you for my paper.
If I've offended you, I apologize.
Why don't we take a walk to change the mood?
I'd like this whiskey, please.
After all, the winds at night are chilly.
Ah, Dr. Gillen?
I still can't get a hold of Richard.
He told me he might be able to
meet his daughter, but...
I don't think he's out meeting
her this late at night.
In any case, please tell him to be
careful when you reach him.
I'm heading over there now.
Do you know Stephan Joss's record?
If I remember correctly, when he was young,
he was in an East Berlin orphanage.
You need to know more about him.
Huh?
It's important if you want to know
where he's coming from.
The orphanage he was in...
It was a horrible place.
He was truly a nice boy.
But no one knows what kinds of horrible things
happened to him at that orphanage...
or just how badly his spirit was destroyed.
Convention on the Rights of the Child, Article 6,
the right to life, and guaranteed
survival and development.
Article 8, the right to preserve one's identity.
Article 19, protection from child abuse.
No, those things were not provided
for them in that hellish place...
at 511 Kinderheim.
Will you be able to meet your daughter?
H-How...?
How did you know about that?
Was that your daughter on the
phone back at your place?
Will you be able to meet her?
Tomorrow?
What is it?
What's your purpose?
To write a paper for my university.
Not that!
Your purpose for being with Schubert now!
Who...
Who are you?
You said you shot the boy
because you were drunk, right?
Before that, answer my question!
It's true that on that day, you were seen drinking
in a bar after shooting that young boy.
But something's amiss.
According to my research, there wasn't a single person
who saw you drinking before you shot that young boy.
Could it be possible that you weren't drunk
when you shot that young boy?
Wha...
You were sober.
You were calm.
You calmly pulled the trigger because
you wanted to execute him.
Am I mistaken?
You're wrong!
Why are you trying to forget?
Or are you just lying?
Are you just lying to others...
or just to yourself?
Did you confirm that young boy's crimes?
Did you have the right to execute him?
Do you think that just by pretending,
your sins would go away?
What a heavy sin.
How can one who has committed such a sin... meet his
daughter as though he's made a complete comeback?
How about it?
Will you have a drink?
Gillen?
Is that you, Dr. Gillen?
This is the police.
Your patient, Richard Braun, is dead.
Decision