Go on. Eat up.
The white sausage is great here.
How is it? It's delicious, isn't it? It's Dieter, isn't it?
If you don't eat, Dieter's going to eat it all.
Don't worry, Dr. Tenma.
It's safe here. Only regulars come here.
If someone new came,
Otto would throw them right out.
Because I only have people like you
here, business does not improve.
Who ordered the Spetzel?
That was me.
I've prepared a bed in the attic.
If you can stand the rats, you can rest there.
Thanks, Otto.
He might seem a bit unsociable, but
he's got a good side to him, too.
Eat! You can't go on an empty stomach.
Thank you. You've even gone so
far as to arrange a room for me.
I'm the one who should be thanking you.
If you hadn't saved me, I'd be in the morgue.
I feel more alive eating this great food.
Oh, I'm so full.
I've contacted Dr. Gillen.
He's relieved that we've found you.
He left a message for you in a newspaper ad.
"Let's discuss our memories of cheating."
You knew about it?
Yes.
Then why didn't you contact him?
I didn't want to draw him into this.
Don't be silly.
The thing we need the most is friends.
So, you said that you were watching over me for some time?
Because of the incident with Richard Braun.
Richard?
When he was on the police force, he
shot a young serial murder suspect.
When I was reading that newspaper article,
Dieter saw the boy in the photo.
He was in 511 Kinderheim.
511 Kinderheim?
An orphanage in East Berlin.
A special one.
Dieter's foster parent was originally a teacher there.
Was there something about that orphanage?
Johan was there, too.
So the boy that Richard shot and Johan
might be connected somehow then?
I don't know.
I came here because I wanted to investigate that
in more detail, but now Richard is dead.
At the cemetery, I saw you in front of his grave.
It's as if Richard brought you to me...
You've hung in there for so long by yourself.
But now you're not alone.
I will prove your innocence.
Johan is just in front of our eyes.
The photo... Huh? What happened to it?
I must have left it in the office.
I thought we'd know everything once
I'd shown you Johan's picture.
Probably, the man who came to kill you...
Was ordered to destroy it...
That man's name was Hesse.
His wife had been coming for counseling.
I looked at his contact information and found
out there wasn't anyone named Hesse.
Johan is right in front of our eyes.
And if he's so close, that means we'll meet him.
We'll meet him face to face...
We'll meet Johan...
In Broad Daylight
Tahlbach & Schubert AG...
That company was the center of Schubert's financial world.
Schubert, who usually didn't appear
anywhere, began to show up again.
At about this time of the morning, he used to inspect
the companies that he was involved in.
That's what Richard found out.
Not only this company, but all of his financial groups
came here and greatly improved their earnings.
Ever since that certain boy became his assistant, that is.
Here he is.
The one in the wheelchair is Schubert.
The one pushing him is Karl.
And...
Well, is it him?
There's no doubt.
Good.
It's the first time...
It's the first time I've seen him in broad daylight.
That's right. We'll bring everything into broad daylight.
It has to be now.
That's right!
We have to prove your innocence now!
But for now, we should go hide in Otto's attic.
We'll clear your name soon.
Richard's file is around here somewhere.
There it is.
I'm glad I brought this home.
We're almost there.
We're almost there, Richard.
Your revenge will be complete when
we find one more person.
We're right on Johan's heels.
I've found Dr. Tenma, a key witness.
All that's left is...
We need to find a witness from
the night of Richard's death.
There's got to be one.
We just need someone to verify that Johan
was the one with Richard that night.
If we can't do that, there's still the student, Farhen, who
claimed to be Schubert's son, and committed suicide.
If Johan was the young boy who went
with him to see the prostitute,
and if we could find that prostitute, we'd be able to prove it.
That's not all.
If we find the people who said they were Johan's parents,
we might be able to find out exactly who Johan is.
After all, I found the grave of Johan Liebert.
We've got Johan right where we want him.
Say, Dr. Tenma.
When I look at you, you remind me of Richard.
It looks like you're fighting for all the justice in the world,
but you're not alone.
Dieter is with you.
So is Dr. Gillen, too.
And so am I!
It's okay. Sleep well tonight.
I didn't want to drag him into this.
It's the first time...
It's the first time I've seen him in broad daylight.
It has to be now.
You're...!
Hurry, run away!
Now!
Hello, this is Reichwine.
Doctor, it's Gillen.
Oh, actually, I was just about to call you.
I'm on my way there now.
Where's Tenma?
He's at the hideout I mentioned before.
Tell him not to leave!
Something's wrong...
I felt there was something wrong.
Dr. Tenma isn't chasing after Johan to clear his name...
I was worried about that, too.
Dieter...
Why are you here?
Tenma told me to come here.
Where's Tenma?
He left.
Where d he go?
He's going to do it.
Huh?
Tenma's going to do it.
Stop him.
Mr. Reichwine, stop him.
Tenma...
He's going to become a murderer.
Let's quit here for today.
Don't say that. Please listen to me, Doctor.
It gets interesting here.
I'd like you to take your time telling me the next part.
The third woman I killed was the best.
Come on, Doctor.
Listen to me.
Do you have any idea what her voice
sounded like as I strangled her?
C'mon, Doctor. Listen to me!
Doctor, that woman...
Where did you go, Tenma?
So, we finally meet, Dr. Gillen.
Who are you?
I'm Lunge from the BKA.
I've heard the rumors.
Many of my research subjects were arrested by you.
I read your book as well.
Thank you.
It's a great book.
"A Summary of Abnormal Criminal Psychology."
There are no other books that go
so deep into the criminal mind.
Especially the 3rd Chapter, pages 262 to 294 on Heinz Kaul.
I had a deep interest in the discussion
that claimed that the trauma he
experienced at a young age led him to crime.
How detailed. I'm honored you read it so thoroughly.
My method of investigation is to
dive into a criminal's heart...
and walk through what he would think and do.
You have a lot of experience.
If you have some time, I'd love to talk with you...
Since we both don't have much free time, let me ask one thing right now.
You've been in Munich a lot lately, haven't you?
And what about it?
Please sit.  It won't take long.
You met with Dr. Reichwine, a psychologist, there
just the other day.
Yes, he was a great teacher I had in college.
At Dusseldorf University, right?
Yes.
There was a great brain surgeon that graduated from
Dusseldorf University at around
the same time as you, right?
What are you trying to say?
Did you meet him,
Dr. Tenma?
What are you talking about?
"Let's discuss our memories of cheating." --Rudi.
From May 1st until May 22nd, you printed this three
line ad in all the major newspapers in the area.
That's quite surprising.
I can't believe that such good students like you
and Dr. Tenma were cheating in college.
Great things, aren't they? True friends, that is...
We weren't really friends back in college.
Last year in May, in Oder Park...
With your cooperation, the Velbert police were just
about to arrest Dr. Tenma, but he got away.
That was because the bug I was wearing broke.
I think you helped him escape.
He, Dr. Tenma, is innocent.
I want you to listen with an open mind.
The three murders at Eisler Memorial
Hospital in Dusseldorf,
the murder of the patient in the building
that was under construction,
the murder at Heidelberg,
the murders of the middle-aged couples across
the nation were not committed by Tenma.
That's my opinion, as an expert in criminal psychology,
from my face to face meeting with Tenma.
I see.
Then, where is he now?
He's gone somewhere.
Why is he running?
If he's innocent, why is he running?
He's not running.
Why did he leave without telling
you? You're his friend, right?
I have proof that he's not the killer.
Take a look at this.
All of the case's information has been
gathered and analyzed here.
It must have been quite a lot of trouble to put this together.
Do you understand now?
Yeah.
The death of Farhen, the man who
pretended to be Schubert's son,
the death of the former police officer investigating
the case, Richard Braun.
The suspicion about Schubert having an illegitimate son...
The one in the center of it all is that young boy...
and that boy's name is the same as the name
of the real killer that Tenma spoke about.
Johan Liebert.
There is a person with the same
first and last name in Bruntal.
After the death of Richard Braun, someone
began to target Dr. Reichwine.
I understand quite well.
It's useless.
It's impossible to prove that all those things are related.
And because he knew that fact the best, Tenma left.
Am I wrong?
Those hand movements...
Don't pay any attention to that.
It's something I use to help me remember.
A psychologist like me would say that it's the physical
representation of the uncertainty in your heart.
I'm the same.
Instead of my hands, I play with this cassette recorder.
The information recorded in your hand
movements is by nature, subjective.
That's how you've done your work
for a long time now, hasn't it?
Your hand's memories are correct.
Your decisions were never mistaken.
What are your hobbies?
Do you live only for your work?
Have you ever made a mistake?
Are you horribly afraid of making a mistake?
To you, Tenma must be the killer.
If he's not, your identity will be destroyed.
Look at the truth.
This is a photo of Johan Liebert.
Can you prove that everything is just Tenma's lies?
This guy...
Where is this young man now?
He's a student at Munich University.
He's Schubert's secretary.
Can I have this photo?
This is police business from now on.
I might have made a terrible mistake.
Where is Dr. Tenma now?
He should be in Munich.
It's Lunge.
Send a message to the Munich Police.
This is a request for emergency police officer deployment.
Tenma is in Munich.
A sniper rifle?
I don't know what you're talking about.
You should have gotten a call from
a Mr. Heitmeyer in Fussen.
It'll be an advanced payment of 10,000 Marks.
I've got it right here.
Your order will be a bit hard to get ready
for you, so you'll have to give me a week.
You better toughen up before then.
If you pay a heap of money for something you can't use,
On to the next item of news...
The reception party for next week's Munich Electronics
Fair was held today by the Chamber of Commerce,
and was attended by many leaders of the financial world.
The News Media Network, which is involved with the EU,
is now supported by Bayern's industry.
This will be a large-scale convention as never seen before.
Furthermore, at this reception a man who has not
been seen in public for the past twenty years,
Harts Georg Schubert, attended and
received a unanimous welcome.
Although Schubert was in a wheelchair, he looked healthy and had great appeal with the financial leaders.
Sanctuary