Hi, Karl.
Hey, Lotte.
Do you have some time right now?
Not really. What is it?
I was going to see if you'd like to get some
tea and talk about Mr. Schubert.
I don't care about that anymore.
But...
Sorry, I'm in a bit of a hurry.
There's a meeting my dad needs to chair.
See ya.
About the upcoming dance party...
I thought that we could...
go together.
Sanctuary
We're closing up soon.
Okay
We're closing for today.
That girl's here again.
She's so pretty.
She probably has nothing to worry about.
But she...
It's closing time!
Got it!
Geez!
Where have I seen her before?
Dance party?
It's not really my taste, but my friend made me buy them.
I'm sorry. I can't tonight.
There's a state congress dinner meeting.
It's not just an ordinary dinner meeting either.
I'm sure you'll have no problem finding
a date for the dance party.
Bye.
I didn't really want to go anyways.
Are you...?
Huh? Are you looking up info on Margot Langer?
You don't need to hide it. I'm investigating her as well.
It's for a college report.
I'm a cultural anthropology major, Lotte Frank.
What's your name?
You're quite impressive, Ms. Nina Fortner.
This is about the accountant murder.
This is a newspaper article about
the "Voice of God" murders.
And this is about the murders of the middle-aged couples.
You're amazing.
I have confidence in my ability to gather information,
but you definitely beat me this time.
I'm looking into all the unsolved murders
in the Bayern area in the last 4 years.
Could you tell me everything you know about the
murder of Margot Langer, the ex-prostitute?
I've already told you all I know.
The child of Margot Langer and Hans Schubert was
joyously reunited with Mr. Schubert, the millionaire...
and has become his successor.
Is there a possibility that the son is involved
in the incidents surrounding Mr. Schubert?
No. I'm 100% sure he's not involved.
I see.
You're really into this.
You're in this pretty deep for just a college report.
W-Well, maybe.
This isn't for a research paper at all, is it?
The truth is I'm looking for someone.
Can I ask you a question?
Does a person like you even have anything to worry about?
Huh?
Everything goes just how you want when
you're as pretty as you are, doesn't it?
What are you trying to say?
You probably have no love problems at all.
I'm sorry. I shouldn't bother you with my problems.
God is so unfair.
Do you want to hang out with me
tonight? There's a dance party.
I'm not really used to places like this.
Don't talk like that. If I'm with
you, everyone will talk to us.
See look. Everyone's looking this way.
I'll just take your leftovers.
Jeez! Lotte!
Hi!
See! Here's one now.
I'm Constantine from the Supernatural Phenomenon
Research Group. Nice to meet you.
Oh my, a weird one has come over.
I can't believe a guy like him has
the balls to approach you, Nina.
Excuse me, Lotte.
Would you be my dance partner tonight?
Me?
What do you mean?
Way to go, Lotte.
I'll just excuse myself.
Wait, Nina.
He's not my type.
Not at all!
Let's leave together, Nina.
Geez!
I don't think we fit in here.
Yeah, you're right
What's with that?
Tons of guys have come up to you.
You've been cold to every one of them.
I haven't been trying to.
But it's been so long since I've had fun.
All the students are gathered here and having fun.
It's really been a long time since I've
been around something like this.
Nina, are you...
Huh?
Nothing.
You're just very different than you look.
What do you mean by that?
Hey, Lotte. I begging you, dance with me.
He's here again! He's a persistent little bugger.
Just for a while. C'mon!
He's drunk this time, too!
No, let go of me!
Get serious!
I'm not asking you because I like you.
What's with you? You're so rude!
Come on! One dance.
No, stop!
I can get my money then.
Money? What do you mean?
Stop asking questions. Karl asked me.
He asked me to be your partner.
Karl asked you?
Just dance with me a little bit. That's all I'm asking.
Stop.
Don't say that.
Stop!
Just for one song.
Ouch! I'm sorry! Stop!
Let's go.
I liked him.
I liked Karl.
I helped him search for his father because I liked him.
I liked him.
But when we proved that he was Schubert's real son...
"I have things to do with my dad."
"I promised my dad that..."
"Dad this. Dad that."
It hurts.
I hate it!
I never thought being ignored would be this painful.
It does hurt.
It all hurts.
But it's all right.
It's going to be okay.
Bad things can't continue to happen forever.
We can't let them continue.
Right?
I guess this is goodbye.
Tell me where I can get in contact with you.
Sorry. I don't have a place to live yet.
Then call me at home. Promise?
Sure.
It was fun.
I hope you find who you're looking for.
Nina... that girl,
I could have sworn I've seen her somewhere before...
She looks just like Johan.
You're pretty good, Doctor.
Although it's probably due to the accuracy
of the gun rather than your aim.
It failed the trials for the German Army, but it will
hit within 5 cm of where you aim from 300 meters.
Even if you can't aim.
I don't know what you're going to shoot, but
as you get closer, the accuracy increases.
The only thing after that is picking a spot
where nothing will get in the way.
The bullets are .338 Lapua Magnums.
It can hold four bullets, but you won't
have time to shoot all four.
It's the end for you, if you can't do it in one shot.
You come here everyday.
Are you bird watching?
Yeah.
There are a lot of visitors every week on Thursday.
That old man and those two young ones,
...and you.
Do you like this forest?
Yes.
Who are you?
Me?
I'm apologizing to this forest.
I have been for over sixty years.
Haven't seen him before.
What's with this? He just left that
food that we're so famous for.
Today, answer the quiz and win some wonderful prizes.
Our first contestant is Mr. Weindler from Frankfurt.
This is the prize!
It's an... RV!
Wow!
It's just what my family always wanted.
Mr. Weindler seems excited.
It would be great if his family could go camping with this.
But he needs to get ten questions right
or he doesn't leave with the RV.
Question number one!
Are you just going to go home without
touching your food again?
You came a week ago. I remember every customer's
face, no matter how many there are.
If you're not hungry, at least take the soup home.
It's on the house.
You look horrible.
Thank you.
That's the place.
I have to shoot him in this forest.
You saved me.
I can't believe I lost my footing after walking
in this forest for seven years.
I must be getting old.
I don't think anything is broken. I performed first aid,
but please have it looked at in a hospital as soon as you can.
Are you a doctor?
When I first saw you I thought you were
a hunter, but it seems that you're not.
What a surprise!
What's wrong?
The birds.
The birds are gathering here.
A long time ago, there was a man. The wild
birds would ride on his shoulders.
If he held out his hand like this
the birds would land on him.
When he was a child, he would always spend
time with the birds in this forest.
Then came the age of Hitler.
He belonged to the police force.
He truly believed that the National Socialist German Workers' Party
would bring prosperity to this country.
One day, he received some orders.
A vicious criminal was hiding out in this forest.
Since he knew the forest so well, he
was sent to chase after the criminal.
He was ordered to find the criminal and kill him.
He chased and chased the criminal through the forest.
When he caught him, the man he chased wasn't a criminal at all. He was just an ordinary foreigner.
He had no way of knowing beforehand
who this person really was.
And so he simply carried out his orders.
Ever since then, the birds have never
ridden on his shoulders ever again.
For over sixty years, he has been apologizing.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry!
But, the birds never came back.
What's this?
It's okay now.
Never again...
Never again will blood flow through this forest.
Isn't that right?
A Child's View