I was the one who saved his life.
I was the one who saved that monster...
This is it!
Did you figure something out?
Schubert's book donation ceremony!
Is Tenma there?
Dieter, you wait here!
Don't follow me!
It's Schubert!
I want to see Hans Georg Schubert.
Contact him.
Yes, sir.
If I'm not mistaken, he's at the University of Munich
for a book donation ceremony today.
We're heading there immediately.
Tenma is going after Schubert.
Nina!
Lotte! Thanks for coming.
I'm sorry. I looked all over for him,
but he doesn't seem to be here.
You and I just got to be good friends, too.
It's such a shame.
You guys, aren't twins are you?
I'm right, aren't I?
I'm right, aren't I?!
What is this picture book?
He saw this and suddenly fainted.
Picture book?
Kill... him...
A long, long time ago.
In a land far away, there was
a monster without a name.
The monster wanted a name so badly.
So the monster left to go on a journey to find a name.
But the world was so large that he
split into two to make his journey.
One went to the west and the other went toward the east.
The monster who went to the east found a village.
At the entrance of the village there was a blacksmith.
Mr. Blacksmith, please give me your name.
You can't give away your name.
If you give me your name, I'll enter
you and give you strength.
Really? If you can make me stronger,
then I'll give you my name.
The monster entered the blacksmith.
The monster became Otto the Blacksmith.
Otto the Blacksmith became the strongest one in the village.
But one day he said, "Look at me. Look at me. Look
at how large the monster inside of me has become."
Crunch Crunch!
Munch Munch!
Chomp Chomp!
Gulp!
The hungry monster ate Otto from the inside out.
The monster returned to being a nameless monster.
Even when he entered Hans the Shoemaker,
Crunch Crunch! Munch Munch! Chomp Chomp! Gulp!
He returned to being a nameless monster.
When he entered Thomas the Hunter...
Crunch Crunch!
Munch Munch!
Chomp Chomp!
Gulp!
He once again returned to being a nameless monster.
The monster came to a castle
looking for a wonderful name.
In the castle, there was a sick boy.
If you give me your name, I'll give you strength.
If you can cure this illness and make
me strong, I'll give you my name.
The monster entered the boy.
The boy became well.
The king was so pleased! The prince
is well! The prince is well!
The monster liked the boy's name.
He also liked living in the castle.
So even though he was hungry, he endured.
Every day his stomach growled, but he endured it.
However, he was so hungry that one day he said,
"Look at me. Look at me. Look at how large
the monster inside of me has become."
The boy ate the king and even his servants.
Crunch Crunch!
Munch Munch!
Chomp Chomp!
Gulp!
Since there was no one there anymore
the boy went on a journey.
He kept on walking for days and days.
One day, the boy met the monster
who traveled to the west.
"I have a name. It's a wonderful name, too"
The monster who went to the west said, "I don't
need a name. I'm happy even without a name."
"We just have to accept that we are monsters without a name."
The boy ate the monster who went to the west.
He finally had a name, but all the people who could
call him by that name had disappeared.
And Johan was such a wonderful name, too.
A Nameless Monster
So, you know about this picture book?
Can you read Czech?
Are you Czech?
I don't know.
What do you mean, you don't know?
I have a feeling...
I have a feeling... that someone read this to me a long time ago.
Who are you?
Are you really Nina Fortner?
Give me a straight answer.
Who are you?
I don't know.
You don't know? We're taking about you here!
There's no way that you cannot know.
Answer me! Tell me what this is about!
Why did I get such a horrible feeling when I read this?
The suicide of the student who called
himself Schubert's son, Farhen,
the fall of the detective that Schubert hired,
the shooting of the prostitute called Margot Langer...
After I read this book, it feels like all those weird
things that have been happening lately
are part of just one big clump.
Why is this happening to me?
Why do I feel like it's all connected to Johan somehow?
Sorry.
I just got excited all of a sudden.
That guy who collapsed after looking at that book...
Did he look that much like me?
Like he was my twin.
He looked just like me, like he was my twin.
Your friend, Johan, that is.
Where is he now?
He's at the university library attending a book donation ceremony.
Hey, w-wait, Nina.
Wait up. C'mon!
Today, this large collection of books being donated by the CEO of the Schubert group, Hans Georg Schubert,
to the East Munich University's Friedrick Emmanuel Library, has many books of extraordinary importance.
One may say that it's a literary treasure
of the German language.
We have a responsibility to preserve
this wisdom of humanity
for the next generation of students.
The head librarian of the Friedrich Emmanuel
Library will continue on from here...
Dammit.
If only I could pull the trigger, it'd be all over.
Move.
Please help me, Doctor!
I don't want to die!
Doctor!
Mr. Mauler!
I have to shoot.
I have to shoot him!
And now our guest of honor will take the stage.
- He's not just an important part of the Bayern
area economy, but a vital part of the EU.
- Watch. This is how you shoot a gun.
- He's not just an important part of the Bayern
area economy, but a vital part of the EU.
And by donating such a large collection of books, he has
done a great deed for our beloved Bayern once again.
I introduce him with great honor.
Ladies and gentlemen, Hans Georg Schubert!
You shoot a gun...
like this.
There sure are a lot of people here.
It seems he has got a lot of influence.
He's pretty popular, that Mr. Schubert.
Really.
And by donating such a large collection of books, he has
done a great deed for our beloved Bayern once again.
I introduce him with great honor.
Ladies and gentlemen, Hans Georg Schubert!
You're after me, aren't you?
There are many people here.
There were people swarming here to see you.
So that was it.
Unbelievable.
Don't make a sound.
Just shut up and watch. Got it?
I want you to listen to what I have to say.
I want you all to stay calm and listen to me.
I'm nearly blind.
I can't see how many people have gathered here.
You mustn't move all at once.
That's right. Just lie here quietly.
Watch what I have to do.
Make a single file line...
and carefully get out of here.
What's going on?
What's wrong?
The books!
They're on fire.
Put out the fire!
Hurry up!
What's going on?
My job was to shoot Schubert.
I see!
So you've changed your mind, Johan.
I like it better this way. It's much better.
They're all running around in circles,
like ants running from a fire.
This is great. It's great, Johan.
It's great.
Take a look at this.
The books... The books are burning!
They're all running around.
They're all scrambling to escape.
Can you feel it?
The fear.
I have to shoot.
You can't do it.
You can't shoot anyone.
I have to shoot.
You're Just a doctor.
You can only give people life.
Taking someone's life is my job.
You can't do it.
Yes... Gazing at what is known now in this world...
Yes... Your eyes believe in kindness...
Make it home... to your land of harmony...
Make it home... to your land of purity...
The Demon In My Eyes