The victims of the Friedrich Emmanuel Library
fire include five dead and thirty-four injured.
The official search continues for
those who are not accounted for.
I've taken interviews from those who were rescued, so please continue watching.
G-Geez, I didn't know what was
going on, there was a sea of fire.
When I couldn't breath because of the smoke,
I thought I was done for.
There was someone who saved us.
It was an Asian man.
Is that man all right?
He shot the hinges off the door with
his gun and opened it for us.
If it wasn't for him,
a lot more people would have died.
The authorities say that this fire was started with gasoline.
The police have announced that they will use all their
resources to find the culprit as soon as possible.
The Hell In His Eyes
Everything burned to ashes.
It might be the wisdom of humanity, but when
it's all burned, the books mean nothing.
Did you find any fingerprints on the sniper rifle you recovered?
It was burned in the fire, so I don't know if we can lift good prints off of it.
The gun's type is definitely the same as the
one we thought that Dr. Tenma bought,
a Mauser SR93.
But with everything burned like it is,
it's hard to find any traces of the culprit.
There are no crime scenes without clues.
Huh?
A cuff link was left here.
Take it to CSI.
Uh, sure.
Someone was there.
There isn't a person who can leave
this place without leaving a trace.
If someone can do that,
that person is not human.
If by chance, someone was able to do that,
then what?
Then he's a demon.
There's no such thing in this world.
Therefore, there's no criminal that we can't arrest.
Were you able to get an interview with Mr. Schubert?
Yes, he's in a hospital room.
He wasn't burned very badly,
but because of his age, they're refusing interviews.
Let's go.
Huh?
I can't let you do that.
I cannot approve of you meeting with him.
He's conscious, isn't he?
It will only take a moment.
Mr. Schubert is in a state of total shock.
He needs to rest for a while.
Who is he?
He's Mr. Schubert's son.
I'm sorry that your father went through so much trouble.
I am Lunge of the German BKA.
Um,
I asked the policeman here before, but...
I have someone I want you to find.
Who is this?
He's the man who tried to assassinate your father.
Huh?
Do you really not know him?
No, I don't.
But if it was him...
Him?
That's right. That's what I was trying to say.
Find him please.
Find Johan Liebert.
Johan...
Liebert.
Johan should have been at the ceremony with my dad.
But no matter where I search, I can't find where he went.
Johan...
Johan Liebert.
I understand.
I'll start the search for him as soon as possible.
This is the room that Johan Liebert was renting.
He left about two weeks ago.
His name wasn't in the law school's registry.
He wasn't a real student.
Have you contacted his parents in Offenbach?
They are gone as well.
They didn't know many of the neighbors.
Should we take fingerprints from this room?
Nothing's going to show up.
Huh?
No data available.
This is the first time...
The first time I've seen a room with so
few traces of a person living in it.
Yeah...
I am Johan.
I am Johan Liebert.
Who am I?
I was here.
But I don't exist.
A demon?
I'm so glad you weren't hurt badly, Nina.
I'm sorry to make you worry, Lotte.
That's right. I was really worried.
People were being rescued one after
another, and I didn't see you.
I wondered what happened to you.
You did well getting out of there
by yourself with those injuries.
You even surprised the firefighters.
I made it because someone saved me.
Someone saved you?
You were the last one to come out of the fire.
A Japanese man.
Is there a Japanese doctor at any of the hospitals here?
There are many Japanese people.
But they are all businessmen.
That can't be.
Huh?
Because he pulled me out from underneath a heavy curtain.
Nina!
That man was definitely...
there.
Just before the fire started,
you faced all the people seated at the ceremony
and told them to evacuate, right?
Why did you do that?
You knew something.
Am I wrong,
Mr. Schubert?
Can you end it there?
Do you know this man?
If I hold it this close, can you see it?
This is the man who tried to assassinate you.
Many people said that he was at the library.
According to the testimonies of the eyewitnesses,
he was trying to rescue everyone.
That's enough.
End it already.
If he remembers anything, have
him contact us immediately.
One more thing.
Do you know where your secretary, Johan Liebert, went?
Please, get out!
He was totally out of it.
I guess it's expected that seeing something so horrible
at that age would do that to a person.
That's the end of the financial emperor,
the man they called the "Vampire of Bayern."
No.
Huh?
Those were the eyes of a man who was fully conscious.
Oh?
Let's talk to some other witnesses.
Do you have a list of the victims?
Yes.
But what did you mean by that?
Testimonies that a demon like Tenma was rescuing people.
Is this another one of his personalities?
Nina.
Nina Fortner.
What about that name?
Nina Fortner was released this morning.
The address we had in the police statement was falsified.
What about the hospital records?
Sure. I'll go look it up for you.
Nina Fortner.
The name of the daughter of the couple murdered in Heidelberg.
Whereabouts currently unknown.
Thank you for telling me such a horrible story.
The story I heard from Tenma matches
up completely with what you told me.
Tenma?
That's right.
He showed up when I was working on a series of cases.
On that day,
I thought that Tenma was going to go through
with his assassination plot at that library,
and I ran after him.
By the way, that large fire...
We don't know if Tenma or Johan were there.
Got it, Nina?
Stop chasing Johan.
He's not an opponent that you can safely pursue.
I know the police aren't of much help.
You have to fight him slowly and carefully.
Someday the truth will be proven.
Don't worry.
You must be tired.
You should stay here and rest for a while.
He was there.
Eh?
He was there at the library back then.
Tenma was there.
You should eat something.
Thank you,
Dieter.
The bread is Kaiser Semmel.
Roast ham and gouda cheese.
It's Tenma's favorite.
Thank you.
It's good.
Really?
Yup!
When you eat good things, it makes you feel good.
Tenma always said that.
I want to see him.
I want to see Tenma.
Yeah.
The weather's so nice.
You're right!
When you get better, would you like to travel?
How about Asia?
It'd be a good change of pace.
Please take it easy.
You've fought enough, Dad.
Bridge...
Huh?
Three...
What is it?
What do you want to say?
Three...
frogs...
Huh?
His eyes...
Eyes?
I could see hell in his eyes.
Hell was inside the eyes of a living human being.
Karl.
Yes?
I have something I want you to tell a certain man.
Y-Yes.
That man is waiting in Dresden.
Dresden?
What do you want me to tell him?
Okay.
All I need to do is go to Dresden and tell him this?
Do I need to go soon?
I got it.
I'll go as soon as possible.
Karl.
Your mom...
She must have hated me.
No.
She didn't hate you at all.
Karl,
when you return from Dresden,
will you stay with me?
Yes.
I'm scared.
Scared?
Of what?
I don't really know.
But I'm very scared.
Remember.
Don't rush.
Just go slow.
A town out of a fairy tale.
A town in a fairy tale?
Where is it?
What did you feel when you looked at this picture book?
Tell me whatever you can. Just off the top of your head.
Dr. Gillen.
No, just a little more.
Stop!
Three...
Three frogs.
frogs?
What do you mean?
A picture.
A picture?
There was a picture in this book that
caused Johan to fall unconscious?
There's no picture of three frogs anywhere in that book.
Where did you see them?
That's enough.
Let's end it here for today.
Yes.
It was a mistake to ask that BKA man, Inspector Lunge.
Yes,
I think it's a good idea to change our plans.
The next time we try to bring any proof to the police,
we need to bring it directly to his superiors.
And that's only after we've taken the
time to thoroughly gather the data.
How much time do you mean when you say that?
We don't have very much information on Johan.
There are too many unknown parts.
I think that Mr. Schubert, who employed him
as his secretary, must have some information,
but he's still refusing visitors.
What about his son, Karl?
It seems that he left about two days ago,
and he hasn't been reachable since.
This is by no means certain, but...
A witness testified that an Asian man
was there trying to help people.
But if Tenma's fingerprints are found on the sniper
rifle recovered at the scene of the crime,
we can't help him no matter how much proof we have.
How long do we have to wait?
We're out of time.
By the time the truth is known,
by the time the police do anything...
it'll be too late.
Tenma will be...
Nina.
S-Sorry.
Nina,
I understand exactly how you feel.
I also lost a precious friend, Richard, in this whole case.
He had a bright future ahead of him.
But Johan took that future away from him.
I won't ever back down.
Ever.
So, let's eat.
Three frogs.
A town out of a fairy tale.
I know.
Dieter...
I'm coming, too.
What are you saying?
You can't come.
You're staying here.
Tell Dr. Reichwein, "Thank you for taking care of me."
Bye.
Dieter!
I want to see him.
I want to see Tenma!
Dresden
(Sachsen)
The third day and nothing...
He said wait in front of the station.
But its useless...
Father, it seems like I'll never see
the man you told me about.
Karl.
You're Karl, aren't you?
You...
The man who tried to assassinate your father...
Or that's what the police told you.
Yes.
I've been watching you for three
days from on top of a building.
It looks like the police aren't following you.
Can you let me hear the message?
Hang on.
Keep on your feet.
Go!
Get out of here!
The police are coming.
B-But...
Dresden...
wait in front of the station.
My son, Karl, will give you a message.
Hurry, give me the message.
Here.
Cedok Bridge.
Three frogs?
And then my father said this...
"If the monster you're chasing is a twin..."
Their mother is alive and is living in Prague.
Yes... Gazing at what is known now in this world...
Yes... Your eyes believe in kindness...
Make it home... to your land of harmony...
Make it home... to your land of purity...
Grimmer