A key...
A key and a card... number code...
The experiment data and a tape are in a safe deposit box.
A tape?
A tape of an interview with that certain young boy.
The monster who led 511 Kinderheim to destruction.
The Adventures of the Magnificent
Prague Police Station
It's this room.
Inspector Zeman, he's here.
Huh?
Inspector?
Oh.
Ouch.
This person was the first one at
the murder scene yesterday.
It's Mr. Grimmer, isn't it?
I'm sorry for making you stay all night.
I dropped my nail clipper under the desk.
When you're as big as me, you bump into a lot of things.
You're big, too.
Yeah. I bump into a lot of things.
My name's Zeman. I'm in charge of this investigation.
I'm Grimmer.
Go ahead and sit down.
Pardon me, but I was in the middle of clipping my
nails, so if you'd allow it, I'd like to continue.
Go ahead.
My wife's so annoying.
When my nails grow out...
She doesn't let me have any white parts that stick out.
Thanks to that, I'm always cutting them too short.
Yesterday was terrible, wasn't it?
Yeah, I never thought that...
I hear you're a freelance journalist.
Do you know his whole history?
Mikhail Ivanovich Petrov.
Real name, Reinhart Bierman, a German.
After the German unification,
he was charged with many counts of human rights
violations, internment and child abuse.
After the Berlin Wall fell, he fled
here to the Czech Republic.
The Germans wanted him arrested,
but the Czech Republic authorities left him alone and kept him under surveillance.
Surveillance?
Yes, in order to follow the movement of the unstable
element in the former secret police of Czechoslovakia.
Secret police?
You knew how scary the limitations of free speech
were during the Cold War, didn't you?
They even supplied weapons to extremist groups
all over the world for terrorist activities.
They were that kind of group, but in
order to make the talks of separation
between Czech and Slovakia go quietly, they
went underground without censure.
Petrov was in contact with that group.
He might have sold them the information that he had.
Ouch!
Look at that. I cut them too short again.
That's right. You didn't happen to see
a woman by any chance, did you?
A woman?
Petrov's killer was apparently a young woman...
and a fairly attractive one at that.
The children said they passed by
a woman in front of their house,
but I didn't see her.
I see.
Those children...
the orphans that Petrov was taking care of...
What's going to happen to them?
They're at the station for the time being, but
they'll all be taken to nursery homes.
I see.
It must have been hard for you to get involved in all this.
Not really.
Speaking of which, what information
were you trying to get from Petrov?
The many things that you just mentioned
that involved Petrov.
What did you learn from him?
I was just about to find out.
There, perfect!
Now my wife won't get mad at me.
Please feel free to leave whenever.
I'm sorry for holding you here so long.
No problem.
While he was dying...
did he say anything before he stopped breathing?
No.
Milslov, Josef... Where's Thomas?
Here.
So all three of you are here.
Then, get in this car.
C'mon, hurry up. Get in.
Next. Three for Vinofrady Nursery.
Honza, Antonin, Izzy.
Here.
It makes me sad.
We all just became such good friends
and now we're going to be separated.
But even when we're separated,
we're still under the same sky.
Someday we'll all be able to play soccer together again.
Cheer up, Antonin.
You were the leader, weren't you?
You can write letters to everyone.
That will keep them in good spirits.
Okay.
Yes, that's it.
Where are we going, Mister?
Hotel Kafka.
And before that Prochazka Bank.
To Prochazka Bank and then to the hotel.
I don't know Czech.
Can you speak German or English?
Today is a nice day, isn't it?
Why did you stop? We're not there yet.
Where will it be, Mister?
Drive me to the industrial district.
Hey, turn away other people.
Did you watch the soccer game yesterday?
No, I was busy.
Why are we so far from the city?
I want to go to a hotel in the city.
The key.
Huh?
The key!
What are you talking about?
What a trouble-maker!
Shoot him!
Stop him!
Are you all right?
I thought you might be in trouble, so I followed you.
Are you injured? Are you okay?
Inspector.
They're probably the former secret police I mentioned before.
Did they want anything from you?
No, not really.
I don't think they would go this far for nothing.
No, nothing.
You aren't hiding anything, are you?
N-No.
You must have some idea. They came this far.
I'm telling you, nothing.
So maybe he took it out of the safe deposit box already...
The tape...
the audio tape.
They're looking for the roots.
The... roots?
The roots of the monster.
Monster?
We'll know easily once we hear the tape.
We'll know exactly where the monster's
mother is in the Czech Republic.
Hello, this is Inspector Zeman.
Yeah, that supermarket robbery suspect...
Did he name any accomplices?
I see. Good job, Detective Suk.
Me?
I still have a few odd jobs I need to do.
I think I'll be back at the station in about an hour.
Bye.
If you don't stop there, he won't be able to speak.
Are you ready to talk yet?
Where's the key?
I don't know what you're talking about.
You little...!
Hey, wait.
There's no reason for you to hide it, Mr. Grimmer.
Where's the key to the safe deposit
box that Petrov gave you?
I told you, I can't give you answers to things I don't know.
I see. You want money.
Well then, let's talk.
How much do you want for it?
I might be a third-rate journalist but
I'm not so poor that I can't eat.
Mr. Grimmer.
This won't do. Your nails are so long.
Didn't I tell you? My wife gets annoyed about these things.
When your nails get too long...
Hey, it'd be better if you didn't move.
Or else I'll cut them too short.
Where? Where is the key?
Where?
Even if you opened that safe deposit box
and got the tape and documents...
you wouldn't be able to use them.
It only has worth in our organization's hands.
What we're trying to achieve is...
the resurrection of the Eastern world.
That tape has the identity of the monster recorded on it.
Our organization needs that monster.
If we have the monster, reunification is possible.
The reunification of the graduates of 511 Kinderheim.
We'll assemble the alumni of 511 Kinderheim,
the ones who were raised in former East Germany, to be the communist elite.
There is no group more elite than that one.
The monster is said to have controlled all of
511 Kinderheim and made it destroy itself.
He's the only one.
He's the only one to unify such an elite squad.
So where's the key?
An elite group?
What's so funny?!
What are you after?
If you want money, I can understand.
I'm a capitalist.
I'm just selling the key to make a fortune.
Why are you doing this?
For social justice?
No one would go this far for that.
Who are you?
You said you were a journalist from East Germany,
but most of those people are with foreign intelligence agencies,
so I wouldn't be surprised if you were a spy.
Where were you sent from?
Is this some 007 movie?
What were your orders?
You're going to die, you know.
This is your last chance. Where's the key?
Do you know of "The Magnificent Steiner?"
In the sixties, it was a cartoon that aired in West Germany.
You could see it in East Germany.
The main character was normally a weak, sickly man.
When he was in an emergency,
someone would come and help him.
A secret friend.
But, the main character never realized...
that his secret friend...
was actually himself.
When the main character was in mortal danger,
he'd transform into the terrible Magnificent Steiner.
When the main character came to his senses,
the bad guys would be defeated.
Then give it a try and transform.
C'mon, transform!
Throw some water on him.
He's about to cough it up.
It's just a matter of time.
What do you want?
Huh?
A woman came in...
One gun shot.
One dead body shot with the gun.
The other two dead bodies didn't have bullet wounds.
Was it "The Magnificent Steiner?"
He did it again.
Yes... Gazing at what is known now in this world...
Yes... Your eyes believe in kindness...
Make it home... to your land of harmony...
Make it home... to your land of purity...
Detective Suk