Where's the crime scene?
Under our feet.
Were there any victims?
Three men.
I want the perimeter around the
scene thoroughly inspected.
We were told to wait until Agent Kratkiy arrived.
I'll take responsibility.
Find suspects immediately. Move it!
Who should we detain?
Anyone suspicious.
But...
Can't you take a new detective's order?
Get going!
I'm Detective Suk from the Prague police.
This was pretty horrible.
Inspector Zeman.
He was violently beaten to death.
He doesn't even have facial features anymore.
If his police badge hadn't fallen nearby, we probably
wouldn't have been able to identify him.
The bodies of two men are over there.
We don't know who they are yet.
One was shot in the head.
The other one, just like the inspector, was beaten to death.
Preserve the scene.
Detective Suk.
So who are the suspicious people?
You've got to be kidding me!
They think I'm a novice and make fun of me.
The guys in uniform won't listen to my orders.
Well, the orders are coming from a very unreliable guy.
Yeah.
What did you say?!
You puked at the crime scene, didn't you?
Who'd want to take orders from such a lousy detective?
Just because you like police dramas doesn't
mean you have to be a policeman.
You've been frivolous even back when we were in college.
What do you know?
You don't know how well Inspector Zeman treated me.
He taught me, a novice who didn't know
left from right, how to be a detective.
I respected him from the bottom of my heart.
I promise!
I'll get revenge for Inspector Zeman.
If I have to find the killer by myself, I'll do it!
We have to get up for work early
tomorrow, so if you'll excuse us.
C'mon. Hang out with me a little longer.
While you're working in your safe
little jobs, I'm fighting for justice!
C'mon! Drink up!
Hey, quit it!
He worked every day for the sake of justice
and he ended up getting killed.
I can't take it.
It was all for nothing.
Huh?
What is it?
That girl was at the supermarket.
Huh?
I saw her twice at the supermarket
when I was on night-duty.
I wanted to talk to her, but I couldn't...
and now she's here!
Hey, you better stop now.
You don't have a chance with that babe.
Umm...
H-Hey, there.
Do you remember me?
I see.
But I recognize you.
I'm Jan Suk. I'm not a stalker or anything.
I might not look like it but I'm a detective.
Don't get scared because I'm a detective.
This is my free time, my private life.
I think this is a waste of time, but...
let's give him a hand.
Excuse us for butting in.
He's a bit depressed today, so could you talk to him a bit?
His boss, whom he respected, had an incident.
He's been doing nothing but sobbing like a baby.
I-I wasn't crying!
There aren't people as good as him.
I wanted to be like Inspector Zeman.
That's why I won't let the killer get away.
I'll catch him for sure!
Sorry, I've just been talking about myself.
Don't worry about it. You have to do your best and
catch that criminal for the inspector's sake, too.
I've talked about myself a lot, but I
haven I heard anything about you.
What's your name?
I don't know my...
real name.
Wh-What's with that?
Ah, wait a sec.
I can tell who you are.
I am a detective, so you can leave this to me.
Your name is...
I don't know myself, so there's no way you could know.
What I know about myself is...
...Cedok bridge and three frogs.
That's it.
Wait a sec.
When can I see you again?
I knew it wouldn't work out
Just give up on that daydream.
We've established the identities of the two men who were found dead along with Inspector Zeman.
Prauge Police
One of them is Cemistr Malat.
The other one is Yakov Sughachek.
They were part of the former Czechoslovakian secret police.
After communism collapsed, they were involved
in illegal underground activities.
The analysis of the blood at the crime
scene detected blood from
Inspector Zeman, Malat, Suchachek, and someone else.
The blood-type was AB, RH+.
From the amount of blood, we assume
that he had some serious wounds.
We need a description of him as soon as possible.
Detective Suk!
Suk!
Yes!
Why are you spacing out like that?
We've lost such a fine officer and we're all working hard on this case.
What's with your attitude?
I-I'm sorry.
Anyways, as I was saying,
the witnesses say that there was a man walking around the vicinity at the time of the crime.
He was tall and thin.
He carried around a large bag which
made him look like a traveler.
We have to use all our manpower
to determine who this man is.
That girl...
I guess she'll never come back.
Mr. Detective.
Did you find the criminal you told me about?
N-No. It's pathetic.
While I'm doing this, the criminal is wandering the streets.
Just the other day, Inspector Zeman was burning
the midnight oil on a murder case of his own.
What kind of case was it?
It's a case where an old man who ran an unlicensed nursery home
and the woman who helped run it were killed.
He was interviewing the first person at
the crime scene the very next morning.
Who was he?
Who was the first person at the scene?
Let's see. It was a kind-looking young man.
He was tall, thin and carried a large sack.
Huh?
Thin...
tall...
with a large bag!
Could it be...?
Do you know where that man is?
I-I think I do.
Maybe if I check at the station...
Hello?
Good luck, Mr. Detective.
Hello.
Hey, wait!
Hello?
Cedok Bridge...
Three frogs.
The Cedok Bridge is in the former town of Michalska.
Three frogs?
This is it!
If I come here, I can meet that girl.
He checked out?
When?!
Let's see. Mr. Grimmer, Grimmer...
He checked out two days ago in the morning.
I'm 100% sure.
The person who killed Inspector Zeman was the
person who was in this room, Mr. Grimmer.
Damn it! Why didn't I realize it sooner?
Inspector Zeman, I'll catch him!
I promise you.
S-Suk, why are you here?
Why are you here, Head Detective Patera?
I see. I'm amazed you made it this far by yourself.
I thought I was going to be able to take the credit for
the Inspector Zeman case, but you were here first.
Well, it's still quite an achievement. You did well.
Or that's what I'd like to say.
I'd like you to keep this a secret.
Huh?
Why?
It's our duty to arrest Grimmer as soon as possible-
There's more to this case than you think.
You don't know about the top secret investigation
that Inspector Zeman was involved in, do you?
Inspector Zeman was on a secret investigation?
He was to root out the former Czechoslovakian secret
police who were hiding in the Prague police station.
Former Czechoslovakian secret police?
The two men that were killed with him were with
the former Czechoslovakian secret police, right?
Very few people besides me and the
Chief of Police know about this.
If you get too involved in this, you might be killed, too.
Keep quiet about this one. Got it?
Wh-What should I do?
Let's see... Grimmer might show up at this hotel again.
Be on the lookout.
Y-Yes, sir.
By the way Suk, do you have a girlfriend now?
Huh?
You were spacing out while sitting
at your desk during the meeting.
N-No, she's not really my girlfriend.
She just shows up at a bar I go to from time to time.
She's totally hot isn't she?
W-Well, kind of...
Hey, introduce me to her. What bar?
Introduce you? I don't think I could do that...
You just said that she's not your girlfriend.
Th-That's true, but...
Suk's not coming today.
Wow! You really are quite extraordinary!
Who are you?
I'm Suk's senior at work. My name's Patera.
He said there was an incredibly
beautiful woman at this bar.
He's on a stake-out tonight, so he can't come.
Want to have a drink with me?
Huh?
Hey, wait.
Spending a little time with me won't hurt.
Hey, Suk!
Hey there, Detective Janacek. Good morning.
I heard from Mr. Patera that the
girl you found is a total babe.
Mr. Patera, did you go to that bar?
Yeah.
D-Don't tell me you put the moves on her?
Hey, Suk! Don't get so worked up.
But the rumors are that Detective
Patera has his way with women.
Don't worry. She dumped me.
If she doesn't fall for Mr. Patera
she must be pretty hard to get.
Th-That's not it.
I-I was just talking to her. Just that much was fun.
What are you grumbling about?
Section Chief Farobek wants you
to go to Inspector Zeman's room.
O-Okay.
Oh, yeah.
I got a gift. How would you like a whiskey bon-bon?
I don't need one.
How about you, Suk?
No, I'm fine.
Hey, Suk!
Yes?
You have to keep things about the tall, thin man a secret.
Yes, sir.
We've pretty much cleaned out Inspector Zeman's desk.
All that's left are his personal belongings.
Organize it and take it to his wife.
Yes, sir.
Huh?
A gym locker key.
This is horrible.
There's a bunch of sweaty shirts and towels.
Huh?
Documents?
What's this?
These are files that contain information on everyone
at the station, including their personal behavior.
Even my profile is in here.
You don't know about the secret investigation
that Zeman was involved in, do you?
He was to root out the former Czechoslovakia!! secret
police who were hiding in the Prague police station.
Huh?
What's the meaning of this?
How come only Head Detective Patera and
Detective Janacek don't have files?
This is not a normal amount of money.
Y-Yes, Chief.
So Suk, what can you deduce from this?
Yes. Inspector Zeman was conducting an
investigation of the people at the station.
Th-The results showed that Head Detective
Patera and Detective Janacek...
were members of the former Czechoslovakian secret police.
Then I'm...
Then I'm sad to say...
I believe he took money to conceal that fact.
That is a big problem.
It makes me sad to say it.
Detective Suk.
Yes?
You must keep this a secret for the time being.
Yes, sir.
I will contact you later.
Return to your regular duties.
Yes, sir.
Oh, man.
This has become more troublesome than I wanted it to be.
It was a mistake to underestimate a greenhorn like Suk.
We haven't even tidied up the matter of Zeman's
killer and now we have a bigger problem.
At this point, should we go for money just like Zeman did?
If that doesn't work out, we only have one option left.
At any rate, I want to avoid any problems that may
come from me knowing your past work's history.
I hope we can keep this all under wraps.
Man, I want a drink.
I have some whiskey bon-bons if you'd like.
Gee.
Don't say that.
I got them from that extraordinary beauty.
Here, take one.
What's wrong? You look really depressed.
I can't trust anyone anymore.
Why?
You can talk to me if you want.
I believed in him.
I never thought Inspector Zeman would do such a thing.
What happened?
I believed in him.
The only thing that brings peace to my heart right now...
is you.
Yes... Gazing at what is known now in this world...
Yes... Your eyes believe in kindness...
Make it home... to your land of harmony...
Make it home... to your land of purity...