Oh, man.
I hope we can keep this all under wraps.
Man, I want a drink.
I have some whiskey bon-bons if you'd like.
Gee.
Don't say that.
I got them from that extraordinary beauty.
What's wrong? You look really depressed.
I can't trust anyone anymore.
You can talk to me if you want.
I believed in him.
I never thought Inspector Zeman would do such a thing.
What happened?
I believed in him.
The only thing that brings peace to my heart right now...
is you.
An unbelievable and brutal incident has occurred inside the Prague police station.
Chief Hamlik, Head Detective Patera, and Detective
Janacek were poisoned and found dead.
What was the culprit's purpose in
committing such a daring crime?
Rumors talk of a connection between the Czech police
and the former Czechoslovakian secret police...
- Is there a possibility that larger scandals
are behind this incident?
- Hey!
- Is there a possibility that larger scandals
are behind this incident?
Someone's coming.
Do you know who the culprit is?
Is it true that the poison used was
some sort of muscle relaxant?
Is it true that even Chief of Police Hamlik
was connected to the secret police?
Well, that is...
Is there a connection to last week's
murder of Inspector Zeman?
W-We are still investigating that case, so...
So the investigation department is thinking
that at all the cases are somehow connected?
Well, umm, we will consider all possibilities and
from that we'll continue the investigation.
Excuse us, he is in charge of a different case, so...
Don't say anything unnecessary and get out of here.
Y-Yes, sir.
When will there be a formal press report?
Please wait until we have all the facts straight for you.
Your press report are always too late.
Come on.
You're here for data collection again?
I'm sorry,
but I was ordered by the higher-ups to
investigate this case from step one.
I've already talked to the other children who were taken in by other nurseries.
Think of the boys.
They saw Mr. Petrov, a man who was like a parent to them, and his female assistant die before their eyes.
Some of the children are still having nightmares.
I want them to forget about it as soon as possible.
Although, it's not something you can
ever forget even in a whole lifetime.
Someone they loved with their whole hearts was killed.
Fifteen minutes per kid.
Don't ask any questions that are too raw for them.
Got it?
Yes, living there was fun.
Mr. Petrov and Miss Anna were very nice people.
I see.
I'd like to ask you about the day of the incident.
Did you ever see the man who came to
visit that day, Mr. Grimmer, before?
No, that was the first time I saw him.
Why did he go there?
I don't know.
Were Mr. Petrov and Mr. Grimmer
getting along well together?
Hmm, it didn't seem like they were that close, but...
But what?
They were talking about something serious.
You kids know a little German, don't you?
What were they talking about?
He said, "This place doesn't have a license,"
and "I'll report you to the police."
Something like that.
Mr. Grimmer said that?
Yeah. He also said something about
"education" and an "experiment."
Experiment?
Anything else?
Something else...?
If there are things that you don't want
to remember, it's okay, Honza.
The other thing was 511 Kinderheim.
511 Kinderheim?
Do you know where that is?
No.
Do you?
There isn't a place like that in the Czech Republic.
About Mr. Grimmer... What kind of person was he?
He was a really nice guy.
You think so too, Izzy?
He played soccer with us!
He wasn't that good, but he looked like he was having fun.
He was so bad at heading!
He fell on his butt.
Honza's probably the next worse.
And then!
You were the leader there, weren't you Antonin?
I wasn't really the leader.
I was just a little older than the rest of the boys.
I'd like to ask you about that day.
About Mr. Grimmer?
Honza and Izzy said you asked them about Mr. Grimmer.
Y-Yeah.
So you were saying?
He's a good person.
You don't suspect him do you?
No, that's not it.
Mr. Grimmer isn't the culprit.
We were playing soccer with him.
When we came back, Mr. Petrov and Anna were dead.
We told this to the police before.
We saw her.
We saw a pretty blonde lady leaving our house.
Are you going to arrest him?
Arrest who?
Mr. Grimmer.
No, I haven't decided to do that yet.
We're going to meet him.
We promised. We even decided on the place.
Will you tell me?
Yeah.
Are you sure? We might arrest him.
I told you, he's not a killer.
Yo!
It's been a long time.
How are you guys doing?
We're doing great.
You didn't cry, did you?
He wet the bed twice.
I wet the bed much more than you.
Huh?!
Antonin, do you have what I left you?
Thank you.
You did a good job holding onto it
It's something important that I got from your grandpa.
Well, I'm out of time.
Take care all of you.
Let's play soccer, Mr. Grimmer.
I'm sorry, I don't really have the time.
I'll introduce you.
They're our new friends.
Okay! I'll play, but just for a little bit.
Hooray!
Pass!
Go! This is our chance!
Pass the ball!
It got stolen?!
Gotta dribble better than that!
Hold on, Defender!
Oh, man.
Here we go! Take that!
You're Mr. Grimmer, aren't you?
Did you come to arrest me?
You shouldn't go waving a gun around in front of children.
You throw me your gun first.
I'm not carrying a gun.
You tossed it?
I've never carried a gun before.
Are you the one who murdered Inspector Zeman?
I don't know.
I was tortured and half-dead.
Your nails!
I wasn't the one who shot that man with a gun.
I might have killed the others.
I don't remember.
Mr. Grimmer!
Why are you resting?
Our team doesn't have enough members now.
Give me a break. I'm completely exhausted.
I was the one who told them to invite you to play soccer.
I've been watching you for a while.
So, what do you think?
Do you think I'm a criminal?
I don't know.
I've been betrayed by many people in the last few days.
I just don't know anymore.
I don't know what to believe.
In the end, the only one you can trust is yourself.
The last thing you can believe in, is you yourself.
Aren't you going to arrest me?
Can you promise me you won't run away?
Where are you staying now?
Pavla Hotel, Room 302.
If you can confirm that I'm a criminal,
come whenever you like.
I'll let you hold on to that.
I think that it's the cause of this series of events.
It's the key to his safe deposit box.
Is it this signboard?
This is an old one.
It's the sign for a bar from over 200 years ago.
Even though the bar's gone, the sign is still hanging there.
The color is fading, but it's a landmark on this street.
A long time ago, many misfortunes
must have befallen this place.
But this sign survived.
It even survived the fire some umpteen years ago.
The fire?
A woman with a child moved into the second floor there.
She was very beautiful, but she seemed pretty gloomy.
She didn't come out much and
I heard she used a fake name.
One day, a black car came out of the blue
and took the woman and child away.
There were rumors that she was involved
with some anti-government activities.
A lot of people were back then.
Those were the politics of fear back when
communism was coming to an end.
It was a horrible age.
It wasn't odd for people to just disappear
off the face of the Earth.
Were the children she had with her twins?
No, there was only one child.
And the child had such a beautiful face.
Was it a boy or a girl?
Huh? Now that you mention it, I don't really remember.
When they're young, you can't really tell sometimes.
Everyone said, "I can't believe that they'd take
a mother, let alone an innocent child away!"
And then that place caught on fire.
A fire started when you'd think that no one
would be there, but that child was in there.
They must've released the child alone.
The child must have been hungry and tried
to light a fire in order to make some food.
That child was...
After the child was rescued from the fire,
they lost track of the child's whereabouts.
I don't know what happened after that.
What if that child was one of the twins?
Huh?
What if one of the twins was taken away and the
other one was left alone in that apartment?
I see. That is a possibility.
But why are you so sure there were twins?
About the person you told me to check out, Mr. Grimmer...
I don't think he's a criminal.
I see.
I'm sorry, Mr. Suk.
I wanted to help and ended up saying
something irresponsible.
He's not a bad person.
While I was chasing him, I learned many things.
At first, I was eager to avenge the death of Inspector Zeman.
But while I was conducting the investigation,
I learned that Inspector Zeman,
who I respected as a detective,
was in reality, corrupt.
And in the end, the chief and two
of my seniors were poisoned.
When I heard that they were poisoned,
I was dumbfounded.
I wonder how far the world of darkness
expands into this world.
Darkness?
The former secret police of Czechoslovakia are the ones
pulling the strings behind these recent events.
They were an organization under the direct control
of the former Ministry of Internal Affairs
that was the Iron Fist of the Soviet Union.
About ten years ago, during the democratic revolution,
the organization was dissolved and the officers
in the organization were put on trial, but...
many of them went underground.
Even now, many of them are plotting to regain
the great power that they once had.
That's all I know.
But why must there be so many sacrifices?
Are the secret police the only ones behind this?
I wonder how much darkness is spreading
in the world we live in.
I can't believe anything anymore.
But Mr. Grimmer said this to me,
"In the end, the only one you can trust is yourself."
When he said that, he gave me something.
I'm sorry.
I've only been talking about this one thing.
I don't even know your name yet.
Oh, it's okay. You don't have to tell me.
Until now, I didn't believe trust could be had
between people who didn't know each other's name and personal background.
But I can tell you anything.
My parents were both teachers.
But my dad was singled out by the authorities
for democratic activities.
My mom left him for my sake.
When I said I wanted to be a detective, my mom opposed it.
Why did you want to be a detective?
My friends said it at the bar before.
You were actually influenced that much by cop dramas?
It's been my dream since I was a kid.
I've always been a fan of cop dramas.
Bang!
Don't laugh so hard!
But it's funny.
So what did he give you?
You said before that Grimmer gave you something.
A key to a bank safe-deposit box.
A safe deposit box?
It seems there's something very important in it.
It has something to do with the case in which the German man,
Mr. Petrov, was running an unlicensed orphanage.
Yeah?
It seems that inside that safe deposit box, there's some
data from human experiments that Mr. Petrov ran.
It seems to be the cause of these series of events.
You can't tell them.
You can't talk about it to the police or anyone.
But, this isn't a problem I can handle on my own.
Your mother is...
Huh?
Do you know why your mother didn't
approve of you being a cop?
She thought that something might happen to you.
She just had a bad feeling about it
So you mustn't tell anyone about this.
I have the same feeling as your mother.
I'm sorry.
My name.
I'll tell you my name.
Anna...
Anna Liebert.
Anna, what a nice name!
So you're German.
I'll be seeing you.
Anna...
Good evening, Mr. Trunka.
It's such a nice night, isn't it Anna?
Oh, my. Good Evening, Anna.
Good everting, Mrs. Jalka.
So a safe deposit box key?
Yes... Gazing at what is known now in this world...
Yes... Your eyes believe in kindness...
Make it home... to your land of harmony...
Make it home... to your land of purity...
The Monster's Afterimage