This is the biggest scandal in the
history of the Czech police.
Regrettably, the three people who were killed
had been involved with the former
Czechoslovakian secret police.
With this case, I believe that the dark tendencies
in the Prague police have all been wiped clean.
Gentlemen, you are all proud members
of the Prague police force.
I'm expecting your actions to reflect the
embarrassment you feel in your heart.
Furthermore, as the new Chief of Police,
I'm going to make some big changes in
order to gain back the people's trust.
I'm going to introduce the special five-member senior
investigation team sent from the central office.
I want you to cooperate with them so that this
horrible incident can finally be resolved.
Detective Suk, is it?
Yes.
I want to express my deep gratitude to you as the
new Chief of Police for your investigation.
Thank you.
So what's the case you're in charge of now?
It's the case about the caretaker of an unlicensed orphanage that Inspector Zeman was investigating,
the Petrov murder case.
I see. Please continue your investigation and finish it up.
Yes, sir. Well, if you'll excuse me...
Oh, one more thing.
The tall man that is suspected of killing Inspector Zeman...
Do you know anything about him?
No, I haven't found out anything about him.
I see. You may leave.
Excuse me.
Jan Suk.
He's been assigned here for one year.
He had a close relationship with Inspector Zeman.
He exposed the hidden past of
detectives Patera and Janacek.
He had a meeting with Chief Hamlik just before his death.
Mark that man!
Yes, sir.
Hey, there.
I was very pleased to actually reach you by
phone at the place you said you'd be at.
Did you think you'd been betrayed again?
No.
Orange juice.
Mr. Grimmer, are you sure it's okay
to be in such a crowded place?
What do you mean?
The new Chief of Police hasn't taken you off the
suspect list for the murder of Inspector Zeman,
and the former Czechoslovakian secret police must be after you as well.
Or could it be that being in crowded places is actually safer?
There are no safe places.
Huh?
If they want to get me, they could do
it wherever or whenever they want.
For instance, they could do it from the
window with the red curtain up there.
Mr. Grimmer, who exactly are you?
No way. Why do you have to go through so much?
I guess I just step into things a little too deep.
That's nothing to laugh at.
They're coming to kill you!
It's okay.
I step that deep because I want to.
Suk is currently at a cafe in the Republic Square.
He's here.
That man he's with is definitely Grimmer.
Yes.
Should I continue following them for a little longer?
So you were collecting data on
the brainwashing experiments
that Petrov was performing on children in former East
Germany, and that's how you got involved in all that.
Yeah.
And right before Petrov died, he gave you
the key to a bank safe deposit box?
Yeah.
He said something about "The Upbringing of a Monster."
"The Upbringing of a Monster?"
I don't know what that means, but it
seems that a lot of people want it.
You mean the former secret police?
And a blonde woman.
The children at the nursery home also said that.
Just after Petrov was killed, they saw a pretty
blonde woman outside the house.
Do you have a clue who that could be?
I don't have the faintest idea.
Are you going to be okay?
You must be hiding the fact that you're meeting
with me from your higher-ups.
Are you okay betraying the police like that?
I'm not hiding anything.
This is part of my investigatory discretion.
After I'm done investigating, I'll give
a full report to my superiors.
If I search hard enough, I'm sure
I can prove your innocence.
What's wrong?
Don't look now, but to your left...
there's a man under a parasol reading a newspaper.
He seems suspicious.
The secret police?
Who knows?
Well then. Shall we go?
Go where?
Did you bring it? The key I gave
you to the bank safe deposit box.
Yes.
Do you want to know the true nature of a monster?
Then let's go do it.
Although we might be better off never knowing...
Haha! You look pale.
That woman is close.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
It must have been my imagination.
Suk is on the move.
I'll follow him.
I called you earlier. I'm Suk from the Prague police.
Please wait a moment.
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
It's right here. Please go in.
Here are the safe deposit boxes.
You can verify the contents in the room over there.
A data report and a cassette tape.
I have a tape recorder.
Are you ready? I'm going to play it.
Where is this?
511 Kinderheim.
A child's voice...
What is your name?
My name is Johan.
What is your last name?
I'll ask you again.
My name is Otto.
My name is Hans.
My name is Thomas.
My name is...
Which one is your real name?
A long, long time ago.
In a land far away, there was a monster without a name.
The monster wanted a name so badly.
Is that some kind of story?
I was waiting for Anna.
Who is Anna?
I was waiting for Anna... while I
was reading that picture book.
This boy is being questioned under the influence of drugs.
Where is your father?
I don't know.
Your mother?
I think she's alive.
You are quite an exceptional boy.
Are you afraid of anything?
What is the thing that frightens you the most?
I'll ask a different question.
Have you ever killed a person?
Huh?
Many people died.
So many that it seemed like Anna and I
were the only two people in the world.
Where was that?
I'll go back to the other question.
What is the thing that frightens you the most?
The monster inside of me is getting larger.
"Crunch Crunch! Munch Munch! Chomp Chomp! Gulp!"
That is the thing that frightens me the most.
That is it.
I feel sick.
I feel like I'm going to throw up.
Are you okay, Mr. Grimmer?
Yeah.
What is on this tape?
Is this "a monster's true nature?"
I don't understand it.
Even if we don't know what it means...
there are plenty of people who want to get a hold of it.
The former Czechoslovakian secret police...
It's the same if you listen to just the beginning
or if you listen all the way through.
You can't go back.
What are you going to do with that tape and report?
No.
Naturally, it'd be better to store the evidence here, but...
but you're going to hold on to it?
Then let's leave separately.
I'm the one they're probably marking.
Give me your cellphone number and your address.
If we both make it out safe, we can
get in contact with each other.
I made it home safe.
What a bad feeling.
He doesn't seem very reliable.
So? A flat on Lanover St, huh?
What's the meaning of this?
We're the ones asking the questions here.
You know about us, don't you?
You're from that special senior team that
was sent from the central office.
This is Detective Third Rank Novak,
and I am Detective Third Rank Zander.
Why are you in my apartment?
How long have you been meeting with Grimmer?
Don't tell us you haven't been.
You met him at the cafe in the Republic Square
then headed toward the Prochazka Bank.
Do you know the man in this photo?
Captain Karl Ranke.
He's a big-shot in the former Czechoslovakian
secret police who's gone underground.
I-I don't know that man.
We looked into your bank account.
There was a large deposit this month. What was it for?
Huh?
What are you talking about?
I don't know anything about that money.
Your mother is currently seriously ill at the
Krumlov National Hospital, isn't she?
It must take a lot of money to pay
for a hospitalization like that.
What are you trying to say?
After your mother divorced your
father, she raised you by herself.
You also think very well of your mother.
What are you trying to say?!
We'd like to search your apartment.
Do what you want.
I don't have anything to hide!
Zander, come here.
What are these?
They were in your washstand.
I've never seen these things before.
They're not mine.
We can't tell if there's a drug in it until we test it.
The muscle relaxant found in the dead bodies...
was inside whiskey bon-bons.
Let's go to the station for a little talk.
That's fine. Investigate as thoroughly as you like.
That's fine.
Excuse me, but could I change my shirt before we go?
Calm down. Calm down.
I didn't do anything wrong.
If I explain it to them, they'll understand.
Do I smell gun powder?
Suk!
Yes... Gazing at what is known now in this world...
Yes... Your eyes believe in kindness...
Make it home... to your land of harmony...
Make it home... to your land of purity...