Hey, Anna.
It's getting pretty chilly, isn't it?
What's with her?
She's not too friendly today...
Did you just get off work, Anna?
Nina!
All the restaurants in this area are already closed.
Let's go back to the hotel, Nina.
What's wrong, Nina?
The people who live on this street...
for some reason, they all know me...
They...
called me "Anna."
The Door to Nightmares
What's going on here?
Even though Suk, a suspected serial
killer, is hospitalized here...
there aren't any police officers or patrol cars around.
Yeah.
In any case, I'll go take a look.
No.
Either way, there's no point unless I go.
It's the same in here.
There's no sign of police anywhere.
Excuse me...
A patient named Suk should be registered here.
Jan Suk.
He's a detective.
A detective?
There were a number of casualties from
an abandoned building on Brno Street.
Oh, the one where a bunch of unemployed
men got into a fight?
Unemployed men?
A fight?
Yes.
We didn't understand what they said on the news, but...
I guess that must be their cover story.
So, which rooms are they in?
They were seriously wounded, but...
they were all transferred out after receiving treatment.
Transferred?
To where?
No idea.
An ambulance came and took all six of them away.
Six men attacked us, too.
What about Suk?
What about Detective Jan Suk?
He was shot.
We don't have any patients who were
admitted with gunshot wounds.
There's no record of an emergency patient
named Jan Suk being brought here?
No, there isn't.
Research documents and a tape
pertaining to 511 kinderheim...
Yeah...
Petrov, who was the former director of 511 kinderheim...
and operated an unauthorized orphanage in Prague...
entrusted me with them right before he died.
And who exactly is after them?
To tell you the truth, I don't actually know.
But the former Czechoslovakian secret
police definitely want them.
Where are the documents and the tape right now?
I don't have them on me.
They're being held at a certain place.
Because of them, Detective Suk was seriously injured...
and abducted from the hospital.
Those people...
Who knows what they'll do to Suk in order
to get their hands on what they want...
This is bad...
What do those things say?
The documents are full of research data with
technical terms along with a roster...
I didn't take a good look at it.
I only listened to the tape briefly, as well...
What was recorded on it?
The voice of a child...
A child?
He was probably interrogated after being drugged.
When asked for his name, he answered "Johan."
What's wrong, Dr. Tenma?
511 kinderheim...
Research documents...
Johan...
Where is the tape right now?
Would you please come with us?
Where is Suk?
Let's conduct business.
Would you please come with us?
I'm okay, but...
Dr. Tenma.
There's no reason for you to become
further involved in all this.
No.
I also have something I'd like to ask the
former Czechoslovakian secret police.
What are you trying to accomplish?
the problem now is whether or not
these people will actually talk.
I doubt you're inviting us to dinner, are you?
Welcome.
This way, please.
That man is...
Looks like he's a bigshot in the former
Czechoslovakian secret police.
Yeah, I looked them up at the newspaper agency.
He's Colonel Karel Ranke.
So the top man decided to come himself.
My deepest apologies for my subordinates
treating you so roughly.
Due to a miscommunication in our command structure,
we have an unexpected situation on our hands.
We are currently suffering from
a serious misunderstanding.
By you, and by society.
As if we're a group of killers.
Where is Suk?
He's been placed in a hospital where we have connections.
He has not been harmed.
That's some misunderstanding.
We did not kill anyone in this case.
What about that girl?
Girl?
Isn't that blonde girl acting on your orders?
We do have reports about her, but...
she has absolutely no ties with us.
We are extremely inconvenienced by her as well.
What we want aren't human lives.
A friend of mine in Germany wanted
those documents and the tape.
So we had cautiously approached
Petrov many times to negotiate.
And then he was targeted and killed.
Looks like there must've been lots of money involved.
Yes, this is a business.
I just want to talk business.
I would like to have the documents
and the tape in exchange for Suk.
I don't know where they are.
Let's avoid such talk.
Something like that must not be repeated...
If something like that existed in the world...
who knows what could happen...
Something like that must never be repeated.
Let us put aside that sort of talk for now as well.
It has nothing to do with this business negotiation.
Because I'm from that place...
Because I'm from 511 kinderheim...
How old are you?
When did you leave there?
Supposedly, when I was fourteen.
It was thirty years ago.
When were you put in there?
Who knows?
Probably when I was seven or eight.
Around 1963, correct?
I don't know.
Do you know this child?
He's my nephew.
In the early 60s...
I was officially stationed in Berlin as an intelligence
officer for the Czechoslovakian embassy.
I had a younger sister.
She married a German.
But she and her husband tried to defect by crossing
the Berlin Wall and they were shot to death.
And only that boy was left.
I signed them.
On paper, that place provided a wonderful environment.
An ideal, educational environment
where children with a past...
would be nurtured into the elites who would
shoulder the communism of the future.
I signed the papers that allowed that child
to be placed in 511 kinderheim...
I don't know.
I don't have any memories.
Anything that happened there...
or from before I went there...
I don't remember anything at all.
I don't even know my real name...
You're...
You're trying to change something so horrible into money.
You're even trying to sell documents containing
experimental data on your own nephew!
It appears we've gone off topic.
I would like you to think of this
as a beneficial business deal.
I understand.
You guys are free to go for today.
I hope for a positive answer.
Take them back with the utmost care.
What are you going to do?
Right now, the most important thing is to rescue Suk.
If you agree to his demands...
I believe he will release Suk.
Mr. Grimmer...
Cocoa...
I remember...
I remember!
Mr. Grimmer!
The cocoa he had once a week!
He looked forward to the weekly cocoa ration!
When I had a fever and was lying in the infirmary...
he brought me some cocoa.
His own cocoa...
Even though he loved it so much!
It was delicious...
I never had such delicious cocoa before...
So I wanted to do something to repay him.
Then he said...
He said to remember him.
Back then, it was popular among us.
We talked about ourselves to our friends.
We didn't really understand it...
but our memories were fading...
with the strange classes we attended every single day.
We were even in danger of forgetting our own names...
That's why...
we had our friends remember who we were!
He loved cocoa!
He loved to draw pictures!
And he loved insects!
But he didn't like to collect insects because
he had to kill them, and he didn't like that.
The most fun he had was when he went
into the forest with his parents.
He caught lots of butterflies.
But he released all the butterflies from
the bug cage on the way home.
His dream was to become an entomologist!
His...
His name was...
Adolf Reinhart!
That's my nephew.
Welcome back.
Don't hide things from him.
People....
can become anything.
Cheers!
Hey, welcome back.
What's wrong, Nina?
I...
I know this place...
The road leading to this place...
This scenery...
This storefront signboard...
I know it all...
Did you live here?
I don't know.
Just...
Just?
I'm scared...
You know this door, too?
I don't know...
But...
I'm scared, so...
These stairs...
I know them, too...
Mr. Grimmer.
I thought things over last night.
There's something I'd like you to hear.
Dr. Tenma.
Neither those documents nor the tape
have anything to do with you.
No, I'm also...
Doesn't seem like we have time to talk.
Looks like they can't wait for more negotiating.
The former Czechoslovakian secret police have
bothered to come all the way but here.
Were you able to think things over?
Yeah.
I have no intention of giving you either
the tape or the research documents.
You don't care what happens to Detective Suk?
If anything were to happen to Suk...
the tape and research documents would be lost forever.
Let's not start this kind of meaningless negotiation.
However...
I can let you listen to the tape.
On one condition.
You have to forget your business deal with
your German friend who's trying to buy it.
If you want to listen to it because of a personal interest...
then I'm willing to let you listen to the tape.
No...
You should listen to it...
for the sake of the nephew you
placed in 511 kinderheim.
You should listen to the voice of the boy named
Johan who was recorded on the tape.
Is that your deal?
I'm not making any deals.
Please stop this already!
We don't have time for this!
Even as we speak...
someone might be killed because of that tape.
How many people involved with your
Czechoslovakian secret police...
do you think have been killed?
Who do you think killed them?
It was the person who wants that tape the most.
The owner of the voice that was recorded on that tape...
Johan!
Dr. Tenma...
I have no idea what you're talking about.
Don't play dumb!
You must've learned what that tape
is from your German friend!
What did he tell you to get?!
"The true identity of the monster..."
That was all he said.
I didn't want to get you people involved...
But I'll tell you everything...
before more people are killed.
It happened ten years ago...
I see.
So Johan was tracing his own roots...
and came to Prague.
I don't know...
He may be trying to erase everything, instead.
Just what did you people do fifteen years ago?!
There was a family living near Cedok
Bridge in the Michalska district.
One day, they were taken away by the secret police.
After taking him away from the building
with the three frogs on its signboard...
what did you guys do to Johan?
These stairs...
Big brother...
What's wrong, Nina?
As if being dragged down these stairs...
he was taken away...
Who was?
My big brother...
It's true that at the time, I was in a position
to receive all the information.
But these three frogs...
And a family being taken away...
I have absolutely no recollection of that.
Don't pretend you don't know!
Of course, there was information that didn't reach me.
Like the things that man did.
I didn't know which division of the
secret police he belonged to...
nor did I know whose command he was under.
For some reason, he could detain anyone
freely without reporting to his superiors...
I wonder what he was doing?
Even though he was just a lieutenant...
he was given a luxurious mansion as his workplace.
Yes...
He was known as the "Man of the Red Rose Mansion."
You're saying that man was involved?
He was a quiet man with an extremely elegant demeanor.
He didn't wear a uniform...
and liked tea and cake.
What was his name?!
Franz Bonaparta.
Franz... Bonaparta...
However, I don't know if that was his real name or not...
since he also had a pen name.
A pen name?
He was also the author of a picture book.
Are you scared of this door, too?
I...
was reading a picture book in here, and...
Someone opened the door...
and came home...
A picture book?
Yes.
It was a very peculiar picture book.
The title was "The Monster Without
A Name," or something like that.
There's nothing here, Nina.
What is this... memory...?
I should have been reading a picture book in here, but...
the one who opened the door and came in...
was me.
I'm welcoming myself back home?
Welcome back.
Yes... Gazing at what is known now in this world...
Yes... Your eyes believe in kindness...
Make it home... to your land of harmony...
Make it home... to your land of purity...
The Scariest Thing