Shoot me.
So, are you ready?
There's no need to be nervous.
Your headband is crooked.
I'll fix it for you.
Smile.
There you go. You're so cute.
Now, let's hold hands.
Shall we go?
The other day, Mr. Liebert, who emigrated
from East to West Germany...
appeared before the media with his wife and children.
The Lieberts showed no signs of exhaustion...
and they, along with their fraternal
twins, a son and a daughter...
smiled brightly at the cameras.
Mr. Liebert, any opinions about the West?
Well, it's difficult to say.
It's just... now that I can freely express myself...
I can't find the words to describe it.
Oh, I see.
For now, the answer to that question...
lies in the smiles of my wife and children.
It seems that your children are
fully enjoying their freedom.
Yes, it seems that way.
Then, would you tell us how things really are in the East?
Brother, what are you doing?
Brother?
Pick a hand.
This one.
You're right.
This is yours, Anna.
Yay! An acorn!
Okay, let's do it again.
Which hand?
This one.
You're right again.
Here, this is yours.
Wow!
Brother, show me both of your hands.
Oh.
So I would've been right either way.
That's right.
That's because all the acorns here are yours.
Hey, hey, brother! Did you see...
the city from the car on our way here?
It's completely different from the other side.
There were a lot of pretty stores.
Lots of different clothes and toys, too.
Hey, you saw them too, right?
Yeah, I saw them.
They're all yours too, Anna.
Really?
Really.
Why are they all mine?
They just are.
I saw you on TV, Mr. Liebert.
Well, come in...
Brother, I wonder if someone's over.
Brother?
Brother...
Did you... do this?
All this time?
When Uncle Josef and Aunt Klara died...
When Mr. Bodecker died...
You did it all?
Today is special.
Did you do it?!
Because today...
a monster came.
You killed them all, didn't you?!
A monster came to take us away.
Put out your hands.
Shoot me.
After you shoot, wipe the gun with a cloth...
and throw it out the window.
Make sure you shoot me in the head.
After you shoot me, run.
Run, so the monster won't get you.
It's okay.
Even if I die...
I am you...
and you are me.
That night...
On that rainy night...
someone came...
Nina?
Someone came to that mansion!
Nina!
Who?!
Who came?! Who?!
A monster came.
Nina!
That Night
This is terrible...
How could this mansion catch fire?
No one was supposed to be living there.
They say it might've been arson.
That's so dangerous.
Dr. Tenma.
Could you please come with us?
General Wolf is asking to see you.
General... Wolf...
General Wolf.
Dr. Tenma.
Yes.
Just as I thought, you were summoned
as well, weren't you?
"I'm waiting at the Red Rose Mansion."
A letter from Johan.
Just getting to this hospital here in
Prague took everything I had...
So you also received a letter.
It's so ironic.
Now, only Johan sends letters to the man named Wolf.
You shouldn't talk too much.
I was born into a military family.
I was guaranteed the path of the chosen at birth.
But now...
the only one who knows me
for what I am is that monster.
I heard the Red Rose Mansion burned down.
I'm sure they're going to emerge...
into broad daylight...
The ones who had their names
taken from them, like myself...
Were you able to determine the cause of the fire?
Yes.
It looks like it started in the second floor hall.
Judging from how severely it burned in that area...
it could've been kerosene or gasoline.
kerosene?
So it was arson...
We won't know for sure until we investigate further, but...
there are signs that a wall in the
hallway had been torn down.
What does that mean?
Who knows.
E-Excuse me!
P-Please come with me!
What happened?
This is!
We saw something at the base of the rose
bushes, so we started digging, and...
the bones keep appearing, one after another!
After all these years, they'll finally see the light of day...
However...
there's no one still alive who knows their names.
How could this happen?
It burned down to the ground.
This mansion was our only clue to Tenma's whereabouts.
But now...
Out of my way! Let me through!
Out of my way!
What's going on?
P-Please contact headquarters!
Immediately!
Skeletons!
A massive number of human bones were...!
Forty-six people?
Yes, that's what I heard.
In 1981...
forty-six people suddenly disappeared in that mansion.
According to the little information I was able
to obtain in East Germany at the time...
a certain experiment was being
conducted at that mansion.
An experiment...
Step back, please!
This is only a theory, but...
that child was probably born there.
Brother, I'm cold.
I can't walk anymore.
I'm hungry.
Brother...
are we going to die?
Brother, please say my name.
Please say my name.
We don't have names.
Please say my name...
Please say my...
A blanket.
Yes, sir!
And something warm to drink.
"Johan. It is a wonderful name."
Johan...
Those children didn't have names.
Perhaps when I gave him the name Johan...
something inside of him awoke.
No...
There's no point in talking about the past anymore.
Let's talk about the future, and what will come.
Even though I no longer have a future...
It's okay, General Wolf.
You don't need to talk anymore.
Eva Heinemann is...
Eva Heinemann is with someone from our organization.
Our organization was unified by four people.
Professor Göderich, who was killed, and myself...
Right now, Eva is with the other two.
They're trying to use her.
You must not let them meet.
Whether I live or not...
I'm not able to stop them anymore.
They're about to go berserk.
Stop them.
Please save them, Tenma.
Dr. Tenma!
My name is Helmut...
Helmut Wolf.
However, those who knew me as Helmut...
are no longer in this world.
Please say my name.
That is the proof of my existence.
Helmut...
My name...
Helmut!
You are Helmut Wolf!
So this is what Johan saw...
A world without names...
General Wolf...
It all burned down.
The gates are locked, too.
The police must've made this place off-limits.
It's useless.
Mr. Lipsky.
I know this place is important to you because of
the book readings when you were a child...
But...
Nina...
This place must have been important to you, as well.
It might've been the trigger to recalling
your memories, and yet...
That vision...
A lot of people were dead...
and piled on top of each other in
the great hall of this mansion.
Yeah, since the visions you saw were real.
I was surprised when I saw the news.
They said they found the remains of forty-six
people at the Red Rose Mansion.
So it was just as your brother, Johan, told you.
My brother...
What did Johan see?
Was it something horrifying, beyond all imagination?
The true terror?
If I was...
If I had been there at the time...
would I have been the one to become the monster?
It might be for the best that this place burned down, Nina.
I thought it would be hard.
I thought I wouldn't be able to continue
living if I lost this place.
But I can't feel that way.
Maybe it's because this place is full of sad memories.
I wasn't an excellent student.
That's what makes me sad.
I couldn't meet his expectations.
If...
If only I'd been able to meet his expectations...
But reality wasn't like that.
I became an unwanted child.
What about your mom and dad, Mr. Lipsky?
They're alive.
But I've never lived with them before.
Nina's memories...
If Nina's memories do come back...
I hope they're happy ones.
Happy memories...?
Yes...
Happy memories...
I wonder what happy memories are...?
Tenma said...
that if you don't have any happy memories,
you can just make some.
Tenma said you can just make them from now on.
Dieter, your mouth is covered in ketchup!
So is yours, Nina.
Nina...
I'm creating a new puppet show right now.
What kind of puppet show is it?
No one has ever wanted to see my puppet shows.
But I think people will like this next one.
Let me see your new one!
I want to see! I want to see!
I'm a girl who lost her memories.
I have dreams that I'm being chased by a monster.
I have dreams that I'm chasing after a monster.
But I love songs.
And I love to dance.
Someday, I will have wonderful dreams.
Someday, those dreams will come true.
Someday...
I can't think of what should come after this...
I want to make this girl's story have a happy ending.
But...
I can't think of one yet.
I want to make it a happy ending.
Thank you.
The girl decided to embark on a journey.
She doesn't know what kind of journey it will be.
She doesn't know what lies ahead.
However...
the girl will stay strong and continue her journey.
The girl looks back and waves many times.
Over and over again.
And then, she's gone...
in search of a happy ending.
Nina!
Nina, you've come!
I've been looking for you, Mr. Lipsky.
You're the son of Franz Bonaparta...
the owner of the Red Rose Mansion, correct?
Yes... Gazing at what is known now in this world...
Yes... Your eyes believe in kindness...
Make it home... to your land of harmony...
Make it home... to your land of purity...
I Hate This Job