If I knew it would turn out like this...
I wouldn't have taken the job.
I didn't like it from the start...
Everything is going to be okay!
Just relax!
T-That's just a scratch!
We're almost at the hospital!
I told you, no hospitals.
I said a doctor, but not a hospital.
The Hellblau Hotel.
I... I know what you're trying to say.
If you go to a hospital, the police will come.
And then you'll be back in prison again.
But you know what?
We don't have time to get to that
underground doctor's place!
To the Hellblau Hotel...
Your life is more important!
- if you're alive, you can...
- Hurry the hell up!
The Hellblau Hotel!
That's why...
nothing good ever comes from
getting involved with women.
Please...
get to Dr. Tenma quickly...
Two Months Ago
Behave yourself.
The person you're about to see...
I Hate This Job
is someone you wouldn't be able
to see under normal circumstances.
I guess I should've brought my autograph book.
I'll kill you if you joke around.
Come in.
This man, Martin, is my subordinate.
You can leave now.
I wish to speak with him alone.
Y-Yes, sir.
I'll really kill you if you screw something up.
Can I sit here?
Go ahead.
How long have you been with The Baby?
Almost three years, I think.
And before that?
Prison, huh?
How many years?
Eight years.
Murder?
Something like that.
You got out rather quickly, considering.
I was an exemplary inmate.
I hear you're exemplary when it
comes to doing jobs, as well.
I'll do anything.
Any job.
Except...
Except?
I'm not too thrilled with jobs that involve women.
Well, I won't be picky about my jobs.
I just don't want to get involved with women.
This job does involve a woman.
I want you to look after a certain woman for a while.
An unpleasant job...
I want you to pick up a certain woman from Düsseldorf.
Since you say you don't like to get involved with women...
you should be perfect for this job.
You should be able to keep things professional.
Miss Eva Heinemann?
Who are you?
Martin.
Well, I don't think my name matters.
I was told to take you to Frankfurt.
Told by whom?
A man wearing glasses and an expensive suit.
A man wearing glasses?
He's not with Roberto's group, is he?
I don't know much myself.
But he seems to be a very important person.
If you don't want to go, I won't force you.
I'm not too thrilled about this, either.
I'm being targeted.
Will you be my bodyguard?
Well, that's part of my job, so...
Wait here.
Carry this.
Let's go.
It's better than getting killed by that man.
What an unpleasant bitch.
The way she shakes her ass...
The smell of her perfume...
It pisses me off.
I hate this job.
Why don't you talk to me?
Well, we can talk about something if you want.
I don't really feel like talking.
Then I'll be quiet.
Any drinks?
Aren't there any drinks?
Sorry, but I don't drink.
I'll go check the dining car.
I see. So you're traveling alone.
I'm traveling alone myself.
Oh, if you don't mind, could you please
tell me where you'll be staying?
Oh, here. This is my card.
What are you doing?
W-What do you mean?
This woman asked me for a drink, so I...
Don't you lay a finger on this woman.
Why don't you talk while you're eating?
Like I said, I'll talk if you want me to.
Why don't you drink alcohol?
My mom was a terrible alcoholic.
No, I don't mind if you drink.
Your mother probably had a reason why she had to drink.
You think so?
I do.
There's a reason I have to drink...
No, please, tell me.
That is, if you don't like eating without a conversation.
It's a long story.
Sure, go ahead.
I used to have a fiancé.
He was a Japanese surgeon...
with brilliant skills.
And then...
And then I tried to kill my former fiancé.
Well, are you surprised?
I tried to kill that man!
But you didn't shoot him.
Your story is better than mine.
What's your story?
Tell me.
I... actually pulled the trigger.
My girlfriend was on top of some guy in the bedroom.
I shot the guy along with her...
until the gun ran out of bullets.
The room was filled with the smell of
her blood, the smell of his blood...
and the smell of her perfume...
When I realized it...
I was standing alone in the middle of everything.
You're so stupid.
Right?
What an unpleasant job...
My employer is waiting at this hotel.
You said you killed someone.
Don't touch me.
Which room?
I'll take you there.
The way you're dressed isn't suited for this hotel.
Just wait here.
It's room 1014.
What a bitch.
I don't know what the man with the glasses will say to her.
But if that woman refuses his deal...
this unpleasant job will be over.
I won't have to deal with that woman anymore.
What's the matter?
You don't look too good.
It wasn't a bad deal.
He said I could use this card as much as I wanted.
What are you doing?
Let's get going.
Where are we going?
Shopping.
I really hate this job.
This place next.
But they sell men's suits here.
I need you to look decent, too.
I'm fine with this.
I'm not.
I can't have a man in my company looking so shabby.
I like this one.
As for the necktie...
Kenzo...
Try this on.
Necktie, huh?
It's hideous.
How is it?
Well...
You look a little better.
However...
wear your tie properly.
Stop walking around with your shoulders
slouched like a gangster.
I thought I was walking normally.
Your "normal" isn't normal.
From now on, you have to guard me.
I'll make sure I won't be embarrassed.
no matter where I go.
That's your job, isn't it?
That's right.
That's my job.
Don't put your elbow on the table.
Fork in your left hand, knife in your right.
Don't make any noises when you're eating.
Looks like it's true.
What is?
Your story.
That you were the daughter of
the director of a big hospital.
You thought it was a lie?
Before I brought you to this city...
you just seemed like an alcoholic woman,
no matter how I looked at you.
I'm quite different now, aren't I?
You look like a classy lady, no two ways about it.
This is my true form.
Eva Heinemann just returned to where she belongs.
What's that?
An invitation to a party.
A party?
That's right.
This was the Job that was given to me.
Job?
To attend several parties.
That's it.
That's good.
It sounds like a fun job.
You're coming as well.
You'll be my escort, a gentleman worthy of me.
This is getting more unpleasant by the second.
How does it feel to finally be back on home ground?
What's so funny?
What are all these people talking about?
The weather?
Stocks?
I can't even tell what language they're speaking.
I'm starting to feel sick.
There you are.
Don't mind me.
Please enjoy yourself.
Let's go.
We're leaving.
W-Wait!
He wasn't at this party.
My job here is done.
Who wasn't here?
Take me away from here!
I don't care where!
Just hurry up and take me away from here!
At the time...
I didn't know why this woman's hand was trembling.
I've managed to somehow survive the day.
What's wrong?
Didn't you return to the place where you belong?
My life used to be like that every day.
I thought if I returned to that world...
the real me would come back.
But now...
places like this bar are the only places
where you feel comfortable.
I don't belong in a place like this, either!
Not a place like this!
Not places like that, either!
There's no place for me, no matter where I go!
I knew that!
I think...
that after I've finished this job...
I'll surely be killed.
I thought it'd be better than staying a mess and
getting killed by Roberto in Düsseldorf.
I thought it'd be better to die as the
well-dressed Eva Heinemann.
Even though it's all the same...
once I'm dead.
I thought I'd protect her.
My bad habit came out.
At the time, I suddenly thought to myself...
that I wanted to protect this woman.
Man!
How the hell did this happen?!
T-That's why I'm going to tell...
everything to Dr. Tenma right now...
H-Hang in there!
Almost there!
We're almost there!
Necktie...
If I didn't have something like this...
I wouldn't have had to go to a place like that.
I wouldn't have had to...
see something so terrifying.
Yes... Gazing at what is known now in this world...
Yes... Your eyes believe in kindness...
Make it home... to your land of harmony...
Make it home... to your land of purity...
The Man Who Saw the Devil