Jahreszeit Hotel
(Frankfurt)
The Red Rose Mansion experiments are still going on.
The devil has an apprentice.
The man with the glasses.
The survivor of the Red Rose Mansion.
Peter Capek.
He's trying to manipulate the devil.
Follow that car.
He's running away!
A Pleasant Dinner Table
Where...
Where am I?
So, you're awake.
How do you feel?
I... um...
You're lucky. You got away with only a sprained ankle.
From my inspection, it seems that you
didn't hit your head that hard.
Although I'm not an expert like you.
You know about me?
Dr. Tenma, a genius among brain surgeons.
I saw you in the paper.
Who are you?
I'm a dentist who practices around here.
Milan Kolasch.
I was passing through the area
when you were hit by that car.
It was a hit and run.
You should rest.
But I've caused you so much trouble.
It'd be even more trouble for me if you left on
those legs and drew the cops around here.
Around here?
This is a Turkish neighborhood around Frankfurt.
Turkish?
Or rather it was a Turkish neighborhood.
They're tearing it down for redevelopment.
The Turkish people that were here have
all pretty much moved to other places.
In the past, they worked together to fight off a bunch
of extremists who tried to set this whole place on fire.
So the Bahir cafe is gone, too?
Yeah, it's gone.
Did you know this neighborhood?
Yes, I did.
If you're awake, let's go eat over there.
Food tastes better with company.
Today were having Vietnamese food.
Minh made it.
Pho Ga and Cha Gio Tom.
Minh's cooking is excellent.
Please, eat up!
It's good.
I love pork, but it's forbidden in the Turkish diet.
We don't get to eat Czech food very often.
That's because Milan's not very good at cooking.
Sorry about that.
We all take turns making our own native food.
It's pretty luxurious to enjoy food from different
countries every day, don't you think?
What's Japanese food like?
You're Japanese, aren't you Dr. Tenma?
Japanese food?
Yeah. Please make some for us.
I'm looking forward to it.
We use pork in Katsudon and Sushi... Some
people might not be able to eat raw fish.
I wonder if oyakodon would be okay...
Oyakodon?
Yes, you put soy sauce and egg on top of rice with chicken in it.
Why is it called oyakodon?
Note: Oyako means parent and child.
The chicken is the parent and the egg is the child.
That's why it's called oyakodon?
I can't believe the sense in Japanese food.
With chicken and egg, they have the parent and child!
What's wrong, Tenma?
Nothing.
You don't like the food?
No. Its delicious.
Food this good...
A meal this fun...
It's really been a long time since I've experienced this.
Good night, Tenma.
Good night.
How long will it take...
I don't have time to waste.
Peter Capek.
A gun.
A report on Peter Capek's activities.
Do you think that's strange?
Back then, the police weren't organized
enough to capture you.
The police were there waiting for me.
I'm going to kill Peter Capek.
That one's no good.
How strange.
I used to be able to make ones that could fly really well.
Milan is good at making paper airplanes.
They fly all the way to the roofs over there.
Really?
Milan always says that...
He always promises us...
We'll go farther than just those roofs over there.
We'll go to Turkey, Vietnam, and the Czech Republic.
We'll see everyone's home country.
Right?
Yeah!
Yeah.
Here we go.
Oh, another bad one.
Why won't it fly?
That's strange.
I'm going to kill Peter Capek.
Why? Why are you going to do something like that, Milan?
That man...
The man called Peter Capek is the devil.
In 1989, when the communist regime in Czechoslovakia
fell, he escaped to this country.
Capek lived here in Frankfurt and he
held classes as a German teacher.
He was a secluded man.
But ever since then, the children began to change.
The children who had his class began
to commit suicide, one after another.
And they started to exhibit extremely violent behavior.
And then one day, there was a violent incident that you
could even call "a massacre among fellow children."
I went to interview the boy who was said
to be the ringleader of that incident,
at the facility he was being kept at.
He said to me...
"I want to go back to the seminar."
The seminar?
That night, he committed suicide in the facility.
He was my son.
Capek disappeared from town after the commotion.
The next time he appeared, he was
like a totally different man.
He ran the underworld in Frankfurt,
and was aligned with the extremists.
And then he began purging this town
of Turks and other foreigners.
I don't know what he's trying to do here, but...
their violence had reached its peak.
In 1996, they tried to burn down the Turkish neighborhood.
You know about that, don't you?
Yeah, I heard it in the news.
The people here assembled their own
vigilante force to fight against them.
In just three days, five of the leaders
of that group mysteriously died.
Those five who died...
were Suleiman's son, Tung's father, Minh's husband,
Mustafa's son, and Shemel's father.
They didn't die.
They were murdered...
by Peter Capek.
I don't know why you're after Capek,
but I'll tell you this.
The one who's going to kill Capek...
is me.
Just you wait. This next one looks
like it's going to be a good one.
It's impossible.
No, I'm going to do my best.
Even if you do your best, if it's impossible,
it's still impossible.
We know.
Turks and Vietnamese people can't all travel together.
Even if we can't all travel together, I enjoy
living with Milan and Tung like this.
Yeah!
I'm done.
This time it will fly.
Here it goes.
See.
Hey!
You did it! It's flying!
Amazing, amazing.
I don't think it can make it to the roofs on the other side like Milan's can.
But it is flying.
Aren't you glad I didn't give up?
Yeah.
You can't give up!
Where's my gun?
Where did you put the gun that I keep in the drawer?
My chance to shoot Capek has come.
I'm going.
Give me my gun.
I can't let you do that.
I can't give you your gun.
This is the gun that was in your coat.
I want the gun that I did my training
with, the one that I'm used to.
Do you want to give it to me?
You have a family now.
You mustn't do this.
I've been following Capek for a long time now.
I've never had a chance to shoot
Capek like the one I have today.
I'm begging you. Don't do this, Milan.
I told you. Don't get in my way.
Even if you take your revenge, the people
who are dead will not come back.
You have to focus on the future.
You have no right to say that to me.
Milan.
You and I are the same, Dr. Tenma.
I've done my research on you.
If what you claim is true, then what we're trying to do is the same.
He wasn't always like that.
The man I knew wasn't such a demon.
Peter Capek and I were childhood
friends from the same town.
I asked him to come to this country.
What do you think is across the border?
You can't cross the border.
I know I can't.
But you,know...
there are wonderful places across the border.
There's a city that is lit up all night long.
Really, Peter? Who told you that?
Old Mr. Gregor.
He's an alcoholic.
There are things that make people like
Mr. Gregor worthless across the border.
Things that make people worthless?
I'd like to see that.
Who'd ever want to see something like that?
There we go!
It's riding on the wind!
You're so good at that Milan.
It's still going!
Amazing! I bet it can cross the border!
Go see the world for us.
We lived in a town near the Austrian-Czechoslovakian border.
I was the son of a craftsman and he was
the son of a government official.
But we hit it off for some reason.
In 1989, when the communist government fell, I was the one who helped him flee the country.
I'm the one who summoned that demon to this country.
Prague
I was worried about you during last year's Soviet invasion.
They did drag off a lot of my friends.
I'm safe and I'm right here.
How about you?
Me?
I've been making enough to keep eating as a novice dentist.
So you're a dentist?
You were always good with your hands.
I wish I had your skill at making it big in the world.
Maybe it's because of those skills that I can hold my current social status after the invasion.
I've enjoyed many things after "The Prague Spring."
I've even gone to the West.
You talked about that a lot when we were kids.
What's on the other side?
Did you find an answer?
I did.
So?
There's nothing.
Both here and on the other side.
This country is mistaken.
But the other country isn't right either.
I see.
You said I'm good at always having
a good social status, but...
the truth is I owe my abilities to one man.
Oh?
He's such a wonderful man that if you'd meet him,
you wouldn't care about your social status.
Just when I thought there was nothing
of worth in this country or the next,
he showed me a light I had not yet known.
He will bring forth something entirely new into this world.
What will he bring?
What will he bring?  How should I put it?
You might consider it terrifying.
Now that I think of it, he might have been starting to crack back then.
Give me back my gun.
Here's your gun.
You mustn't, Milan.
You mustn't do something like that.
You can't stop me.
I'm going to kill him.
You have a family that you're living with now.
He's the one who killed their relatives.
Because I brought him to this country, they were killed...
along with my son...
During the arson incident, and even now, there was
a person that the Turkish people talked about.
A man who gave his all to treat the injured.
A certain Japanese man who risked
his life to put the fires out.
That was you, wasn't it, Dr. Tenma?
I believe in you.
I understand very well what you're trying to do.
We're the same.
I'm going. It's time.
If I let him get away, I might not have another chance.
Milan!
Thank you for trying to stop me.
If I was in your place,
I wouldn't be able to stop you.
Huh?
What?
It's delicious!
Yeah, this is really good.
This Japanese Oyakodon is fantastic.
Yeah!
Is your ankle okay?
Let me help you, Dr. Tenma.
I'll have your serving ready in just a bit, Mrs. Minh.
Milan sure is late. I think he'll be home soon though.
- It tastes better right after it's made, so I'll make some for Milan later.
- Next in the news.
- Really? Please do then.
- Today at about 11 A.M., at the Roedelheim
Convention Center in Frankfurt,
- Really? Please do then.
- Today at about 11 A.M., at the Roedelheim
Convention Center in Frankfurt,
a man with a gun opened fire.
However, the policemen securing the convention grounds
shot and killed the man.
Although there were no other fatalities in the incident,
because there were so many important people in the
financial world at the convention at the same time,
there was a major concern among the attendees.
Furthermore, the attacker's identity
and purpose remain unknown.
Here is some amateur footage of some of the attack.
Everybody loves it.
I can't wait until Milan gets home.
Here is some amateur footage of some of the attack.
That man...
He's from the Red Rose Mansion...
You mustn't hide anything from him.
Yes... Gazing at what is known now in this world...
Yes... Your eyes believe in kindness...
Make it home... to your land of harmony...
Make it home... to your land of purity...
Unrelated Murders