In the beginning, my dressing room was sometimes
so full of flowers that you could barely get in it.
And then I started getting designer clothes and bags.
And after that I started getting gems
bigger than I had ever seen.
I had no idea who it was all from.
It was you, wasn't it?
I felt something special when I saw
your show for the first time.
Something special?
Do you mean my boobs or my butt?
Something you can't see with your eyes.
I wish you had just come to my dressing
room to meet me in person.
Just as myself?
Huh?
What do you mean?
It seems like you're willing to listen to me.
The Baby's Depression
It's delicious!
I've never had food this good before.
Please eat as much as you like.
Do you eat this all the time?
Yes, but food is only good as the company it's had with.
I always eat alone. Do you always have company for meals?
Yes. I pay a lot of people to eat with me.
What? Why do you do that?
Why do I pay people to eat with me?
Looking back, even though I had a lot
of people over to have a good time,
I always felt like I was eating alone.
How about now?
I'm actually having fun!
I'm so glad!
Do you think we could make this a regular
thing where we have dinner together?
Sure! I might get tired of eating the
same thing all the time though.
It's been strange lately.
What has?
I've never felt like this before.
I've made my own kingdom in Frankfurt.
I've fought to create a new order.
My dream is to become just like Fuhrer Hitler.
My dream is to become a dancer.
What I'm doing now isn't what I had in mind.
But everyone is mesmerized when I'm dancing.
People feel better when they see me dance.
I'm scared.
Huh?
This is the first time I've felt like this.
I'm scared!
What are you saying?
Uh, umm, I mean...
The three murders that happened in the last month.
It was Johan's will.
Yes. Just as you said.
I understand the meanings of the murders of the
Bilker Investment Bank employee, Fritz Overt,
and the general store owner's daughter, Frieder Schelling.
It was to hide scandals.
We can understand those two murders.
But,
the foreign trader, Erich Klemperer.
Do you know him?
He doesn't have anything to do with Johan.
Do you really think so?
Do we really know where Johan came from?
Or are you hiding something from me?
There's no use worrying about that.
Anyway, you've found out where Nina is, haven't you?
She has left the psychologist's house in
Munich, and she's coming to Frankfurt.
Our top priority right now is to secure Nina.
I'm sure you know this already, but may
I remind you that she is Johan's sister.
Those eyes back then...
Her eyes, when she held a gun at me when
we burned down the Turkish district...
It makes me shiver just thinking about them.
Isn't it wonderful?
Are you talking about the program you built?
I only helped with it.
It was all my master's doing.
It's all proceeding according to his program.
Is it really all proceeding according to his program?
There it is!
It's my favorite.
This time it's my treat.
Isn't it good? This is the best ice cream stand in Frankfurt.
I finally feel at ease.
I've been pretty tense lately.
Why?
Why am I?
I don't need a bodyguard.
It's Mr. Capek's orders.
You don't have to worry about me.
No one out there knows who I really am.
It will cause us a lot of grief if we let you
go out on one of your joyrides again.
I don't go out on joyrides.
Three people have died to hide your scandals.
I wonder how many people I can
kill without getting caught.
Who do you think gave you the power you hold now?
The four founders of the organization
Professor Geidlitz, General Wolf, Mr. Capek,
and your late father.
I know you think you can just take your
father's place, but it's not an easy task.
We don't know if you're cut out for the job.
Are you trying to say you're the one
who's going to take his place?
I know all about your hidden scandals.
You know what happens to people who know about them.
You can't threaten me.
I don't want to make you, the leader of
the extremists in Frankfurt, my enemy.
I had a good time tonight.
So did I!
I'm glad I called you.
Call anytime.
It's been a long time since I've been able to walk
around town like this, without a bodyguard.
Will you be okay? Should I escort you?
You're... going to protect me?
Don't worry. My hotel is just over there.
Wow! You live in a hotel?
This isn't much, but please...
I don't need it.
Good-bye.
I'm sorry.
It's just a habit.
Let me apologize.
I've always bought people with money.
May I...
come to your hotel room?
People call you The Baby,
but what's your real name?
My name is...
Yes, we know where the sister is.
I've been trying to reach The Baby by
phone, but he hasn't been answering.
I'm going to see him in person.
Yes. Good-bye.
Hello.
It's me.
Th-The Baby's...
The Baby's...
been murdered.
Come on.
Don't be scared.
Are you okay, Mr. Capek?
You look pale.
Please forgive my rude question,
but were you the one who had The Baby killed?
What a stupid question!
The news of The Baby's death will be well known by dawn.
With his death, the balance within the organization may crumble.
I don't know what will happen.
We are bodyguards.
We just carry out whatever job were hired for.
But, if this was your doing, you've made a mockery out of it.
Why do you think I called you here
after I heard of The Baby's death?
Because you felt threatened.
Do you have any clues on who killed The Baby?
Are we really controlling Johan's actions?
What are you scared of?
Everything is going according to plan.
Everything...
is proceeding according to his program.
Fine. Let's take you somewhere safe.
I have a villa in Idstein.
No one knows about it.
Let's go there.
But what about the twin sister?
You said you knew where she was.
Yes. She's here in Frankfurt.
She's at a motel called Tourette.
Securing her is the most effective
thing we can do to keep me safe.
We'll get on it in the morning.
No! Right now!
I understand.
I've contacted two of our men and told them
to meet us at your villa in Idstein.
The Baby sent his guards away last night
so he could do whatever he wanted.
Were with you, so don't worry.
Yeah.
You weren't hurt that day at the convention
center when you were shot at.
You're a very lucky man.
Milan.
Milan, listen to me.
I've met someone incredible.
Nice to meet you. I'm Peter Capek.
You've shown me something amazing.
Those are your reading seminars!
Will you let me ask you a few questions about your new...
Read this.
Everything is drawn in these.
How beautiful. What beautiful children.
These children are growing exactly as
Franz Bonaparta's program dictates.
These are the children who will lead the human race, right?
Stop...
Stop the car.
What's wrong?
Your villa is just at the end of this road.
What did you say earlier?
Huh?
You had two other guards...
Yes, they are at the villa.
They may be there already.
Are you sure that they won't leak any information?
Huh?
Is there some kind of guarantee that no one knows that I'm going to my villa?
Yes, they are trustworthy.
We're not going there.
Hold on a second.
Where are we going then?
We're just not going there.
But we'll just end up driving all night then.
That's an order.
I know you feel your life is in danger.
We're going to the villa.
A l-lignter.
He wasn't going for his gun.
It's me.
Is anyone...
here?
J-Johan.
Many people drank that wine...
at the Red Rose Mansion.
Don't worry.
Look, I'm drinking it, too.
What happened to the bodyguards
who were supposed to be here?
Why did you kill The Baby?
We were supposed to be working together.
You helped us and we were to find your sister.
Everything is going according to plan.
We... We'll soon have your sister.
If anything happens to me, your sister will...
I won't let you have your way.
Got it? Everything is going according to my calculations.
What am I?
The monster inside of me isn't inside of me.
It's outside of me.
What are you saying?
Franz Bonaparta...
is alive.
Yes... Gazing at what is known now in this world...
Yes... Your eyes believe in kindness...
Make it home... to your land of harmony...
Make it home... to your land of purity...
Johan's Footprints