It's me.
Is anyone...
here?
J-Johan.
Many people drank that wine...
at the Red Rose Mansion.
Don't worry.
Look, I'm drinking it, too.
What happened to the bodyguards
who were supposed to be here?
Why did you kill The Baby?
We were supposed to be working together.
You helped us and we were to find your sister.
Everything is going according to plan.
We... We'll soon have your sister.
If anything happens to me, your sister will...
I won't let you have your way.
Got it? Everything is going according to my calculations.
What am I?
The monster inside of me isn't inside of me.
It's outside of me.
What are you saying?
Franz Bonaparta...
is alive.
Johan's Footprints
I'm sorry to bother you at night, Ms. Nina Fortner.
Ms. Fortner.
Ms. Nina Fortner.
Don't move.
Who sent you?
I see. Just like The Baby said. You're not just a little girl.
The Baby...
Did The Baby order you to take me?
No. The Baby is dead.
Dead?
Peter Capek ordered us to get you.
He says he'll be safe if we take you hostage.
Capek?!
Take me.
Take me to Peter Capek.
Police!
We will conduct a search in the home of the perpetrator
of the Roedelheim Convention Center shooting, Milan Kolasch.
Get going.
Out of the way!
Out of our way!
Is this Kolasch's room?
I think so.
The police will be here soon to search the place.
I have to leave.
Is Milan...
Is Milan really dead?
Milan...
Milan died for our sake.
Peter Capek killed our relatives and he was killed
trying to take revenge for us. Revenge...
Revenge!
No!
Don't think that.
But... But, Milan...
Milan never wanted that.
Revenge begets revenge.
It happens again and again.
Milan didn't want you to think like that.
Someone has to stop it.
Milan tried to end it all.
What do you think Milan's true wish was?
He wanted us to see everyone's home country together.
Study hard.
Some day that wish will be granted.
Thank you for your hospitality, Mr. Mustafa.
Mrs. Minh.
Mrs. Suleiman, thank you for all the great food.
Dr.  Tenma, you aren't going to...
There's a lot of material on Peter Capek.
It seems like Milan Kolasch was after this Capek character.
Let's find this man.
I want to question him.
Detective!
The leader of the extremist organization, The Baby,
has been found murdered at the Kaiser Hotel.
Someone has to...
I have to... stop it.
That young man has gone to that hotel
with Peter Capek many times.
Is that the Devil's Apprentice?
Follow that car.
Johan?
Are you here, Johan?
Where have you been, Johan?
You must be... Eva.
Where is he?
Where is Johan right now?
Mr. Capek.
We've brought Nina.
Peter...
Capek.
Come on. Don't be scared.
Hey!
Wait! Stop!
Which one is it?
Is it Johan?
Or the sister?
At this point, it doesn't matter which one.
Johan let me live.
The one who's going to kill me...
is the sister.
Everything is going according to plan.
But whose?
Mine?
Or Johan's?
Whose plan?
Kill me already.
Johan was here?
Where did he go?
Take me to him.
Where is Johan?
It's pitch black.
I'm scared.
I want to get out of here.
You can't leave yet.
Is it still going on?
The massacre.
If I hadn't pointed you out at that party...
you and that demon...
If only I hadn't done that
Martin wouldn't...
have died.
I understand.
Just hold on a second.
Where is Johan?
I don't know. I want to know myself.
Calm down.
I've been watching this apartment for two weeks.
He's never been here.
Where is he?
I told you.
I don't know.
For real.
My ear! My ear!
I'm serious.
It hurts! It hurts!
Next time, you'll wish it was just your ear.
Christof Sievernich.
I've done my homework on you.
Although I knew about your late father,
Ernest, without any research.
The Sievernich group was one of the largest
financial groups in Frankfurt, no,
all of Germany.
I'd never have thought that you were the heir of that group.
Why did Peter Capek want me to point Johan out for you?
Look at how much I'm bleeding.
Let me go to the hospital.
What's going on?
What happened when I pointed that demon out for you?
You've got it all wrong.
What do I have wrong?!
He thought that he introduced me to Johan.
But Johan and I have known each
other for quite some time.
What?
Capek never knew.
We were friends in East Germany over 10 years ago.
Over 10 years ago... in East Germany?
I'm Sievernich's foster son.
That's what they say at least.
The truth is, I was sold on the black market by a merchant.
Johan and I met each other at
East Berlin's 511 Kinderheim.
511...
We met each other there.
We survived.
He and I were the only survivors.
I'm scared.
I'm hungry.
I need to go to the bathroom.
Is the massacre over?
Is everyone dead?
Let's take a look.
Don't worry.
It's gotten quiet outside, hasn't it?
It's okay. Take a look.
You'll go insane if you stay in here.
I'll take a look.
If it's safe, return and let us know.
Okay.
I don't know why, but all the people at
511 Kinderheim went insane that day.
It wasn't just the children.
The staff were killing each other as well.
He's not back yet.
He ran away.
Huh?
He left us and ran away.
No way!
He decided to save himself.
I don't think so.
If you think I'm lying, go take a look.
He's probably enjoying a nice hot meal right now.
A hot meal?
I'll just take a glance.
You won't betray me, will you?
Of course not.
He didn't return either.
I'll stay hidden.
With an empty stomach and a dry mouth, I fell
in and out of sleep over and over again.
Am I going to die here?
And then he was there,
standing in front of me.
It's just you and me.
I have a plan.
Was that Johan?
Capek saying that he has a plan is a joke.
We already talked about it as kids.
What's his plan?
Do you want to know?
Where do I begin?
You shouldn't have.
You shouldn't have shot me in the ear!
A politicians face is everything to him.
This is not good.
I am going to run the world.
Isn't that right?!
With Johan's help, the world is going to be mine!
What am I going to do about this ear?
Don't ruin our plan!
Don't ruin it!
Drop the gun!
Kenzo!
Johan told me...
that if you showed up, I should tell you where he is.
After that, he said you might kill me.
Why didn't you kill me?
Have you regained all of your memories?
Yeah.
Then why didn't you kill me?
You must be overflowing...
with hatred, anger, and grief.
You know...
what we are, don't you?
I've heard the story of how...
you, the twins, were born.
Yes... Gazing at what is known now in this world...
Yes... Your eyes believe in kindness...
Make it home... to your land of harmony...
Make it home... to your land of purity...
Welcome Home