Mom!
Don't let go of my hand!
Mom! Mom!
Welcome Home
The man.
He was a German-Czechoslovakian
who stayed in Bohemia after WWII,
the eldest son in his family.
He was a soldier who graduated
from a military officer school.
He was an elite who would carry
his country into the future.
His name...
His name doesn't matter.
The woman.
She was the only daughter of a Moravian
elementary school teacher.
A beautiful woman with blonde hair and blue eyes.
She attended Brno University, majored in genetic engineering,
and carried the hopes of her teachers.
Her name...
Her name doesn't matter.
They met at a cafe in Prague.
They instantly fell in love.
Soon after, she became pregnant.
And then the man confessed...
that this was his mission.
Men and women selected by their race, intellect,
physique, and endurance were to have children.
This experiment was conducted with dozens of couples.
They were one of those couples.
The man completed his mission exactly
as the scenario prescribed.
But at that point, he no longer wanted to play his part in it.
And then he said this:
Let's run away!
The two of them ran away.
The man said he wouldn't be a
part of the scenario anymore.
But the scenario had already taken that into account.
The woman was confined to an unfamiliar room.
Let me see him.
He has received a new mission.
The woman said over and over
"Let me see him."
She knew.
She knew he wasn't alive anymore.
The pregnancy went well.
She was carrying twins.
Show me your face.
She came to notice that
the man who often came to visit her,
the man who drew her,
was the man who was conducting the experiment.
I won't forgive you.
I will never forgive you.
Even if I die, the children growing inside
of me will have revenge on you.
You say some pretty interesting things.
After a few months, she finally went into labor.
When she was put in the delivery
room to ease her labor pains,
she went into action.
Through an opening about 20 to 30 cm wide,
her heavy body racked with the pain of labor,
she escaped through the air ducts.
She collapsed on the road only
a few meters outside the gate.
Her water had broken.
How beautiful!
What beautiful children!
These are the children who will lead the human race, right?
Wonderful.
I've thought of names for them.
Don't concern yourself with unnecessary things.
I've thought of them...
their names.
You didn't have to.
Names!
Give them names.
Give them...
Don't worry.
They don't need names.
Franz Bonaparta.
That's right.
Johan asked me where he was.
Bonaparta's alive?
"I won't forgive you."
"I will never forgive you."
"Even if I die, the children growing inside
of me will have revenge on you."
Franz Bonaparta is alive, isn't he?
You should ask Johan that.
He's here.
You're quite the doctor.
There's a hospital up ahead.
I'll take you there if you tell me where Johan is.
At this rate, you're going to die from blood loss.
I-I can't tell you what I don't know.
Tell us now.
You're quite the doctor.
You shoot me and then threaten me
after I've lost so much blood.
Where is Johan?!
You're quite the doctor.
Tell us now.
Hurry!
I can't tell you what I don't know.
Eva.
There's a pay phone over there.
Call the hospital and tell them there's
an injured person in the car.
Wh-What are you saying?
He's just about to tell us where Johan is.
His life is in danger.
Hurry, make the call.
You saved someone again.
You're always the same.
You can't kill anyone.
I wanted to meet you.
I'll tell you where Johan is.
Kenzo, an ambulance from the hospital will be here soon.
Let's get out of here.
Where is Kenzo?
He left...
He had a message for you.
"I can't get you involved in this."
"I ruined your life."
"I'm truly sorry."
"Please be happy."
Why are you crying?
I don't understand.
I don't understand it at all.
Johan?
Welcome home.
Fire!
There are flames coming out of the Three Frogs!
Now, eat up.
But if you eat so quickly, you'll choke.
You must have been hungry.
Where are you from?
What are your names?
You don't like talking, do you?
That's fine. You can talk to us after your stomachs are full.
Wait up!
I said wait up!
Over here!
What should we do?
What do you mean?
With those kids...
Do you think they're really orphans?
Even if they have parents, they must have some
reason why they don't want to go back.
Don't you think?
We wanted kids, didn't we?
Yeah.
Lets adopt...
Don't be ridiculous.
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
Either way, let's call the police.
Huh?
What's wrong, little one?
Look at these. Aren't they pretty?
I'm going to give them to those nice old people.
You don't have to.
Huh?
I told you. I have a plan.
Let's go.
Wait up! I told you to wait!
We finally meet.
Back then, when I ran away from the Red Rose Mansion
and arrived at the door of the Three Frogs.
You greeted me.
So this time, I'll say it to you.
Welcome home.
I came to see you on our 20th birthday in Heidelberg.
A lot of time has passed.
You came to see me?
You came to kill.
The Fortners, the Lieberts, and all the people
who were kind to us... all of them...
You killed them all!
Please live!
Huh?
I said, today is a nice day.
Y-Yeah.
Driver.
Yes?
Could you go a bit faster?
Don't worry. Hang in there.
Shoot me.
Kill.
I'll save you.
Are you going to shoot me like you did back then?
Yes.
I'll end it all.
End?
What is the end?
The end...
The end... The end...
The end.
I've seen the end many times.
What is the end?
I'm ending it!
You will die and so will I.
You've seen it.
What did you see?!
You don't know anything.
I'll tell you...
a truly frightening tale.
I'm home.
Yes... Gazing at what is known now in this world...
Yes... Your eyes believe in kindness...
Make it home... to your land of harmony...
Make it home... to your land of purity...
I'm Back