You'll be okay. Hang in there!
Shoot me.
Kill him...
I'll save you!
Will you shoot me like you did back then?
Yes.
I'll end everything.
End?
What is "the end"?
End...
End.
I've seen "the end of the world," time and again.
What is "the end"?
It will end.
You'll die, and I'll die, too.
You've seen it?
What have you seen?
Hey!
You don't know.
I'll tell you...
the actual, horrible story.
I'm home.
I'm Home
This actual, horrible story...
The various things I saw...
The various stories...
that I told to you...
I was taken from the room at the Three Frogs...
and placed in a pitch black room with no walls.
Everything I touched felt funny.
A room without an up or down, left or right...
but I knew someone was observing me.
A completely silent room...
No... Sometimes, I..
faintly heard screams.
Meals were provided from some unknown place.
I counted the number of meals I was given...
Five.
Six.
Seven.
Eleven, twelve, thirteen...
Twenty-one, twenty-three...?
When I could no longer keep track
of the number of meals...
that man was standing there.
Listen to me now.
People...
can become anything.
Huh?
A little child like you shouldn't be wandering
around in a place like this.
No, this is the child who...
Oh, this is the child?
Wow, you're cute..
Oh, this is the child.
Wonderful. How beautiful.
Look here. This is the child.
This kid?
Our achievement.
This is our achievement.
This is the child?
This is the...
Our...
I can only remember bits and pieces of the speech.
by the achievement of the...
new... this...
know... we, selected comrades... propose a toast...
to the future of our nation.
Cheers!
The first person collapsed.
Several people ran towards him.
Those who ran towards him...
also started collapsing, falling down, one after another.
Groans...
Yells...
Fear filled the room.
The forty-two people who were there died...
except for one man, Franz Bonaparta.
I ran...
trying to escape from that place.
I didn't notice when my arm was scratched
by the thorns in the rose garden.
I ran.
When I arrived at the Three Frogs...
you welcomed me home.
I kept talking...
day after day...
telling you all that I had experienced.
No...
No!
Nina...
Can you hear me, Nina?
Calm down.
Nina.
It's me.
It's Tenma.
Do you understand?
It's me.
Right.
That's right.
Calm down.
All right.
Good girl.
It's all right.
It's all right now.
No!
No, no!
It wasn't me!
I wasn't the one who said "welcome home"!
The one who said that was...
I...
What I said was...
I'm home.
Welcome home.
Johan's wrong.
He only listened to my story.
The one who was taken to the Rose Mansion was...
me!
The one who was taken and dragged
down the stairs in the Three Frogs...
The one who was counting the meals in the
pitch black room, the one without walls.
The one who was standing in the
midst of all those dead people...
That...
That was me!
I'm scared.
I'm home.
Welcome home.
Tell me everything.
Well...
I told him...
for days and days...
It's all right.
I told Johan what I experienced.
Johan thought my experience was...
It's all right now.
his own experience.
It's my fault that Johan...!
It's all right now!
I told Johan everything just a little while ago.
Johan listened to my story...
and he looked like he was smiling.
But he also looked like he was crying.
I've...
I've never seen...
such an expression before.
I couldn't...
shoot him.
But he will probably destroy himself...
just like me.
No, you can't!
Just like I'm destroying myself!
You can't!
You can't...
If you die...
If something happens to you...
what am I supposed to do?
If you die...
where would I go?
Stay alive.
Please.
No matter what.
Please!
Yeah, it's me.
A car was found near a lodge?
Yeah...
It fell off a cliff.
Edward was killed in this car.
The one who did this was probably...
Johan is probably...
going to kill Franz Bonaparta.
His son lives in Prague.
I told Johan about that.
But...
I wonder if that will put an end to everything.
I wonder if that will calm his madness.
His sister's memories...
The things that are missing from her memories...
Inside Johan...
was there one more memory?
I wonder... what we were trying to create.
Franz...
Franz Bonaparta...
Stay alive...
at any cost.
The place you should go...
The place we should go...
We'll definitely get there someday.
Hey, it's great to see you!
This is a rare visit.
Now...
please come in.
I was just making tea.
I wanted you to try my famous tea.
So, do you like it?
It's a special herb tea.
You came all the way out here.
You must have something important to say.
Just tell me what it is you need.
I'll prepare it right away.
Who are you going to kill next?
Huh?
Enough with the strange jokes.
Stop it.
I woke up...
from the dream.
You must be tired or something.
What are you going to do about the plan?
I woke up.
Wait a minute.
Then why did I raise so much money?
I woke up...
from the dream.
Then why did I kill all those people?
I've seen the final scene so many times...
but I see a different scene now.
The true final scene.
The memory that only I possess.
The place where I should truly go.
The place where I should go...
Ruhenheim...
This is it.
Yes
Cherish what you know is true in this world.
Ima kono sekai de wakaru koto mitsumete
Yes
Please believe in the kindness of your eyes
Anata no hitomi no yasashisa wo shinjite
Make it home to your land of harmony
Make it home to your land of purity
Make it home