Ruhenheim.
This is it.
Hey, Ludwig.
What are you barking at?
Ruhenheim
Is your bike broken again?
Yeah. The chain keeps slipping off.
I should have known this piece of trash was in the dump for a reason.
It doesn't look like trash to me.
When I'm riding it, everybody says,
"Look at that piece of trash. He's riding that piece of trash."
"That trash is riding a piece of trash."
Don't pay any attention to them.
It's an outstanding 5-speed super-cycle!
Let's try fixing it again.
Hey. It looks like a guest.
Oh, I had a call.
Do you have reservations?
Yes. I'm Lunge.
Oh, Mr. Lunge. Welcome!
I'm so glad you had a room for me on such short notice.
No, I have nothing but free rooms.
Well, it's still the off-season.
It feels like the whole year is the off-season.
The only people staying here right
now are that old couple there.
The old man has trouble walking, so it looks
like it's tough for them to go on vacation.
I'll take your luggage.
Thank you, Wim.
It's room 303.
How's the view from that room?
I got you the room with the best view.
I'm going to leave your luggage right here.
It's not trash.
Huh?
It looks like a pretty outstanding bike to me.
Inspector Lunge from the BKA?
Why is there a BKA inspector in
such a small town like this?
Actually, I was wondering how much backup I could call here.
Backup?
If we contact the state police, we could
have backup in less than an hour.
Although I don't think a situation that requires that would happen in such a simple, laid back town like this.
You should check everyone who comes
to this town from now on...
Huh?
before something terrible happens.
Awesome!
It's working pretty well.
I'm having a pretty good run.
Time to accelerate. Gear change!
Ouch!
So, the piece of trash is out riding again.
Stop! Stop it!
Trash!
Are you okay?
Are you alone?
Are you traveling alone?
Yes.
For work?
No, for private business.
Are you lonely by yourself?
No, I'm used to it.
Do you have family?
Yes. My daughter has a son.
Oh, you have a grandchild.
Grandchildren are great.
Our grandchild knows us so well.
See, I was just writing our grandchild a postcard.
I love letters.
If you can't say something to someone in person,
at least you can always write them a letter.
Why don't you write one?
A letter to my grandson?
I don't even know what to write.
Whatever you feel like.
Maybe I could just draw a picture.
Excuse me. Do you have a room for the night?
Oh, of course.
Thank you.
I love wandering around and having picnics,
but this time I got lost.
So I just headed toward town and
by the time I got here, it got late....
You're a real lifesaver.
So no one ever comes to this town.
A gunshot?
I didn't hear any damn gunshot.
I swear. I heard a gunshot.
No one in this town even owns a gun.
If anyone did own a gun, it'd probably be that drunk out back.
If he was shooting out back, the sound would have been louder.
Besides, if he did have a gun, I bet he couldn't
even hit the broadside of a barn.
I lost again!
I lost again because you jinxed me.
Geez.
Shut up! It's not my fault.
You gotta stop playing the lotto.
Ludwig!
My Ludwig is nowhere to be found!
You heard that thing that sounded
like a gunshot earlier, didn't you?
If my Ludwig was shot, I wouldn't know what to do!
Calm down, Mrs. Hillman.
There wasn't a gunshot. Calm down.
What's wrong?
Her dog is missing.
That's too bad.
Let's notify the police.
I already have!
But that man is useless. You can't
count on him for anything,
and he hates dogs.
Should I go look for him?
Are you sure you're okay with that, Mr. Neumeyer?
I was just about to wander around town anyways.
Yeah, I've seen Mrs. Hillman's dog before.
It's that stupid mutt that won't stop barking, right?
He's missing. Have you seen him recently?
No, I haven't.
I see. Thank you.
I have another question. Have you seen
anyone you've never seen before?
Yes, I have.
Oh?
You!
A dog? I thought you were going to stay here.
Sorry, I'm already staying at the Versteck Hotel.
He takes all my customers.
So that means that there aren't any guests here.
Not a single one!
It's dead silent here thanks to him.
So if a barking dog was here, I'd know right away.
Did you hear any barking?
No, I didn't.
But I did hear something that sounded like a gunshot.
Maybe some degenerate couldn't take the barking
anymore and shot the damn thing somewhere.
Hello, umm...
I'm Lunge, Mr. Neumeyer.
Mr. Lunge.
Where are you headed?
I'm looking for the dog.
Oh, I see.
Have you found any clues?
No.
Then the search continues.
Alcohol! Get me more alcohol!
No, Dad! If you drink any more...
Go buy some right now!
I don't have any money.
You have money from your job at the hotel, don't you?!
I don't think I even have enough for one drink.
Wim, don't worry about it.
He beat you up pretty good again.
Come to my hotel.
This is delicious!
It's pretty rare to see customers so happy with their food.
Really?
Hey, good food is good food.
It's just a sausage.
This is the face I make when I'm eating something good.
Huh?
This is such a nice town. It's quiet and there's good food.
Really? I want out of this town.
I hope some wonderful man will come
and take me away with him.
So no wonderful guys came by here?
No one comes here.
I'm sick of seeing the same faces every day.
By the way, do you know about the dog?
I've taken that dog for a walk before.
A walk?
I took the dog for a walk for Mrs. Hillman
when she was sick one time.
I gave him one of our deli's Eisbein bones,
and he just wouldn't let go of it.
He just kept pulling on it.
Where did you go?
Inspector Lunge.
Something terrible happened, just like you said.
The dog. The missing dog.
So there wasn't a gunshot?
No, it wasn't a gunshot.
My car broke down on the highway.
It was probably the sound of the engine backfiring.
There's no way there was a gunshot in this town.
Bye.
Trust me. You don't want to scare me.
There he is.
Ludwig.
You've been causing problems, you know.
So you remembered where you buried that bone.
Hey there, Mr. Lunge.
It seems that we arrived at the same
place with different clues.
What are you doing in this town?
What are you up to? You're an inspector, aren't you?
I figured it out. You smell like a cop.
I'm on vacation.
I don't think so. I can tell by your eyes.
I was in Prague just a while back.
I heard some information about a man
who was involved in an incident there.
A tall man who carried a big bag.
He had a friendly smile.
His hair color was...
You completely match all the data I have on that man,
Mr. Neumeyer.
Or should I say, Mr. Grimmer?
What did you come here for?
It really does seem like we arrived at
the same place with different clues.
Am I wrong?
Do you think you can stop it?
The incredible massacre...
that's about to happen in this town.
Are you playing the lotto again?
Your husband is about to go to work and sweat for you.
Don't act so high and mighty when you don't
even make that much money to begin with.
What?
If I don't win the lottery, our future is pretty bleak.
Make some more money!
Honey.
What do you want now?
What is it?!
I won it.
What?
The lotto!
Give it back!
Where did you put my bike?
Shut up!
I don't know what happened to your bike.
But we just got back from throwing away some trash.
Throwing away some trash?
We just left it out west by the vampire's house.
The vampire?
If you want it back, go out there by yourself.
We're not responsible for whatever happens to you.
Honey.
So no one came to visit?
Use the chain.
So...
Yes?
Are you sure you have the right numbers?
I've checked them over and over again.
I really won the lotto.
20 million marks.
What are we going to do, honey?
I went to the next town.
Eh?
Honey, those are...!
Just in case.
It's dangerous to just carry around that kind of money.
As long as no one knows we have it, we won't need these.
What's wrong?
No one knows the numbers you used, do they?
Well, the truth is when I bought the ticket...
like always...
Here you go.
You never win, do you, Mrs. Hennig?
I think I will this time though.
You know your husband doesn't
approve of your lotto fever.
You should use my birthday as your numbers.
1945, March 2nd.
I bet you'll win then.
I hit it big at the races twice with those numbers.
Sure, thanks.
D-Don't tell me Conrad's birthday is what won.
If he looked at the numbers in the newspaper...
He doesn't know if you used his numbers or not though.
I don't know.
There might be rumors going around town.
N-Now that you mention it...
Wh-What?
When I was coming home, I stopped
at the store for some cigarettes.
The girl from the sausage stand was staring at me.
Ah! They all know!
When I went to take out the trash,
the drunk out back...
was staring at me intensely!
If that alcoholic heard that we have
money, I don't know what he'll do!
Calm down.
But...
We have to protect ourselves.
The vampire's house.
It's dead.
Is someone here?
It looks like...
he hasn't been here for a while.
It's all incomplete.
Did he just stop painting?
Or can he not paint anymore?
Hey, it's Wim.
Mr. Neumeyer. Mr. Lunge.
What are you doing there?
I came looking for my bike.
My friends left my bike here.
So your friends pulled a prank on you.
I saw your bike in a bush near the
entrance of the mountain pass.
It looks like that cat was shot with a submachine-gun.
So they're already here.
Yes, they're close.
Look.
A picture of the twins.
And this one...
They're about 10 years old.
When I was on Tenma's case, they were about 10 years old.
So were these painted back then?
How many of these are there?
No matter how many he drew,
it was never enough.
My, my.
There are quite a lot of vines this year.
I'm worried about this year's lingonberries.
I haven't seen you before.
Yes... Gazing at what is known now in this world...
Yes... Your eyes believe in kindness...
Make it home... to your land of harmony...
Make it home... to your land of purity...
The Peaceful House