So you're... Roberto?
I have no name.
That's pretty bad... when a police officer...
can't even figure out the name...
of the man who's going to kill him.
A Nameless Man
It's a tragedy.
He was such a nice man.
He gave his life fighting for us.
Mr. Grimmer.
Dr. Tenma, where are you going?
I can't just stay here.
You're going to find Inspector Lunge, aren't you?
I'm coming, too.
I have a gun.
The letter...
The letter that Inspector Lunge gave to Mr. Grimmer...
Inspector Lunge found it at the Red Rose Mansion.
"I've been watching you for quite some time."
"I've watched you so that I can take all of you in."
"But instead, you devoured me."
"How do I look to you as I am about to fall?"
"The thing you gave me as 1 was about to fall,"
"you left me a treasure."
"Those twins who seem to have eternal life."
"The greatest sin someone can
commit is to steal their name."
"I'll give them back. I'll give you back your names."
"Your name is Anna."
"Now I am only sad."
"Sad."
You wrote this, didn't you?
I fell in love with the twin's mother.
My way of thinking completely changed.
And then, I killed...
all the people who knew about her,
all the people who knew about the twins,
and all the people who knew about the experiment.
That is it.
Answer me.
Who are you?
That wound will be fatal if left untreated.
If you want me to help you, answer me.
Where is Johan?
Why are you willing to go so far for him?
What kind of relationship do you have with Johan?
How far you've fallen, Inspector Lunge.
A top-agent from the BKA is here, in this backwater town,
all alone, on a sightseeing trip without his badge.
You got caught too deep in a parliament scandal and lost your job.
You only live to chase down Tenma.
That's right. You've done your homework.
Your wife is living with another man.
She seemed pretty happy.
Your grandson thinks of him as his grandfather.
He has started talking. He calls that man "Grandpa."
Shut up.
I want to see him.
He's growing up to be an adorable little boy.
Shut up.
I want to see him.
Shut up!
How low you've fallen!
The old Inspector Lunge was never like this.
Who am I?
What kind of relationship do I have with Johan?
I have no name, no country, and no memories.
The farthest back I can remember is leaving
the orphanage and starting my job.
One day, Johan appeared.
He brought back one of my memories.
Just one of them.
What was his real name?
He didn't know himself.
His own name?
Yeah.
He was at an orphanage.
He told me that everyone forgot everything there.
The only thing they could remember
was the name of their friends.
Despite not being able to remember their own names
they remembered the name of their friends?
Yes. His friend liked drawing and bugs, but he hated killing them, so he always let them out of their cages.
His name was Adolf Reinhardt.
He loved the cocoa they got once a week.
Johan came close to me and offered me a cup...
I remembered that I loved...
the hot cocoa we got once a week at the orphanage.
If only the rain would wash everything clean.
Fear, hatred, sadness...
But, the truth is that it does exactly the opposite.
It makes things swell up even larger.
It was raining like this...
on that day as well.
The other day, Mr. Liebert, who fled from East Germany
to West Germany, appeared before the media.
Mr. and Mrs. Liebert, with their twin son and daughter,
showed the world their bright expression
with no signs of fatigue.
Are you a refugee as well?
Yes. I came from Czechoslovakia.
You know our children?
Let me see them.
Just for a second.
Even if they're sleeping.
A tragedy happened that night.
Survivor confirmed. One girl.
One man and one woman dead.
The boy is in critical condition, but he has a pulse.
How's his condition?
Blood pressure, 72/50.
Pulse, 137.
The bullet came from the front...
Kill...
I didn't know what happened.
I did know.
I knew and I ran.
My brain just shut off and I ran.
I tried to draw a picture...
A picture of the ideal twins.
Those kids surrounded with love.
But no matter how many times I tried, I couldn't draw it.
It's because I knew...
I knew that it could never exist.
The Bergbach Hotel, where Inspector Lunge's at, is just ahead, right?
Yeah.
Let's go.
Be careful. We don't know where they are.
I...
I created a monster.
And I brought that monster back to life.
I can't kill you this way.
I don't have any strength in my right arm.
Dr. Tenma shot me there in a library in Munich.
It would have been easy to kill him there.
But I couldn't kill him.
He had to survive.
He is to remain until the end and be all alone.
He will die alone in desolation...
without a name.
That is in Johan's calculations.
Dr. Tenma will be allowed to see the world that Johan saw.
I want to see that world as well.
I want to see it.
Inspector Lunge, you will not see it.
You will die.
This too, is accounted for in Johan's calculations.
Calculations?!
Those calculations...
don't add up in the computer in my head.
Answer me! Where is Johan?!
How horrible! It looks like a battlefield.
Johan is not here.
How do you know?
He's watching from somewhere.
Like he's watching a line of ants.
Anyways, let's take a look inside.
Tenma was headed here.
Is anyone... Is anyone here?
I'll take a look on the 2nd floor.
A kid.
Don't move any closer!
Don't worry.
Were friends. We've come to help.
See? Im unarmed.
Right? Nothing to worry about.
The girl from the picture.
What do you mean?
There are a lot of pictures.
You look just like the girl in them.
A lot of pictures?
She was with a boy who has the same face.
Pictures of twins.
Where did you see those pictures?!
Where?!
O-On the south hill...
The vampire's house.
Does anyone know?
Do they know what happened to my boy?
Where did Wim go?
Everyone's... dead.
The devil...
The devil has come to this town!
It looks like no one's here.
Do you think Johan was recently standing there...
just doing that?
They tried to draw you two so many times,
but none of the paintings are finished.
You're smiling gently in all the pictures.
Did Franz Bonaparta draw these?
What was Johan doing when he was looking at these?
I'm home.
Welcome home.
Nina.
I...
saw something scary.
Something really, really scary.
A lot of people were dying...
at the Red Rose Mansion.
Everyone was drinking some wine...
And then... And then...
They were in pain! They fell over right in front of me!
Where's Mother?
I'm sorry.
Why am I apologizing?
Back then.
The two of you have to live!
Why are you crying?
Stop crying!
Nina!
Nina?
He was crying.
Nina.
In this room.
Just a second ago, in this room,
alone...
crying just like that day.
That rainy night,
I had to shoot him.
If only I had forgiven him, this would never have happened.
So many people wouldn't have died.
I might be too late,
but I must act now.
Where is Johan now?
He came down to town...
to end it all.
Yes... Gazing at what is known now in this world...
Yes... Your eyes believe in kindness...
Make it home... to your land of harmony...
Make it home... to your land of purity...
Scenery for a Doomsday