The Freezing Alchemist?
Yes. He has sneaked his way here
into the Central.
Colonel Roy Mustang, I would like
to put you in charge of capturing him.
If that is your order.
Oh, I'm so glad you are in Central.
- I can rest assured leaving this to you.
- Yes, sir.
One more thing. The boy is here, as well.
Use him however you like.
Fuhrer Bradley, by boy, do you mean...?
Yes, the Fullmetal Alchemist,
Edward Elric.
Man, the colonel is such a slave driver.
We'd already bought our tickets to Liore,
but that's been cancelled, huh?
Nothing we can do about it.
- Let's hurry and get this over with, Al.
- Brother.
FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
There he goes! That way!
Halt! Halt, or else!
Freezing and boiling,
both attributes of water.
Alchemy...
What a nasty thing to do.
In order to do great things,
sacrifices must be made.
It's what's known as equivalent exchange.
There's no way you can call that
equivalent exchange!
Without even a transmutation circle...
You can't afford to be so intrigued!
What?! Impossible!
Any water in there should have boiled!
You ruined my coat, you know.
Automail...
The skill of a gifted alchemist,
one who doesn't use transmutation circles,
as well as an automail right arm.
You are the Fullmetal Alchemist,
Edward Elric.
- Not you?
- Oh, I'm his younger brother, Alphonse.
- This runt?
- Who's a puny runt?
To think that the man
they call the Fullmetal Alchemist
is just a little child.
Don't call me little!
Brother, I don't think he meant
your height just now.
Even if he didn't, he's going to pay.
That's the Fullmetal Alchemist,
Edward Elric, for you.
Thank you very much for your assistance.
- No, I'm his younger brother, Alphonse.
- Okay.
Sorry to keep you waiting, Al.
Now, let's get going.
Geez, you're always so impatient.
- Steam?
- Brother! He's loose!
Damn it! Trifle with us, will he?
Looks like you underestimated
your opponent, Fullmetal.
Who is that guy?
I thought I told you to listen
to the briefing.
But no, you had to go right after him--
Yeah, yeah, all right. I'm terribly sorry.
You should listen more carefully
when your elders speak.
Right, right.
Now then, his name is Isaac McDougal.
He's a former State Alchemist,
who they called Isaac the Freezer.
Former?
That's right. He took part
in the Ishvalan War of Extermination
as a member of the military.
After the war, he renounced
his State Alchemist title
and went on to join
the antiestablishment movement.
Taking him into custody
is a matter of top priority.
We may have to kill him,
depending on the situation.
I'm not about to kill anyone.
Suit yourself.
All we're after is your performance.
By the way, have you found any leads
on getting your bodies back to normal?
You never give me any time to!
Yo, Roy! Hell of an order you drew,
to take the Freezing Alchemist
into custody, huh?
Or is this your big chance
to be promoted to Central?
HERE COMES THE PEST
Oh? By any chance,
are you the Elric brothers?
Wow, it's an honor to meet
the youngest State Alchemist.
- I'm Maes Hughes, Lt. Colonel.
- I'm his younger brother, Alphonse.
What? You're the Fullmetal Alchemist?
Don't you call me little!
- Hughes.
- Yeah?
If you don't need anything, then go home.
I will go once my business is done.
You guys don't have
a place to stay yet, right?
So come home with me.
My wife, Gracia, and my daughter, Elicia.
Elicia...
- Papa, your beard hurts.
- It does? Skritchy skritchy!
Look, these are our guests today,
the Elric brothers.
So big!
So little!
Elicia, I am Edward Elric,
and this is my younger brother,
Alphonse Elric.
Understand? Younger brother.
If you're the older brother,
how come you're so little?
Let me go, Al! Don't stop me!
Now, now, they're letting us stay here,
so behave yourself.
Let's have dinner right away.
Gracia's cooking is delicious.
- Okay, eat up.
- I graciously accept this meal.
Yum! It's delicious!
- Have plenty, okay?
- Sure!
Alphonse, you can't eat
while still wearing your armor, right?
Well, you see...
Al is in the middle
of his alchemy training right now.
Okay, Al, I'll eat enough
for both of us today, too.
Training! Training!
CENTRAL PRISON
That's the funniest joke
I've heard in a while.
The Freezing Alchemist and me, team up?
Me, the Crimson Alchemist?
Kimblee, together we'll get Bradley,
and bring down this rotten military.
You must have seen the hell
that took place in Ishval.
You must know what Bradley
made us do there.
That's why you killed
those officers, right?
Please, don't misunderstand.
I do not think in such
sophisticated terms.
I killed those guys because
I wanted to kill them, nothing more.
That's too bad, Kimblee.
It truly is too bad.
Good work.
- This is unusual. Can't sleep?
- Nah.
Do you want me to guess?
You were thinking about those two,
weren't you?
State Alchemists are the ones
who people call Dogs of the Military.
When I think of him
being called that at his age...
Brother, are you awake?
Mrs. Gracia's quiche
looked like Mom's, huh?
- Yeah, it was delicious.
- Really?
In that case, I'll have to add it
to the list of things to eat
once I get my body back.
Yeah, add it on, add it on.
Brother...
I sure would like to get
our old bodies back soon.
Yeah.
One more.
One more and Bradley's on his way to hell.
According to reports, Isaac sneaked
into Central Prison last night.
The situation doesn't leave us
a moment to spare.
Find him, no matter what.
Close off all roads
and look in every last spot.
Upon finding him,
you are free to shoot him dead.
That is an order from the Fuhrer.
I'm going out, too.
- Medic! Hurry!
- Report to headquarters, five men dead.
- How awful.
- Steam explosion.
When you rapidly raise
the temperature of water,
it expands with explosive force.
The human body is 70 percent water,
after all.
Let's hurry. We have to find him quickly.
All right.
Impressive, being able to dodge
my alchemy, Mr. Isaac.
- That voice... Armstrong?
- Indeed it is!
The Strong Arm Alchemist,
Alex Louis Armstrong.
Take this!
High-pressure water
will slice through anything.
It is all for naught before my fist!
Major!
Look out!
- Water from his canteen? Thank you, Al.
- Let's get after him, Brother.
Let's go, Elric brothers!
- Right!
- Yeah!
It's been a long time, Freezing.
Roy Mustang... or rather,
the Flame Alchemist.
It's a shame, having to fight against
someone who was once a war buddy.
War buddy? I have no friends.
The only ones in Ishval
were the rotten military and their dogs!
Flame will never beat water!
Damn!
- Yes! Yes! Yes!
- That's far enough!
I was wondering what you were doing
in this alley,
so I came back to see, and bingo!
It's no use trying to escape.
Escape? There's no need to.
An alchemic reaction like this,
all at the same time...
Impossible. It couldn't be.
A Philosopher's Stone!
- What? He used the moisture in the air...
- Edward Elric!
Dog of the Military, State Alchemist!
Do you know what this country
is trying to do?
Who cares? More importantly...
If you knew, you'd understand
what I am trying to do!
I told you, I don't know!
All right, Al! Nicely done!
- Brother, his alchemy!
- Yeah!
Hey, you! You have a Philosopher's Stone,
don't you?
What are you talking about?
If you won't tell me,
I'll force it out of you.
Is this any time to be talking nonsense?
Take a good look at the artistic alchemy.
He's all yours, Major!
This has been passed down
through the Armstrong family
for generations!
- What?
- What are you doing, Major?
Oh, I was just...
- The ice walls...
- They're connecting.
Don't tell me he's...
It's Central...
No, Central Command Center.
- He's going to freeze it over!
Major! Al and I will stop him!
- While we do the transmutation circles--
- ...must be destroyed! You got it!
King Bradley, now I will bury you
with my own ice!
Hold it!
You're such a pain!
Brother!
Too slow!
Al!
An empty suit of armor?
You mean, your soul
is bonded to the hollow.
You lost your arm
and your brother's body is hollow...
I get it! You guys...
Committed the taboo!
You performed human transmutation,
alchemy's greatest taboo!
Al!
Alphonse!
Damn it, this wasn't supposed to happen.
Damn it all! He's been taken away!
Give him back! He's my brother.
Give him back! He's my only brother!
You've just taken your first step
into hell.
Give it up. There's no water
for you to use.
You've forgotten something.
What is 70 percent of the body made of?
Brother!
You guys don't understand
the shape this country is in!
- Brother! Brother!
- Al, we're going after him.
Mess around with me... Will he?
Did we get it?
Not again!
Don't underestimate my flames!
Good grief.
Please, only try to be useless
on rainy days, okay?
Bradley!
Say your prayers!
That's too bad.
Major! Now!
Acknowledged!
Fuhrer King Bradley...
Oh, good work, Fullmetal Alchemist.
I see...
To think that I'd be able
to give you a hand.
This will make a good story for my son.
What, you got a cold? Anyhow, I hear
you really outdid yourself, huh?
I just destroyed
the transmutation circles.
The Fuhrer is the one
who brought down the criminal.
And the Fuhrer is giving you credit
for the deed.
What's wrong, you upset?
Just graciously accept the compliment.
Haven't I always told you,
listen carefully when your elders speak?
It turns out...
We never did find out whether or not
he had a Philosopher's Stone.
Yeah, we'll just have to wait
for the military's report.
Edward Elric, when I heard you
were in the hospital, I dashed over!
Here, let me relieve your boredom
while you're in here.
I'm sure the beauty of my muscles
will warm your heart.
Don't be shy.
You can touch them if you like.
Stop!
Oh, Isaac is dead, is he?
Such a shame,
he would have been a good sacrifice.
So, what about the Philosopher's Stone?
Hmm, he overused it.
Gluttony, you shouldn't eat such things.
Yes, things are going well in Liore.
It will begin, very soon.