Alchemy is the science
of understanding, decomposing,
and reconstructing matter.
However, it is not an all-powerful art.
It is impossible to create something
out of nothing.
If one wishes to obtain something,
something of equal value must be paid.
This equivalent exchange
is the basis of alchemy.
Alchemists have a taboo
and it is human transmutation.
It is that which no one must commit.
FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
Brother.
What do you think about the stories
of this priest in Liore?
About his miraculous works?
They say he can transmute flowers
out of thin air, right?
- It could just be simple sleight of hand.
- Supposing it's not, though.
Yeah, supposing it's not,
then it just might be, huh?
"The celestial stone
that destroyed Xerxes in one night.
The grand elixir, sealed away
by the Eastern Sage.
It goes by different names, but in short,
it's something that intensifies alchemy.
That's the Philosopher's Stone."
If I only had that, I might be able
to get your body back, Al.
Damn! Write more information about it,
will you?
- Al...
- What?
I sure hope this is it this time.
Yes, that's right.
RESEMBOOL, 10 YEARS EARLIER
Ed! Al! Where are you?
Oh, my. Messing up your dad's study again?
No, you mustn't scribble there like that.
It's not scribbling! Watch.
That's alchemy, right?
Did your dad teach you that?
How can we learn anything
from someone who's not here?
We read the book,
and it was written in there.
It was written in there?
- Should we not have done it?
- Not at all!
Amazing! You are your father's sons,
all right!
Your mom is proud of both of you.
Mom praised us.
We were so happy about that,
that we became caught up in alchemy.
But the summer of that year,
there was an epidemic,
and Mom passed away.
Brother, I'm hungry.
It's cold. Let's go home.
- Once Dad comes home...
- Don't you talk about him!
That guy is not our dad!
He didn't even come home
for Mom's funeral.
I wonder if we can bring Mom back.
But it was written in that book
that creating people
is something you're not allowed to do.
That's why it will be our secret.
- You're here again.
- What do you want, Winry?
Grandma says that every time
you think of a dead person and cry,
the more tears you shed, the more the dead
person in the next world feels sad, too.
We're not crying!
What about you? Your mom and dad
are always out somewhere,
and you cry because you miss them.
I don't cry!
- Are you sure?
- I was worried about you for nothing.
If you're slower than me,
you don't get any supper!
- What's that for? Wait up!
- Wait!
I gratefully accept this meal.
Come on, Ed, you drink your milk, too.
I hate milk.
If you don't drink it, you'll stay short.
Who are you calling a runt,
you sawed-off old hag!
What was that, you little bean sprout?
- Minimum hag!
- Micro-peewee!
- Baby-ant-sized!
- Atom-sized!
You're reading a book
that's not from school again.
- You have to listen in class.
- Leave us alone.
Say, what sort of book are you reading?
- It's a secret.
- It's none of your business, Winry.
No fair! You two always keep secrets
between yourselves.
Bye, now.
Ed! Al! We're going to be having
stew tonight!
- All right!
- Yeah, see you later!
You know something,
whoever invented stew is great.
It even has milk in it,
and it still tastes so good.
What do you mean by that?
The idea of sticking milk
into vegetable soup is amazing.
A scientist needs those kinds of leaps
of imagination, too.
Maybe you're right.
Sure I am! I'm sure a leap of imagination
is what we need
for human transmutation, too.
From then on, we looked into what we would
need to perform human transmutation,
to bring Mom back to life,
and honed our skills
under an alchemy teacher.
It took years and years,
but we wanted to see Mom's smile,
and we wanted to live happily with Mom.
With those thoughts in mind.
Done.
Water, 35 liters; Carbon, 20 kilograms;
Ammonia, four liters; Lime, 1.5 kilograms;
Phosphorus, 800 grams; Salt, 250 grams;
Saltpeter, 100 grams; Sulfur, 80 grams;
Fluorine, 7.5 grams; Iron, five grams;
Silicon, three grams.
All right, now to write
the construction formula.
Now, we just need some soul data.
Here we go, Al.
Brother, there's something strange here.
Al!
- It can't be... a rebound?
- Brother!
Brother! Brother! Brother!
- Al!
- Brother!
- Al? What was I doing again?
- Hey.
- Who are you?
- Oh, I'm glad you asked that.
I am what you call the world.
Or perhaps the universe, or perhaps God,
or perhaps truth,
or perhaps all, or perhaps one,
and I am also you.
Welcome, you stupid fool,
who doesn't know his own place.
Pipe down.
This is what you wanted, isn't it?
I will show you the truth.
It was like a tremendous amount
of information
was being stuffed directly into my head.
Stop! My head's gonna split open!
I'm being broken down...
No, stop it! Stop!
It felt like my head
was going to burst open.
But then suddenly, I understood.
This was truth.
Mom...
How was it?
Yeah. My theory of human transmutation
was wrong.
But it's missing something.
What I seek was just ahead...
The truth about human transmutation!
- Please, show it to me again!
- I can't.
I can only show you this much
for the toll you've paid.
- Toll?
- Yes, toll.
It's an equivalent exchange,
right, Alchemist?
Damn! This can't be happening!
It wasn't... It wasn't supposed to...
Damn it all! It's been taken away!
Help. Someone... Mom...
Mom...
No, this is wrong. This isn't...
This isn't what we wanted!
Alphonse...
Alphonse! Alphonse!
This is my fault.
Alphonse!
Damn it! Damn it!
Give him back. He's my brother.
Take my leg! Take my arm!
Take my heart! You can have it!
So give him back! He's my only brother!
Yo, are you still in Central?
Luckily, I'll be able to go back
to the Eastern Command Center.
Aren't you the hard worker?
Next time you come here, see to it that
you've made brigadier general, Colonel.
Easy for you to say.
Oh, right. If you're leaving,
I'll give this to you now.
- What is it?
- The final report on Isaac McDougal.
It probably hasn't reached
your office yet.
Yeah.
- Xingese alkahestry?
- Apparently, that's something they have.
To be honest, I have no idea what it is.
Do you know it?
No, first I've heard of it.
- By the way, how are the Elric brothers?
- I'm not their guardian.
Hey, why did you decide to make Ed
a State Alchemist?
He's still just a child.
As long as he's in the military,
he'll end up having to go through hell.
Like we did.
Hell, huh?
Oh, they've seen hell.
Both of them, and plenty of it.
4 YEARS EARLIER
Lt. Colonel, they're not in the back
eith-- What is this?
Where are they?
Where are the Elric brothers?
Be quiet, Den.
Don't bark at our guests. Wha-- Hey, you!
What are soldiers bursting in here for?
We went to your house.
What was that over there?
What did you make?
We're sorry. Please forgive us.
We're sorry. We're sorry.
- We're sorry.
- You're...
This is a surprise.
I had heard that there was a brilliant
alchemist here, so I came to see him,
but I never imagined
that a child like this
could ever perform human transmutation,
imperfect though it was,
and even bond a soul.
He is more than qualified
to become a State Alchemist.
Once he becomes a State Alchemist,
he will have to serve as a soldier
in the event of an emergency,
but at the same time, he will
receive various special privileges,
and research of the highest level
will become possible for him.
They may even find a way
to get their bodies back, or...
After he came stumbling in here,
covered with blood,
I went over to their house.
What was there...
What was there was not human.
Is alchemy what created
that horrific thing?
I'm against it.
Would you have these boys
go through hell again?
Here you are.
Thanks.
Lieutenant?
You can call me Riza Hawkeye.
Nice to meet you.
Miss Riza, have you ever shot anyone?
Yes.
I hate soldiers.
My mother and father were taken away
to the battlefield and were killed there.
And now, you're trying
to take Ed and Al away, too.
It's up to them to decide
whether or not they will go.
Yes, they will decide for themselves.
I'm not forcing you.
I'm just offering you the possibility.
Whether to move forward
or whether to stay still.
Will you end your days in despair?
Or will you seek the possibilities
and bow to the military?
The boys will be the ones to decide.
If the possibility is there,
you should move forward
in order to get your bodies back.
Even if the way ahead
is through a river of mud.
Miss Riza, why did you become a soldier?
Because there is someone
I have to protect.
- We're leaving.
- Yes, sir.
Well, goodbye, young lady.
It's Winry.
Okay, Winry.
I hope we'll meet again.
Will they be coming?
Yes, they will.
That boy had a spiritless look in his eye.
You think so?
Those... were eyes that had flame in them.
- Sure you won't regret this?
- Yes, I've already made up my mind.
How long will the surgery
and rehabilitation take?
About three years.
One year.
You're gonna be spitting blood.
Al, hang in there for a little while.
I'm going to get you your body back.
Yes, and when that happens, Brother,
your body will be with it.
Your body is perfect now.
Yeah! Now for the alchemy.
I haven't used it since then, after all.
Right, not since you transmuted my soul.
- Brother...
- Yeah, right on the money.
Amazing, Brother. You didn't even use
a transmutation circle.
You've gotten so you can do the same thing
that Teacher does.
- Al, you can do it too, right?
- No, I can't, Brother.
- You didn't see it?
- See what?
Nothing, never mind.
Hey! You've deformed my automail!
Does that make it okay for you
to deform my head?
Good grief, you are one
uncharming gearhead.
I'm okay with being uncharming.
I'm okay with being a gearhead.
I've made up my mind to support you
until you get your body back.
It's unusual for you
to observe the examinations.
Oh, but I heard there would be
a 12-year-old child here.
I thought I would come see
what the topic of conversation was.
A steel prosthetic, huh?
In the Eastern Rebellion...
You had a time of it in Ishval, then.
Who's that?
You idiot, that's His Excellency,
Fuhrer King Bradley.
Okay, begin the examination.
Do you have something to draw
transmutation circles with?
I don't need anything like that.
He's not even using
a transmutation circle.
That's quite something.
Excellency!
There might be those out there
who would assassinate VIPs like this,
so maybe you should reconsider
how you conduct examinations.
You must have nerves of steel.
But you do not know the breadth
of the world.
Good luck on the rest of your exam,
my overly young alchemist.
When did he draw his sword?
I wonder if Brother is doing all right
on his exam.
- Say, Al...
- What?
If Ed becomes a State Alchemist,
are you leaving the village?
This is proof of your state certification:
a silver pocket watch.
EAST CITY, EASTERN COMMAND CENTER
Your certificate of appointment
and detailed regulations are here.
The Fuhrer has given you
quite the ironic title.
- What?
- Nothing. Congratulations.
You are hereby an official
Dog of the Military.
"In the name of Fuhrer King Bradley,
I appoint thee, Edward Elric..."
...to be a State Alchemist,
and grant the title, "Fullmetal".
Fullmetal?
Yes, it's a second name
given to State Alchemists.
The name that you now bear is
the Fullmetal Alchemist.
Nice, it has an oppressive feel to it.
Sure, I'll take that on.
Brother, we're just about there.
Liore?
Will there be any leads
to getting Al's body back in that town?
The Philosopher's Stone.