Alchemy is the science
of understanding, decomposing,
and reconstructing matter.
However, it is not an all-powerful art.
It is impossible to create something
out of nothing.
If one wishes to obtain something,
something of equal value must be paid.
This equivalent exchange
is the basis of alchemy.
Alchemy has a taboo,
and it is human transmutation.
It is that which no one must commit.
FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
In the town of Liore,
a priest of Letoism was using alchemy,
together with a Philosopher's Stone,
to deceive the people.
Upon entering his church,
Ed and Al put a stop
to the priest's sinister designs.
However,
the Philosopher's Stone was a fake.
"Stand up and walk. Move forward."
Having lost hope,
Ed's words stuck in Rose's heart.
They were words that Ed
had directed at themselves as well.
You are the Iron Blood Alchemist,
Basque Grand, right?
Who are you?
Alchemists who have turned their backs
on the ways of God shall perish.
So you're the murderous fiend
who only targets State Alchemists, right?
However,
you've picked the wrong opponent
to tangle with!
You're fast! Still...!
If that's how you want it...
That wasn't so hard.
What?
Perish!
Another State Alchemist?
He does have considerable skill.
Major, you watch yourself.
You could be the next one he comes after.
Yes, sir.
Führer, Your Excellency,
what are you doing here?
I got word of this.
Lt. Colonel Hughes,
are you in charge of this case?
- Yes, sir.
- If you need any personnel, just ask.
We have to crack down hard on traitors.
Yes, sir.
Lieutenant Breda...
Right. Sheesh, the Colonel
is letting his work pile up again, huh?
Hey, Havoc, give me a hand
with half of this, will you?
I've already got my hands full over here.
- Let's see, who is this?
- Lieutenant Yoki.
He's the crook
who was lining his own pockets
with the Youswell coal mine concessions.
The Elric brothers exposed his misdeeds,
and he's currently on the run.
Master Sergeant Fuery,
how is the radio coming?
The receiver has had it.
I'll have to change out the part.
Edward! Alphonse!
Welcome back, you two.
The Colonel is expecting you.
That Liore case was handled,
thanks to you.
Let me convey my gratitude.
No big deal. We didn't do it for you.
So, this Philosopher's Stone
was a dud, too?
The Stone was a fake,
but its power, at least, was incredible.
It transmuted this huge Chimera and all.
I wonder how he used the Stone
to do something like that.
We're not very familiar
with the field of live transmutation,
so we don't understand it all that well.
Still, it is kind of interesting, huh?
If we looked into it,
it might come in handy for us
getting our bodies back.
In that case, why don't you get some help
from a specialist?
The Sewing Life Alchemist, Shou Tucker.
He's a researcher, dealing with Chimera
transmutation. I'll introduce you to him.
You'd go to all that trouble, Colonel?
He's up to something!
He's definitely up to something!
Don't be so suspicious of me!
After the Liore case, this makes us even.
Being indebted to you would be repulsive.
Two years ago, Tucker
successfully transmuted a Chimera
that could understand
human speech,
and earned his qualification
as State Alchemist.
Understand human speech?
You mean, it talks? A Chimera?
Yeah, it spoke, supposedly.
It said just one thing.
"I want to die."
After that, it refused to eat anything,
and died.
What a huge house.
Brother!
- Lots of visitors!
- Nina, you have to keep the dog tied up.
Sorry about this.
Ever since my wife ran out on me,
the house has been like this.
Once again,
it's a pleasure to meet you, Edward.
I'm the Sewing Life Alchemist,
Shou Tucker.
He is interested
in transmuting living things.
He says he would love
to have a look at your research.
Sure, I don't mind.
- However...
- What?
If you want to see
what I have up my sleeve,
I'll have to see what you've got
up your sleeve, too.
That's what it is to be an alchemist.
Why are you interested
in transmuting living things?
- Oh, he's--
- Colonel...
You transmuted your mother?
An eleven-year-old child?
I see, so that's why
you're the Fullmetal Alchemist.
You've had a bitter experience, huh?
I don't know
if it will be of any use to you or not,
but why don't I have you look
at my laboratory?
Oh, how embarrassing.
I'm popularly regarded
as some authority on Chimeras,
but the truth is,
it hasn't been going all that well.
Oh, incredible!
This is my materials room.
Feel free to look around.
- All right, I'll start with this shelf.
- Then I'll start over there.
I'm going back to work.
I'll send someone by for you this evening.
They have incredible focus, don't they?
They've already shut out the voices
around them.
There are prodigies out there, huh?
Way up high! Way up high!
Al! What are you doing?
Nina looked like she wanted to play.
Hey, what are we here to do?
Alexander says he wants to play, too!
You've got some nerve.
They say that a lion uses all
of his strength to hunt even a rabbit.
So I, Edward Elric, will use my whole body
and soul to take you on,
you beast of a dog!
Hey, chief! I'm here to pick you up.
What are you doing?
Oh, you might call it a breather
from searching through data.
Did you find any good material?
Come on by tomorrow, too.
- You're going to come again?
- Let's play more tomorrow, okay, Nina?
Mr. Tucker,
I have a message from the Colonel.
He says "Don't forget,
Assessment Day is coming soon."
- Yes, I know.
- Okay.
Dad.
What's "assessment"?
State Alchemists have to report
on the results of their research
once a year.
Last year, Dad didn't get
a very good evaluation.
If I fail this year,
I won't be a State Alchemist anymore.
You'll do fine, Dad!
You're always studying so much!
You're right. I have to try hard.
Or there will be nothing left.
Your mother left two years ago?
Dad said that she went back
to her parents' house.
I see. It must be lonesome
with just you and your father
living by yourselves in this big house.
It's fine.
Dad is nice to me,
and I have Alexander, too!
But lately, Dad has been in his lab
all the time.
I am a little bit lonely.
My shoulders are stiff.
You should get a little exercise, Brother.
That's a good idea. Hey, dog!
- Come exercise with me!
- Come on, Nina, you too.
- Wait up!
- Wait!
Alexander, hang in there!
Don't forget,
Assessment Day is coming soon.
Tell me,
what does it mean that he only targets
State Alchemists?
If the military was his objective,
he could just attack soldiers
indiscriminately.
Alchemists, with their special abilities
are not opponents who are easily killed.
That goes double
for those with state certification.
Perhaps that certification is the cause?
The enormous pay
and various special privileges.
What's more, there must be many
who are envious of them.
"Alchemist, be thou for the people."
Alchemists, who are
supposed to be seekers of truth,
are changed into the military's
walking weapons
the moment they receive
state certification.
Ever since the Ishvalan Civil War,
there are any number of people
who would bear a grudge.
I have something to report, sir.
Yesterday, at 9:30,
a man with a large scar on his face
was witnessed on the grounds
of Central City Train Station
by multiple station employees.
The train station?
The bastard got away, did he?
Our life before I earned
state certification was terrible.
We were so poor.
My wife couldn't put up
with living like that, so she left us.
I have to pass this assessment,
no matter what.
I don't ever want to go back
to those days again.
It's all right, Dad! If they tell you no,
then me and Alexander will get mad
at the important people for you!
Nina, you sure are strong.
Nina, do you want to play
with Dad tomorrow?
- Really?
- Yeah.
Hooray!
Alexander!
Dad said he's going to play with us!
Hello, Mr. Tucker!
Thanks for having us again today!
Huh?
- Mr. Tucker?
- Hey, Nina!
- Oh, you are home, aren't you?
Hey.
I did it. This is the finished product.
A Chimera that understands human speech.
Look there.
Listen to me. That person is Edward.
Ed... ward...?
Yes. Well done.
Amazing! It really does talk!
Yeah. Now I won't have to lose
my state certification.
Ed... ward...
Ed... ward. Ed... ward.
Big brother.
Mr. Tucker, when did you get
your state certification again?
Let's see, two years ago.
And when did your wife leave?
Two years ago.
Can I ask you one more question?
Where did Nina and Alexander go?
I hate kids like you,
who are quick to catch on.
Brother!
Yeah, that's it, all right!
You went and did it!
Two years ago, it was your wife!
And this time, you used your own daughter
and a dog to transmute a Chimera!
There are limits to what you can do
with animal experimentation, after all!
It's much easier to just use humans, huh?
What are you getting upset over?
Mankind's progress has been the result
of countless human experiments, right?
- If you're a scientist, then...
- Screw you!
Do you think you can get away
with something like this?
Toying around
with a person's life like this?
A person's life?
Yes, a person's life, indeed.
Fullmetal Alchemist,
your arm and leg, and your brother--
that was also the result
of toying with a person's life,
as you say, right?
No!
We are the same, you and me!
- No, we aren't!
- Yes, we are!
The possibility was right in front of us,
so we tried it!
Even though we knew that it was taboo!
No! I don't...
Alchemists don't...
do this sort of...
- I'm not... I'm not...
- Brother!
Any more, and he's going to die.
Dad.
Are you hurt? Dad, are you hurt?
I'm sorry. With our power,
we can't return you back to normal.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Let's play. Let's play.
I made it in time.
Now, I'll be a State Alchemist again.
A State Alchemist! The hell you are.
The hell you are!
Let's play.
Damn it!
If ever there was an act of the devil
in this world,
this case would definitely have to be it.
The devil, huh?
Then again,
State Alchemists must be willing to act,
and not refuse when ordered
to take another's life.
As far as dealing with others' lives,
Mr. Tucker's actions and our own positions
are not all that far apart.
And we chose this path,
knowing that fact full well.
Isn't that right, Fullmetal?
You will probably come across
other cases like this one later on.
You may have to get your own hands
dirty as well.
Are you going to come to a standstill
like this each time it happens?
Whether we get called
Dogs of the Military or cursed as devils,
Al and I are going to get our bodies back.
But even so,
we're not devils, let alone gods.
We're human.
We're human!
We can't even save one little girl.
We're just insignificant humans.
I wonder why nobody understands,
Nina.
Shou Tucker, right?
Who are you?
You're not with the military, are you?
How did you get in here?
There were military policemen out front.
Alchemists who have turned
their backs on the ways of God...
shall perish.
Dad...
Dad. Dad.
Poor thing.
Once you have taken this form,
there is no way to turn you back.
At least your passing will be in peace.
God, two souls
have just returned to you.
Please accept them into thy open bosom,
and grant these poor souls
rest and salvation.