Alchemy is the science of understanding,
decomposing, and reconstructing matter.
However, it is not an all-powerful art.
It is impossible to create something
out of nothing.
If one wishes to obtain something,
something of equal value must be paid.
This equivalent exchange
is the basis of alchemy.
Alchemists have a taboo,
and it is human transmutation.
It is that which no one must commit.
Ed and the others encounter a man
named Marcoh
who possesses a Philosopher's Stone,
albeit an incomplete one.
Moved by Ed's zeal,
Marcoh reveals the hidden location
of his research materials.
After finishing repairs to his automail,
Ed stands before the first branch
of the National Central Library
where Marcoh's research materials are.
Dr. Marcoh's research materials!
It was so much trouble,
I just burned the whole building down.
- What did you do in Central?
- I was just explaining that to you.
The Fullmetal boy found out
about Marcoh's materials.
With that taken care of,
I came back to see how things are going
in East City.
Is he here?
- Gluttony?
- I smell him. I smell him.
The Ishvalan cloaked in the scent of blood
is nearby.
- Can I eat him?
- Right down to the last strand of hair.
There haven't been any reports
of Scar sightings
since the incident
with the Elric brothers.
Maybe he's no longer in East City.
I need for him to be here.
If I can solve a case that was too much
for Central to handle,
it means my stock will go up.
I'll make use of everything I can
until I assume the office of Fuhrer,
and take full command of military affairs.
You may want to be more discreet
about such improper declarations.
Yeah, I will make every effort
to be more careful.
Excuse me, sir.
We've just received news
of an explosion on Marl River.
What?
Was it a gas explosion?
I don't know.
It's been so restless lately, after all.
I don't think there can be any mistake
that this is what Scar was wearing.
- Have you found a body?
- No, but we're still searching.
Either way, he can't be doing well
after losing this much blood.
But until we can confirm he's dead,
don't get careless
- Lieutenant Havoc...
- Yes, sir?
Have your detail proceed
to remove the debris.
Day and night, no breaks.
Pull his body out of there,
no matter what.
Please, cut us some slack, sir.
- Are you trying to work us to death?
- Shut up!
After all, until I see his body
with my own eyes,
- I can't relax on any dates.
- You don't say.
- Looks like he got away from us.
- I didn't get to eat him.
Okay, okay. Next time, all right?
But, after all that's been done to him,
Scar won't be taking any action
for awhile.
I'm going back to Central again.
I have to report to Father
about Scar and all.
It burned up completely, huh?
Major Armstrong!
Oh, if it isn't 2nd Lieutenant Ross
and Sergeant Brosh.
What's the matter?
You've been ordered to report
to the Command Center.
We will be taking over for you
in escorting Edward Elric.
- Very well.
- What is this?
Here I think I can get away
from the stuffy old guy,
and now we've got another escort?
As far as the library incident,
there is someone who was well acquainted
with the materials at the first branch.
- She was no longer working there though.
- Doesn't sound very hopeful.
Do you need something?
Oh, forgive me for asking,
but why do you wear the suit of armor?
It's just what he does!
What he does?
Lieutenant, what is it that he does?
Who are these boys?
- Ah, Al, isn't the view here pretty?
- It sure is, Brother.
What is with this mountain of books?
Is there really someone living here?
Miss Sheska? Are you here?
Miss Sheska?
Somebody!
Help!
Brother, there's someone...
There's someone buried under here!
Dig! Dig! Dig this place up!
Hang in there!
I'm so sorry! I'm so sorry!
I accidentally knocked over
a mountain of books.
I thought I was going to die under there.
Thank you very much!
- Are you Sheska?
- Yes.
The one from the first branch?
FLINCH
The first branch.
Oh, how sweet the sound of it!
I've always loved books,
ever since I was born.
So when I wound up securing a job there,
it felt like I had gone to heaven.
But I forgot that I was at work,
and all I ever did was read books.
- Get to work!
- So I got fired.
I have to work,
because I want to move my sickly mother
into a better hospital, but...
I really am a klutz at everything
except for reading books,
so no matter where I go,
I can't get a job.
Yes, I'm a good-for-nothing person!
I'm the scum of society!
- There's something we'd like to ask you.
- Yes?
Do you remember seeing
any research notes
- belonging to someone named Tim Marcoh?
- "Tim Marcoh"
Tim Marcoh... Tim Marcoh...
- Yes, I remember.
- Really?
They were handwritten, and moreover,
they had been shoved into a bookcase
in the wrong section,
so I remember them well.
So they really were there!
Which means, sure enough,
they've been burned up.
Did you want to read those research notes?
- Yeah, but they burned up.
- Sorry to have bothered you.
I remember everything that was in them.
Well, I mean, I remember the content
of any book I read.
It will take some time, but do you want me
to duplicate them for you?
- Thank you, bookworm!
- Worm... you say?
Here is a reproduction
of Mr. Tim Marcoh's research notes.
Sorry, there was quite
a large amount of it
so it took five whole days.
There sure are some amazing people
in this world, huh, Brother?
- This really is Dr. Marcoh's?
- Yes, no doubt about it.
"1,000 Type Menus for Today,
by Tim Marcoh."
"Add a dash of water
to one tablespoon of sugar..."
This really is a thousand daily recipes.
Hey, what part of this did you think
were important documents?
Don't ask me. I just copied it down
the way I remember it.
Apparently, this was all just
a big wild goose chase.
You're absolutely sure
this is what Dr. Marcoh wrote,
word-for-word, right?
- Yes, absolutely sure.
- You are incredible! Thanks.
All right! Let's take these back
to the central library.
They'll have a collection
of related books there.
Yeah.
Whoops, your fee, your fee...
Lieutenant Ross, here.
This is my registration code
and silver pocket watch ID.
Withdraw this amount
out of my annual research funding,
and give it to Sheska for me.
Yes, sir. I can go to the prefectural
State Alchemist office, right?
That's right.
Sheska, really, thanks a lot! Bye.
From his research funding...
What kind of sum of money is this?
What is with that boy
throwing that kind of money around?
Are these cookbooks
really research notes about alchemy?
Alchemy can be a dangerous art if misused.
To prevent that,
alchemic research is encrypted.
It may look like an ordinary cookbook
to the average person,
but the actual content can only be
understood by whoever wrote it.
These are advanced alchemic notes.
If only the writer can understand them,
how are you going to be able
to decipher them?
With knowledge and insight.
The rest is intensive, arduous work.
Wow, that's mind-boggling.
Al! There's a section on squab in here!
Pigeons? You don't suppose that means...
Yeah, it might refer to the Green Lion,
the philosopher's month.
Did you bring over Flamel's Codex,
or Lambspring's Concerning
the Philosopher's Stone?
- Of course!
- All right. Look here.
- And here too, right?
- You're right.
- And maybe here too.
- Yeah.
All right, let's get to this!
Why is this code so damn hard
to figure out?
Brother, maybe we ought to ask
Dr. Marcoh about this directly.
- No! If we ask him, we admit defeat.
- Is that what the issue is here?
Sheska...
Thanks to you, Edward,
I was able to move my mother
into a better hospital.
- Thank you very much.
- Don't mention it, don't mention it.
Have you made any progress deciphering it?
Have you found a job yet?
Still, thanks to you,
I've come to believe that even
a good-for-nothing person like me
can be of help to someone.
- Thank you very much.
- You're not a good-for-nothing person.
I think that being able to try
your hardest to be something
is a talent all by itself.
And besides, your memory is incredible.
I think you should have faith in yourself.
Thanks.
- Yo!
- Lt. Colonel Hughes!
I heard from Major Armstrong
that you were here.
What gives?
I told you, whenever you get to Central,
give me a holler.
Oh, we just had something urgent come up.
Well, I've been busy too
and haven't been--
They're speaking casually
with Colonel Hughes there.
Who are these boys?
Lately, we've had a lot of cases
and whatnot.
The Tucker Chimera case
hasn't even been settled yet.
Oh, sorry, I guess that brings up
some unpleasant memories, huh?
But you know,
as if it wasn't bad enough,
the first branch had to burn down,
right when things are hectic.
The first branch?
Yeah, our case records and stuff
were being stored in the stacks there,
so it's impeding our duties.
Something awful.
What?
What do you say, Lt. Colonel?
She is looking for a place to work.
And I have indeed read
the military's criminal records,
and remember them.
All righty!
We'll get you processed right now.
My office pays well!
Huh? You mean...
Thank you very much.
I'll have faith in myself, and do my best.
Really, thanks so much.
Come on, come on, right to work!
Who is this guy, a kidnapper?
Being able to try your hardest
to be something
is a talent all by itself, huh?
Nicely said, little brother.
Whenever I look at a certain someone,
that's what I think,
deep down in my heart.
Okay, well, that certain someone
will continue to try his hardest.
It's closing time.
It's ten whole days today.
I'm impressed they persevered
until closing.
The hell with it!
A little quarrel between brothers?
You can't get desperate
just because you can't crack this.
We did crack it.
We did crack the code.
Really? That's good, isn't it?
There's nothing good about it, damn it!
This is the devil's research,
which shouldn't be pursued.
Curse you, Dr. Marcoh.
What exactly is it?
The ingredients for a Philosopher's Stone
are live humans!
What's worse,
in order to manufacture one Stone,
it requires multiple sacrifices.
How could the military carry out
such an inhuman practice?
This is unpardonable.
Would you mind not speaking to anyone
about this?
- But...
- Please!
Just pretend that you never heard this.
What's this?
The Elric brothers are holed up
in their rooms again tonight.
Yes.
They haven't even eaten all that much.
Their fatigue must have caught up
with them.
Lately, they seem to have devoted
all their energy to this.
After working so hard
to decipher the material,
and have it be that...
It disturbs me too just thinking about it.
- What?
- Nothing at all!
Most suspicious!
- Brother, go get something to eat.
- Don't want anything.
What a pain, huh?
You know, it's kind of like,
just when we think it's within reach,
it slips away from us.
When it's finally in our grasp,
we get kicked down
by whatever we've caught.
God must really hate people
who commit taboos.
I wonder if we'll be like this
the rest of our lives.
There's something I've been meaning
to say to you for a while,
but I've been too afraid to mention it.
What?
Elric brothers, I know you're in there!
It is I! Open up!
- What do we do?
- Ignore him, ignore him.
I heard, Edward Elric!
Such a tragedy!
To think that such a terrible secret
was being concealed
by the Philosopher's Stone!
We're sorry.
When someone as stuffy as he is
closes in on you...
Imagine, the military conducting
something like that!
The truth can be a cruel thing at times!
The truth?
- What is it, Brother?
- Do you remember what Dr. Marcoh said?
Knowing you, you'll be able to find
the truth within the truth.
The truth within the truth...
It's the same
as with alchemy research notes.
What you see on the surface
is only a portion of the truth.
There's still more.
There's still...
Currently, there are four alchemy
laboratories within Central
which have connections to the government.
From among those,
Marcoh worked at the Third Laboratory.
That one is the most suspect.
We went around to all of the laboratories
in the city,
but they weren't doing
any remarkable research--
Here. What is this building?
It was the building
for the Fifth Laboratory,
but it's not currently in use.
There's a risk of it collapsing,
so it has been declared off-limits.
- It's here.
- Eh? What makes you so sure?
- There's a prison next door to it.
- What about it?
What were the ingredients
for a Philosopher's Stone?
Let's see, live humans--
They'd have condemned criminals
in a prison.
Officially, they could say
they were executed...
You don't mean,
the prisoners were the ingredients?
Don't make that face.
I don't want to think about it either.
And if prisons from other jurisdictions
were involved...
I wonder if the government is involved.
I kind of get the feeling
that we've stuck our noses
into something terrible here.
You see? This is why we told you
to pretend you never heard anything!
This could become
a highly political issue.
I shall look into this.
In the meantime, 2nd Lieutenant,
Sergeant, speak of this to no one.
Yes, sir!
And you Elric brothers, behave yourselves.
Look here, you two!
You were just thinking
of sneaking into this building
and looking around inside, weren't you?
- No, we weren't. No, we weren't!
Yeah, sure we weren't.
A guard posted at an unused building, huh?
That's suspicious.
- How do we get in?
- We could make our own entrance.
They'd notice the light
from the transmutic reaction.
In that case...
Ups-a-daisy.
It's locked up tight here too?
- Al, wait here.
- Will you be all right by yourself?
All right or not, with your huge size
you can't get through here, right?
DEJECTED
I didn't get this big because I wanted to.
- 66...
- What, 48?
After all this time, we've got guests.
Some daredevil dumbasses, huh?
Damn it,
it's even tighter in here than I thought.
I couldn't have gotten through here
if I were regular-sized.
Luckily, my body is smaller.
I just said I was small!
There are lights on.
"Not currently in use" my foot.
Bingo.
Brother sure is taking a long time.