Alchemy is the science of understanding,
decomposing, and reconstructing matter.
However, it is not an all-powerful art.
It is impossible to create something
out of nothing.
If one wishes to obtain something,
something of equal value must be paid.
This equivalent exchange
is the basis of alchemy.
Alchemists have a taboo,
and it is human transmutation.
It is that which no one must commit.
The first branch
of the National Central Library
which held Marcoh's research materials
had been lost to fire.
With the aid of Sheska
who had been a librarian,
Ed and Al were still able to obtain
the research materials. However...
The ingredients for a Philosopher's Stone
are live humans!
In search of further truth,
Ed and Al sneak into the dilapidated
Fifth Laboratory.
You move pretty well
for as big as you are.
It wouldn't be worth
fighting you otherwise.
Who are you?
I'm Number 66.
At least that's what my work name is.
I'm going to take you apart,
nice and neat.
Just relax, and scream!
What is this?
Is it possible that this is
for transmuting a Philosopher's Stone?
That is correct.
I don't know who you are, kid,
but if you can tell that just by looking
at the transmutation circle.
Who are you, pops?
I am the one charged
with guarding this place.
I'll go by the name "Number 48" for now.
And by the way, I'm not your pop.
I have orders to dispose of any outsiders
that come in here.
- Don't think ill of me, kid.
- I could say the same.
Don't go thinking ill of me,
once you're defeated by a "kid."
You're an alchemist, are you?
Let's have a look at what you've got.
Your prosthetic arm just saved your life.
However, my trusty sword
will pierce even steel!
Hey, hey, hey!
Let me guess, pops,
you're hollow on the inside, aren't you?
I'm impressed that you realized that.
I spar against someone like you
all the time, you see.
Oh, so there are those like me
on the outside too, are there?
Well, that's annoying.
Imagine,
there's some other idiot out there
who came up with the idea
of bonding a soul to a suit of armor!
Let me introduce myself once again.
"48" is my condemned prisoner number.
In life, or should I say,
back when I had a living body,
I was known as Slicer, the mass murderer.
So you are a condemned prisoner.
Tell me,
they use condemned prisoners in this place
as ingredients to make
Philosopher's Stones, right?
That is difficult for me to answer.
They just recognized my skills,
gave me this body,
and made me the watchdog of this place.
Which means, you have a seal that serves
as the medium between soul and armor.
Yes, that is correct.
This bloodseal.
If you destroy this, you win.
It's very kind of you
to show me your weak spot.
I'm the type that seeks out
a little tension during a fight, you see.
As long as you're being kind,
you think you might let me go?
I figure I might as well ask.
There's no way a mass murderer
would do nothing
and let his prey escape
when it's right in front of him.
Now, here I come!
Like I said,
Elicia is going to turn three!
EAST CITY, EASTERN COMMAND CENTER
Lt. Colonel Hughes, I'm at work right now.
Isn't that a coincidence? I'm at work too.
Oh, she's just the cutest thing too!
All right, just stop calling me
to brag about your daughter!
And on a military line too!
It's not just my daughter!
I'm proud of my wife too.
All right, all right, I'll listen to you
brag about your cute, cute...
Scar.
We've found multiple unidentified bodies,
but all of them are so decomposed,
it's difficult to identify them.
There haven't been any sightings of him
in the eastern area,
so at present, many here regard him
as being dead.
From the sound of it,
I'll be able to lift the escort
from the Elric brothers before long.
Is Major Armstrong
still serving as their escort?
No, the major's men
have apparently taken over.
We've been had!
I thought it was awfully quiet in here!
We're gonna be chewed out
by Major Armstrong
for dereliction of duty!
Those little brats! Put yourselves
in your escorts' shoes, will you?
- Let's go!
- Huh? Where?
Isn't it obvious? To the Fifth Laboratory!
What is this?
My shoulder feels out of sorts.
This automail is less prone to rusting,
but the tradeoff is that
its strength isn't as great,
so don't try anything too crazy.
I have to settle this quickly...
Or I'm in trouble!
- You're just like a monkey, huh?
- Hey, what was that?
I'm so glad! It's been so long
since I've had any worthy prey!
But given your wound and your exhaustion,
the end of the battle is within sight.
Right about now, my companion
is finishing off your partner.
Is this companion of yours strong?
Yes, he's strong.
He's still weaker than I am though.
In that case,
I've got nothing to worry about.
I've been fighting him
for a long time now,
and I've never beaten him!
No!
Damn.
Sit still for a moment
and let me cut you up,
you big behemoth!
Your body...
There's a bit of a story behind this.
I know, let me tell you a story.
You've probably already heard it.
It's a story about an old codger
named Barry.
Once upon a time, here in Central,
there was an old codger named Barry
who enjoyed cooking.
Barry loved to cut meat apart.
But one day,
after he was no longer content
with just beef or pork,
Barry started going out into town,
night after night,
and began cutting people apart.
In time, Barry was caught, but by then,
23 people had fallen prey to him.
This man, who had plunged
the populace of Central
into the very depths of terror,
was naturally sent to the gallows.
And all was well that ended well.
At least, that's the story circulating
out in the world.
However, there's another part to it.
Barry isn't actually dead.
He is alive, and charged
with guarding a certain place.
However, his body has been taken from him.
Yes! He is the very person
you see before you!
That infamous mass murderer!
Barry the Chopper! I'm him!
Sorry, never heard of you.
I'm from a rural town in the east, so...
Even if you don't know about me,
when you see this body, there should be
some sort of reaction, right?
Something more like, "Yaah!"
Or "What happened to your body?"
or something.
- Yaah! What happened to your body?
- That hurts.
I get it. You were executed too.
You had me startled there.
- I'm not a criminal!
- Then, how come?
It's kind of a long story.
When I lost my body,
my brother transmuted my soul for me.
Your brother?
- I see, your brother, huh?
- What's so funny?
Are you sure this brother and you
are really siblings?
Well, our personalities
are different, but...
No, no, no, that's not what I mean.
Are you sure you're not
a suit-of-armor puppet,
created by your so-called brother?
Were you ever really a person, originally?
Of course I was!
I am, without a doubt,
the person named Alphonse Elric!
How can you believe that?
Well, because of the memories I have,
ever since I was born.
What if those are also made-up?
But Winry and Grandma know me.
Well, they're, you know, in on it.
Yeah, that's right.
You were never alive to begin with.
- Then, what about you?
- That's simple.
Don't move! This area is off-limi--
There, you see?
I love to chop up live people.
I enjoy killing so much, I can't stand it.
I kill, therefore, I am!
That proves I am who I am,
and that's good enough for me!
Oh, your brother is that good, is he?
Then I'll have to hurry up and defeat you.
- Al! Now!
- What?
That was dirty.
There's no such thing as dirty in a fight!
What's the matter?
You still haven't destroyed my bloodseal.
Hurry up and destroy it--
There's something I need to ask you about.
The Philosopher's Stone?
Why don't you tell me everything
you know about it?
I can't.
Hey, now, beaten dogs
don't get to show me up.
I haven't been beaten yet.
Impossible!
I forgot to mention,
this mass murderer Slicer
was actually a pair of brothers.
An independent head and body?
That reeks of foul play!
Who was it who said
that there's no such thing
as dirty in a fight?
Now, let's begin the second round,
short stuff.
Don't call me short!
I'm not giving you any time to transmute!
Damn, I'm losing too much blood.
I'm starting to feel dizzy.
This is bad...
Gonna die... gonna die... gonna die...!
Now to finish you!
You reminded me of someone I can't stand.
Now I've gone and done
the same thing he did, haven't I?
- Now you've done it, you little brat!
- That's just gross!
- My brother...
- I hate to say it, but we've lost.
You're not going to tell me
you're actually three brothers, are you?
No, no.
Kid, hurry up and destroy us.
Don't ask me to become a murderer.
With bodies like these,
are we even people?
If I don't consider you to be people,
then that would mean I don't consider
my brother to be a person.
Come on, come on.
What's the matter, armor puppet?
- I am not an armor puppet!
- You just think you're not!
Was there ever a real you?
Were you ever really alive?
There is a way for you to prove
that you're not an armor puppet.
You've got a bloodseal too, right?
Go ahead and break it yourself.
If you die, then you were real!
If you're still up and moving around,
you're an armor puppet!
There's no way
I could do something like that!
Then I'll do it for you!
My brother is human.
You guys are also human.
That's why I don't want to kill you.
Brother?
We two, as brothers, have been
stealing, destroying, and killing
for as long as we can remember.
And now, to be treated as humans
for the first time,
after taking the forms we have...
It's hilarious!
Kid, as a parting gift,
I will tell you everything.
The ones who made
the Philosopher's Stone,
and ordered us to protect this place...
That was a close one.
No, 48, we can't have you
speaking out of turn.
Oh, my.
What is the Fullmetal pipsqueak
doing here?
Such a trying boy.
How did you find out about this place?
Brother! Brother! Brother!
Pipe down, you halfwit!
You were just about to kill
one of our precious sacrifices.
Do you understand?
How were you going to account for this
if it messed up the plan?
Who are you people? What plan?
What do you mean, sacrifice?
Oh, my, the pipsqueak is raring to go.
You shut up with that pipsqueak talk!
A pipsqueak is a pipsqueak,
right, pipsqueak?
I don't like fighting.
It's painful when you get hurt, you know.
You're the one who picked this fight,
and I accept--
POP
Looks like you have a malfunction.
Wha--?
Lucky me!
You're fortunate your arm broke.
You're getting off
without being hurt too badly.
Listen to me, boy.
Don't forget that you're being allowed
to live.
We can't have this boy showing up again.
Let's burn this place down.
There's something I've been meaning
to say to you for a while,
but I've been too afraid to mention it.
What was Brother about to say to me?
What was he so afraid to tell me?
What was he so afraid to say?
Are you sure you're not
a suit-of-armor puppet,
created by your so-called brother?
Were you ever really a person, originally?
What's the matter, my little armor puppet?
Shut up! I'm not...
Go ahead and admit it. You'll feel better.
You've left yourself wide open,
you big behemoth!
Don't move!
Surrender yourself, nice and easy!
This is starting to get more complicated.
Sergeant, take cover!
What are you doing? Get out of there!
- But Brother is still inside!
- What?
You know what this means.
Time to hightail it outta here!
Hey, you!
- You'd better hurry away from here too!
- Hold it!
Brother! Brother!
Take cover!
You'll end up getting caught in it too!
But...!
- Hey there, I brought you some baggage.
- Brother?
His life isn't in any danger,
but he's lost a lot of blood
so you should hurry
and get him to a hospital.
Also, you should keep
a closer watch on him
to make sure
they don't do anything too crazy.
- He is a precious resource after all.
- Who are you?
Lieutenant Ross! Quickly!
- Sergeant, give me a hand!
- He's covered in blood, isn't he?
- Talk later! Hurry and get out of--
- He's gone.
- Let us out!
- It's an earthquake!
- Are you trying to kill us?
- Hey, shut up! Take it easy!
What a nice sound.
That's the sound of a building crumbling,
using explosives.
As close as it is,
I'd say it's the Fifth Laboratory,
right next door.
What a nice sound.
A truly great sound, that reverberates
down to the core of my body.
No talking to yourself, Kimblee!
Oh, excuse me.
I was just recalling
the Ishvalan War of Extermination,
and I couldn't help but feel happy.
Are you sure you're not
a suit-of-armor puppet,
created by your so-called brother?
So, in Central, the senior staff
in control of State Alchemists
are shorthanded, thanks to Scar.
Rumor has it that Colonel Mustang's
promotion to Central is not far off.
- Central, huh? Not bad.
- Watch yourself.
When you encroach on senior staff
as young as you are,
you're going to make more enemies.
I've been prepared for that
from the start.
Just a word of warning from one
who's gone before you in Central.
Find as many people who understand you
and support you as you can.
Which means, hurry up and find a wife!
Shut up!
What? He just hung up on me!
Colonel Hughes, please don't make
so many personal calls, okay?
Sorry.