In search of the secrets
of the Philosopher's Stone,
Ed and Al break into the Fifth Laboratory
where they encounter people
who have had their souls bonded to armor.
In the midst of their fight,
Al begins to have suspicions
that he might be a counterfeit soul,
created by Ed,
because of what Number 66 says to him.
I see you're able to sit up now, huh?
- How is the Fifth Laboratory?
- Well, you see...
It was blown up by somebody,
and there's nothing left of it.
Damn it! Everything's been wiped out?
That hurt!
Damn.
I was so close
to getting hold of the truth, too.
This is no time for me
to be in the hospital!
- Fullmetal Alchemist, sir!
- We apologize in advance for this!
That was a selfish thing to do!
You could have lost your life in there
if you hadn't been so lucky!
Don't try to do everything
just by yourselves,
turn to those who are around you!
You can put more trust in adults,
you know.
- That is all!
- Please forgive the abusive words
- and conduct unbecoming our rank!
Nah. I'm sorry.
What about censuring me for slapping you?
I wouldn't do anything like that.
Why are you so anxious?
State Alchemists have the military rank
equivalent to major, and all.
It's not as though I got
my state certification because of that.
And you don't have to speak
so politely to me, either.
- Oh, really?
- Huh, guess we were worried for nothing.
You sure adjusted fast.
Come to think of it, where's Al?
I gave Alphonse a little lecture earlier,
with my fist.
There's still one more event remaining
where I'm gonna get royally chewed out.
Yes, Rockbell Prosthetic Limb Outfitter.
Ed? It's pretty unusual for you to call.
Listen, I hate to ask,
but could you come out to Central
on a service call for me?
- Service call?
- Yeah, it's my right arm.
I can move the fingers,
but I can't lift the arm at all.
- No dice after all, huh?
- Huh?
Nothing, just talking to myself.
Did you do anything to it
before it stopped working?
I was in an all-out fight.
Again?
How can you use my automail for that?
Hello? Winry, ma'am?
Guess I've got no choice, huh?
Where in Central?
You sure seem nice today--
I mean, nothing...
Sorry. Thanks for doing this. Bye now.
- Calling your girlfriend?
- Who are you calling my girlfriend?
- Aw, how dull. Back when I was your age--
- Huh?
What are you doing over there?
Hey, Al!
- Brother.
- Why don't you come to the room?
It's nothing. You go on ahead.
Okay.
Bye-bye!
Are you sure you're not
a suit-of-armor puppet,
created by your so-called brother?
My bottom hurts.
I'm surprised Ed and Al can ride these.
He said there would be a familiar marker
standing at the west exit,
and I would know it right away.
Major Armstrong!
Oh, Miss Winry!
Where are those dumb Elric brothers?
As it happens...
Ed is in the hospital?
That was fast.
Now, you're going to charge me
for express service, right?
Well, I didn't service your automail.
So it broke, and you got yourself
this seriously injured, right?
It's not your fault, Winry.
I caused this by using it
in a reckless way.
Your maintenance was as flawless
as it always is.
He hasn't noticed that I forgot
to put in that screw?
Besides, you could say
that because my arm broke,
I got out of it without getting hurt.
Don't worry about it, okay? Okay?
You mean, it turned out all right?
Well then, let's get right
to discussing this service call.
I will be including a rush order fee.
You left your milk.
I hate milk.
You're going to be a beansprout forever
because you keep saying that!
Shut up! If I hate it, I hate it!
You're being inconsiderate, Edward Elric!
Every child drinks it.
If you don't drink your milk,
you won't be popular with the girls.
Al?
Al has been acting weird lately.
Weird how?
It's like there's something bothering him.
Are you sure you're not
a suit-of-armor puppet,
created by your so-called brother?
Go ahead and admit it. You'll feel better.
All right, maintenance complete!
Oh, you did it!
It's finally fixed. Thank you.
You're welcome.
Yo, Ed! I'm told you invited a girl
into your hospital room,
and you were getting frisky?
- She's just my automail mechanic!
- You've seduced your mechanic, have you?
I say one thing,
and you completely turn it around!
- Maes Hughes. Pleased to meet you.
- Winry Rockbell.
Are you sure you should be skipping work?
Not to worry.
I gave Sheska some overtime.
You're such a demon.
By the way, I hear you guys aren't going
to be under guard for much longer.
- Really?
- Under guard?
Hold on, how much trouble
have you gotten yourself into?
Well, you see...
It's not a big deal!
Right. You two brothers won't talk to me
when I ask anyhow.
Well, I'll see you tomorrow.
I have to go find a place to stay tonight.
What?
In that case, come stay over at my place.
- But--
- Don't worry!
My wife and daughter will be delighted.
- No, I--
- All right, let's do it!
- Hold on--
- Come on, come on, let's go!
Hang on!
Congratulations, Elicia!
Mr. Hughes, what is this?
I'm so glad you asked.
Today is Elicia's birthday. That it is.
That it is!
- How old are you now, Elicia?
- Tw--
Three!
How cute!
I've always been with them
ever since we were little,
so they're like brothers to me.
You must always be worried about them,
the way they are.
That's the truth.
On the rare occasion
that they do come back,
his arm will be all busted.
Now that I get called out here,
Ed has been seriously injured,
and Al is upset about something or other.
But they won't ever tell me what happened.
It's the same as when they left Resembool.
There wasn't any need to discuss it.
They figured that knowing you, Winry,
you would understand
without them saying anything.
But there are some things
that don't get across
unless you say them out loud.
What am I going to do with you?
Men are creatures that let their actions
speak louder than words.
When they're in pain,
they don't want to burden anyone else,
if they can help it.
They don't want to make others worry,
that's why they don't say anything.
Even so, when those brothers
do give in and cry for help,
that's when you make sure
to be receptive to them.
Isn't that good enough?
Elicia, let's play.
- I want down!
- Okay, there you go.
No way, Elicia is gonna play with me!
- Your daughter is quite popular.
- No, with me.
Hey, you kids!
You try anything funny with my daughter,
and you'll pay for it!
Your actions are speaking too loudly!
Are you sure?
You're welcome to stay with us
for as long as you're here.
I couldn't be so presumptuous.
She's gotten completely attached to you.
Looking at you like this,
it's just like you're sisters.
Sissy, be safe out there.
Come back soon, okay?
I guess that settles
where you're staying tonight.
I'm so glad I found a little sister.
You're here again today,
are you, you bastard?
Brother, you have a living body,
so you have to drink it.
If I hate it, I hate it.
It may not look like it,
but I have grown some.
And yet everyone calls me shorty, short.
I wish I were like you, Al.
Your body as big as it is...
I didn't get this body because I want it!
Sorry. You're right.
It's my fault you ended up like this, too,
isn't it?
That's why I want to get you back
in your original body.
Can you guarantee that you'll ever really
get my original body back?
- I'll get you back. Believe me!
- Believe you?
What am I supposed to believe,
when I'm in this hollow body?
I mean, when you boil it down,
memories are just a bunch of information.
It should also be possible
to artificially construct them!
What are you talking about?
Brother, you told me before
that there was something you were
too afraid to talk to me about, right?
Was it, by any chance,
that my soul and my memories,
are both really counterfeits
that you just invented?
And that Winry, you and Granny...
are all trying to fool me, aren't you?
How about it, Brother?
Did you have that pent up all this time?
Is that everything you wanted to say?
Okay.
Ed...
Ed!
Al, you...
Idiot!
Where did that suddenly come from?
- Winry?
- Al, you dummy!
You have no idea how Ed feels!
You know what Ed was so afraid
to talk to you about?
Whether or not you resent him
for what happened!
It's all... my fault.
He can no longer eat or sleep
or feel pain.
I'm sure he must resent me for that.
Al is not the sort of boy
who would resent you.
Ask him, and you'll see.
I'm too afraid...
I'm too afraid to ask him.
And... and yet you just had to...
In what world do you find someone so dumb
that he's prepared to give his own life
to create a fake brother?
You two brothers are all you've got,
aren't you?
Now, go after him!
- Run!
- Right!
- Broth--
- Come to think of it,
we haven't sparred in a while,
and I'm starting to get flabby.
Huh? Hey--
Just a minute, Brother!
Wait!
You're gonna open your wounds up!
I won!
That's the first time
I've ever beaten you!
- No fair, Brother.
- Shut up! A win is a win!
We've fought a lot,
ever since we were little, huh?
Thinking back on it now,
we fought over some stupid things.
Like who got the top or bottom
of the bunk beds.
Yeah.
- We even fought over candy, huh?
- And we squabbled over that toy.
I won that one. And when we were playing
at Rain River, too.
I got pushed into the river, didn't I?
We fought while we were training,
too, huh?
Teacher told us we were
making too much noise,
and beat us half to death.
That one was a draw.
We even fought over which one of us
was going to marry Winry.
- I don't remember that!
- I won. But then she shot me down.
Oh, yeah?
And you're telling me those were all lies.
I'm sorry.
You're saying that your feeling
of wanting to get your body back,
no matter what it takes, is also fake?
- It's not fake.
- That's right.
The two of us decided
that we'd get back to normal together.
We're gonna keep on pushing forward.
Push forward, and make our hearts
and fighting skills stronger.
- What about the milk?
- I'll drink... as much as I can.
Let's go get much, much stronger.
Mr. Hughes,
there are some things that do get across
without saying them out loud, huh?
There sure are.
My brother...
Master...
Where are you all?
Hey.
You're not Ishvalan, are you?
Oh, pardon me,
we haven't had the pleasure yet.
I am the State Alchemist
in charge of exterminating this sector.
You're awake.
- Where am I?
- A slum, just outside of East City.
- Old man, who are you?
- An Ishvalan, just as you are.
Relax, we will not sell out
one of our own.
Then there are other
Ishvalan survivors here?
Yes, indeed there are.
You can say, "there's no place like home,"
even here, where it reeks of soot.
But the whole world
is the bosom of our god, Ishvala.
You don't say.
Don't force yourself.
You're injured all over,
and were floating down in the sewers.
- Say, is my right arm still attached?
- Yeah, it's still there.
This tattoo sure is awesome.
Yeah. It's a precious bond I got...
from my family.