Alchemy is the science
of understanding, decomposing,
and reconstructing matter.
However, it is not an all-powerful art.
It is impossible to create something
out of nothing.
If one wishes to obtain something,
something of equal value must be paid.
This is the concept
of equivalent exchange,
the fundamental basis of alchemy.
Alchemists have a taboo,
and it is human transmutation.
It is that which no one must commit.
Maes Hughes is dead.
He was murdered by mysterious people
with Uroboros tattoos.
Harboring suspicions about his death,
Mustang learns of the
military senior staff's involvement,
and reaffirms his determination
to make his foray into Central.
Meanwhile, unaware of what had happened,
Ed and Al, along with Winry,
had departed southward,
toward the town of Dublith,
where their teacher lived.
However...
Rush Valley!
Automail!
I'm so happy!
It's the Gods '11 model!
GASP
I never thought the day would come
where I'd behold it with my own eyes!
That's the Holy Land of Automail for you.
This place is bustling.
Why do we have to come out
in all this freaking heat,
and look at automail?
We should have left Winry behind,
and gone straight to Dublith!
You there, you have a second?
What an unusual model of automail.
It really is. Everyone, come look at this.
Hey, hold on! Stop, stop that!
SWARM
JOSTLE
No, don't undo that! That's--!
Everyone's eager to study them.
Stop screwing around!
Geez.
BADGER
AWESOME, HE'S HUGE
This is why I can't stand
automail engineers.
Huh?
What is it?
It's gone...
What is?
The thing that proves
I'm a State Alchemist.
My silver watch is gone!
That must be the work of Paninya.
Paninya?
A pickpocket that targets tourists
as her marks.
Do you know where she might be?
That thing is important!
We'll tell you...
But in return...
Show us your automail once again.
The shop of an automail engineer
named Dominic.
They say he lives deep in the mountains
because he can get
high-quality ores out here.
Is this really the right way?
They didn't trick us, did they?
This is all because you said you wanted
to go see that town, you know!
It's your own inattentiveness
that allowed your watch to be stolen!
Shut up!
- Hey, both of you!
- What?
Isn't that her?
I've found you!
Give it back!
Amazing. Who are you, mister?
I'm an alchemist!
Amazing, amazing!
Stop moving around!
Come on, come on,
you're starting to breathe hard.
I've been waiting for you.
Nicely done.
Now, why don't you give me back my watch?
It's not all that unusual, is it?
Not in this town.
By the way...
I have a 1.5-inch culverin in my left leg.
- Wait!
- Just try to catch me!
I'm not gonna let you get away.
Nice work, Winry! Don't let go of her!
SQUEEZE
Yeah, as if I'd let go!
Not until you let me have
a closer look at your automail!
Oh, Paninya,
friends of yours?
- I'm so gonna study those!
- Not exactly.
I've never seen automail like this.
It has an advanced suspension,
but more than anything, it's the balance!
- This streamlined design is true art--
- About my silver watch...
RUB
EEP
It's no use, brother.
I really respect you for being able
to make automail like this.
Oh, I'm not the one who made this.
I am.
Isn't that a bit heavy?
Yes, it is.
It's no good to place a strain
on your wearer.
That's why this guy's so small, ain't it?
Don't call me small!
AH!
So you're saying that if these
were made lighter, I would grow taller?
It's possible.
Brother, you're so big!
So tall!
HA HA HA HA
You guys sure are small.
Hmm, that settles it, all right.
Mr. Dominic...
Please take me on as an apprentice!
Not a chance.
If you would take some time to consider...
Cork it. I don't take apprentices.
Could you at least see your way
to teaching her how to make automail
so that I can grow taller?
Shut up, water flea.
Sorry about that.
My old man is pretty stubborn.
Water flea... Water flea...
Water flea...
You're having a baby, right?
That's right.
Would it be okay if I touched your tummy?
Go ahead.
It seems so miraculous somehow.
Yeah. To think that we were once
inside Mom's tummy like this too.
Are you okay?
Yes.
My stumps always ache
when the weather turns bad.
How did you end up with automail?
I was in a train accident,
and my parents were killed.
I lost both my legs.
Not only could I not walk anymore,
I didn't have anyone to turn to,
so it felt like my world had ended.
That's when I met Mr. Dominic.
You look like you're the most miserable
person in the world.
Nothing grates on me
more than people like you!
Let me go! Let me go!
"Eyes of a dead person..."
At the time,
I'm sure I really did look miserable.
So without ever really understanding why,
I was outfitted with automail.
The surgery was painful,
the rehabilitation was hard,
it was as bad as anything could be.
But...
When I was able to stand
on two legs again, I was so happy.
I really am grateful to Mr. Dominic.
I plan to pay him back,
even if it takes my whole life.
He's never once accepted
any money from me, though.
Which is why you're a pickpocket.
If you're really grateful to him,
stop picking pockets!
Mr. Dominic gave you these legs
out of his good will.
So you have to live up
to that with good will too.
If you're ready to spend your whole life,
then don't pick pockets,
stand up tall on those legs, and work!
I'm sure that by doing that,
you'll please Mr. Dominic too.
Yeah. You're right.
Yeah, I'm giving up picking pockets.
I'll work honestly, and pay him back!
Oh, that's right.
I have to give this back.
Right!
Huh? Oh, I may have broken it.
It won't open.
Let me see.
No, you didn't.
It's been closed up with alchemy.
Why?
Isn't that obvious?
It's because there's something in here
he'd be embarrassed to have anyone see!
HM, HM, HM, HM
It's open!
Now, let's have a look at Ed's treasure.
"Don't forget, October 3rd, '11."
What's that?
Give this back to Ed.
Winry?
I...
I'm going to go ask Mr. Dominic
if I can be his apprentice again.
What's the matter?
The ba...
The bay?
The ba... the ba...
What about the bay?
The... the...
The baby's coming! Mrs. Satera said so!
In this rain, we can't take her
to a hospital in town.
I'll dash over there,
and call for a doctor.
Pop will be right back with a doctor.
Just hang on a little while longer, okay?
Hang on?
It'll come whenever it comes--
What's the matter?
Huh?
Hmm? What was that? I didn't hear.
It's coming!
It's coming?
What do we do? The doctor isn't here!
- We'll just have to do it.
- Do what?
Deliver it.
Have you ever been there
when a baby was born?
No, but we don't have
any time to dither around.
Everyone, help me out here.
We're going to deliver this baby!
- Ed and Al, go boil some water.
- You got it!
Paninya, gather up
as many towels as you can.
Roger!
Mr. Ridel,
do you have any disinfectant alcohol?
I think there were some in the storeroom.
Ah, and some drinking water
for Mrs. Satera, at her bedside!
Say, is she okay in there?
She comes from a family of doctors.
She grew up reading medical-related
books instead of picture books.
But it's not as though she
actually learned anything, did she?
I'd guess whatever she knows,
she just vaguely remembers.
Ah, jeez...
But right now,
all we can do is defer
to her knowledge and nerve!
Boil water, disinfect...
What else was there?
Remember... remember...
Winry.
Good luck!
Yeah.
- Paninya, give me a hand in here.
- Okay.
Brother...
Right now, when it really counts,
I can't do anything.
It hurts!
I'm gonna die here!
COWER
It hurts! I can't take any more!
I know we don't believe in God...
Yeah.
But just this once,
for God's sake, please...
Brother!
Hey...
The blood...
I can't go on anymore.
Hey, what's going on?
The baby's been born!
Hooray!
Awesome! The baby really has been born.
- Awesome! Awesome! Awesome!
- "Awesome, awesome!"
What a childish sentiment.
But this is the birth of a new life.
Alchemists have been working for centuries
and we still haven't accomplished that,
a person creating another person.
Don't go lumping alchemy in
with the mysteries of life!
I can't help it.
It's the line of work I'm in.
Still, it really is awesome.
People are awesome.
Now then, the baby has been safely born,
is there anything else I can do now?
Yes, there is.
You can start by picking me up.
UNABLE TO STAND UP
It's humiliating, being carried
by a man smaller than me.
I'll drop you.
Ed...
I saw what was inside your silver watch.
It hurts.
You forced it open?
I'm sorry.
You dumbass.
I haven't even shown it to Al.
Why?
It's my resolve, and admonition to myself.
I hate to admit what a pansy I am,
having to put what happened
that day in this form
so I can carry it around with me.
What are you crying for?
- There's no turning back for us now, huh?
- Yeah.
What are you crying for?
You two brothers won't cry,
so I'm doing it for you.
Dumbass.
You should go back to the countryside.
Granny must be lonesome all by herself.
No. I'm not leaving.
Hey, now...
Not after I saw your resolve, Ed.
I can't live with myself being
only half-committed either.
There's no reason for you
to be involved too.
I want to hone my skills,
and make you some better automail,
so that you can continue your journey
with peace of mind, Ed.
That's why I'm going to ask Mr. Dominic
to accept me as his apprentice again.
Okay.
Good luck.
Yeah.
Winry, Mr. Ridel said he'd like you
to come over for a minute.
Huh? What's the matter?
Oh, it's nothing. I'll be right there.
Paninya...
Ouch! What was that for?
Shut up and give me
my silver watch back, you thief!
You didn't have to hit me
with your right arm!
Then I'll hit you again with my left!
I'm your granddaddy!
You sure are cute!
MUSHY
That's out of character.
Mother and baby are both doing just fine.
Postnatal treatment
has also been appropriate.
Being present at a childbirth is something
that even adults freak out over.
Oh, well, we were desperate.
We really are in your debt.
Especially the young lady.
Thanks.
Please, no need to be so formal.
Aw, gosh, now I'm gonna blush.
PING!
What do you say?
Just this once, take on an apprentice?
This doesn't have anything
to do with that.
I don't take on apprentices.
But...
if you insist, I can refer you
to an accomplished engineer
who lives at the base of the mountain.
Would it be okay if I came by
once in a while to watch you work?
If you were to come by once
in a while to see my grandchild,
that would be okay.
Same goes for the tomboy, there.
Yikes! We gotta hurry!
If we miss this one, the next one
to Dublith isn't for three days!
- Be careful!
- You too!
Make sure you call Granny!
You're a fine one to talk!
You steal all
of that old man's techniques,
and make me something better
next time we meet, okay?
They're gone.
Don't you worry about it.