To think that you saw it
and made it back alive.
You may be my pupils,
but that is really something.
Nah...
Still, you will have to take
responsibility for what you've done.
You're expelled.
- Teacher--
- Al.
The trains are still running. Go home.
Thank you for all you've done.
If you're ever in the area, come see us.
But we're--
You idiots!
There's no teacher or pupil relationship
any longer,
which means that from now on,
you can interact with each other
as equal individuals.
What reason is there to be so aloof now?
Damn.
Al, what did we come to Dublith for?
Mr. Sig, we're heading on back.
Don't get yourselves killed.
Teacher!
How dare you show your faces again here?
Who are you calling "Teacher"?
I no longer consider you pupils!
- Get out of here now!
- Teacher!
We came here to find some leads
on getting our original bodies back.
- We can't leave here empty-handed.
- Get out!
No!
You imbeciles.
Al, you didn't see "the Truth," right?
Right. I have no idea what that means.
You may have lost your memory of it
out of shock.
Why don't we try getting your memory back?
Your whole body was taken away.
There's no way you wouldn't have seen it.
Right.
Teacher, it was just a part of our bodies
for you and me,
but considering the toll that Al paid,
he must be more closely acquainted
with the "Truth" than any of us.
Then, once my memories
of that time return,
I'll have a lead on getting my body back.
Still, the memories of that...
Yeah, that...
Huh? Is it something bad?
Not so much bad as awful.
Yeah, more like awful.
It might wreck your mind.
If it goes wrong, you'll be crippled.
Even so, if it means finding any leg,
I want to go for it.
All right.
Let me ask someone I know
about how to get your memory back.
But before I do, let's eat.
Give me a moment.
Right!
No doubt about it.
He's the one who transmuted a soul.
EAST CITY, EASTERN COMMAND CENTER
You'll be transferring
to Central next week, eh?
Yes, sir.
I'm going to miss you around here.
You kept things pretty colorful.
Oh, no, not as much as you did
when you were younger, General.
You worked as hard as you could
which allowed me to be at ease too.
And thanks to the work
that you allowed me to take on,
my insight has also been expanded.
Check.
I finally beat you, here at the end.
This win will be my parting gift to you.
General...
While you're giving out parting gifts,
there's something else I'd like.
Master Sergeant Kain Fuery.
Warrant Officer Vato Falman.
Second Lieutenant Heymans Breda.
Second Lieutenant Jean Havoc.
First Lieutenant Riza Hawkeye.
You five men will be transferring
to Central with me.
I won't hear any objections.
You're coming with me!
Colonel, I'm in a fix.
- I just recently got a new girlfriend.
- Break up with her.
NOT AGAIN!!
Your wounds haven't even closed up yet.
Master.
I'm glad that you are safe.
I understand you've been
going around killing State Alchemists.
I understand the animosity you feel.
It was a State Alchemist
that burned down our village.
But vengeance will only cultivate
more vengeance.
You must break this fruitless chain
and stop it.
You must abide by this.
We're coming in.
Oh, he really is here.
The Ishvalan with the X-shaped scar.
We'll split the reward with you evenly
as promised, Mr. Yoki.
Huh? Mr. Yoki is gone?
- Why, you--
- What do you think you're doing?
We took you in like family
when you had nowhere else to go.
Shut up!
Don't lump me in with you, Ishvalans!
I will rise up again!
I will rise, I will rise.
And I will take down
that detestable Edward Elric!
Now you two, get him if you please.
It appears that my presence here
will make trouble.
That's a reasonable fellow.
Why, you--! What the hell did you do?
I'll give you a moment to pray to God.
What God? Who needs--?
Wait. Stay back.
I was wrong!
Spare my life!
I will follow you from here on!
You're leaving?
Your brother would be grieved.
I can't turn back now.
He's here.
We've been expecting you, visitor.
"We know your secret.
Come to the Devil's Nest."
Are you people the ones
who know my secret?
Yeah, we know all sorts of things.
I'd like to know what my secret is too.
Then that makes this simple. Come with us.
But my teacher taught me
that I shouldn't go with strangers.
- Hey, how old are you?
- Fourteen.
Fourteen is old enough to think
and act for yourself, right?
You can't go around saying
"my teacher says such-and-such" forever.
Oh, right. I have to think for myself.
There you go. Now come with us--
After thinking it over for myself,
I've decided to hog-tie you guys
and ask you what my secret is.
So we'll end up doing this by force, eh?
Forgive the intrusion.
- You're going inside?
- Hey, be a good little boy!
Well, how does it feel having someone
inside you moving your body?
You can't completely stop me
from moving by doing this!
You're right.
But if I can slow your motion
even a little...
We can finish this.
- Are you hurt?
- I hit my head.
You're making this awfully hard.
Just what are you people?
They're Chimeras and they work for me.
Oh, incredible.
You really are hollow.
I'm Greed. Let's you and I be friends.
What are you people, really?
It's not true that you're Chimeras, right?
After all, there's no way
that Chimeras can talk.
There's no such thing as "no such thing."
In fact, the girl inside you is a Chimera
who was made by combining with a snake.
And the fellow behind me, here...
Roa, what were you again?
- A cow?
- Yeah.
There's also a lizard and a crocodile.
The man you went up against earlier
pees on one leg.
No, I don't!
A dog?
Yeah. It comes in pretty handy.
Impossible. It just isn't possible.
For one thing, who has ever made
a successful combination?
The military.
You mean...
In any event, there is an underworld,
one where the sun doesn't shine.
And by the way, I'm not a Chimera.
I'm a Homunculus.
Homunculus?
You know of them, right?
An artificially-created person.
That's what I am.
- A Homunculus?
- It's a man-made person.
It says in that book
that you're not supposed to make people.
You're lying.
I've never heard of anyone
successfully creating a Homunculus!
My, my.
Let me show you the proof.
How could you do that?
There, now I'm once dead.
It can't be...
Do you get it?
There's no such thing as "no such thing."
There's no better proof of that
than your very existence, is there?
- You, who exist only as a soul.
- How do you know that?
Most of what happens in the underworld
reaches my ears.
Now then, let's get down to business.
How does it feel to be just a soul,
having a body that will never die?
Transmuting an individual soul
and attaching it to something else...
Depending on how it's done,
you can gain immortality.
Am I wrong?
I am Greed. That's desire, you see.
I want money. I want women.
I want status, glory,
and everything else the world has!
And I want eternal life too!
But you are immortal, aren't you?
Well, I am put together pretty tough.
I've been alive for nearly 200 years.
But I'm not exactly immortal.
Well, I've told you my secret.
Now it's your turn.
Tell me the secret of your body.
You'd best start talking.
You don't want to be taken apart
limb from limb and examined, right?
It's no use.
I don't have any memories
from when I got this body
and I'm not the one
who did the transmutation.
I don't know anything.
Then, I can ask the person
who did the transmutation for you.
Well...
Where has Al gone off to?
I'd be willing to tell you
once you tell me your brother's secret.
Brother.
Who would have ever thought
you'd get abducted?
Brother, this man is a Homunculus!
A Homunculus?
Hey, don't go giving it away right off.
So he might have some hints
as to how to get our original bodies back.
An Ouroboros tattoo.
That's right.
It would have been easier
if I could have dealt with
just the little armor boy there.
If you're one of that bunch, ask them.
That bunch?
The folks with that tattoo
who were at the Fifth Laboratory.
We met some others there
who were souls bonded to armor.
Is that right? Well, it's kind of a lot.
I'm afraid I can't do that.
I have a proposal I'd like to discuss.
The two of you want
to get your bodies back.
Isn't that right?
I will teach you how to fabricate
a Homunculus.
In exchange, you teach me
how to transmute a soul.
That's an equivalent exchange.
Then again, is there really any need
to get your original body back?
I think the body you've got is nice.
- No, it isn't!
- Oh, no?
You don't get hungry,
you don't get sleepy,
and you don't get fatigued.
That's great, isn't it?
Stop spouting that ridiculous nonsense!
Handy? Great?
I can't sit here and listen
to you go off on your own
when you don't know what it's like!
The way to transmute a soul?
I don't see any reason
to share even one iota of it with you!
I pound on bad guys, beat them up,
make them spill their secrets!
Snatch them away!
In other words,
it's all for me and none for you!
I don't have any need
for equivalent exchange with bad guys!
So we end up doing this by force again.
- Don't kill him.
- Yeah, yeah.
You're a lot slower
than a certain condemned prisoner!
Next.
Roa, take the armor boy away.
- We'll take him apart and analyze him.
- Right.
Just a minute! Hold it!
No way, no way.
You can't even scratch the Ultimate Shield
with that steel sword of yours!
You left your noggin wide open!
Oh, that one hurt.
Any normal person
would be on his way to the hospital.
You're not normal at all?
Well, my body is normal enough.
All I have are slightly advanced
regenerative powers
and my Ultimate Shield.
You get it, right? You cannot beat me.
You'd be smarter to make a deal.
You're one of those guys, huh?
You don't mind if you get all beat up
but you can't bear to have a family member
get even a little hurt,
and you lose your cool.
How foolish.
Are you going to give yourself over
to your passion
and lose both the precious information
and your brother?
Once I've defeated you,
I'll get my brother back.
Your regenerative powers
aren't unlimited, are they?
As long as I keep pounding away
at the exposed parts of your body--
My apologies. I've been skimping on you.
This doesn't look too handsome
so I don't like showing it to people.
Didn't I tell you?
You can't lay a single scratch on me.
This was lying in the back alley
off of the road to the west.
Al has disappeared, and now Ed too.
Those idiots!
I ought to make them my pupils again
then beat into them
how they should take care of things!
I know something!
Earlier, a boy matching Ed's description
supposedly went into a bar
called the Devil's Nest.
Are you dead?
Good, that's better.
Children should be energetic.
No matter how much you try,
you cannot beat me!
Now then,
why don't you tell me your secret?
- Thanks.
- Huh?
The blood that had rushed to my head
has settled a bit
and my brain is starting to cool off.
That's my mechanic for you.
Even like this, it still works.
You're still going to put up a fight?
Would you go down and stay down?
I'm hardened, right? That was strange.
What was that for?
You've got a single-pattern style!
That's not gonna cut it!
What the hell did you do to my shield?
It's simple when you think about it.
You may be a Homunculus,
but if you have a normal body,
it means that a third
of your structural material
is made up of carbon.
Depending on the degree
to which the carbon atoms combine,
its hardness can change
from pencil lead up to diamond.
Once that is known,
the rest is all in the realm of alchemy.
Good.
That's more like it!
It's no fun otherwise!
And I just learned one other thing!
You can't harden yourself
and regenerate at the same time!
I thought you were just some reckless kid
rushing in here.
But then, how much more
can you attack me in your condition?
Hello, pardon me.
Teacher!
You imbecile!
What do you think you're doing,
not even putting the broom away?
Sorry about that!
It looks like you've shown
considerable hospitality to my boy there.
Teacher, he's--
I know.
Your voices were carrying out
into the hallway.
Hey now, give me a break here.
I have no interest in fighting a woman.
Why, you--
who the hell are you?
I'm just a passing...
housewife!