- So that's Roy Mustang.
- The Flame Alchemist, huh?
I wonder what connections
he used to be selected at his age.
When your rise is this rapid,
your fall will be rapid as well.
Come in.
Excuse me.
Colonel Roy Mustang.
Ah, Colonel Mustang. I'm terribly sorry.
His Excellency the Führer is not in.
Where is he?
He went to the south
to conduct an inspection.
The south?
I don't like the smell of this.
Still, it brings back memories.
Here, I've come on an inspection
and I make quite the discovery.
Move in!
A kid and a housewife, huh? That's right.
But I wouldn't quite feel comfortable
fighting you.
I'll be running away.
Why, you--
Teacher, hang on!
Running away. How cowardly.
Teacher...
Teacher! Teacher!
Behave yourself!
No way!
Mr. Greed!
Martel, are you safe?
What happened?
Roa and the others haven't come back.
Yeah, things have gotten
a little more complicated.
We have to come up with a way out.
I can't have that.
Who are you, old man?
The Führer! Why are you here?
King Bradley?
What is the highest man
in the country doing here?
How old are you?
Huh?
I will be turning 60 this year.
As you grow older,
your body stops moving
the way you want it to.
I'd like to finish this job right away
and get back home.
Retire, old man.
Hey, now, what kind of old man are you?
Mr. Greed?
Did you see that?
That is the statuary technique
that has been passed down
in the Armstrong family for generations!
Well, then, I'll take this more seriously.
Most peculiar.
We've secured the boy and the woman!
Now exterminate those monsters!
Those are the Führer's orders!
It has been a long time
since the blood danced within my veins.
Impressive, Mr. Armstrong.
I also participated in the Ishvalan War
of Extermination.
A former comrade, huh?
Then that's all the more reason
to avoid meaningless bloodshed.
Surrender.
Even when you're about to kill me?
Major!
Roa!
You bastard!
I have neither the Ultimate Shield
such as yourself,
nor the Ultimate Spear
which can pierce anything.
Do you know how I survived flying bullets
on the battlefield,
rendered such distinguished service,
and am now in my current position?
You're...
Just as you have your Ultimate Shield,
I have my Ultimate Eye.
Now then, Greed,
how many more times
can you be killed before you die?
Where is Mr. Greed?
I don't know.
It's too dark for me to see.
- Mr. Greed!
- No!
Why, you--
- Open up!
- No!
- Let me out!
- I said no and I mean it!
You've died 15 times now, is it?
How many more times will it take?
Why, you--
Ah, damn.
The Führer himself?
You can turn tail and run if you want.
I'd like to do just that
but a dog's loyalty is a powerful thing.
Get her out of here.
We're counting on you.
Roa! Dolcetto!
Hey, get out of the way! Let me out!
No.
I don't have time to mess
with you right now!
Open up, I tell you!
No, you can't come out!
Just open up!
Are you telling me to just sit here
and watch my friends die?
I can't let you out. Those two asked.
Dolcetto!
Roa!
Please.
You can't come out.
Hey, now, Mr. Bradley.
How could you do that to my men?
Become attached to your pawns, have you?
What nonsense.
Attached?
You fool, who do you take me for?
I am Greed the Avaricious.
Money, women, subordinates,
all of them are my possessions!
As such, I cannot just abandon
my possessions.
For my avarice runs deep.
Avarice? You grow even more nonsensical.
Lie down there for a moment.
- We have to get away.
- Hold it there.
You are Edward's younger brother, yes?
Are you injured? Let me give you a hand.
Oh, sure. I mean, no, I'm all right.
I can get home by myself.
No, Miss Martel!
Bradley!
Al!
Mom!
Mom! Mom!
Al, hey, snap out of it!
Hey! Answer me!
Al!
Brother.
Are you all right?
What about you, brother?
You're covered in blood.
We took the liberty of opening you up
and pulling her out.
I wasn't able to save her.
It wasn't your fault, Al.
Come on, let's go home.
Al.
Just a moment.
There is something that I must ask you.
Did you know the mastermind here?
A man named Greed.
No.
Did you get any important information
out of him?
No.
Nothing that would be of any benefit
to the military.
Don't misunderstand.
I don't mean for the military.
If you have arranged a deal with him,
then depending on what it is...
Have you taken up
with those who would do harm
to the heart of the military?
No.
Any other questions?
Your steel arm and your brother's armor,
are they somehow related?
Such an honest boy.
We're pulling out.
You take good care
of that brother of yours.
Thank you for what you've done
for the Elric brothers.
Not at all.
One of the duties of the military
is to protect our State Alchemists.
What do you say?
Would you like to be protected as well?
As a State Alchemist?
Indeed.
As you can see,
I am just a frail housewife.
Is the country so hard-pressed
that it needs the help of someone like me?
That was pretty harsh, huh?
I will be back.
When I do, perhaps,
you'll have had a change of heart.
Greed had an Ouroboros tattoo on his hand.
Ouroboros...
Remember?
I told Colonel Hughes about them too.
Those guys are involved
with the Philosopher's Stone.
Hughes.
Edward Elric,
do not do anything too rash.
Yeah.
Well, then...
Brother.
Listen, my memories of when my body
was carried over have returned.
What was it like?
It was sort of awful.
But I didn't find out anything
about human transmutation.
Oh.
Ultimately, it got us nowhere, huh?
No, that's not true.
The Führer mentioned something before.
He said that there was unrest
in the ranks.
Yeah, and that the Philosopher's Stone
and the guys
with the Ouroboros tattoos were involved.
As such, he said he wanted
to get some information on them.
Greed had an Ouroboros tattoo too.
So why did they have to kill everyone?
If he wanted to get anything on them,
he could have captured them
and extracted what he wanted, right?
Yeah.
What's more,
with only that many people to deal with,
it's strange that the Führer
would show up.
Yeah.
All of this is kind of hard to swallow.
I guess we'll stick with the military
for a while.
Welcome back, Führer.
How did your inspection in the south go?
The Fullmetal Alchemist's brother
and perhaps their teacher
would make good material
for a sacrifice as well.
And there was one other thing.
An unexpected catch.
My, this takes me back.
It's the face of someone
who left here a century ago.
Wake up, Greed.
Oh, my, the gang's all here.
Serves you right, Ultimate Shield.
And you're the same old fine woman
as Ultimate Spear,
Lust the Lascivious.
Gluttony the Voracious,
you haven't slimmed down one bit, huh?
Envy the Jealous,
are you in that tasteless getup again?
Where is Sloth the Indolent?
He's always absent.
Still at work.
None of you have really changed
in a hundred years, huh?
So then, who is this?
Wrath the Furious.
Wrath? You're King Bradley, right?
Yes.
Our brother,
who, as the human King Bradley,
has been prepared by Father
for the final endgame.
A Homunculus that ages? Is that possible?
There's no such thing as "no such thing."
That was your favorite phrase.
Have you forgotten it?
Or are you just going senile?
You shut your mouth, ugly.
Oh, I like that look in your eye.
That's more like it.
Show us your true self
for old times' sake,
"Cobbled-together Envy."
Damn you.
I'll crush you just like you want me to.
Stop it, both of you.
No more carrying on
ugly brotherly quarrels in front of me.
Hey there, Daddy, sir.
I don't see you for a little while,
and you've gone and aged quite a bit,
haven't you?
Greed, my son,
with whom I have shared my soul,
why have you betrayed me, your father?
Why, you ask?
You know why better than anyone,
don't you, Daddy, sir?
I am Greed the Avaricious.
That is how you created me
and that is exactly how I have lived.
If I had stayed with you,
my desire would have gone unfulfilled.
Will you work for me again?
No!
I see.
Whoa, how cheesy.
Damn, that water sure feels nice and hot!
I don't suppose the flames of hell
will be quite so tepid though!
I'm going on ahead
to see what they are like, my brethren!
Back to where you were born,
into my soul, Greed.
Fine!
Don't blame me if I upset
your stomach though, Daddy, sir!
I pray for your unwavering loyalty
and well-being
as we move toward the forthcoming day.
Father!
Welcome back, Father!
I'm home, Selim.
How was your inspection?
It truly was a fulfilling inspection.
You're not as young
as you used to be, dear.
You could give up your seat
to a younger man and settle down.
Oh, no, I'm not ready
to be mothballed yet.
Oh, right.
I ran into the Fullmetal Alchemist
down south.
The little alchemist?
Really?
Selim, you sure do enjoy stories
about Edward.
Well, he is the youngest State Alchemist.
That's so cool, isn't it?
Wow, I'd like to learn alchemy too.
What would you do once you learned it?
I'd want to get a state certification
and help out Father.
Well, in the future, Selim,
maybe I will have you help me out.