You would challenge the Silver Alchemist
Giolio Comanche to battle?
You've got guts.
However...
Not bad at all.
You got off with just a scratch.
Just a scratch, was it?
What the hell is this?
Oh, sir, you're back?
What is this?
Pleased to meet you.
My name is May Chang.
As I had collapsed by the roadside,
your master, Mr. Yoki, saved me.
Master?
If you've recovered,
then be on your way at once.
What?
Let me close up your wound.
It's healed!
This is alkahestry from the land of Xing.
Xing?
That's right. She says she crossed
the great desert to the east
all by herself to come here.
Ridiculous, isn't it?
I wasn't all by myself!
It was me and her!
Her? You mean that little thing?
That's right. This is Shao May.
This is alkahestry, right?
The art of reading the dragon's pulse,
the power that flows
through the earth, and using it.
This tattoo matches up
with the flow of alkahestry from my land.
My brother researched
both alkahestry and alchemy.
This tattoo is the result of his research.
My, your brother
is really outstanding, isn't he?
I'm not sure what any of this is,
but your wound is now healed.
So now,
we can go to Central without trouble.
In that case, let's get ready.
See here! He told you to get going, right?
We're not going there for the fun of it.
But I'm serious about this too.
You mean that immortality affair
you spoke of earlier?
There's no such thing.
Yes, there is! That's why I'm here!
Shut up! A kid should act like a kid--
Immortality could not be attained
through alkahestry.
But by using alchemy...
That's why I have to meet the man
I've heard so much about.
With golden hair, golden eyes,
gallantly sporting a red coat,
brilliantly saving others,
that gifted alchemist,
Sir Edward Elric!
What do we do, sir?
Suit yourself.
What's the matter, Black Hayate?
It's dangerous to be out
walking alone at this hour.
If you do, you'll get attacked by me,
Barry the Chopper!
What'd you go and do that for?
Damn it! Then how do you like this?
Whoa, how come you're not surprised?
Because I know someone similar to you.
Similar? You mean,
that Alphonse what's-his-face guy?
You know Alphonse?
So you're a friend of his, huh?
You know, sweetheart,
you're pretty strong.
The Philosopher's Stone.
To think that the Fifth Laboratory
was involved in making them.
There's a possibility
that the military's senior staff
is connected as well.
Plus, there are those others,
Lust and Envy.
Are they the ones
who turned you into that?
Nah, it was the researchers.
They ripped my soul
out of my body by force.
If we look into those researchers,
we might be able to find out the identity
of whoever ordered the experiments.
No chance.
Those guys were all used
to make Philosopher's Stones with,
and there's not a single one of them left.
Both hushing them up and using them
as ingredients. How economical.
Does this mean there's no need
to make the stones anymore?
Let me ask you one last thing.
Are you the one
who killed a military officer
at a telephone booth in Central
a little over a month ago?
Don't know about that.
Was he all chopped up?
No.
If you don't know about it, never mind.
Yo, Miss Winry!
We appear to find you
in good spirits today.
Ed, Al!
What are you up to, popping in like this?
Good grief.
Even Paninya is holding down
an honest job now, and look at you.
Paninya is?
Yeah, she's given up pick-pocketing
and is now making a living fixing roofs
and other work in high places.
What about you guys?
Made any progress?
Yeah, we're taking the long way, though.
We're moving ahead, little by little.
I guess.
Okay. Good, then.
There, the first aid is done.
Thank you, Winry.
We're short on parts right now
so make do with that for the time being.
I'll go get them right now,
so would you mind killing a little time?
Yeah, but...
this place has nothing but automail shops.
- Al?
- Brother.
What, did you find another cat
or something?
Yeah.
Ah, I feel alive again!
You guys saved my life. Thank you.
And thanks for treating.
I never said I was treating.
- Don't worry over such a little thing.
- Don't say "little"!
You know, I sure am glad
for kindness found in foreign lands.
Foreign lands? You're a foreigner?
Yeah. I came from Xing.
Xing?
You mean, the large country to the east?
Yeah. Man, crossing the desert was rough.
Why on earth would you take that route?
Because I wanted to see the ruins
of Xerxes?
Xerxes?
I'd heard there was nothing there.
I just looked around a little.
I came to this country to check out things
relating to alkahestry.
Alkahestry?
Ah, I think you call it alchemy
in this country.
In our country, it's called "alkahestry,"
and it's a prominent art
in the medical field.
Huh. Different lands, different style.
Here, it has lots of military uses.
Even now, there are unending skirmishes
near the borders
of Aerugo to the south and Creta to west.
We face the huge country
of Drachma to the north.
We have a tentative nonaggression treaty
with them.
Briggs Mountain is in the way
and that keeps them from attacking.
But our relationship is still dicey.
What a restless country.
I'd say things started tending more
to the military
once the current Führer, Bradley,
came to power.
I have to admit, though,
I'm interested
in this medically-specialized alkahestry.
You bet.
By any chance, are you guys alchemists?
Oh, yes.
I am Edward Elric, State Alchemist.
I am his brother, Alphonse Elric.
Pleased to meet you.
I'm Ling Yao. My pleasure.
Say, Ling,
tell us more about this alkahestry.
I can't. I'm not an alkahestrist.
If you're not an alkahestrist,
what did you come to investigate?
I'm kind of looking for something.
Maybe you might know of it.
The Philosopher's Stone?
I really want it badly.
Do you know anything about it?
Nope, we don't know.
Looks to me like you do know.
I wonder if you'd tell me about it.
What are you going to use
the Philosopher's Stone for?
I'm looking for the way
to gain immortality.
So would you tell me about it?
Immortality. What a bunch of nonsense.
I'm serious.
In any case, is this the attitude you take
when you ask people for things?
I don't think so!
Brother!
You defy us too?
Hold on!
You jerk. What are you, an acrobat?
Maybe it's a "Xingese" fighting style.
Must be challenging.
- Even so...
- Yeah.
- They're not as strong...
- As Teacher!
Huh?
Off they go.
- Pops, add on some dessert, okay?
- Sure.
Yikes.
Damn.
Bringing up the Philosopher's Stone
and immortality,
then picking a fight with us
out of nowhere like this--!
What are you up to?
Both you and that closed-eyed idiot?
Whoa, I hit him. Yow!
Ouch...
As soon as I called that bastard
a closed-eyed idiot...
I see.
Ah, long time no see, Paninya!
What on earth are you up to?
Then again, I have a pretty good idea.
Oh, right, Paninya,
I have a favor I need to ask.
Strange. I don't sense the flow of chi
that any living person
should have from this suit of armor.
What exactly is...?
Did you think it would do any good
to bring others to your side?
You fool!
What's wrong, what's wrong?
I'm starting to predict your movements!
If this is the best
his flunkies can manage,
that Ling bastard
must not be all that special either!
Sure enough, as soon as I put down
his master, he suddenly loses his cool.
Once that happens...
his attacks become dull and overblown!
Now then, I think it's about time...
I had a look at your face!
You're a girl?
A cannon in her prosthetic limb?
This country
is something to be reckoned with.
What?
Hmm, well, for my first time,
I guess that's what you'd expect.
Alkahestry, without an array?
Now then.
I wonder if brother is all right?
I overdid it.
What do I do?
Master Ling is going to yell at me.
Hey, girly.
How could you use something like that
in the middle of town?
If it hadn't been me,
you could have killed someone.
You removed your own arm?
I chased a lot of rabbits around
as a kid.
So setting traps is a cinch for me.
Brother!
Hey, Al.
Okay, good work, everyone.
Why, you--? How can you be so carefree?
Wow, you guys are good.
How about if you come and work for me
and we'll rule the whole country?
Enough of your blathering!
You go back to Xing, right now--
Oh, there they are!
You've done quite a number,
wrecking the town, haven't you?
You're paying for the damages.
And your dinner bill.
Just a minute.
Have this guy and his entourage pay
for the food and damages.
I no understand this country language.
Goodbye.
Hey, you, wait the hell up!
Huh?
Ah! He ran away!
This one too!
Aw, man. How can I fix things
in the shape I'm in?
It's okay, brother. I'll do it.
So you can do it now
without transmutation circles?
I think it's because I got my memories
about the truth back.
Which means...
ALCHEMIC TECHNIQUE
OLDER BROTHER'S DIGNITY
HEIGHT
Leave the rest to me.
What's the matter, brother?
We're back!
Hey, we meet again.
Don't just sit there drinking tea!
How cruel, even though we're friends.
Who are you calling "friend"?
Those two gave us a real hard time.
Let it go. I'll give them
a good talking-to later.
The girl's name is Lan Fan,
and the old man is Fu.
Those two are from a family
that has served us for generations,
so accept their regards.
For someone
who shakes down others for food,
you must have considerable status
to have two attendants.
Well, I am the emperor's son.
Huh? The emperor's son?
You mean you're a...
prince?
Usually, one would be surprised by that.
Oh, sorry. It was just so unexpected.
Imagine, the guy who collapsed
by the side of the road
and freeloaded a meal out of us
being the son of an emperor--
I won't allow you to speak ill of Master.
You are here?
Okay, sure,
maybe it's not all that surprising.
The emperor has many sons.
Xing is a nation made up
of 50 different clans
with an emperor reigning
over them at the top.
Also, the daughter of each clan's chief
is wed to the emperor,
and bears his children.
The current emperor has 24 sons
and 19 daughters.
I am the 12th among them.
Forty-three children...
Is there any competition
to be his successor?
That is indeed a problem
that we are faced with right now.
The emperor is in fairly poor health.
Each clan is going all-out to try
and kiss up to him while they still can.
Which is what I'm up to also.
You're going to use the method
of gaining immortality to entice him.
You are correct.
Okay? So tell me some information
about the Philosopher's Stone.
No way. The Philosopher's Stone
is not a tool for you to get ahead!
Tell me or I'll tag along
with you forever.
Don't you tag along!
I'm back!
There was some kind of huge commotion
on the main street
so it took a while to--
Why is it broken off?
Why, you--! Why, you--! Why, you--
I'm sorry!
Young Lord!
There is no need for you to bow your head
to someone so beneath you.
If all it takes is me bowing my head,
it's a small price to pay, right?
The fate of 500,000 Yao clansmen
are riding on this.
We can't be so fussy about appearances.
So where are you going to break
your automail this time?
You just assume I'll break it?
We were thinking
of looking around in Central.
Huh? You're going to Central?
I want to go, I want to go!
What are you going there for?
I want to go to Mr. Hughes' place
to visit.
But, Winry, you have to work, don't you?
That's okay, Winry.
You should take a breather
once in a while.
Really? Thank you, Mr. Garfiel!
- Okay then, why don't we all...
- Go to Central.
Yeah.
I can't wait to see Central!
I told you, you're not tagging along!
So she's tagging along with us after all.
By the way, sir,
you still haven't told me your name.
Won't you please tell me?
The Ishvalan people take pride
when they speak their names,
as they are a gift from God.
Well, well, sir,
yours must be a fine name.
As such, I have renounced my name.
Go! Keep moving!
Yes, sir!
If this is to be a road
from which I cannot return,
then I will leave behind
all that I have received from God.