Ah, I'm worn out.
You were being spied on that whole time.
Mr. Fu and Lan Fan, wasn't it?
Hey, where is Young Lord?
- He's not here.
- Could he have gone missing again?
My word, he does this
as soon as I take my eyes off him!
Young Lord!
Where have you gone off to?
What if he's collapsed again?
Ah, that's a relief. Let's go.
Right!
Young Lord! Where are you?
There's something weird
about this country.
It's me. I came to check on you.
You're doing a fine job.
This is from the colonel.
Yo, it's the smoking dude.
Well? Have you beaten him even once?
Not even once.
And anyway, this game is boring.
Hey, if it's nighttime,
I can go out and cut someone up, right?
Of course, you can't.
Then, at least,
bring that lady Hawkeye here.
Yeah, I'll tell the lady.
How long do I have to keep watch
over this guy, anyway?
What did the colonel say?
He said, "Sorry to have assigned you
to this dangerous assignment.
Don't worry about your military duties.
We're treating it like sick leave.
But if anyone from the general public
or any military personnel other than us
sees you, you'll pay for it."
- Any news of a slightly brighter future?
- Yes.
What is it?
I've found myself a girlfriend!
She was really nice to me
when I was having trouble
with the move here.
She's a really fine girl, too.
Hey, would this girl be fun to cut up?
Please leave now.
Hey, you okay?
Food...
Aw, collapsed by the side of the road.
Where are you from?
What? You came from Xing?
What a faraway place to come from.
Now then, where's your entry visa?
Hey, make way, make way!
Illegal alien coming through!
Young Lord, where are you?
He's collapsed. I'm sure he's collapsed.
Now then, I guess we should drop by
the military offices first.
Yeah.
Well, I think maybe I'll go on ahead
to Mr. Hughes' house
and pay my respects.
I want to see Mrs. Gracia
and Elicia quickly.
Gotcha. We'll be right behind you.
Okay, see you later.
I wonder if Colonel Hughes has
put together any more information
about the Philosopher's Stone
for us since we left.
The Führer was pretty clear about it.
Let's first give him the information
that we've found out.
- The Homunculus.
- Yeah.
The colonel is
in the court-martial office, as I recall.
That way.
- Sheska? Sheska!
- Yes, ma'am?
You had the key to that room, right?
Yes, ma'am.
Ah, you mean number three, right?
It's still a mess
from when I was using it.
That's all right.
I just have to get the documents I need.
Really, you can't!
I'll tidy it up quickly,
if you could just wait a moment!
Okay, I'll come by later for them,
so take care of it before then.
Yes, ma'am!
Colonel? Colonel Mustang?
How long have I been asleep?
About ten minutes, I'd say.
There's no time left
before the council meeting.
Perhaps it's none of my business,
but maybe you shouldn't push yourself
so hard and you should get some rest.
Yeah, I'll be back later.
Was that Colonel Mustang just now?
Good morning, Captain Focker.
Good morning, Sheska.
By the way,
what was the colonel doing here?
Ah, well...
The storeroom is open.
I'm sorry! The truth is, I...
I bet the colonel twisted your arm, huh?
I won't tell anyone.
Thank you very much!
Then again, I wonder
what the colonel was looking into.
Do you know?
I don't know all the details,
but he asked me
if there were any materials
about the Fifth Laboratory.
Also, he asked
about the General Hughes case.
I got my job here through the general.
Ah, that's right.
There's a huge stack of work
to get to today.
Carry on.
Yes, sir.
Good morning, Sheska.
Sir?
Huh?
Hello.
Hey.
Have you lost some weight, sir?
Maybe.
Did you get injured?
Something happened down south.
But this is just a scratch.
I see.
I saw the Elric brothers.
They had gone to Dublith
to see their teacher
and I chanced upon them.
- Major...
- Sir?
Did you tell them about Hughes' death?
No, I couldn't bring myself to tell them.
- They're going to find out eventually.
- I know.
The Fifth Laboratory
and the Philosopher's Stones.
The Stones' ingredients are live humans.
He used to enjoy doing things for others.
He stuck his nose into what
the Elric brothers were investigating
and learned something
he would've been better off not knowing.
Am I wrong?
If the brothers find out that Hughes died
because of what they were involved with,
it will hurt them.
You're a good-hearted person.
You're well-informed.
I'm almost there.
Please be careful, sir.
There's no telling who might be listening.
Well, if you'll excuse me...
Huh? Lieutenant Hawkeye...
Oh, long time no see.
- Lieutenant, if you're here, then...
- Thanks for waiting.
Sure.
Oh, Fullmetal.
Colonel, what are you doing here?
I was assigned to Central last month.
What about you? What brings you here?
Well, just a little information gathering.
After that, we were thinking
of saying hello to Colonel Hughes.
How's the colonel doing?
- He's not here.
- Huh?
He retired out in the country.
He took his wife and kid
and said he was taking over
the family business.
So, he's not here.
He's not? That's too bad.
We were hoping to see him.
Fullmetal.
Don't get ahead of yourself
and do anything crazy.
Yeah...
You're going to treat him like a child?
There's no need for him to find out now.
The fewer obstacles those brothers have
to block their progress right now,
the better.
But they are going to find out someday.
I'm in no position
to call Major Armstrong a soft touch.
Are you sure this is a matter
that calls for a soft touch?
It's cruel.
The colonel isn't here.
Ah, that's right, Brother.
We have to tell Winry.
She went to Mr. Hughes' house.
You're right.
Lieutenant Ross!
I haven't seen you two in a while.
What's wrong?
We heard about Lt. Colonel Hughes.
Oh. That's rough, huh?
There was so much we wanted to tell him.
We wanted to say goodbye at least.
We weren't able to reach you.
It's okay. The military gave him
a proper send-off.
- Wow, that was nice of them.
- It's only natural.
Also, you might have heard,
they promoted him two ranks,
so he's not a lieutenant colonel,
he's a brigadier general.
Promoted him two ranks?
He retired to the countryside
and they promoted him?
Lieutenant Ross?
Here you go.
Thanks.
It can't be.
Why the colonel? Why?
Brother!
General Hughes was killed by someone
right after you were discharged
from the hospital, Edward.
We still haven't caught the culprit.
It's my fault.
I'm the one who pulled
Colonel Hughes into this!
Okay, be careful on your journey.
If you ever come by Central,
give me a holler.
Alphonse, you can't eat
while still wearing your armor, right?
You guys don't have a place to stay, yes?
So, come home with me.
Papa!
What do we do?
Tell it like it is.
You go on back.
I'm the only one
who has to take the blame for this.
Brother, this isn't just your problem.
It's both of ours.
That's why I'm going, too.
Say, Al, what if--?
We made up our minds
to get our bodies back, no matter what.
But if people are going to die
because of us,
I don't want my body back.
- Winry is...
- Right.
Winry...
There's something
that I have to tell Mrs. Gracia. May I?
- To me?
- Yes.
You too, Winry.
My husband learned something
about the Philosopher's Stone.
My husband's death
is a warning from those criminals,
telling you not to stick your noses in
any further, isn't it?
We dragged him into this.
I'm sorry.
That's just like him,
dying while trying to help others out.
He always came out worse
due to his meddlesome,
busybody ways, even back then.
But I don't think he ever had any regrets.
Not even in his dying moments.
We...
Don't say you're giving up, okay?
If you give up now,
my husband's death
will be utterly meaningless.
Even if the Philosopher's Stone
doesn't work out,
there might be some other way, right?
Mrs. Gracia...
Keep moving forward
in some way that you can accept.
Mama...
Mama, don't cry.
Winry, are you in there?
You haven't eaten, have you?
The dining room is closing soon.
Yeah.
You have to eat, to keep up your strength.
Okay, I'm going back to my room.
Apple pie?
I've practiced making it a few times.
I hate to say so myself,
but I've gotten pretty good at it.
Though I'm not nearly
as good as Mrs. Gracia.
Someday...
I was hoping to have Mr. Hughes
eat it someday.
You're saying the colonel
is snooping around the Hughes matter?
Yeah.
He may have discovered something.
Maybe.
What do we do?
We moved him to Central
thinking we could observe him better
where we could keep an eye on him.
Why can't he behave himself?
He's an important candidate
for sacrifice after all.
Haven't you gotten anything
out of your boyfriend?
Nothing. Either he was born an idiot
or he's just a hustler.
I'm going to gather more intelligence.
Come along, Gluttony.
Hey, Gluttony!
Don't leave the place a mess.
Geez, man.
Hey, Lust,
sure would be nice if the Flame Colonel
would behave himself, huh?
Yes.
You feel like making another play?
Have you got something?
When you've got a noisy dog,
you have to give it some food.
Second Lieutenant Maria Ross.
Henry Douglas, Provost Marshal's Office.
Did you need something from me?
You'll have to come with us. Your gun.
Can I ask what this is about?
Your name has come up
as a material witness
in the Maes Hughes murder case.
That's absurd!
You may tell your side later.
Come with us.
Lieutenant Maria Ross herself
is pleading not guilty.
Gather all the materials you can
pertaining to her.
Be quick, but do it secretly.
Yes, sir.
Ma'am, bundle these flowers for me.
Oh, my, you have a date, lover boy?
Been waiting long, Solaris?
No, I just got here.
I've missed you, Jean.
Tell me some more interesting stories.