This is the bullet that was used
to kill General Hughes.
It's a .45 caliber.
Only one bullet was used.
I'd like to say it was a good shot,
but it was at point-blank range.
Close enough that even a woman
could have done it.
- What caliber is the gun that you use?
- .45 caliber.
This is your ammunition re-supply request,
is that correct?
It says here that you fired one shot.
What was it used for?
As it says on there, to protect
Edward Elric at the Fifth Laboratory.
The Fifth Laboratory had been closed
and was unmanned.
It was not unmanned.
So you claim.
Shall I request that the bullet
you say you fired be searched for?
The Fifth Laboratory
is now a pile of rubble
because of a mysterious explosion.
So the location where you claim
to have used your gun was unmanned,
and even if we were to search
for the body, it's under a pile of rubble.
Is that what you're saying?
We have an eyewitness testimony
that states that, on that day,
at the time of the murder,
you were spotted leaving the scene.
- That's preposterous!
- Calm down.
What were you doing at that time?
I had that day off
and I was at my parents' house.
Please check with my parents.
The testimonies of your family
and those you are close with
are not admissible as alibis.
Lieutenant Maria Ross
is currently being questioned.
Not even her superior officer
may be present.
I see.
Major Armstrong!
- Sergeant Brosh...
- You're here too, Major?
- Is this about Lieutenant Ross?
- Yes. The truth is...
The truth is, the lieutenant and I
both fired a single shot
to defend the Elric brothers
at the Fifth Laboratory.
What?
I said so in my report,
but it's being rejected.
Are they trying to frame
the lieutenant as the culprit?
When you look closely,
you're full of scratches.
You're having a hard journey, huh?
Say, what are you going to do now?
Hey...
What are we going to do?
Mama, don't cry.
What would you like us to do?
What?
It's just that you've never asked
for advice about yourselves before.
I was scared.
Ed and Al, you were fighting so long
in such a dangerous place,
the place where Mr. Hughes was killed.
I got really scared
when I thought about it.
I mean, you could die. Suddenly,
you wouldn't be around me anymore.
Like Mom and Dad did.
I got really scared
when I thought about that.
To be honest, I wished you
would give up your journey.
I do want you to get your original body,
but I wish you'd give up
your dangerous journey, too.
I mean...
Then again...
Sorry.
I don't know what I want to do, either.
- Winry, you're sure being nice.
- What are you talking about?
- I'm always nice! What do you mean?
- Stop! You're adding more scratches.
Here ya go.
- Evening edition!
- Oh, it's here, it's here!
- What, the newspaper again?
- I'm stuck hanging out with you all day.
This is about the only pleasure I get.
This is Lieutenant Falman,
calling on an outside line.
Please connect me to Colonel Mustang.
Yes. My code is...
Man, what's all this about?
...Airam, George, Oliver, Four, Six.
This is that chick from back then.
The Philosopher's Stone...
The people with the Uroboros marks...
Homunculi...
How do they--?
Brother!
- Here.
- Don't startle me like that.
The newspaper at the front desk...
What?
"Lt. Maria Ross found to be the culprit
in Gen. Hughes' murder"?
I can't believe it.
The colonel or the major might know
something about this.
- What about Winry?
- We'll explain later.
I don't like these.
Quit your complaining.
They're like a collar for a mutt.
By the way, I have to ask you again,
are you really 15?
- That's right.
- Get out of here!
It's the truth.
What's that?
- What's the matter?
- There's an intruder! Give us a hand.
What?
- You behave yourself.
- Okay.
Lame! Lame! Lame!
You guys think you're tough?
- What's with this guy?
- Guns don't have any effect.
Move it! Why, you...
"Ghost!"
GHOST!
Man, it sucks not being allowed to cut.
Hello there,
man who isn't affected by guns!
Let me out of here!
- Who are you?
- An illegal immigrant from Xing.
Oh, yeah? Nice going,
coming here from a faraway land.
If you let me out, I'll help you.
I don't have time to bother with--
- Where did you say you were from?
- Xing, to the east.
- Come with me.
- Thanks.
What?
Hello, honey! I finally found you!
You were at the Fifth Laboratory!
I'm so glad you remember me.
Every time I look at the hole
you put in my right hand,
I think of the chick who killed Hughes.
- That's a misunderstanding!
- Is it?
The papers say they found you
to be the culprit.
That can't be...
As it stands,
they're going to pin the guilt on you,
and you'll face a firing squad.
It's not true. It's not true. If they
would just do a proper investigation...
Choose. Stay here and be tortured to death
or run away with me.
Choose one or the other.
This is terrible.
- Don't I have any other choices?
- It doesn't look like it.
Oh, man. Mom, Dad, I'm sorry.
Okay, I'll run away. I'm running away.
Just make sure you escort me,
you big, dumb armored bonehead!
Oh, you've got spunk.
A girl's gotta have some nerve!
Yes... Yes, as you wish.
Notify every zone in the city.
Maria Ross has broken out.
She appears to be with a violent
companion. Catch them at once.
If she resists,
they are free to shoot to kill.
- How far are we going?
- Just keep running!
Lieutenant Ross?
Edward! Alphonse!
- You're that guy!
- And even Ling is here!
- Hey, guys, what are you up to?
- I was about to ask you that!
Hey! We don't have time for this!
Why, you!
Hey, sweetheart, take that back alley.
Run directly to the warehouse district.
You'll be able to get away
under the cover of darkness!
Lieutenant Ross! Was Colonel Hughes...
Run! If the MPs show up, they'll shoot.
- Lieutenant Ross!
- Stay back!
Lieutenant! Lieutenant Ross!
Maria Ross, right?
- What?
- Oh, they got her.
Hey, wait!
Watch out!
- Let's go, closed-eyes!
- Okie-dokie.
Ling, what are you doing with that guy?
I'll tell you later.
Man!
Yo, Fullmetal.
What's going on here?
What's going on here, Colonel?
Why?
Why is Colonel Hughes...?
Why did Lieutenant Ross...?
Why didn't you say anything?
You would raise your hand
to your superior officer?
Don't forget your place.
- No, Brother!
- Let me go, Al!
I said no!
- This bastard killed Lieutenant Ross!
- Lieutenant Ross?
What is the meaning of this, Colonel?
There were orders to shoot
the fugitive Maria Ross on sight.
- That's all.
- That's all?
I apologize for hiding Hughes' death.
But do not argue against orders.
Do not ask for explanations.
Just follow them.
That's what a soldier does!
Colonel Mustang... Tell me what happened.
The message went out that if she resisted,
we were permitted to shoot to kill.
She resisted, so I killed her.
I understand the brigadier general
was a good friend of yours.
Yeah.
He was a good guy.
I don't suppose it was one of your men
who broke Lieutenant Ross out.
- Me? Why?
- Why?
So you could burn her to death
by your own hand.
I'd appreciate it
if you avoided such speculation.
I truly am sorry for not telling you
about General Hughes' death.
It's my fault.
Don't be so hard on yourself.
It wasn't your fault.
- You're all together, huh?
- Dr. Knocs...
The damage is severe.
But judging from what little was left
of the dental work,
I was able to conclude
that this was Maria Ross.
It's an awful thing,
turning a beauty like her
into charcoal like this.
You must have held quite a grudge,
Mr. Mustang.
Do you feel better
now that you've taken vengeance?
The hero of the Ishval War
going this far against a little girl...
It makes me sick.
Colonel, let me take this opportunity
to apologize for what one
of my own men did.
To think that Lieutenant Ross
could commit murder...
She was such a straightforward,
earnest, considerate woman.
Fatigue seems to be catching up with you.
You should take leave.
Back east, where I was.
That's a nice place.
There's no big-city hustle and bustle,
and best of all,
there are lots of beautiful women.
And so, Mustang handily avenges
his brother.
And all's well that ends well.
Don't you think the ending is a little...?
The plan was supposed to get
the colonel to behave himself.
Who cares? The dog eating the bait
works out pretty slick, too.
Besides, it looks like
we came across a little antagonism.
There's no love lost between him
and his subordinates, is there?
What's that?
A request for leave.
- At a time like this?
- Is it out of line?
- No, it's fine. Approved.
- Thank you very much.
All right, you, going out
on your own like that...
What would the colonel say to me
if you were found out?
- Nobody saw me when I came back.
- That's not the issue here!
You're just a poor soldier
held captive by a heinous criminal,
so it's all right.
Yo! What are you up to out there?
- A signal fire.
- A signal fire?
What were you thinking, bringing someone
you know nothing about back here?
Young Lord! We've been looking for you.
- Oh, that was fast.
- Now there's even more.
Hey, Elizabeth, how are you?
Thanks so much for calling me.
Are you sure your scary adjutant
won't get mad at you
if you blow off too much work?
That's okay, she's not in.
And I'm able to call you like this
because she isn't.
How about that?
The moment the lieutenant goes on leave,
he gets like this.
Man, she really is like his nanny, huh?
That's right. I haven't had a day off
since I got here,
so I'm thinking about going on leave.
- Are you going somewhere?
- Lately, I've been caught up in fishing.
Care to come along?
Yes? Who is it?
What did you do that for, Major?
Edward Elric...
This is bad. You've broken your automail.
This is a serious situation.
We'll have to repair this at once.
Allow me to escort you to Resembool.
- What's this?
- You're going home to Resembool?
Oh, Al, listen to me.
Alphonse Elric, you would stand out there.
Remain in Central.
- Right.
- All right!
Let's make arrangements for the train
right away! Come along, Edward Elric.
Cut it out already, Major.
I can't do that.
These are my orders...
...from him.
Yes. Roger that.
Major Armstrong and Edward Elric
have gotten aboard the train.
I see.
Now, everyone is out of the way.
I made contact with a witness who saw
the man who stormed the lockup.
And... this is a sketch of the culprit.
Oh, he's still alive, then.
Any link to the Flame Colonel?
Who knows? I'd say the chances
are pretty good, though.
Where did he run to?
Well, he ran away quickly
and he's good at hiding.
In other words, you don't know.
You're lying.
Shut up, you old biddy.
I was short on manpower.
Manpower?
You've got plenty of manpower,
right, honey?
Come on. You're on, Barry the Chopper.