Elizabeth! Hey!
Elizabeth!
And this is a secret.
According to what Barry said,
the colonel is trying to smoke out
the military group that had something
to do with the Fifth something-or-other.
The Fifth Laboratory.
Al...
I have to go.
I might be able to find out
about the person who killed Mr. Hughes.
Just a minute!
What about the secret of your body?
- I'll tell you once I get back.
- Man...
I'll be back soon.
You make sure you come back safe.
I promise.
Are you done yet?
Can I eat you?
What a pest. Move!
Lieutenant!
Out of ammo? Out of ammo?
Well then, time to eat!
I made it in time.
Colonel... Why did you come out here?
You could have eluded the enemy's pursuit,
regardless of what happened to us!
And yet, you just stroll on
in here like this!
Are you, in fact, an idiot, sir?
Yeah, okay, okay. I'm an idiot.
Who is that guy?
Colonel, the target has started to move!
Sergeant, break camp!
Leave no trash behind!
- Hayate, you stay with the sergeant!
- Yes, sir!
- Colonel.
- What?
Thank you very much.
Save it for later.
Right now, we're on a mission.
Yes, sir.
- Get in!
- Yes, sir.
This has something to do
with Mr. Hughes' case, doesn't it?
- Are you coming?
- Yes.
- Don't lose sight of him.
- He's not getting away from me.
My whole soul is abuzz,
saying, "This way! This way!"
Is that monstrous, fat guy
going to show up again, too?
I don't know. Who was that guy, anyhow?
I shot him several times
in critical areas,
but he still kept a straight face.
By any chance,
did he have an Uroboros tattoo?
Tattoo?
There was one on his tongue.
Is that what you're talking about?
That was... probably... a Homunculus.
Watch out!
You idiot!
Hold on, hold on, hold on!
A Homunculus? There's no such thing!
Down south, I met a Homunculus
by the name of Greed. He told me,
"There's no such thing
as no such thing."
Homunculi have incredible
regenerative abilities.
Greed had half of his head knocked off,
but he was back to normal soon after.
Although, I doubt you would believe me.
I have no choice but to believe you
after what I saw.
You're not trying to tell me
that even after he got scorched
and fell out of that high tower,
he still isn't dead, are you?
Probably not.
For the love of--
pseudo-human freak show?
- My body fled here.
- The military's Third Laboratory?
Now I've got something
to hold over the senior staff.
That's a good enough catch.
We're pulling back.
- It's not good enough!
- You idiot!
- This is not good, Colonel.
- No, it works to our advantage.
Move it.
Move it. Move it.
I don't have any interest in your flesh!
Where are you, my little meatie-pie?
All remaining personnel,
evacuate immediately!
- Colonel?
- The intruder is a violent killer.
Leave his capture to us.
- Have guards seal off all the exits!
- Yes, sir!
Where has Barry gone off to?
- Split up into two groups.
- Yes, sir.
Looks like it's been a while
since this place was abandoned.
Was this... a laboratory?
If so, it doesn't look like
they were doing legitimate experiments.
My, what are the chances?
How unkind of you
to stand me up for our date.
I was waiting for you.
I've missed you, Jean.
- Solaris? What are you doing here?
- Hey, Havoc.
- She has an Uroboros tattoo!
- I'm just finding that out myself, sir.
I'm sorry I had to deceive you.
I get it. No wonder you were taken in.
You do like big boobs?
I love big boobs!
Boobs... Boobs... Boobs...
- Did you tell this woman anything?
- I never said anything about work!
Do you know who Maes Hughes is?
He was a quick-witted man, wasn't he?
I'm only sorry I didn't get
to strike the last blow.
On your knees.
Tell me everything you know.
I can't.
You two can't make me get on my kn--
Just what you'd expect
from the hero of Ishval. No mercy?
- You're a Homunculus!
- My, aren't you well-informed, Jean?
As a reward, let me show you this.
Can you see it?
It's a Philosopher's Stone.
People who are created
with these Stones at their core,
like we are, are Homunculi.
- You monster!
- How rude. We do have feelings.
We have affection towards our parents.
We are human.
If you're telling us
such an important secret,
it means you're not planning
on letting us out of here alive.
Yes. It's a shame, too.
Too slow!
Oh, dear. Now you can't produce
your celebrated flames.
What do we do, sir?
At this rate, she's going to slice us up!
Actually, she did me a favor.
With this much water,
I just have to decompose it
to produce hydrogen and oxygen!
This sucks.
I got this from a former girlfriend.
Damn. Colonel, can you give me a light?
- I guess not.
- What am I, a soggy match?
No doubt about it, that woman is cooked.
- How can you tell, sir?
- The smell.
- I've smelled a number of burned bodies.
- You mean your experience in Ishval?
Still, we can't count out
their regenerative abilities.
- Stay sharp.
- Yes, sir.
Havoc!
- Havoc, stay with me!
- Oh, no.
- You can't save him now.
- No!
- It's no use! I'm still not dead!
- The way to save him is right in here!
I'm going to use it to treat him.
Medical field alchemy
is outside of my expertise,
but by using this
to increase my abilities--
Is suddenly plunging his hand into
a lady's chest the act of a gentleman?
Führer. Your Excellency!
I heard there was an intruder.
Yes, sir. The criminal who attacked
the west-end lockup is inside.
Colonel Mustang went after him.
Well, then, I will go help him.
- We will accompany you!
- No.
I will be fine on my own.
I told you,
the Philosopher's Stone is my core.
I'm sorry.
You were a candidate for sacrifice,
but now you must die.
Why, you...
Die, as you watch your own man
grow cold before your eyes.
Lieutenant Havoc...
Answer me. Damn.
You are not allowed to die before I do.
Havoc...
You're late, lady.
Look at how decayed my body has become.
It's inherently impossible
to stick someone's body together
with a different soul.
If a soul is incompatible
with another person's body,
then me being a soul
within an iron body...
That's right. There's no guarantee
that this body will hold out...
until we achieve our goal.
Brother...
There you are, Miss Lust.
Number 66, why were you working
with the colonel?
Because it seemed like
it would be fun! Besides...
I want to chop you up more than anything!
Such a troublesome man.
And what about you, armor boy?
What brings you to someplace like this?
This is taking a heavy toll.
To think that I'll have to kill
two sacrifice candidates in one night!
- Sacrifice? Two?
- Yes. You and one other.
Enough with all the mumbo-jumbo,
Miss Lust!
I hate annoying men.
Now then, Miss Lieutenant,
I'll be sending you
to where I sent your superior.
Wait. You said two sacrifices
in one night, right?
You don't mean... You don't mean...
Why, you...!
Finished?
You truly are foolish and weak.
You poor creature.
- Lieutenant, get up and run away.
- Do you want to die first?
I see. You opened the doorway.
It's too bad.
You'd definitely be a sacrifice.
Alphonse, leave me here and run away.
- No!
- Run away!
- You, at least, have to--
I said no!
I'm sick of people dying before my eyes!
I've had enough!
I won't let anyone get killed anymore!
I'll protect them!
Well said, Alphonse Elric.
I've finally got you on your knees.
You used the flint as a starter,
and a transmutation circle
drawn in your own blood?
How did you get here with your wound?
I burned it closed. I nearly passed out
two or three times, too.
You said you still weren't dead,
didn't you?
Then I'll just have to kill you
until you are dead!
Colonel!
I've been beaten.
I hate to admit it.
But being killed by a man like you
isn't so bad.
Those eyes looking straight ahead,
unwavering...
I can't wait.
The day when those eyes will
be twisted in agony is not far off.
Colonel!
Are you all right?
Never mind me, please.
Worry about yourself, sir!
Alphonse, thank you for protecting her.
Never mind that.
Let's hurry and get you to a doctor!
Yeah. Hurry and call a doctor
for Havoc. Please.
He's all right.
I'm home.
You dummy! Welcome back!
Yeah.
So...
- It came off!
- Yikes, it won't go back on!
Well, well. I barely survived that one.
In the shape I'm in, I wonder
if someone will be able to fix me.
Are you still alive?
Hey, what are you doing?
I've still got killing, killing,
and more killing to do!
Wait! Wait! Wait! Stop!
It couldn't be.
It is...
Hohenheim!