Edward... You've gotten bigger.
I heard from Pinako.
About you performing
human transmutation.
Why did you come back here now?
This is not where you belong anymore!
Oh, right. My house...
Why did you burn it down?
Because we made up our minds
that there was no turning back.
- We did it to show our resolve--
- No, you didn't.
You didn't want to look at it.
You wanted to escape
from your unpleasant memories.
You wanted to hide the traces
of what you'd committed.
You're wrong!
Just like a child hiding the sheets
when he wets the bed.
You ran away, Edward.
What the hell do you know?
Damn! You turn my stomach!
Just like when I was young.
You haven't changed.
You're just...
as you were all those years ago.
Why didn't you come back any sooner?
Trisha was waiting for you all that time.
Pinako...
What my sons transmuted...
Was it really Trisha?
I told you. It didn't have a human form.
- I wouldn't say it was Trisha--
- No, that's not what I mean.
For example,
the eye color and the hair color.
What do you mean?
Are you telling me that wasn't Trisha?
Are you saying that those boys
created someone completely unrelated
and had their bodies taken away
because of it?
You can keep going
without ever eating or sleeping?
As long as this seal is unharmed.
Amazing! You truly are immortal,
aren't you?
No, I'm not.
This body is like a... time bomb.
Barry mentioned it.
A body is inherently incompatible
with someone else's soul.
If you force one into it,
it will undergo rejection.
Whether that will happen tomorrow
or ten years from now, I don't know.
Oh, no. Then you need to get back
to normal as soon as you can.
Yeah, but still,
if your body has some sort of problem,
can't you transfer your soul
into something else and go on living?
If that's the case,
then the way you are now...
You don't feel pain
and you don't need to eat.
That body of yours
is nice and handy, isn't it?
There's nothing nice about it!
You don't know anything!
- Sorry.
- Winry.
Winry? I'm coming in.
Geez, Winry, you and Brother
always get mad so quickly.
My timing is always off
when it comes to getting upset.
Well...
Apparently, this body
is unable to go to sleep.
Al...
You'll be able to get
your original body back. Right?
Give it back! It's my brother's body!
He's the only... the only family I have!
Give it back?
What are you talking about?
You're the one who put your brother
in that body, alchemist.
Yes. You're just like I am, Edward Elric.
Besides...
Edward... I don't like
being stuck in this form.
Ed! Are you still in bed?
Your father is leaving.
Do you mind... if I take this?
This was taken with the four of us.
It's the only one.
- No, I don't mind.
- Thanks.
In return, I'm going to let you in
on something important.
Something awful is going to happen
in this country soon.
Run away to some other land.
Awful things are not all that rare.
For that matter,
there are those who use this place
as somewhere to come home to.
I've given you my warning.
Hohenheim!
Come back once in a while
and break bread with us!
It's a shame, Pinako. I won't be able
to eat your cooking anymore.
Are you really going to dig that thing up?
Do you want to stop?
No. My stumps are aching.
It's going to rain.
Let's hurry and get this done.
Ed!
Didn't I tell you so?
Let's pack it in, already.
No.
I can't move forward
unless I'm sure! Besides...
You ran away.
I'm not about to run away!
Granny, Mom's hair was chestnut-colored.
It's black.
The femur... is too long.
- And the pelvis... This one is male.
- Granny...
Ed...
This is not your mother.
That's it. A dead person cannot be
brought back. That's the truth.
It was impossible to do.
Ed, snap out of it.
Get a hold of yourself.
I'm all right, Granny.
Ever since that day,
this has been a symbol of despair.
But now, it's our link to hope.
Al can be returned to normal.
Yes, Curtis residence.
Oh, it's you, Ed. What's up?
Teacher, there's something
I need to ask you.
It's just...
What? Just say it.
It's about when you transmuted your baby.
What about it?
Teacher, what Al and I transmuted
was not our mother.
What are you talking about?
What are you trying to say?
Teacher, the child that you transmuted...
Was it really your child?
I see.
My son and his wife did
some good on the battlefield?
You don't say...
Where did he...
Where did Hohenheim say he was going?
He didn't say.
I forgot. I have an important message
to give him.
- Message?
- Yeah.
Trisha's last words to him.
Once he comes back,
could you tell him something for me?
Tell him I couldn't keep my promise.
That I was dying before him
and that I'm sorry.
Promise? What promise?
Who knows? I hate to ask,
but if you see him, tell him.
Why should I have to?
Despite how he acts, he really
is quite concerned about you two.
I'll tell him after I pop him one!
You're going back to Central?
Yeah. Al's going to be mad at me,
off doing all this on my own.
What the hell!
I'm sorry.
You're all beat-up!
And what's worse...
- What are you guys doing here?
- We're eating.
Sheesh, what happened to you?
A Homunculus, Barry the Chopper,
and to top it off, a reaction of rejection
between an incompatible body and soul?
I'll extend what's left of your armor.
Al... can go back
to the way he was, right?
Of course, he can! I said I would
put him back together and I will!
Al...
I dug up what we transmuted
together in Resembool.
Why would you do that?
And as a result,
I discovered that it wasn't Mom.
What are you talking about? I mean...
What we transmuted
was something completely different.
So then, that means I was...
And I've become convinced
that you can get back to normal.
Really?
Yeah. But, before I get into that...
Winry, do you remember
when we had that brotherly quarrel
about which one of us
was going to marry you?
You mean what we talked about
on the roof before?
Yeah. Al said you turned him down.
I did, I did.
So, this question is for both of you.
What was the reason?
- I don't like men shorter than me.
Don't go judging the value of men
by their height!
So does this have something to do
with Al's body?
What it comes down to
is that Al knew something that I didn't.
And Winry,
since you remember the same thing,
it means that it was an actual event.
Since Al remembers something
that actually happened,
it means that what's bonded
inside that armor really is Al.
I really was able to pull you
out of that doorway,
even if it was just your soul.
And if I was able to pull your soul out,
we should be able to get your body back
from beyond the doorway, too.
My body...
existing separately from my soul...
Barry the Chopper!
Al, try to remember back,
when you were taken inside the Truth.
Back then...
It's me! It was me in there!
Yeah. So, just like when
I pulled your soul out,
- we just need to get your body, as well!
- Brother!
At the time, I could see you
from inside the thing...
we thought was Mom.
So it was you inside that thing?
My soul probably didn't bind to it
because it was rejected.
We didn't do any harm to anyone's soul.
Mr. Elric, sir? You have a telephone call
from Mrs. Izumi Curtis.
I checked into the family lines
of both me and my husband.
It turns out...
going by the skin and hair color
of the child I transmuted,
it was something that couldn't
have been born to us as a couple.
You've struck upon something, haven't you?
Yes. I'm convinced
that we can get Al's body back.
And that bringing back the dead
is impossible.
I get it. It's not
that we were missing something.
It was impossible to do
in the first place.
- Ed!
- Yes?
Thanks.
What did our teacher say?
I'm not entirely sure why.
But she said thanks.
Al?
Ever since that day,
I've been blaming myself.
I thought that...
I was the one who put Mom
in that form and killed her.
So did I, Al.
Thanks, Brother.
I didn't kill Mom after all.
Izumi...
I feel like I've been saved.
I didn't kill our child a second time.
Still...
The fact remains that I am the one
who put you in that body.
Whatever it takes,
I'm going to make your body right--
Brother...
I agreed to what we did,
and I'm just as much at fault.
So don't talk about it
as though it's all on you.
You always take it all on yourself.
I can't stand to let others become victims
over what I've done anymore!
Like Mr. Hughes!
When I found out he was dead,
I honestly felt that if it meant
others were going to get hurt,
I didn't need my body back.
Brother...
I've seen others
who didn't have human bodies.
And they all managed to live
in their own way.
Even in this body, people around me
treat me as a human being.
Maybe this body is a ticking time bomb,
but even with a live body,
you never know when you might die
in an accident or from an illness.
So because I can live normally,
I'm not bothered by this body.
That's what I've started to think. But...
I just can't take it.
I... I... I can't take
all the nights by myself!
That's the reason
why I want to get back to normal.
Yeah. We'll get it done.
We'll send that Truth bastard flying.
And pull your body out of there!
Have his...
Have his shoulders always been so broad?