You idiot!
You believed the word of the enemy
and lost the will to fight?
I am terribly sorry, sir.
Don't let it get the better of you!
Don't give up on living!
If you're going to be my adjutant,
you've got to be stronger!
Yes, sir.
I'm going to continue
trusting you to watch my back.
Commit yourself.
Colonel, you're not one to talk, sir.
A commander who just waltzes
on in like that.
You shut up!
And why are we even in the same room?
Ordinarily, I'd have my own room,
with a beautiful nurse!
Please try to make do, sir.
Having you in the same room
makes it easier to guard you.
About that...
why haven't they come to kill us?
Why?
Why did you let that flame bastard
out of there alive?
He burned Lust to death!
Lust is dead.
It's still not too late! Kill him!
Roy Mustang. We can make use of him.
Use him?
You don't mean him and the doorway?
Don't you worry about him.
Father has left him to me.
What do I do if I'm all rotten?
My body, which is over there,
isn't getting any nutrition!
Even if I'm able to get back
into that body...
Brother... Winry...
Eh? Hey, Ed!
This is just a hypothesis,
but when we tried to transmute Mom,
you and I mixed our blood together
for the soul information, right, Al?
Now the two of us were both
taken over there, and decomposed.
Isn't there some chance
that during that process, Al,
our spirits got some
of their wires crossed?
What do you mean?
I mean, isn't there a chance
that me, here,
and your body, over there, are connected?
I mean, look, for my age,
I'm a little sh...
Sh...
Short.
He admitted it! He's faced reality!
So, Ed, you're taking on growing
for Al's body too?
That sure seems like a farfetched idea.
It's not farfetched!
You don't grow
because you don't drink milk!
Not the milk thing again!
- Of course!
- Come to think of it.
- It makes your bones grow stronger!
- Brother is always sleeping.
Could it be that he's sleeping
enough for my share too?
- Drink it! Drink it!
- No way! I can't!
- Drink it!
- I hate it!
I hope that's it.
- Drink it!
- No way!
Going to visit the colonel?
Mr. Havoc is injured too.
We wanted to make sure
we paid our respects.
If the colonel hadn't come right now,
who knows what would have happened to me?
Sergeant Fuery, are you visiting them too?
I'm on an errand from the lieutenant.
Based on the number of footsteps I counted
once we got to the basement
under the Third Laboratory,
I figured the approximate distance
from there to that large doorway.
I couldn't be sure about the direction,
so I used the lab as a central point,
and drew a circle around it.
Central Command Center?
And what's more, this building is...
The Führer's residence.
Under there is where the Homunculi are.
So there's a chance that the Führer
is connected to that group?
If he's connected,
then why did the Führer
go after Greed and company?
That's strange,
even if he wasn't connected.
He wiped them out, without trying
to get any information out of them.
The Führer is inscrutable.
Whatever the case,
the enemy has penetrated
fairly high into the military.
From here on, we should
be careful confronting them.
Fullmetal, watch yourself.
The Homunculi and the Führer...
Looks like we made an even bigger catch
than we expected.
I get the feeling that it's too big, sir.
It makes this all worth doing.
Now, I'm going to work you guys ragged.
About that, sir,
you'll have to count me out.
I can't feel my legs.
I'm sorry. I'm retiring.
Yo.
Yo. Are you in here for something?
My lower back.
Medical examiners always have to stand,
and it gets to an old guy like me.
When I heard that it was you
who burned that thing, something clicked.
What are you plotting?
You knew I was plotting something,
and yet you still determined
that other thing to be Lieutenant Ross?
Thank goodness for old war buddies.
We're not old war buddies.
We're partners in crime, aren't we?
You would burn them,
and I would do the autopsies.
Ishbal was just one giant test site.
You get too involved
in this dangerous business,
and you're gonna get hit with a backlash.
I already have.
Has something happened?
One of my men.
His lower half is paralyzed
from a spinal injury.
And I only got permission
to have one of these per day.
It's laughable, being struck
by a woman and having to retire.
What are you going to do once you're out?
My family runs a general store.
I can at least answer the phone.
Can they do anything about it
with automail?
The nerve connections to the lower half
of my body are cut off,
so they can't do anything.
The retired lifestyle
sure doesn't suit you.
Colonel.
About Havoc's legs...
I picked up some information
from Chief Fullmetal.
Doctor Marcoh, an alchemist
with mastery in the medical field
and a Philosopher's Stone.
Can I extend my leave
a little longer, sir?
Approved.
Get going.
Ah, Major!
Are you back from your leave?
How was your trip to the east?
Don't tell him!
It was a nice place
with lots of beautiful women.
Oh, right, Major. This just came
from the Provost Marshal's Office.
It's a priority message to be delivered
to State Alchemists.
What's this?
How did it go?
Once I told them I was a State Alchemist,
they let me in without any problem.
- And the entrance to the basement?
- It wasn't there.
But there were traces of it
being closed up with alchemy.
Not even they are dumb enough
to leave an entrance.
Oh.
It looks like going to see the Homunculi
won't be possible, then.
They said that I was a precious sacrifice,
and that they'd be screwed
if I were to die.
They said the same about me.
I could be a sacrifice,
since I opened the doorway.
Sacrifices probably refer to alchemists
that have the ability to open the doorway
and make it back.
I wonder what they have in mind
by making sacrifices of us.
Let's pry it out of those guys!
- Edward!
- Sergeant Brosh?
Thank goodness.
Hey, what's the matter?
Get back to the hotel right away.
If you'd like, I can escort you.
This is a citywide announcement
from the Provost Marshal's Office.
It appears that Scar
has once again surfaced in Central.
Three are dead,
all of them State Alchemists,
as well as several others wounded.
According to eyewitness reports,
he is distinguished as being an Ishvalan,
having a large cross-shaped
scar on his forehead,
as well as a tattoo
over his entire right arm.
A tattoo on his right arm!
Scar killed Aunt and Uncle Rockbell?
I haven't confirmed it yet, but yeah.
Oh, man.
Brother, we can't tell Winry about this.
How could we tell her?
I don't want to see tears
on her face again.
Me neither.
We're going to have to face
Scar again, aren't we?
To find out the truth?
There's that too,
but also one other reason.
To lure out the Homunculi.
Those guys can't have us dying on them.
So if we get attacked by Scar
and get into a real emergency...
They'll come forward?
I don't think the chances are that good.
It's better than doing nothing.
But last time, it only took Scar
a moment to beat us.
We're probably stronger
than we were before.
Supposing the Homunculi do show up,
how do we catch them?
Not only are they strong,
they're all but indestructible.
Indestructible? You mean...
Immortal, right?
Again through the window.
We'll help you out with that mission!
What?
I'm not interested
in the military entanglements,
but if the Homunculi are immortal,
that's another story.
You doubt me somehow?
I'm grateful to you for helping out
with Lieutenant Ross. Still--
The more friends you have,
the better, right?
I'm being serious too.
The fate of my clan is at stake here.
Okay, fine. Just don't run away
with the Homunculi!
I'll keep my promise.
I owe you for a meal, after all.
A meal?
- A room service bill?
- Thanks for treating!
Like hell this is for one meal!
Shut up! It's still early in the morning,
and I can't sleep!
Oh, that's right.
You're going back to Rush Valley?
Hold on. Cancel that, and stay here
in Central a little while longer.
I mean, you know,
maybe I'll damage my arm.
I'll probably even destroy it.
You're planning to destroy it?
Ah, Brother, your soul!
Good grief!
Don't do anything too dangerous, okay?
Doctor? Doctor, are you in?
Damn.
I see. Good work.
A dead end, huh?
Well, if you'll excuse me.
Who was that?
My mother, and someone
from the Veterans Administration.
I've made arrangements to retire.
We're still not certain
that you can't be treated.
I'm not so dumb that I don't know
when I'm of no use, sir.
But...
You don't need any pawns
that can't move, right?
Why are you looking at me like that?
Leave me behind! Cut me loose!
Do you have time to be concerned
about one of your lowly underlings?!
You've got a promise to keep
to General Hughes, don't you?!
- I don't need your pity!
- Lieutenant Havoc!
Let me pack it in.
I'm begging you.
All right.
I'll leave you here.
I'll leave you here,
so you catch up to me.
I'm going on ahead.
I'll be waiting for you at the top.
He wasn't about to cast even me aside,
and I had given up on living.
He then said he was entrusting me
to watch his back.
He doesn't abandon others.
The fool.
There's no way he can climb his way
to the top of this country
if he's going to be so soft, is there?
I think it's okay to have
at least one fool like that.
Bring me my uniform.
You're in no shape
to leave the hospital yet.
Just bring it.
As you wish, sir.
How could you do that to me?
I'm so sorry!
Now I'll have to close up for the day.
You seem to be having some trouble!
State Alchemist Edward Elric is here!
That's amazing, kid!
Thank you very much!
How much would you like me
to pay for this?
Pay? That's not necessary,
not necessary!
I've broken a vase that's important to me.
- I wonder if you could fix it.
- Easily done!
I'm Edward Elric!
Your neighborhood State Alchemist,
Edward Elric!
- This too, please!
- Could you fix this?
Looks like word about me
is spreading all over town.
Sure, as flashy as you're being.
This isn't like you, Fullmetal.
Colonel?
Are you sure you should be
out of the hospital?
Maybe.
I heard about Lieutenant Havoc.
Knowing Doctor Marcoh--
Wait.
We're drawing attention. Get in.
On second thought, get out.
- Dr. Marcoh is missing?
- They probably abducted him.
By the way, Fullmetal,
you did hear about Scar?
What's with your behavior,
all but begging him to find you?
I want him to find me.
- I have to fight him once more.
- Don't be ridiculous!
Did you forget what happened in East City?
Oh, my. Are you afraid of Scar?
It's because you were useless
against him last time, Colonel, sir.
Don't you mock me!
It's clear and sunny today!
No, instead, you're all weak
and feeble, aren't you?
- You're still useless.
- You shut up!
Well, he's here, isn't he?
What's the matter?
It's not even raining,
and you're dripping wet.
Wait, Lieutenant! Don't shoot!
What are you talking about?
I'm gonna do like the colonel,
and try my hand at a little fishing!
Brother is using himself as bait
to lure out the Homunculi.
After all, he's a sacrifice to them,
one that they can't allow to die.
- That's crazy!
- We don't want anyone else to get hurt.
Using Brother or myself as bait
was the only thing we could do!
What are you going to do if Scar gets shot
by the MPs before the Homunculi show up?
Colonel, you can make sure
that doesn't happen, right?
You're giving orders to me?
You've got nerve.
Once you catch the Homunculi,
I want my cut!
You got it!
Sergeant Fuery's townhouse is nearby.
- Let's go!
- Yes, sir!
It's starting.
You two! Please stand aside!
Don't shoot! You'll hit my brother!
Damn, if Scar gets shot,
we'll lose everything.
Talk about maintaining
a careful distance--
He's wearing me down!
What's taking so long, Homunculi?
Where's the Provost Marshal
Office's channel?
Here it is! That's our Fuery for you.
This is Sector 3 MP Patrol.
We're currently engaging Scar!
Request immediate backup!
Hey, what are you doing?
There, now for Sector 17.
This is starting to be fun. This is--
What's going on here?
Scar is in Sector 17 too?
Then what's happening in Sector 3?
Colonel Douglas,
he's appeared in Sector 8 too!
What?
Central Provost Marshal's Office
calling Sector 8,
Scar and a young man
are fighting each other.
The young man is a State Alchemist!
Hold your fire!
There are false reports flying around!
What? A fourth person has spotted Scar?
This is Sector 3.
Nothing to report on the streets.
This is Sector 8! We've spotted Scar!
Requesting immediate backup!
- Gluttony?
- I smell him, I smell him!
I smell the Ishvalan!
What is that presence?
Do you feel it, Lan Fan?
- Yes.
- All right, let's go!
Which one?
Bodily destruction? Or automail?
Brother!
Lucky!
You cancelled out
his decomposition energy?
That's so reckless!
A tattoo on his right arm?
You bastard, I knew it!
I smell him, I smell him!
Hi! Hello there!
You're pretty unusual on the inside?
How many people do you have inside you?
Who are you?
It's no use trying to get away.
You have a unique chi.
I can follow you anywhere.
Enemy? Enemy?
Can I eat them?
- Sure enough.
- He's a Homunculus.
Oh, you can sense his presence, can you?
That's a pesky ability.
I'll have to eliminate it!
Lan Fan! Get out of here!
Lan Fan!