Scar has once again appeared in Central.
Working together with Ling,
Ed and Al intentionally
draw Scar's attention
in order to lure out the Homunculi.
The strategy pays off,
and the Homunculi Gluttony
and Wrath appear.
However...
Lan Fan!
You parried with your kunai knife,
did you?
- Can I eat her?
- Do it quickly.
Lan Fan! Stay with me!
Do you think that you can escape
from my eye?
I see you're no stranger to fighting.
He's always swinging around to my left,
into my blind spot.
- Gluttony!
- Right!
Now then, no one will see us in here.
How about answering some of my questions?
Who are you people?
How do you know what's inside Gluttony?
Are you still looking for a way
to escape, even now?
You could probably get away on your own,
if you abandoned the girl,
who is now excess baggage.
"Excess baggage"?
You're the highest-ranked person
in all the land, right?
Führer King Bradley, wasn't it?
A king is to be for the people.
There is no king without his people!
"King Bradley"!
You will never be a true king!
Naive fool.
There are no true kings in this world!
You rely too heavily on your eyesight!
Judging by the wind currents,
the exit is...
What's the matter?
This eye still works!
Winry...
We'll be right back,
so you be a good girl,
and hold things down here for us.
Winry...
We're here.
I guess maybe I projected Dad
back onto Mr. Hughes.
Come by and visit
every once in a while, okay?
He gets quite lonesome, after all.
Mrs. Gracia...
I hear the Elric brothers
are wreaking havoc.
Huh? Again?
The MPs have been running around
all over the place.
Another fight? Good grief.
They're taking on that one guy
who only targets State Alchemists.
- Haven't they caught him yet?
- What is the military waiting for?
Oh, no, why are they overlapping?
A dead end!
Damn it!
Nice one, Brother!
Never mind,
we're getting out of here, quick!
- Permission to fire?
- Not yet!
Damn, why not?
The signal flare from Ling
hasn't been sent up yet.
Brother is starting to get tired.
I guess I'll have to buy some time.
Scar, why are you so prejudiced
against alchemists,
saying they've gone against God,
when you use alchemy too?
I thought I told you why in East City.
Where there are creators, like you,
there must also be destroyers.
You're just--
you're just using the name of God
to justify your killing!
You also killed Shou Tucker and Nina,
claiming to be an agent of God,
didn't you?
Oh, so you saw that Chimera too, did you?
The art that created that tragic creature,
is it the same alchemy that you idolize?
It was your hand that put your brother
into that irredeemable body.
It was vanity in the art
of creating something
that brought about that Chimera,
was it not?
Even so, why did you have to kill her?
Why did you take her life?
You knew, didn't you,
that the Chimera could never
be returned to normal?
That as it was, it would have been treated
like a laboratory specimen,
and not have been treated as a human
for the rest of its life?
He's right. Back then, we had an inkling
somewhere in our minds
that Nina might be sent off
to a laboratory.
We put off dealing with the problem
because we couldn't do anything about it.
So we did nothing.
Nothing.
It's true, we alchemists
have committed some mistakes.
But even so, it doesn't mean
we can accept what you're doing!
Do you remember
an Amestrisian doctor named Rockbell?
Even after the order to exterminate
uprising Ishval came out,
they continued to help the Ishvalans.
- Wait, Brother!
- Don't you remember
the doctor couple that saved you,
and that you killed?
Brother!
What are you talking about?
Winry...
This is the man who killed Mom and Dad?
You're kidding.
They were killed by someone they helped?
Why?
What did my mom and dad ever do?
They never did anything
that they deserved
to be killed for, did they?
Give them back!
Give me back my mom and dad!
Hold on, Winry.
Don't. You can't.
Winry!
Don't do it!
I understand the animosity that you feel.
But vengeance will only cultivate
more vengeance.
You must abide this.
You are the doctors' daughter?
You have a right to shoot me.
Brother...
Brother!
Brother, the armed forces are almost here!
- Leave that research alone!
- Wait, I'm almost there.
- What are those tattoos?
- Oh, these?
The basis of alchemy is understanding,
decomposition, and reconstruction.
My right arm decomposes,
and the left arm reconstructs.
Having studied eastern alkahestry,
I arranged them in my own way.
Moreover, I've learned something.
The alchemy of this land is quite unusual.
None of that matters now!
Never mind that, the armed forces are--
Hey...
Why are you stopping me? We must
get away from here as soon as we can!
Please, try to remain calm.
Your brother's research
might just save Ishval.
What?
Did you hear about the State Alchemists?
Word is that they are coming in
as weapons,
and overrunning Ishval
with their terrible force.
Even though we are their
fellow Amestrisian citizens.
I knew about that,
but what does it have to do
with my brother?
Your brother will be able to oppose
the State Alchemists.
And with great power beyond even theirs,
he may be able to find a way
to annihilate the military!
Fight power with greater power...
Retaliate against them with alchemy!
Pay them back in blood!
Behold, Brother, this is the alchemy
you devote yourself to.
You may wish that it is for the sake
of others, and for happiness...
...but no one else sees it
that way, do they?
Run!
So this is alchemy?
This is what is going to save Ishval?
This, which does nothing but destroy
and slaughter, over and over?
No!
Father! Mother!
- Are you all right?
- Yeah, no trouble.
We're lucky that everyone
was getting ready to flee.
I made it.
It took so long because I was compiling
the important things.
The important things?
- Here, you hold on to this.
- What is it?
My research notes.
This is all I was able to bring.
- Take it and get away from here.
- Hold on a minute.
If anything happens to me,
all of my research will be lost.
You can take it
and run away yourself, right?
You are a superb warrior monk,
who has gone through rigorous training.
You have a higher chance
of surviving than I do.
Look.
I can't stop my legs from shaking.
I'm a pathetic older brother.
Brother...
An armed forces soldier?
Transmutation circles!
He's a State Alchemist!
Get down!
Stay with me. Don't you die.
Damn, I can't stop the bleeding.
His arm, where is my brother's arm?
Dad...
Mom...
Everyone... somebody!
Live! You must not die!
I'll fight! I'll show them Ishval's pride!
Then that's all the more reason
for you to run away!
Right! We didn't treat you
just to let you die!
Doctor, you and your wife
are the ones who should go!
You're a patient.
Don't worry over us unnecessarily.
Brother...
Get down!
That's crazy. You protected me?
Brother...
Anyone who can get away
on their own, start running!
He's coming to!
Don't move. You'll open your wounds.
Honey, come here! Honey!
You still need bed rest.
Somebody! Get that cart!
Take him with you!
Brother?
Ah, thank goodness. Brother, you made it--
What...
What is this?!
- Sedatives!
- There aren't any more!
We used them all up on the last boy!
State Alchemists...
Amestrisians...
You will pay...
You're going to... you're going to...
Dr. Rockbell!
Shoot me.
Don't shoot, Winry! Put the gun down!
You shouldn't be holding
that thing, Winry!
Shoot me!
But if you shoot, in that moment,
I will consider you my enemy!
Scar!
Why, you!
You just try to lay a hand on Winry!
Will you kill me? That will also do!
Until one of us perishes,
this chain of hatred will not cease!
But don't you forget!
It was the Amestrisians who first pulled
the trigger in the civil war!
It was you!
No! Don't shoot him!
Quickly put the gun down,
and get away from here!
Winry!
If you cannot shoot,
then leave this place at once!
You're in the way!
Don't shoot!
Get down!
Brother...
Brother, you dummy! What are you doing?
Are you trying to get both of you killed?
Hurry up and take Winry someplace safe!
Winry, let go of the gun.
I couldn't shoot him.
Don't shoot. I'm begging you.
But he's the one who killed Mom and Dad.
He tried to kill you and Al too, Ed.
And yet, why couldn't I?
You delivered that baby in Rush Valley,
saving mother and child.
You gave me the arm and leg
that allow me to stand up.
Your hands are not hands that kill others.
They're hands that give life to others.
That's why.