Smoke bomb and a grenade.
Such a reckless child.
Can you follow their scent?
Officer...
Please take her someplace safe.
Winry, Al is still fighting,
so I have to go.
I'm sorry. I'll tell you everything
once we get back.
Why is waiting the only thing I can do?
We have a girl in custody
on Saint Louis Street in Sector eight.
She appears to be a friend
of the Fullmetal Alchemist.
Escort her to the Central Command Center.
Repeat, Saint Louis Street, Sector eight.
We have a girl in custody.
- She appears to be a friend...
- It's just about time.
Escort her to the Central Command Center.
- Go back them up.
- Yes, sir.
There's a vacant house
outside of town we can use.
We'll meet up here.
- Don't let anyone follow you.
- Yes, sir.
If anything develops, I will contact you.
Yeah.
- And do not go out into the field, sir.
- I know.
He's relentless!
There are fewer people this way.
Are we pinned in?
Scar, huh?
You dispose of him.
I'll finish things here.
- My left arm...
- What's wrong?
Young Lord,
I am no longer of any use to you.
What are you talking about?
If you keep concerning yourself with me,
Young Lord, then you will fall as well.
There is no king without his people.
But without their king,
the people will have nowhere to go.
Young Lord, you must live,
for the sake of our clan.
I'm not leaving you.
There are any number of things
that can be left behind,
for the greater good.
Lan Fan! What do you think
you're doing? Stop!
You're hollow inside that armor, right?
You poor boy. You have the ill fortune
of being put in that body,
and you still place faith in alchemy?
There are a lot of things
that are inconvenient about this body.
But inconvenient
does not equal ill-fortuned!
There's no reason
for anyone to take pity on me!
Brother saved my life with alchemy.
To disavow who I am now
would be to disavow Brother, and alchemy.
I believe in the possibilities of alchemy.
I want to believe!
Is that right?
- Brother! Where's Winry?
- She's all right.
- I'm pathetic. I made her cry again.
- Brother, you're always so thoughtless!
- She saw you engaged in bloody combat.
- Yeah.
Now then, let's get back to the fight.
I found you!
Ishvalan!
- You're...
- That tattoo!
A Homunculus!
Ling?
Run!
- Sturdy wire!
- Right!
Your overactive regenerative ability
is working against you, huh?
Your own flesh,
swelling out from the inside,
is what's holding you tight.
I've caught you, Homunculus!
Nicely played.
I've outwitted you, you monster!
What? A Homunculus?
Put him in! We're getting out of here!
- Hold on, Hawk--
- Shh!
- Just a minute--
- Al!
The MPs are watching.
Pretend we don't know her!
- They're getting away! Catch Scar!
- Yes, sir!
The colonel may be a creep,
but we can trust him.
Right now, we should be...
We're going to catch Scar, Al!
For killing the Rockbells,
and all the other stuff!
You're going to answer for your crimes--
Are you all right, servant?
What are you doing to the manservant
of Mr. Yoki, who saved my life?
You beansprout boy!
What did you call me, you beansprout girl?
Who is that child?
Little girl, move away!
It's dangerous there!
We're outnumbered. It's time to retreat.
- What kind of alchemy was that?
- She transmuted from a distance?
This way.
Damn, I can't see!
Scar!
I've heard about you, Ling Yao.
We're on our way straight to a safe house.
Wait! I have a friend. Pick her up!
We can't. We don't have time!
Please! She's about to die!
She's waiting for me to come get her!
Make it quick!
I'm sure that woman is Mustang's.
Now you've done it, you young punk.
Was that the look in my eyes too?
No matter how far I go,
hatred only leads to more hatred.
- I think I've stopped the bleeding.
- Thanks.
Sir! The MPs are getting close!
We should get out of here!
He's injured.
He can't have gotten too far away yet!
Comb the area for him!
Sir! Quickly! Quickly!
Shao May, we're getting...
Huh?
I found her.
Look, you! Why did you pick
that thing up during this crisis?
But she was all alone
in all that confusion!
You're always, always
picking up stray cats
and secretly keeping them
inside your body! Get rid of it!
Brother, you're inhuman!
Look how gentle she is.
It's all right. Take it easy.
- This way, please.
- Thanks.
You stay in here.
Winry!
Hey there, Fullmetal Alchemist.
- F端hrer Bradley...
- Why are you...?
I heard that your childhood friend
was in our protection.
She's the friend
of one of our most important personnel.
We have to be sure
to treat her courteously.
- Well then, miss, if you'll excuse me...
- Sure. Thank you.
She's a good, honest girl.
Take good care of her.
Ed.
You promised. Tell me everything
about Mom and Dad.
I see, they did all they could for others,
right up to the end.
Still, I do wish they would have
come back home alive.
All I can do is wait.
Perfect timing. Miss Rockbell,
there is a telephone call for you.
For me?
Hello?
Mr. Garfiel!
Sorry about this, Winry.
I tried to get by on my own...
Isn't Winry back yet?
Look at this.
Winry's the only one who can fix this.
...but all of your customers are so fussy!
- Hurry back home, Winry!
- Miss Winry?
Tetsu?
Miss, come back soon.
My leg comes away in better shape
when you work on it,
compared to when Mr. Garfiel does.
Winry, please hurry up
and make an outer covering
for that leg you made a model of for me.
- And get to my arm, too.
- No way, I was first!
- I sure miss you!
- You dumbass, Winry belongs to all of us!
- That's the truth!
- Sorry. I'll be right there.
Just wait there. I'll do my best.
I'll do my best.
Thanks.
Thanks for stopping me back there.
I have people who are waiting for me.
I was this close
to not being able to face them again.
Winry...
Ed, don't forget to take care
of your automail.
Right.
I'll send you
some good polishing oil soon, Al.
- Don't go dying, okay?
- Yeah.
The next time...
What? I can't hear you.
Brother? Wait! Bye, Winry!
Geez. Hey, Ed! What did you say?
The next time I make you cry,
they'll be tears of joy!
I'll make sure that Al and I
are both back to normal,
and make you cry with happiness!
Don't you forget it!
Give me an arm and a leg. One year!
There's no turning back for us now, huh?
What are you crying for?
So that's it. I've...
been falling for him.
- Colonel...
- Get in.
I've got a badly injured person.
I need a doctor.
Gone out on another limb, huh?
You little punk.
I know you have a family.
If this is a problem, you can decline.
Wait here. I'll get my instruments.
You're sure?
My wife and I broke up
soon after I got back from Ishval.
She walked through the sewers
with her arm cut off?
Don't blame me if she gets lockjaw.
I haven't dealt with anything
but corpses lately,
so my touch may be a little rough.
- I'm sorry...
- Don't misunderstand.
I'm the one who propositioned you.
It was in both our interests,
so I worked together with you, that's all.
I left the country knowing
that if I was going to seek immortality,
I would have to be ready
to make certain sacrifices.
No, I wasn't prepared for this.
Lan Fan was more ready than I was.
- Are you all right?
- Is there anything we can do?
Your trap wasn't all that bad.
But I'm useless now.
I need a replacement arm.
Yeah! I can set you up
with a great automail mechanic!
State Military Colonel Roy Mustang.
Ling Yao,
twelfth son of the Emperor of Xing.
I'm grateful to you
for providing a doctor.
Not at all. Thank you for helping out
with the Maria Ross incident.
As well as this one.
Hey, what is that?
A Homunculus, named "Gluttony."
Apparently, these guys have connections
to a portion of the military senior staff.
Just a portion? Far from it.
There's a possibility
that King Bradley is a Homunculus, too.
There was an Uroboros tattoo
on the eye under his patch!
He came after us, together with Gluttony!
It can't be!
The head of our country is a Homunculus?
Then again...
Bradley doesn't have the same sort
of inhuman presence as Gluttony.
His is the same presence
as a regular person.
But then... For one thing,
if the F端hrer is a Homunculus,
how is it that he has a son?
It said in that book that Homunculi
had no reproductive abilities.
No, his son Selim was adopted.
He is not the F端hrer's blood offspring.
Whether monster or human, either way,
this makes it easier for me
to drag the F端hrer out of his seat.
First, we get some information
out of this one.
I'll take his Philosopher's Stone, too.
It may be useful in treating my man.
Hey, now, Lan Fan lost her arm
to obtain him.
He's a lead to gaining immortality!
We're taking him back to Xing!
- Just a minute!
- We've been looking for a way
to get our original bodies
back for a long time, ourselves!
There's no way
I'm letting you run away with him!
That's right, Ling!
You are an illegal alien!
I can't keep up with all of this anymore.
Think you can move
around the country with Gluttony...
- I'm going back home.
- ...without some help from us?
Mustang...
Colonel Mustang killed Lust.
Roy Mustang!
What?