Oh, no, not again.
You're an important candidate
for sacrifice.
We need to have you keep your strength up.
Right, Dr. Marcoh?
I've been thinking, all this time...
what is a sacrifice?
What is it you're trying to make me do?
What you're doing right now
is using this land and its people
to create a giant transmutation circle.
The purpose of which
is to create a Philosopher's Stone.
Am I wrong?
So close. But you're on the right track.
Right track?
So, what are you going to do?
If you don't cooperate,
we're going to wipe out that village.
I heard from Lust,
that in exchange for us
leaving the village alone,
you would work with us.
What will it be?
Work with us,
and destroy all of the country's people?
Or don't work with us,
and wipe out everyone in that village?
You're such a fool.
If you forsake the smaller part,
the greater will be saved.
If you think about it just a little,
you'll see that.
But then again,
that's just the way you humans are.
Your emotions come before logic.
That's the way a man I once killed was.
Once I turned myself into his wife,
he couldn't do anything, and let his
reverse card slip away from him.
Lucky for us, you humans
are easy to take advantage of.
You're having quite a bit of trouble
with the humans, aren't you,
Wrath?
Scar got away from you,
and they even made off with Gluttony.
It's not like you.
Yes, you're right.
- You seem happy.
- I won't deny that.
This is sort of enjoyable.
I've been alive for 60 years,
and now here I am,
at the top spot of this country.
All just as Father planned.
And yet?
Colonel Mustang, the Elric brothers,
and those folks from a foreign land...
As crafty as we are,
they've still got us scrambling around.
The younger generation's time
might be right around the corner, Pride.
Wrath, you've been in contact with humans
for too long.
You may be right.
I hope you won't forget
what sort of beings we are.
I will refrain from informing Father
of your remarks,
which could be taken as treasonous.
Anyway, about Gluttony...
Not to worry.
According to the military police's
information,
I have a pretty good idea where he is.
What is this?
- Colonel! Where are you, Col--
- Stop, Lieutenant!
Colonel!
Lieutenant...
Don't provoke him! He's out to get me!
Mustang!
Lan Fan, we're getting out of here.
What has happened?
That monster was keeping
another monster inside his belly!
He's swallowing up everything around him!
So alchemy can even produce
something like this?
We've got no choice but to bring him down.
But we went through so much
just to catch this Homunculus!
Our first priority is to survive.
Besides, he knows our names and faces.
There's no reason for us
to let him leave here alive.
- He swallowed the flame?
- What the...?
You're useless!
Well then, you try doing something!
For that matter, keep away!
You're the one he's after, Colonel!
Run that way! Spread out!
Damn, not now!
Move it, son!
Hurry, we can't stay here for long!
But Ed and the others are still--
Who cares? I'm just a civilian here!
I'm not about to die in the middle
of this cockamamie battle!
Damn it!
Why are they dragging their feet?
Roy Mustang!
Damn!
He fell for the dummy, huh?
Sounds like he's really ticked off now.
Come on, get going now,
you good-for-nothing.
Lieutenant, over here.
Please take care of Lan Fan.
You're telling me to turn tail and run,
under these circumstances?
- You're just going to slow us down!
- Leave!
Seriously, you're of no use here, Colonel.
Honestly, you boneheaded colonel.
Just go do your own job!
The head of the military
being a Homunculus
isn't something
you can leave alone, right?
The head of the military?
You don't mean, Führer Bradley is...?
We'll talk about it later. Get in!
The car is full, right? Go on.
You dumb ass!
We can't just go and leave you children
on the battlefield!
The people you're fighting
are the military's senior staff, right?
We have to get some information
out of that Gluttony guy.
We're staying here, and fighting him.
The fact that we're children
doesn't have anything to do with it.
We were the ones who brought up
this mission in the first place.
Thanks for all your help up to now.
Edward...
Take this with you.
You know how to use it, right?
That's something to kill people with.
It's something to protect your lives with.
Your hands are not hands that kill others.
Don't go dying, okay?
I'll keep it with me.
Look after Lan Fan.
Young Lord. Young Lord!
Let's go. Let's get going!
Damn kids!
This is how you die young!
Mustang.
Where is Roy Mustang?
How dare you kill Lust?
You'll pay for that!
Yeah, we said we'd fight,
but that thing is seriously freaky.
His personality is different too.
How are we going to catch him?
What is it?
A dog?
Stop, Gluttony!
It spoke?
Hey, long time no see.
Fullmetal pipsqueak.
Who are you calling a shrimpy,
flea-sized paramecium?!
Take it easy!
I'm just here to get Gluttony back.
I have no desire to tangle
with any pipsqueaks--
- That's the seventh time!
- What are you talking about?
You've called me a pipsqueak
two times just now,
plus five more times
under the Fifth Laboratory!
You can't tell me you've forgotten it!
What a pinpoint memory you've got there.
Hold it!
You're starting to become difficult.
Mustang was here! Gonna avenge Lust!
Swallow, swallow, swallow him up!
Not the colonel, nor the Elric brothers.
No way.
I've sensed it before too.
How many people are inside you,
Homunculus?
You're the kid who crossed swords
with Wrath, huh?
What do you mean, "kid"?
I am the twelfth son
of the Emperor of Xing, and my name is--
You can swallow him.
Wait! Wait! Wait!
I get it.
It looks like they can't take any action
against us brothers, huh?
In that case...
Ling, you take care of that one!
Very well, let's have a look, shall we,
at the skills that held their own
against Wrath?
Oh, Selim did?
They said it was the best one
in the class.
It's a paper about you.
May I read it?
Mind your manners. Not right now.
Where's the harm?
Go ahead and read it to me.
Yes, sir!
"My father is the Führer
of the nation of Amestris.
He works as hard as he can
for this country.
The people of this land
are always in my father's heart.
He deals with many different problems,
so that everyone can live in peace.
But no matter how busy he gets,
my father has never forgotten his family.
He loves me and my mother.
My father always listens to me
when I talk.
He always grants my requests.
That is why I love my father."
Thank you, Selim.
Not bad at all.
Thanks for your words of praise!
You fell for it.
What do you think?
This is a trick you humans can't do, huh?
Now then, do you want to be strangled
to death, or bitten to death?
Or shall I just carve you up?
Well, then...
That was a cheap trick,
blinding me like that...
Ever since I was little,
I was in constant danger of assassination.
I couldn't help
but learn a few dirty moves.
How about it? Will you come quietly?
I just want some information
on gaining immortality.
You don't like getting hurt, right?
You scum!
Don't you look down on me,
you mere human!
Don't you underrate humans, Homunculus!
All right, gotcha!
Geez, that was a close one.
Why, you...
I'm not allowed to eat you.
I wanted to eat
that closed-eyed guy earlier.
Caught you!
Hey, now, stay out of my way--
Only human, all right.
Now, Gluttony!
- Ling!
- What?
Damn, I can't let him swallow a sacrifice!
Brother!
Swallowed them.
Brother! Ling!
Hey, spit him out! Spit out Brother!
Can't. I swallowed him.
It can't be... it can't be... Brother.
I have the rooms
that the wife and kid used,
but the neighborhood will get suspicious
if I've got lights on all over the place.
You'll have to make do with my bed.
Young Lord, I must go to Young Lord.
Dumb fool!
What can you do in your condition?
He isn't home yet? I see.
Well then, I shall head directly
to the command center.
Yes, goodbye.
- Let's go.
- Yes, sir.
Where to?
I'm thinking of taking the occasion
to make it clear
who is friend and who is foe.
Jeez, what is it with all of you?
Your wounds aren't even healed yet,
and you're looking
to get into trouble again?
The Führer could be a Homunculus.
I can't just take it easy.
Besides...
We just left the children
back on the battlefield.
If I don't act now,
I'll be setting a bad example as an adult!
- What's so funny?
- Nothing.
I was just thinking, if Edward found out
that you treated him like a child,
he'd probably get angry.
Just repeating what you said.
I have to admit,
this is unexpected, Colonel.
You taking such bold action as this...
Like hell, it's bold.
I'm just paving the way.
Besides...
Find as many people who understand you
and support you as you can.
Belated though it may be,
I'm thinking of heeding his warning.
So are these the gates of glory,
or the entrance to Hell?
Lieutenant, you wait here.
If anything happens to me,
then at least you'll get out of here.
- No, sir.
- That's an order.
I cannot obey it.
- You sure are stubborn.
- As you are well aware, sir.
All right. Wait here.
I promise, I'm coming back.
Yes, sir. Good hunting!
So you're Roy Mustang, are you?
I got a call from my wife a while ago.
Lieutenant General Raven, sir,
I've been so busy
since I transferred here,
so I apologize for not coming
to pay my respects earlier,
and only doing so now, so late at night.
No problem.
By the way,
how is that old fox Grumman doing?
The same as always, sir.
Check.
You've got me, sir.
That's 11 losses in a row for me.
Twelve, although you put up
a pretty good fight this time.
Once you were sure you had won,
you blew it.
You're saying
I didn't finish strong enough?
Yes. You're unable to act ruthlessly,
just like Raven.
General Raven? In Central?
He is exceptional, but too sentimental.
He is known to have gone
to help his wounded men himself,
throwing his line into disarray
in the process.
No matter how many pieces you've got,
it's never enough like that.
What an affront!
I was chosen to transfer to Central
because of the compassion
I had for my men!
That border-dwelling old coot
has no business saying anything!
Pardon me.
Not at all.
In fact, General Grumman said
that if the general became irritated
at that story,
that you were still a just man,
and would be there if I needed you.
That old fox got me again, did he?
It's time for my meeting.
Let's walk there together.
Have you gotten used to Central yet?
No, sir. I make every effort
to speak with the citizens, but...
You can't undervalue
the word on the street.
But most of it is just mindless drivel.
Scar was seen giving food to a cat,
or some people who are immortal
have appeared,
or that the Führer is a Homunculus.
You've got no sense of humor, do you?
Are you sure you were
one of Grumman's men?
I failed to pick up
any of that from him, sir.
Well, even that bit of gossip
will give us something to talk about
over tea.
I couldn't possibly attend
something like...
Go on, tell us that joke you told earlier.
Something about the Führer
being a Homunculus.
Please continue.
What's the matter, Colonel Mustang?
If I were a Homunculus, then so what?
Is that a problem?
I get it, Hughes.
When you said the military was in trouble,
you didn't mean the danger
was closing in on us,
you meant the military itself
was the source of the trouble.
Fullmetal,
it looks like this is the pit of Hell.
Where am I?
Blood?
What is this? What is this place?
Al!
Hey, is anybody here?
Where is this place?