Hey, is anyone here?
Al! Answer me!
Where is this place? Damn.
Ling, you dumb prince!
Dumb? What do you mean, dumb?
Ling?
What a thing to call
the prince of a nation!
You're all right?
- You're...
- What?
- You're not Envy, turned into him, right?
- Now, look...
If you want, I can recite the entire
hotel room service menu!
All right, it's really you.
What about you?
You're not a fake, are you? You bean--
Who're you calling a bean-sized runt?
All right, it's really you.
I have to ask, where is this place?
I'm pretty sure we were swallowed whole
by Gluttony back there.
There's no way the inside of his belly
could be as big as this.
Yeah, but...
Look.
That's the run-down house we were just in.
What's more, over here is...
The lieutenant's car?
The fires all around
are probably the colonel's, aren't they?
Yeah.
Which means,
we really are inside Gluttony's belly?
I don't know.
But it is pretty clear
that this isn't a good place.
Let me borrow this.
What's wrong?
Ling, look at this.
Is that Al's?
If it's just his hand,
that means that Al wasn't swallowed.
Thank goodness.
I'll bet Al's worried, though.
He doesn't know where we are, either.
Awaken conveniently, my telepathic powers!
Elric Telepathy!
- Come in, my brother!
- You can just do that by yourself.
There are all sorts of buildings
and skeletons scattered around.
The time periods are all mixed up, though.
Is there even a way out of here
in the first place?
I don't know.
If there isn't, I'll make us one.
Make us one? Where?
- All right, let's have the torch.
- I've got it.
Let's see.
I didn't hear it hit bottom.
The wall! Let's find a wall!
Yeah! However big this space may be,
if we keep going straight,
we'll reach the edge of it!
We should then find an exit!
I didn't find her.
Where could Shao May have gone?
Are you sure she wasn't eaten
by a stray dog, or something?
Stray...?
Sorry, I was kidding!
She...
Shao May is a giant bearcat,
who was sick from birth
and never grew very big.
I took her in when her mother
abandoned her.
Ever since, we've grown up together,
like sisters.
My clan, the Chang clan,
is the lowest-ranked clan in all of Xing,
and we wield next to no power.
Maybe that's why...
Maybe those whose positions
are weak are drawn to each other.
Maybe at first, it was out of sympathy.
But we've lived together like family,
and gone through hardships together...
and she has become
an indispensable part of my life.
I've been able to endure many things
because of her.
I was only able to cross the desert
Yeah, but there was no need for you
to cross it in the first place.
Why, for the sake of something
as ridiculous as immortality,
would you intentionally...
If I don't return with the way
to gain immortality,
present it to His Highness the Emperor
and gain his trust,
our clan will continue on
until it perishes.
That's why I came to this country
with her...
- Shao May!
- Ah, don't cry anymore! I'm begging you!
Sir?
There's still some time left
before the sun comes up.
There will be fewer military police now.
You're going to help me look for her?
He's a good person.
His people were wiped out
in the civil war earlier.
That's why maybe he feels some kinship
for the survival of your minor clan.
Well? Aren't we going to go look?
Yes, we're going!
It sure is tiring,
when our footing is like this.
Yeah.
What's worse,
after all this, there's no exit.
I'm starving.
Once we get out,
I'll feed you as much as you like.
You can eat as much as you like,
and sleep as much as you like.
Ling?
I've had it.
Hey, now, throwing in the towel?
What a wuss.
You're going to collapse here too?
Get up! Walk!
Move forward! Come on!
Go on.
You spineless wimp! I'm going!
I'm not going to let myself croak
someplace like this, after all this!
I really am going to go, all by myself!
I really, really am!
I thought you were going.
I'm not going to let us both go down!
You've got people
waiting for you too, don't you?
And if you've got strength enough
to talk--
If only we had something to eat...
You know something, Ling?
Leather goods are edible.
Just about there. Here.
There's no athlete's foot, right?
Does it look like there's any,
you bonehead?
I'm full.
- I'm sorry.
- For what?
This is all
because you were protecting me.
It's nothing.
Compared to the training
I went through as a kid,
this is no big deal.
It sucks that we don't know
where this place is though.
But we're still alive and kicking,
so we can look for a way out.
You sure are positive.
I'm just stubborn about staying alive.
If I give up even a little bit,
I find get Al's iron fists
and angry howls flying at me.
- What is it?
- Something's coming.
- Is that...?
- Oh, my, it's you guys, is it?
- It's Envy, all right.
- Tell me the way out of here!
That's pretty ugly of you, Edward Elric!
Shut up!
A man will do anything to survive!
- For shame! For shame!
- Shut up!
Unfortunately, there is no way out.
You've really gone and done it now.
You even got me, Envy,
dragged into this as well.
Where is this place?
Are we really inside Gluttony's belly?
We're both inside his belly,
and not inside his belly.
Fullmetal pips--
Alchemist, you've realized
what this place is, haven't you?
Now that you mention it, from the moment
that Gluttony swallowed us,
I've felt that sensation before somewhere.
You remember it, right?
You experienced it in the past, after all.
The Doorway of Truth!
But...
But it wasn't like this there!
It was an all-white space, with a doorway.
Yeah? So that's what the real thing
is like, huh?
The real thing?
Gluttony is a failed attempt by our Father
to create a Doorway of Truth.
He's what?
But Father couldn't create one,
not even with his power.
This is a defective Doorway of Truth.
I guess you could call this the area
between reality and truth.
Between?
There are no exits, nor any ways out.
All we can do is use up our strength
and wait for our lives to end.
Guys, all we can do is wait
around in here to die.
No way...
I'll be damned if that's true!
Don't go telling us
crap like that, Envy! Hey!
There isn't any exit?
We're going to die here?
Hey... Hey! Hold on! If I die...
What's Al going to do?
I promised him!
We're going to get back
to normal together!
Damn it!
Doorways and creating things aside,
just who is this Father?
Is it Führer Bradley?
Bradley? Ha! No, he's just a Homunculus.
I knew it.
The Fifth Laboratory...
Human lives used to make...
Philosopher's Stones...
Homunculi...
If the Führer is one too, then are
you guys behind the Ishval War?
Ishval?
I've never had a job more delightful
than that one.
Do you know what the trigger was
that started the uprising?
As I recall, a military officer
accidentally killed an Ishvalan child.
Yes. And I, Envy, am the very person
who shot that child.
Um...
I heard from Mr. Yoki
about what happened to Ishval.
That felt so good.
The civil war flared up
right before my eyes, all over one bullet.
Man, that was a real thrill.
Ah, and incidentally...
the officer that I, Envy,
turned myself into
was a moderate, who opposed
the military's intervention in Ishval.
And the guy...
he couldn't even account for himself,
and was court-martialed!
You humans really are easily
manipulated creatures.
So you're the one who shot
that innocent child?
Who ruined our home,
and drove out the Ishvalans?
The one who made Scar
so hell-bent for vengeance?
The reason
why Winry's parents were taken from her?
Why, you...
What? He didn't even flinch.
You wanna fight, you punks?
Ed, get back!
We're all going to die here anyway.
Let me show you something neat
before you pass on.
Did you see his footprints
when we were fighting in the forest?
No.
You mean...
He's unusually heavy for his size.
His true body is quite...
- Damn.
- What is this?
How is he a Homunculus,
a man-made person?
What do I do?
I don't know.
What do I do? Father will be mad at me.
Father? You have a dad?
Yes.
The person who made the Homunculi?
Yes, he made us.
Where does the mass he swallows go?
Is it some kind of trick?
Think! Think!
We promised each other
we'd get back to normal together.
What good will it do to give up?
Gluttony!
Take me with you!
Take me to where your father is!
Okay.
You are a sacrifice, after all.
Ah, right! I'm a sacrifice.
What does that mean, "sacrifice"?
As for that matter, the only ones
that have been confirmed at present
are the two Elric brothers.
What about Dr. Marcoh?
Isn't it about time...?
There's also Kimblee.
He doesn't have the nerve it takes
to open the doorway.
Come to think of it, what about Mustang,
the other sacrifice candidate?
The Führer said he would like
to have a nice long talk with him.
Why are you keeping me alive?
In order to allow you
to understand your position.
How long has the military
been bowing to the Homunculi?
This has all been set up
since the birth of this nation.
So you've been watching us struggle
and snickering to yourselves
for all this time?
Your hands that were trembling
at General Hughes' funeral...
Did you fake that too?
Everyone makes too great a fuss
over the death of one soldier.
He must have at least known
that there was a possibility
that his uniform
was what he would be buried in.
General Hughes' child...
Could there be anything more noisy
in the middle of a funeral?
She truly did grate on my nerves.
I thought you had a child too!
How can you say that?
You mean Selim? He's a very good boy.
What if he were to find out that
the father he looks up to is a Homunculus?
Is that a threat? It won't work.
He will never be a way to get to me.
But your case is different.
She can be used to get to you.
Lieutenant Hawkeye!
What is it?
Someone from the Personnel Bureau
came by earlier.
They informed me that I was being assigned
to duty at the Southern Command Center.
- What?
- And it's not just me.
Lieutenant Breda is going
to the Western Command Center,
and Warrant Officer Falman
has apparently been transferred
to the Northern Command Center.
- Lieutenant Hawkeye?
- Yes, sir.
- I'm Yakovlev, from the Personnel Bureau.
- Personnel Bureau?
And I'm Storche, assistant to the Führer.
Please take this.
- Are these transfer orders?
- That's correct.
If I may look at them...
What's this?
What kind of implausible assignment
is this?
Where are you being whisked away to?
"Starting tomorrow,
First Lieutenant Riza Hawkeye
is assigned
to the Central Command Center...
as an assistant to the Führer."
And that's that, Colonel Roy Mustang.
- Let us out!
- The pain!
Ah, delightful, delightful...
Damn, there's nothing delightful
about this.
Yeah, no doubt.
Ling!
Ed!
- Can you make a weapon?
- Leave it to me!
With this sea of blood,
there's no shortage of iron.
You've got lousy taste.
What part? It's pretty slick, isn't it?
Can we take him?
I'm not sure.
I mean, what with the way he's built.
What's worse, he broke two or three
of my ribs in that last attack.
I'm in pretty similar shape.
Nonetheless,
we have to pump this guy up full of hurt!
Gluttony,
are you sure this is the right way?
But this way is... This is...
Your Father is in Central?