- Ed!
- Damn you!
Ling!
You bastard!
Kill me...
Help me, please... Kill me, please...
- I want to die...
- Mommy...
- Come over here.
- I don't want to be with you.
Don't just stand there, you idiot!
What are you waiting for?
There was someone...
There was someone inside him.
They wanted help.
No, there isn't! It was a monster!
But...
Come to your senses! Those are monsters!
- Kill me!
- How do you like this power?
- Mama!
- Give me back my child!
Shut up! Stop!
- Dad!
- How do you like this power?
- I want to die!
- Help!
- I said stop!
- Big Brother...
Let's play.
I'm done playing around.
Damn it...
- Come over here.
- Help me.
- You can't fathom our pain.
- Let's die together.
Ed! Wake up!
- Open your eyes!
- Come over here with us.
Ed!
All right, all right!
Okay, this way! Okay!
Ah, this little thing?
I saw her over by that rundown factory
a little while ago.
She was with this guy in a huge
suit of armor, who was walking by.
Armor? He could be the one from yesterday!
That suit of armor!
He won't get away with this!
How could he kidnap Shao May?
That ogre! That devil! That loincloth!
- There she is! Shao M--
- Wait.
The fat one...
I remember them calling him a Homunculus.
Homunculus?
They possess a regenerative power
that makes them near immortal.
- We can't take him on too carelessly.
- Immortal?
I couldn't ask for anything more.
Let's go after him!
I told you,
he won't be easy to bring down.
What are those two doing together?
What's wrong?
This place is strange.
Something has felt out of place
ever since I entered this country,
but this...
There are a lot of things
crawling around under our feet.
What's the matter? Are you cold?
Are you okay?
This way.
To think there's someplace
like this under Central...
What is this?
- That is the work of the gatekeepers.
- Gatekeepers?
They won't kill you if you're with me.
There's something there...
- Is it still farther ahead?
- Still farther ahead.
You said he's your Father, right?
He will know where the people
you swallowed went, right?
Father knows everything.
Brother...
You're still alive, right, Brother?
What's that?
A red stone?
That's right.
Envy has a Philosopher's Stone
for his core.
For all the searching I've done,
there's one, right here.
Let me out, Envy! It stinks in here!
We might be able to get out of here!
Work with me, Envy!
What on earth are these?
They're called Chimeras.
There's no end to them.
No way.
There really is something underneath us.
- Chimeras?
- No.
Are these people?
Father made all of us.
Me, and Lust, and Envy...
There is a disturbance.
Somebody is coming.
I do not remember my parents' faces,
their names...
I don't even remember my own name.
I don't know if,
before I was given this name,
I was abandoned, or sold.
Who will be the one to take charge
of this country?
Will it be you?
"Prospective Führers."
That's what they called us.
They gathered us all to one place,
where we were given education
in various matters.
From kingcraft and humanics
to hand-to-hand combat,
marksmanship and swordsmanship.
Don't worry about it.
He was just a pawn
to allow you to reach your goal.
I would be the person
who would run this country.
That's what I believed,
and I endured all training.
This one was no good either.
Next.
Lie down there.
What is this?
Just make yourself comfortable.
It will be over soon.
What are you planning to do?
Those bodies...
You are the twelfth one.
Will you be the one who accepts my wrath?
A Philosopher's Stone
is a high-energy body
that includes the souls of many people.
When placed in a human body,
it is met with rejection,
as it attempts to take over that body.
This was repeated until,
as a result of the destruction
and mending caused by the Stone,
the original body either died,
or it overcame the Philosopher's Stone.
Eventually...
- Outstanding!
- It is a new type of man!
Congratulations!
You have been chosen as the leader
who will guide this country.
He will prepare everything
that you need.
As of today, your name will be...
King Bradley.
All that remained was a single soul,
and the feeling of wrath.
Was the soul made someone else's
by the Philosopher's Stone,
or was it the one I originally had?
I no longer know.
If you were originally human
can't you live as a human, and not
as a Homunculus, Your Excellency?
Go back to being human? Impossible.
This body transcends a human one.
It is a far superior form.
Just as you humans are proud
of being human,
we have our pride as Homunculi.
That woman died with pride, didn't she?
- Ouch!
- A little first aid.
Thanks.
I've collected everything
there was in the area.
Is all of this from Xerxes?
Yeah. It's a part of the mural
from the temple that was in the ruins.
When I first saw that mural,
I thought it was the same one I saw
in the basement of the Fifth Laboratory,
the transmutation circle used
for Philosopher's Stones.
But it's different.
The sun represents the soul,
and the moon represents the mind.
Then there's the stone
depicted on the mural.
This represents the body.
Hey, now, keep it simple,
so that I can understand it.
In other words,
what was depicted over there
was a human transmutation circle.
Human transmutation?
You mean, the kind for bringing people
back to life.
No.
The basis of alchemy
is equivalent exchange.
You cannot create something
by transmuting a soul
that does not exist in this world.
I've made sure of that.
So, I got this sudden inspiration
as to how to get out of here.
What if I were to re-transmute myself,
a living person?
- Re-transmute?
- Yeah.
Using this transmutation circle,
I'll decompose myself,
then reconstruct myself
the way I was before.
That's human transmutation too.
I'm sure it will open the doorway.
If Gluttony is a false Doorway of Truth,
then if we pass through the right doorway,
I'll bet we come out in the right space.
I'll open the doorway,
and you two will jump through it.
- What happens if it doesn't work?
- A rebound.
The failed technique bounces back
onto the alchemist that performed it.
In this case, me.
I'm a complete outsider
when it comes to alchemy.
- It's up to you.
- All right.
Oh, Envy,
there's something I wanted to ask you.
The large mural I saw in Xerxes
was more or less like this.
What bothers me is this symbol.
The writing that represents God
is upside-down.
Then there's the two-headed dragon.
This indicates a "perfect being."
In other words, this says
"I will strike God down to earth,
and become the perfect being."
Quite a brazen thing to think.
If all they were doing was thinking it,
that's one thing.
The problem is...
this missing part here.
The image of the lion swallowing the sun.
That indicates the Philosopher's Stone.
The ingredients
for the Philosopher's Stone
are live humans.
- Isn't that right, Envy?
- Yeah, that's right.
How did a country as prosperous as Xerxes
fall overnight?
Where did its people go?
The reason part of the ruins are in here
was to get rid of the evidence, wasn't it?
You guys
turned the population of Xerxes
into a Philosopher's Stone, huh?
Who did it?
Who was the one who transmuted them?
Who turned an entire population
into a Philosopher's Stone,
and after gaining such mighty power,
tried to become something
even greater than God?
Is it the "Father" that you speak of?
He's using you Homunculi to try
to recreate the same destruction
that befell Xerxes in this country too,
isn't he?
If we get out of here, I'll tell you.
Enough beating around the bush,
Fullmetal Alchemist.
In order to open the doorway,
you require a "toll," right?
Use this.
- Help me!
- Kill me!
- Don't look!
- Give me your body!
These are all people from Xerxes,
aren't they?
They are beings whose bodies and minds
crumbled away long ago,
and who now exist only
as energy to be consumed.
They don't even remember
what their original forms were.
Pity? What a worthless emotion.
You want to believe
that they are human,
because you want to recognize
your brother,
who is in a similar situation,
as being human.
Would you hesitate
to feed coal into a fire,
because you felt sorry for the tree
that perished long ago?
These people can never go back
to being human.
Use logic, not emotion,
to delineate what a human is, alchemist.
All right.
Ling, if anything happens to me,
tell those on the outside
what this group is scheming.
Whatever happens to Amestris
is none of my concern.
Look, you!
There are people you love
waiting for you in this nation, right?
Get out of here alive,
and tell them yourself.
I'm sorry. I will use you with care.
Here goes!
That pose when he puts
his hands together...
I thought it looked familiar.
It's almost as if he's praying to God,
isn't it?
Long time no see, huh?
To think that I would be
opening you up again like this...
Ling! Jump in!
I'm trusting in you, alchemist!
It's just like when I was swallowed
by Gluttony!
Thank you.
Thank you...
Body and soul are connected by the mind.
Part of my body
is before the Doorway of Truth.
I leave everything
to wherever my mind leads,
and go into the doorway.
Huh?
You're not here to get your body back?
- Your Father is inside here, right?
- Yes, he is.
There's a lead to finding Brother
in here...
All right, I'm here.
Why are there two doorways?
Al!
Al! Come here!
Hurry, over here! Al!
- Al!
- I can't.
You aren't my soul.
I can't go with you.
Alphonse!
Someday, I swear, I'll come back for you!
Just you wait!