Here.
- Drink up.
- Pinako.
Mind if I join you?
This is nice, once in a while.
You think we're taking it too easy,
don't you?
Where's the harm?
At a time like this, at least.
Otherwise, this country is filled
with fighting all year round.
What with Ishval and all,
this country is always at war.
No matter how many times they repeat it,
they never learn.
Humans are foolish, miserable creatures.
Between Ishval and these insurgencies,
the Eastern Area is having
a rough time of it, huh?
It's not just the Eastern Area.
There are uprisings and border skirmishes
in the north and west too.
Even now, there are unending
skirmishes near the borders
of Aerugo to the south,
and Creta to the west.
We face the huge country
of Drachma to the north.
The bodies are piling up all over,
are they?
The government might just be overthrown
before too long.
What a restless country.
I'd say things started becoming
more militaristic
once the current Führer,
Bradley, came to power.
Hey! Let's dance.
Oh, you're quite popular,
aren't you, Hohenheim?
- You can go dance by yourself.
- It's no fun dancing by myself!
This old codger can't do anything fancy,
like dancing.
There, go dance
with those children over there.
It was about at that age...
when those boys started thinking
about doing human transmutation.
As their father,
you should have said something to them.
Whatever I could have said to them,
it wouldn't change the reality
of what they have to atone for.
- That's pretty harsh.
- A sin is a sin.
Damn it all!
It's been taken away!
Help! Someone! Mom! Mom...
No... this is wrong. This isn't--
this isn't what we wanted!
Al... Alphonse...
Alphonse! Alphonse!
This is my fault...
Alphonse!
Damn it! Damn it!
Give him back! He's my brother!
Take my leg! Take my arm!
Take my heart! You can have it!
So, give him back! He's my only brother!
The celestial stone
that destroyed Xerxes in one night.
If only I had that, I might be able
to get your body back, Al.
Doctor, just what was it
that you were ordered to research?
The Philosopher's Stone.
You must not seek this thing.
It is the devil's research!
If you learn about it,
you will pass through.
This is the devil's research,
which shouldn't be pursued.
Curse you, Dr. Marcoh.
The ingredients for a Philosopher's Stone
are live humans!
So weak, huh?
They're afraid of the dark
and won't confront it,
instead trying to forget about it
and run away temporarily like that.
Humans are very weak creatures.
Well, what do you say
we make the most use of them,
as our valued resources?
Hohenheim?
Knowing you, you'll be able to find
the truth within the truth.
What is this?
Is it possible that this is
for transmuting a Philosopher's Stone?
Let's have a look at what you've got.
Your prosthetic arm just saved your life.
However, my trusty sword
will pierce even steel!
- My brother...
- I hate to say it, but we've lost.
You're not going to tell me
you're actually three brothers, are you?
- No, no.
- Kid, hurry up and destroy us.
- Don't ask me to become a murderer.
With bodies like these,
are we even people?
If I don't consider you to be people,
then that would mean I don't consider
my brother to be a person.
My brother is human.
You guys are also human.
That's why I don't want to kill you.
Brother?
We two, as brothers, have been stealing,
destroying, and killing
for as long as we can remember.
And now, to be treated as humans
for the first time
after taking the forms we have...
it's hilarious!
Kid, as a parting gift,
I will tell you everything.
The ones who made
the Philosopher's Stone,
and ordered us to protect this place--
That was a close one.
No, 48, we can't have you
speaking out of turn.
Pipe down, you halfwit!
You were just about to kill
one of our precious sacrifices.
Do you understand?
Who are you people? What plan?
What do you mean, "sacrifice"?
You are a sacrifice after all.
Right! I'm a sacrifice.
What does that mean, "sacrifice"?
Their teacher would make good material
for a sacrifice as well.
I'm sorry. You were a candidate
for sacrifice, but you must die now.
I've been thinking all this time...
what is a sacrifice?
What is it you're trying to make me do?
Liore...
Uprisings all over...
the Philosopher's Stone...
ingredients are humans...
what we did in Ishval...
Hey, now, who was it
that came up with this?
What you're doing right now
is using this land and its people
to create a giant transmutation circle?
The purpose of which is to create
a Philosopher's Stone.
Am I wrong?
You actually knew about this, didn't you?
Hohenheim...
why didn't you tell anyone?
Hohenheim!
Even if I'd told someone,
would it have changed anything?
I've been watching for a long time
as humanity keeps repeating
the same mistakes over and over.
How helpless they are each time
and can do nothing but run away.
Humans are very fragile.
I told you,
the Philosopher's Stone is my core.
I'm a Homunculus.
You know of them, right?
An artificially created person.
That's what I am.
We're all going to die here anyway.
Let me show you something neat
before you pass on.
Can I eat you?
Mustang!
That monster was keeping
another monster inside his belly!
He's swallowing up everything around him!
So alchemy can even produce
something like this?
Who are you, old man?
Just as you have your Ultimate Shield,
I have my Ultimate Eye.
I get it, Hughes.
When you said the military was in trouble,
you didn't mean the danger
was closing in on us.
You meant the military itself
was the source of the trouble.
- Father? You have a dad?
- Yes.
- The person who made the Homunculi?
- Yes, he made us.
People have neither an Ultimate Spear,
nor an Ultimate Shield.
Nonetheless, they get snared
by the most trivial things,
and are unable to bounce back.
What do you think folks like that
can do against the Homunculi?
Still, we won't give up.
Like hell we'll give up!
That's something else about humans, huh?
How did you get here with your wound?
I burned it closed.
I nearly passed out
two or three times too.
No matter how much you try,
you cannot beat me!
Now then,
why don't you tell me your secret?
Thanks.
The blood that had rushed
to my head has settled a bit,
and my brain is starting to cool off.
You're still going to put up a fight?
Would you go down and stay down?
There are a lot of things
that are inconvenient about this body.
But inconvenient
does not equal ill-fortuned!
There's no reason for anyone
to take pity on me!
Brother saved my life with alchemy.
To disavow who I am now would be
to disavow Brother, and alchemy.
I believe in the possibilities of alchemy.
I want to believe!
He's a State Alchemist!
Get down!
Stay with me. Don't you die.
Damn, I can't stop the bleeding.
Somebody!
Live! You must not die!
Lan Fan! Get out of here!
Lan Fan!
- My left arm...
- What's wrong?
Young Lord...
I am no longer of any use to you.
Lan Fan!
Stop!
Nicely played.
Whether we're trampled or beaten down,
time and again, we keep going on.
And then, someday...
- It's just struggling in vain.
- You never can tell unless you try!
It's better than knowing and not acting.
Are you sure you're okay with Ed, Al,
and everyone else disappearing?
What are you getting so desperate about?
Even if you do take action
on behalf of those humans,
they'll just end up dying
on their own, won't they?
We're just going to wind up with nothing.
So then, don't you think it's smart
to take only what's important
and flee to somewhere else right away?
Wha--
Pangs of conscience? Worthless sentiment?
Hohenheim?
Whatever you think,
nobody is going to accept you now.
Look at your own face!
Humans are nothing but a resource.
If you leave them to themselves,
they'll proliferate on their own.
Where is the need for you
to take any action?
What will change if you do? This reality?
How weak humans are?
We will change.
We can change. I'm sure of it.
Sure, we may be weak,
but it's for that reason that we try hard
to grow stronger.
You may consider our steps to be futile,
but each step we take,
we are most surely building something.
Those below me
will protect those below them.
We tiny humans should be able to do
that much, at least.
No... I wasn't prepared for this.
We don't have to act so brave.
Lan Fan was more ready than I was.
I'm sick of people dying before my eyes.
I've had enough!
The graffiti flower that someone
was drawing on the wall trembles
I won't let anyone get killed anymore!
I'll protect them!
I'm not about to run away!
We'll send that Truth bastard flying,
and pull your body out of there!
Al!
Al! Come here!
Hurry, over here! Al!
Alphonse!
Alphonse! Alphonse!
Just you wait!
So I'm sure we can change.
Because we are weak. Because we die.
We struggle to live,
and we become stronger.
And if your mind still isn't made up...
try to remember...
the days we spent together in Resembool.
It was a dream?
Thanks for your help.