This sure is a creepy place
we've come to, huh?
Father, I brought a sacrifice!
Father? This is all so sudden...
Who are you?
Dad?
- Envy?
This?
Brother!
Al?
Al in armor? Which means...
- We made it back, huh?
- Yeah.
- Brother!
- Yow-w-w-w!
- Thank goodness you're safe!
- You're hurting me, Al!
The corner of your armor is poking me.
It's just...
Brother, you're alive...
Yeah. Sorry...
to worry you like that.
- I have to wonder, though, where are we?
- This is a surprise.
People, coming out of his belly.
Hohenheim?
A steel arm and leg... armor...
Are you the Elric brothers?
- You're... not him?
- You have me mistaken for someone?
Hold on... Hohen...
By any chance,
do you mean Van Hohenheim?
What is your connection to him?
He's our father.
Father? That is a surprise!
He went and had children?
But as I understood it,
your last name was "Elric."
"Elric" was our mother's name!
- I see. So, where is he now?
- I don't know!
Never mind him, who are you?
You look exactly like Hohenheim,
you know!
- He wouldn't be dead.
- Hey, listen to me!
- But for him to have children...
- Brother, this man is...
Are you injured?
And you don't have your left hand.
There, how is that? It's broken.
It-- it's better...
- Hey... ow-w-w!
- And some broken ribs, too.
You are both precious resources to me.
You have to look after yourselves.
He performed alchemy
without any motion at all.
What's more, he didn't thin out my arm.
In other words, no equivalent exchange!
Who are you?
This is impossible!
What have you got going on inside you?
I'll ask you the same thing. Who are you?
- You can eat him.
- Right!
Just-- just a minute!
He's a friend of ours!
Out of consideration for us
being your sacrifices,
can't you, you know...
It is not my affair.
- He is not anyone that I need.
- What?
Brother, the Homunculi call him "Father."
- He's the one who created them.
- What?
- He did fix up our bodies, though.
- I don't like him...
or his attitude...
He's just like those who laugh
at humans as being fools.
Do you think of bugs
crawling along the ground as fools?
When you see a worm struggling,
you feel no association with it,
because your levels
are so vastly different, right?
That's how I think about you humans.
You may have healed my injuries,
but we still have
irreconcilable differences!
You seem to be the root
of all these events.
I'm going to settle this, right now!
I don't give a damn about the small fry.
You're a fine one to talk
about small fry, pipsqueak!
Pipsqueak?
I got you, boss man!
Ling! What's going on?
How can he transmute
without making any motion at all?
This is a waste of time.
My alchemy isn't working!
Ed! Al!
- What has that bearded guy done?
- Why?
Why can't we use our alchemy?
Really, I can't get over you lower lives.
As soon as you gain a great power,
you get carried away with it,
not even knowing what it is.
Did you think you brought about
the prize you now have
all under your own power?
That's a laugh! You fools!
What is this?
You promised me that once we got back,
you'd tell me everything!
Huh? I don't remember promising anything
- to you worms!
- Why, you!
- You talk too much, Envy.
- Okay, okay.
You may not be such bad material.
I might be able to increase
the number of pawns I can use.
- That's... a Philosopher's Stone!
- What?
- You're planning to do that?
- "That" what?
Create a Homunculus.
A Philosopher's Stone is poured in.
If all goes as planned,
a human-based Homunculus is created.
Although, they usually are unable
to withstand the Stone's power,
- and end up dying.
- I won't let you do that!
- Let us go, Envy!
- Damn it! What's going on?
Why won't our alchemy work?
Hey, you, bearded guy! Stop!
He's got someone waiting for him!
Let me go!
You can't shoot like this, huh... human?
- Why, you...
- It's okay! Don't shoot!
Don't try to pull anything!
- This is what I want!
- What?
I came to this country
to find a Philosopher's Stone!
He's going to just give me one!
- I couldn't ask for anything more!
- What are you talking about?
Ho, this is interesting.
Then, as you wish, I shall give it to you.
No, stop!
Ling!
I... I told you... not to... interfere!
It's all right... just sit still...
I'm the man who will be emperor
of Xing, Ling Yao...
What's a little kid doing here?
No matter. Hand over your body.
I'm going to use it.
Fine with me. You can have my body.
- I told you, I'm accepting you.
- Wouldn't you ordinarily reject me?
I'm the man who will become
the emperor of Xing!
What good will I be
if I don't have a breast
large enough to accept 20 or 30 others?
You're decisive. I like that.
- Just don't go regretting this!
- Regret this?
If I went home empty-handed,
there's no way I could face my vassal,
who went so far as to cut off
her own arm for me!
I want power, to protect with...
Absolute power, to obtain things with!
I know the risks from the outset!
I like your avarice.
Now, let's see just how ready you are!
- Ling?
- You mean the owner of this body?
Sorry, Greed has taken over
this container.
- You're not Ling?
- You're Greed?
Are you... that Greed?
- Huh? Which one do you mean?
- You don't remember?
- The one from Dublith.
- And which Greed was that?
- The Greed before you.
- Ah, that makes sense.
Which means I'm a different Greed
from the one you guys knew.
What about Ling?
He's a fascinating kid.
He accepted me without any trouble.
You're lying! He's not the sort
to be taken over so easily!
Answer me, Ling! Ling!
- What's wrong?
- Ugh... I don't like him...
He's a person, and yet he isn't.
Indeed, many people here aren't people.
Shao May! Thank goodness!
Thank goodness! I was so worried!
Oh... If I had to guess,
I'd say this is a touching reunion?
You don't seem to be in cahoots
with the Homunculi. Fullmetal Alchemist...
- Where? Where is Edward?
- That's him.
- He isn't anywhere, is he?
- I told you, that's him.
The little one there
is the Fullmetal Alchemist.
You've toyed with the feelings
of a pure young maiden,
you grain-of-rice-sized boy!
What was that,
you grain-of-rice-sized girl?
- Brother, what did you do to that--
- That's the Ishvalan I didn't get to eat.
- I haven't done anything!
- An insubordinate, huh?
- We have to hurry and get out of this!
- Indeed, he is the one.
He interferes at every turn with this
destructive alchemy.
Get rid of him, Gluttony!
- He can't use his alchemy now!
- Okay!
- What?
- You'll pay for this!
You trampled the feelings
of a young maiden,
and kidnapped Shao May, to boot!
There's going to be hell to pay
for all of you!
Lucky!
- It just isn't working!
- Why not?
Why are you able to use alchemy here?
What do you mean?
Seriously, what's going on here?
- How come Scar and that girl--?
- I don't know.
I don't know, but...
this could be our chance
to salvage this situation. Scar!
Let me tell you the truth
about the Ishvalan Civil War!
- The truth?
- The child-shooting incident
that triggered the uprising
was carried out by Envy there,
who had changed himself
into a military officer!
These guys set up the whole thing!
It sounds like I need to get
some more details out of you.
Answer me!
Why did you have to destroy us?
Depending on how you answer,
I'll send you to God--
no, you will not get to be with God,
where my Ishvalan brothers sleep.
Consider yourselves
without rest or salvation!
Oh, awesome! Not bad for a human.
- Greed, dispose of the outsiders.
- Right, right.
I don't believe it, Ling!
It's Greed!
That is... Ling, of the Yao family?
A girl! Such tender flesh!
Hey, you. How can you still use alchemy?
You really are using it.
Bodily destruction... no, decomposition.
If I was one moment slower in escaping,
I would have been...
Mr. Scar!
Shao May, run!
You're mine!
Are you all right?
- I don't remember asking for your help.
- You can't possibly be that naive!
These guys show no mercy to anyone
who is of no use to them.
You have to get out of here, quickly!
There's too many of them.
I thought you guys ran away.
Scar, can you take this girl
and flee back to the surface?
You're letting me get away?
Me, the one who killed
that girl's doctor parents?
Yeah, I would like to beat you to death.
To tell you the truth,
I hate having to ask you for anything.
But right now,
getting this girl out of here comes first!
What are you going to do?
Apparently, we brothers
are precious human resources to them.
They won't kill us if we remain here.
I can't break out of here
while protecting the girl
in the state I'm in now.
Besides, I have no intention
of running away to the surface!
You're decomposing the water?
Jeez, if you're going to do
something like that, say so first!
What a reckless thing to do!
Igniting the hydrogen, huh? Not bad.
- Where is he? Where did he go?
- I don't know!
Gluttony, track his scent!
You don't have any regenerative
power left? You've died too much.
That was a pretty good kick.
You'll be even more entertaining
than I thought.
Dumb prince!
- Snap out of it!
- I'm Greed!
Who cares? Give Ling his body back!
I'm afraid I can't!
Play it cool, will you, you idiot?
What about your country?
What about Lan Fan?!
- Yow-ww-w!
- Daddy, sir, I caught him!
Upstairs. Take them to Wrath.
Man, you sure made a mess of things.
If you had behaved yourself,
we wouldn't have done anything to you.
Brother...
He's-- Ling is in there.
You've used up
your regenerative power, have you?
Not to worry, my son.
I will recreate you,
and leave your memories intact.
Chaotic humans, writhe in pain.
That is what proves you are alive.
And once you are done struggling,
kneel before me.