- Hey, where the hell are we going?
- Get in.
Is this...?
The command center. What's going on here?
Hey! You guys are filthy.
To think that the Homunculus stronghold
was deep beneath the command center.
Does that mean it's not just the Führer,
but the military itself
that has ties to them?
But then, it isn't all bad news.
- Really? My body is really in there?
- Yeah.
It told me, "You aren't my soul,
so I can't go with you."
You don't say. So I do have a body.
- All right... All right!
- All right.
That means we're yet another step
closer to our goal!
Hey, what is that black-and-white cat
doing here?
Oh, her?
Actually, inside here, I've got...
- What? The beansprout girl?
- Brother, your voice is too loud!
And for that matter,
hurry up and put on some shorts!
What are you doing in here? Hurry up!
- What did you bring her along for?
- I didn't have any choice, did I?
- She's wounded!
- Hey!
- Wrath will take it from here. In here.
- Wrath?
Wrath? The Führer, King Bradley?
Colonel!
- What happened?
- A lot has happened.
Sergeant Fuery was sent south,
Warrant Officer Falman north,
and Lieutenant Breda to the west.
Lieutenant Hawkeye
is now the Führer's personal assistant.
Wha--
What is this?
They're as good as hostages!
Have a seat.
Right now, it's just us and the Führer
in this room.
He only has one sword for a weapon.
Even so, he's confident
that he could beat us.
COUGH
Führer, sir...
earlier, when I was in the hospital,
you came to visit me.
You had us completely fooled.
Don't go sticking your noses in it.
Treat the whole military as the enemy.
That's what I ordered you to do.
You are important human resources for me.
You don't need to know any more than that.
If you just behave yourselves
until the time comes,
no harm will come to you.
When the time comes,
what happens to all of the other people,
the ones you haven't called "sacrifice"?
I told you, you don't need to know
anything more, Fullmetal Alchemist.
Fullmetal Alchemist, huh?
I chose the path of becoming a Dog of the
Military to get my original body back.
However,
the whole State Alchemist system itself
is probably just something
to select sacrifices with.
If you're going to be using me
for something even worse...
then I quit as a State Alchemist.
Your token as a dog is covered with blood.
I will upset your schemes,
no matter what they are.
I will spread the word
to the other alchemists, and then--
What was that girl's name again?
Ah yes, Winry Rockbell.
Born in Resembool, a childhood friend
of yours, and like family to you.
A skilled automail engineer.
She currently works in Rush Valley,
where she is well-favored
by both her customers and companions.
A nice, unassuming girl.
You keep away from her!
And everyone else around her!
So, what will it be?
If you don't want it, I will cut her down.
- Very well.
- Um...
We're all in agreement.
So, in exchange for us
acting as we always have under your watch,
please allow us to continue our journey,
our journey to get our original bodies.
If you please.
Makes no difference to me, as long
as you don't do anything uncalled-for.
What will you do, Colonel Mustang?
You're not going to tell me
you're quitting the military, are you?
Well, let's see. I may be a kept dog now,
but I couldn't bear
to become a beaten dog.
Moreover, right now,
I still have my ambitions,
so I can't take off this uniform,
or get rid of this.
Very well. You are all dismissed.
May I ask you one question,
Your Excellency?
- What is it, Colonel?
- Are you the one who killed Hughes?
- No, I'm not the one.
- Then, who was it?
I agreed to one question.
If you'll excuse me.
Just a moment, Alphonse.
- Was there something?
- No, you are dismissed.
- That was close!
- A sword just went over my head!
Oh yeah, Colonel...
Give me whatever small change
you've got on you.
- What's this, all of a sudden?
- Just give it to me!
- Not much, huh?
- What are you, a shakedown artist?
- Well, whatever. Bye!
- Hey!
Sorry, Colonel, we'll report back later.
What the hell? Oh, no, the lieutenant!
Lieuten--
What is the matter, Colonel?
You look pale.
Do you know of any man who looks rosy
when he goes to a meeting spot
where a woman is waiting and finds
a muscle-bound mustache-head instead?
- Colonel.
- Lieutenant.
Are you all right? Excuse me.
Lieutenant Hawkeye,
reporting back after using the restroom.
I availed myself
of Major Armstrong's generosity,
and allowed him to relieve me
for a short while.
- Thank you very much, Major.
- Not at all.
You didn't run away?
Who was it that said not to give up,
no matter what happened?
Don't go telling me later that
you'd wished you'd run away, Lieutenant.
It's too late now.
Yes, hello? Ed?
What are you calling for out of the blue?
- You break your automail again?
- No!
Are you okay? You doing all right?
Nothing out of the ordinary?
You aren't being followed
by anyone suspicious, or anything?
- Ed...
- What?
- You're creeping me out.
- What do you mean by that?
I mean, Ed,
you barely ever call as it is,
and what's worse, you're worrying over me?
Ugh, what's going on?
Is it going to start snowing next?
Look, you!
Do you have any idea how--
Thanks.
I'm glad you called. Thanks.
Sure. You're sure you're all right?
Yeah. Bye.
She's safe, for the time being.
It's that kind of desperation
that they're going to take advantage of.
- Ling!
- I told you, it's Greed.
What do you want?
- Your pal asked me for something.
- Ling did?
It's in Xingese. What does it say?
Dunno. Can't read it.
He said to give it to the girl
waiting for him.
Lan Fan-- You're not going to follow
after us and kill the girl, are you?
As if I'd do anything so petty.
Besides, I have no interest in fighting.
I live by the creed of never
telling a lie. Well, if you would...
- Hey, Ling!
- It's Greed.
Who is he?
And why would he need to start
a civil war, and ravage the country?
Who's there?
Is there somebody there?
Are you injured?
Why don't you come on down?
I'd like to know what's happening
on the outside.
It's all right.
The guard won't be around for a while.
Besides, I'm a doctor.
I can take a look at your wound.
You're Ishvalan, aren't you?
That scar on your forehead...
Don't tell me you're Scar!
Who are you? What are you doing here?
Oh, God!
I am... I am an alchemist that took part
in the extermination of Ishval.
It's all right. She's in no mortal danger.
Once she gets a little rest,
she should recover.
- That's good.
- The hell it is!
You keep bringing patients here
without asking!
They're occupying my bed and sofa,
so where am I supposed
to sleep from now on, eh?
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
- Now I've got two young girls!
- Alphonse...
- In my house!
- Lan Fan! No!
- You should still be in bed.
- The Young Lord...
the Young Lord isn't with you?
It's okay, he's alive.
I brought a message from him.
I have obtained the Philosopher's Stone.
Lan Fan?
It says...
It says he has obtained
a Philosopher's Stone.
Now, our clan will be--
Yes, I have to return to my land,
and let everyone know about this!
Where is he? Where is the Young Lord?
What is it? Why won't you tell me?
Don't tell me something has happened
to the Young Lord.
Answer me, Alphonse!
Where is the Young Lord?
How are you feeling, Greed?
You're Wrath, are you? I feel fine.
Did you hear?
This body belongs to a Xingese prince.
He voluntarily accepted me,
because he wanted the power
to become the emperor.
Fascinating little chump.
That prince once asked me
what it was like to be a true king.
He said that a king
was to be for the people,
and that he could not be,
without his people.
The fool. He lacks desire,
and has lost everything, hasn't he?
Shut up!
Don't go looking down on humans.
There you have it.
He's just watching closely
for any opportunity to take over.
So he's even willing to take in
a monster like you, is he?
How great the avarice of humans.
The Führer is a Homunculus?
I only ever wanted to fight
for the weaker citizens of this country.
Many others think so,
believe in the military, and enlist.
- And yet, the military is...
- Why don't you quit the military?
With your character,
it would be hard on you to stay in.
This war is wrong, sir!
Are you going to disobey an order?
Very well!
Call in a replacement State Alchemist!
In Ishval, I fled from the fighting.
I knew that the way
the military operated was in error,
and I should have fought
against that error.
From then until now, not a day has gone by
that I haven't felt ashamed of myself
for not sticking to my convictions,
and running away.
If the military is once again
the battlefield,
how can I tuck my tail and run away?
Colonel, what are you going to do now?
I told the Führer that I still had my
ambitions, and that I would not give up.
Since the Führer has made it clear to me
that he is a Homunculus,
it implies that even if I were
to topple him,
there is still someone behind him.
I'm being tested. It's an honor, isn't it?
- You're surprisingly relaxed, sir.
- I don't know.
It's just that, as it was
when I was fighting that Homunculus Lust,
after having been called a weapon,
or a monster,
it's only when I'm fighting real monsters
that I truly feel that I'm just a human.
I see. The Young Lord voluntarily accepted
the Philosopher's Stone.
Sorry. If we had stopped him...
There's no need to apologize.
I'm just mad at myself,
because I was unable
to fulfill my role as bodyguard.
The Young Lord is...
the Young Lord is still inside
of this Greed person, right?
- Alphonse, I want an arm, right now.
- Right now? But...
Take me to an automail engineer. Please!
All right.
I'll refer you to one as soon as I can.
But before I do,
you have to get back your strength.
I'll get you something to eat
from Dr. Knocs...
Should you be out of bed yet?
- May Chang, isn't it?
- May?
- What?
- That's a Yao family watchdog for you.
- And you-- you're the Chang heiress.
- Indeed I am.
The 17th princess, May Chang.
If you're here in this country,
you must be after immortality.
You're the last ones
I'm going to let have it!
You're never even going to find it!
Just a minute!
I don't know what's going on,
but stop fighting!
- Don't butt into our national affairs!
Don't underestimate me
just because I'm injured!
I would say the exact same thing to you.
Hey, what are you doing?
You're my patients!
Now go lie quietly in your beds!
Do not butt into our national--
I don't care about your national affairs,
dumb ass!
Patients are the same in every country!
Are you planning to mess up
my house any further?
There could be an unknown pathogen
in this doctor's house
that could get out,
and kill everyone in it.
It really is a mess in here.
I wonder if he has anyone
who straightens up.
Doctor, here.
Ah, so that's where that was.
- That's a family photo, isn't it?
- It's my estranged wife and son.
What? It's up to me
what I do with my own stuff, right?
Once you've straightened up,
go get some coffee or something.
Thanks so much for coming.
After all, the way things were,
I didn't know what I was going to do.
I just realized, I'm able to use alchemy.
Good work.
That takes care of all of the repairs.
Just what you'd expect
from a State Alchemist.
You're a cut above
the other alchemists around here.
As it happens, this morning,
there were some local alchemists
who were helping us out
with the recovery efforts,
but they ended up being useless.
They strolled on in here,
all full of confidence,
but when the time came,
they said their alchemy wasn't working.
This morning?
When we were down underground?
Mr. Alchemist! Thank you!
Thank you.
Can I really believe what Envy told me
about them only being energy forms,
without body or mind?
Snap out of it!
Think about what lies ahead!
Earlier, it wasn't just Al and I.
Other alchemists couldn't use
their alchemy, either.
But that beansprout girl and Scar
were able to use theirs.
What does that mean?
Their alchemy is different from ours.
If I get the secret of it out of them,
then maybe we won't even need
a Philosopher's Stone
to get Al's body back, and go up
against that mustachioed bastard.
I have to give this back
to the lieutenant.
I made Philosopher's Stones,
and deprived many Ishvalans
of their lives.
And now, they're about to make me
work with them on experiments
that are likely to cause
many more casualties.
So... so please, kill me! Here, now!
I will strike back at them with my death!
You appear as a god to me.
I still haven't heard
the whole story of Ishval.
What did you people do there?
Tell me everything, Marcoh!
Before this right arm of mine
destroys you!