So you ended up
becoming a soldier after all.
Sure enough, you're not ready
for "flame alchemy" yet.
Still, sir?
Up to now,
you have only taught me
the fundamentals of alchemy.
Of course.
It's a waste to even teach
the fundamentals to someone
who lowers himself
to becoming a dog of the military.
Is not alchemy for the people?
Master, now that the country
is threatened from all sides,
there is a pressing need
to strengthen the military.
- Alchemy in defense of the people is--
- I'm tired of hearing that excuse!
I find it difficult to abide this.
Master, how can someone as great as you
suffocate in such poverty?
Please, get your state certification.
Once you do,
you could further your research, and--
I completed my research long, long ago.
What?
The greatest, most powerful alchemy,
depending on how it is used,
it could bring about disaster.
I have perfected it,
and now, I am convinced.
As long as an alchemist lives,
he is a creature
that must pursue the truth.
Once an alchemist stops thinking, he dies.
I died a long time ago--
Master!
Master! Master Hawkeye!
Look after... my daughter...
My daughter...
has all of... my research...
Thank you for everything
that you've done for him.
Don't worry about it.
As his pupil, it was a matter of course.
If anything comes up,
feel free to call on me in the military.
Are you going to scorn me
for becoming a soldier too?
Sure, someday, I might die like trash
by the side of the road.
Even so, if I can be one
of this country's building blocks,
and defend the people with these hands,
I believe I'll be happy.
Man, I've revealed such
a naive dream of mine.
Not at all.
I think it's a wonderful dream.
Is it okay for me to believe in a future
where we will live happily?
Should I let you carry out
my father's dreams?
Hayate, bad!
Sorry about that.
Nah, it happens a lot.
I heard you'd been assigned to the Führer.
Yes.
Looks like you had
a pretty hard time of it.
I didn't shoot anyone.
I didn't have to shoot them.
Or rather, I couldn't shoot them.
I'm hopeless, huh?
I've got no resolve,
so I'm always putting everyone else out.
Did something happen?
It turns out Scar is the one
who killed Winry's parents.
At that moment,
deep down in my heart,
I felt it was wrong.
Suddenly, the gun
looked like something scary.
Before I knew it...
I think she hated Scar enough
to want to kill him.
Afterward, she bawled
like I've never seen her bawl before.
I really am hopeless.
I didn't understand her one bit.
It's because you came back alive
that you're worried about this.
But then, you have to go on living.
For the sake of those important
to you as well.
Protect her.
You love Winry, don't you?
No, she's just a childhood friend!
She's like family!
I... It's only natural
that I'd protect her--
I apologize.
This turned out
to be a heavy burden for you.
Lieutenant, have you ever thought of it
as a heavy burden?
I don't have the right
to call it light or heavy anymore.
I've taken the lives
of many people in the past.
Also...
I'm the one
who chose to go down this path.
Ishval?
Is it okay if I ask you about Ishval?
Tell me what you people did in Ishval.
Ishval is a harsh land,
full of rocks and sand.
The land being what it is,
it's no surprise that such a strong people
and a religion with such strict tenets
would be born there.
However,
a number of people were discontented
over their annexation by Amestris.
As a result...
With that one bullet fired,
their discontent became anger
and spread throughout all of Ishval.
In time, the uprising became a civil war
and it went on for seven long years.
And then, a one-page document
determined everything.
Führer's Order #3066.
The piece of paper that declared the start
of the Ishvalan War of Extermination.
Just that one sheet of paper.
It was hell.
The air was filled with the smells
of decay and gunpowder,
and the sand was heavily soaked
with the blood that had been shed.
Ordinary soldiers
would fire rounds indiscriminately,
and one of them might happen
to take the life of someone.
But for snipers, it was different.
When we pulled the trigger,
someone was sure to die.
The only ones for whom the link
between cause and effect was so evident
were snipers...
and State Alchemists.
My name is Iron Blood Alchemist,
Basque Grand!
Iron and blood!
In other words, weapon and soldier!
If I do not take the lead in battle,
who else will?
Why, those Ishvalan punks!
How dare they? Damn them!
Roy! Roy Mustang!
You're here too, are you?
Long time no see.
But then, you've got a different look
about you.
I could say the same for you.
You've got the eyes of a killer.
Yeah.
Back at the military academy,
we all talked about the future
of this country, huh?
Yeah. And what a beautiful future it was.
Captain, you have a letter.
Oh, thanks!
What?
It's my beautiful future!
Her name is Gracia.
She's waiting in Central for me
to come home.
All by herself, all this time...
What if another man puts the moves on her?
Nah, Gracia wouldn't disregard
a fine man like me
to have an affair with someone else.
No, but then again...
Hughes, a little word of warning.
This often happens in movies and novels...
A guy on the battlefield
who brings up stories of his woman
immediately dies.
Look, you...
Now I can live until tomorrow.
This letter is enough
to let me dream about tomorrow.
Here on this battlefield, where
we don't know when things will end...
It's true, I see no way out of this war.
No matter how much military force
the country throws this way,
the desert just sucks it up like water.
After trying so hard to gain control,
what's left?
All in all, it's just the sand, right?
Yeah.
This is more than comprehensive
for bringing an uprising under control.
Long time no see, Major Mustang.
Do you remember me?
How can this be?
She has developed the eyes of a killer.
Please tell me something, Major.
Why are soldiers killing citizens,
when they should be protecting them?
Why is alchemy meant
to bring about good fortune,
being used to kill people?
Because that is the job
of a State Alchemist.
Why are soldiers killing citizens
when they should be protecting them?
Because that is the duty
placed upon soldiers.
Am I wrong?
Are you saying we should accept
this devastation as part of the job?
Well, now, let's say...
Miss, you seem reluctant to be here.
That's the face you're making.
Can you tell me for certain
that when you defeat an enemy,
there isn't the slightest moment
where you say, "I got him! Great!"
take pride in your own skills,
and feel a sense of accomplishment?
Miss Sniper?
Don't say another word!
For my part,
I can't understand you people.
The battlefield is, after all,
a place where you kill the enemy.
Did you put on your uniforms
without being ready for that?
Don't avert your eyes from death.
Look forward.
Look directly at the people
you are killing.
And then don't forget them.
The enemy
isn't going to forget you, either.
Whoops, it's time.
I have to get to work.
I have to go too.
See you, Roy.
Hughes.
Why do you fight?
It's simple. I don't want to die.
That's all there is to it.
The reasons are always something simple.
Well, then what is the reason
for this war?
Reason?
There is one. A terrible reason.
Are you saying you used our blood
to make a Philosopher's Stone?
What became of the Stone?
Major Solf J. Kimblee,
the Crimson Alchemist, had it.
The man with long, black hair tied back
and cold eyes?
Brother...
And then?
The tide of the battle
turned over that single Stone.
Oh, I love that sound.
It resonates deep within my body.
I truly love that sound.
It makes my spinal cord
dance with sorrow,
and my eardrums quiver with glee.
It is a joy I can feel
here as always, side-by-side with death.
What fulfilling work this is!
I love this sound!
How wonderful the Philosopher's Stone is!
It was only a matter of time
before they were exterminated.
It was then that the High Priest
of Ishvala, Logue Lowe,
stood before the Führer
on behalf of his brethren.
Ho... you want me to accept your life,
to spare the remaining tens
of thousands of Ishvalans?
- Indeed, I am--
- Don't flatter yourself.
Are you saying that your life
and the lives of the remaining
tens of thousands are of equal value?
Let's not get carried away, human.
A single person's life
is only worth that one person,
nothing more and nothing less.
I will not accept this exchange,
nor will I stop the extermination.
Why, you...! You're inhuman!
You will suffer the hammer of God!
God?
This is intriguing.
Even under these circumstances,
the hammer of God
has not befallen me yet, has it?
How many more...
how many thousands more Ishvalans
must I kill before it falls?
Why, you!
God is, after all, nothing more
than something created by people,
by human hands.
If you wish to lower the hammer on me,
then don't rely on God,
do it yourself, human!
In time, the war was over,
and we ended up returning to our homes.
Ultimately, we foot soldiers
were as good as garbage, huh?
Yeah.
The power of one person
does not amount to much.
As such, I will do all I can,
however little that may be,
to protect those who are dear to me,
those below me
will protect those below them.
We tiny humans should be able
to do that much, at least.
After all you went through in Ishval,
you still ended up choosing this path.
Yes, sir.
If the ways of this world are based
on equivalent exchange, as alchemy says,
then in order to allow for a new
generation to enjoy good fortune,
then the price that we must pay
is to carry the bodies of the dead
across a river of blood.
I'm going to appoint you
to be my assistant.
I would like to have you watch my back.
You understand, don't you?
That by leaving my back to you,
you can shoot me from behind at any time.
If I ever step off the path, shoot me.
You are entitled to do so.
Will you follow me?
As you wish, sir.
Into hell, if you so desire.
But even if the colonel
becomes top soldier,
it won't change the fact that this country
is a military state, will it?
Yeah, well, you have to take the Assembly,
which is now more or less
a puppet of the military,
and move it back to a democratic system,
like it should be.
Until you wring out the corruption
from the military-state era,
the country can't be renewed.
Corruption?
For example, the war criminals
of the Ishvalan War of Extermination
could be brought to trial.
Yes.
The hero of the civil war
would just be a mass murderer
in a peaceful world.
And the colonel is aiming for the top,
knowing all this?
That's a path to suicide, isn't it?
The Homunculi were the ones
pulling the strings behind the scenes
during the civil war.
Even if the Homunculi
were the cause of it,
we're the ones who carried it out.
You must not turn away from death.
You must not forget the people
you've killed.
The reason being... they certainly won't
forget us for killing them.
But...
Before you start worrying about us,
you have something else to do, right?
You and Alphonse have to get back
to your original bodies.
There must be many people
who are waiting for that day to come.
Al and I will get our bodies
back together for sure.
Dr. Knocs, sorry to have intruded.
Mr. Armor?
Thank you for all the help you've been.
My name isn't Armor. It's Alphonse Elric.
Elric?
You remember Edward Elric, right?
The little alchemist,
I'm his younger brother.
It's a long story, but my body
was taken away from me.
HIM
If you're his brother,
then I'll bet you're just like him.
That's pretty rude!
Obviously, I'm far taller than Brother is!
My face isn't harsh like his,
and I'm a better fighter than him.
But I'm not short-tempered.
I'm a gentleman.
Oh, Alphonse!
I sure do hope you get your body
back soon.
Right.
Dr. Marcoh, time to eat.
Huh? It sure is quiet.
Are you thinking about Ishval again,
and crying to yourself?