Vengeance... Damn it!
It's Scar! He knows
about Marcoh's involvement
in the War of Extermination, does he?
If I get any new information,
I'll let you know.
Being the Führer's assistant
is like being a hostage, right?
Will you be okay?
If you think about it positively,
it also means that given a chance,
I can kill the Führer while he sleeps.
You scare me.
Oh, right. Give the colonel a message.
Tell him Scar is still on the prowl.
You got it.
- Lieutenant...
- What?
Thanks for telling me about Ishval.
Al!
Brother! What is it?
So, that's what happened in Ishval, huh?
She described everything about it,
to a kid like me.
"Alchemists are seekers of truth."
But I didn't even know
about something so near at hand.
The colonel is thinking about what happens
after he attains his goal.
After he attains his goal, huh?
Al, after you get your original body back,
what do you want to do?
Let's see... First, I guess I want to eat
some of Winry's apple pie.
What about you, Brother?
I've had my hands full just trying to have
our original bodies back, so...
First thing I might do is go around
and pay some courtesy calls
to Granny and Teacher,
and tell them, "We're back!"
Yeah, after all they've done to help us.
They'll all be smiling when they greet us.
- Yeah.
- We'll get to see everyone smile, right?
Yeah.
The situation is pretty rough right now,
but somehow, I'm starting to cheer up.
There are some cheerful stories
to be had, too.
Back there, our alchemy didn't work.
At the same time, they apparently
couldn't use it above ground, either.
Then, that girl and Scar...
Yeah. They're the only ones
who could use it.
There's something about their alchemy.
Something we don't know about.
Yeah. We're not at a dead end yet.
She left?
The little beansprout girl?
Yeah, early this morning.
- So, where did she say she was going?
- She didn't say.
- We'll look for her!
- Throughout Central? Without any clues?
But we do have a clue!
- What's this?
- With my compliments.
Have you got any, you know, magazines,
with lots of girls in them?
- Don't go slacking off while we're gone.
- You're leaving already?
Yeah. Gonna get me some
of that famous western food.
Make sure to hold down the fort here.
Yeah. See you later.
You eat well, and grow up
big and strong now.
- Keep everyone safe while we're gone.
- Sergeant Fuery...
- Yo.
- Warrant Officer Falman?
You haven't left yet?
I came to return something
I borrowed from the colonel.
Aw... Sure was a short posting in Central.
Sergeant, you're in the
South Command Center?
Yes, sir. Completely opposite from you.
I'll bet the Northern Command Center
is cold.
Well, see you later, Sergeant Fuery.
Yes, sir. Let's meet up again sometime.
- Excuse me, Colonel.
- Lieutenant.
I came to get something I left here.
- I hear that Scar is still on the prowl.
- I'll have to watch out for him.
I'm losing my skilled bodyguard.
Please don't go dying, sir.
Yeah.
It must make you anxious, huh?
I may have picked the wrong person
to side with.
If you think I'm wrong, shoot me dead.
That's the promise you made that day.
You're still within my threshold.
Lieutenant, you're so nice to me.
Well, Colonel, see you later.
Later.
- Please don't let your work slide.
- Yeah.
My pawn...
Oh, you might say it sprang from my house.
My bishop...
Yes, sir! It is an honor!
My rook...
Hello, sir.
My knight...
I'm not all that bright, so I struggle
through the military academy.
And...
Into hell, if you so desire.
My queen has been taken.
But I still haven't been checkmated...
just yet.
Here, this cat! I'm looking for
the little girl who is with her!
So, do any of you recognize her?
I'm sorry.
Please ignore that alien over there.
- No word on that black-and-white cat.
- Maybe they're not in Central anymore.
Fullmetal...
Colonel!
I see... Xingese Alkahestry, huh?
All right. I'll ask around about this.
I really do hate to be
in your debt, Colonel.
Oh, yeah, speaking of debts,
give me back my money.
Watch where you're going!
You remember about that, huh?
How much was it, again? 500 cens?
Five hundred twenty cens!
Don't try wrangling me!
What? How nitpicky!
It's not that big a deal!
Sorry about this.
Actually, I'm going to keep
borrowing this.
I'll give it back to you, Colonel,
when you become Führer.
Who told you?
Lieutenant Hawkeye.
She told me about Ishval, too.
Fullmetal...
You keep that borrowed money.
I'll make sure you return it to me.
Then, once I do, I'll borrow
some more of your spare change.
I'll say, "I'll pay it back once
the country is a democracy."
Then, once I return that,
I'll borrow some more.
And make you promise something else.
In other words,
you're telling me that I'm going
to have to live a long time, huh?
That's right. Don't you go
worrying the lieutenant, either.
Thanks for dropping us off.
You're late.
I got tired of waiting for you.
Yo.
Oh, Roy! Long time!
- You're looking well, Vanessa.
- It's been a long time, Roy.
- Good evening, Madam Christmas.
- How have you been?
Oh, absolutely terrible.
- I'm here to lift my mood.
- Want something to drink?
I'm recuperating,
so I can't have any alcohol.
Fix me up something special, Madam.
You got it.
General Grumman, sir...
You have a call
from a Madam Christmas, in Central.
Please, don't go giving out
our secret line to the general public.
Not half bad, huh?
The old man is being called upon.
You lose your arm, you were unable
to protect the young lord...
and now look at you...
Hey, what are you doing?
And you call yourself one
of the chosen ones from the Yao clan?
- You should be ashamed!
- Stop that, old man! She's injured!
Stop it, I said!
It's gone...?
Your arm... is gone...?
I'm sorry, Grandfather.
I'm sorry.
You fool.
You fool!
I have to keep my promise to Lan Fan,
to set her up with an automail mechanic.
You can't.
We accept your kind intentions,
but we need no more of your help.
We will find an automail mechanic
on our own somehow.
But we can't just leave you like this.
Now that the enemy
has seen Lan Fan's face,
we cannot allow your friend
to be caught in the middle.
All right. Thanks.
It is thanks to you
that my granddaughter is still alive.
- I am grateful.
- Wha...!?
I'm not the sort of doctor
that gets thank-yous!
Dr. Knocs, thank you very much.
Just get out of here!
I'm not such a softy that I'm about
to let you outstay your welcome!
His Majesty's condition appears to be bad.
We must quickly recover the young lord
and return to our country
with the means of attaining immortality.
- Let's go.
- Right.
Just you wait, denizens of the underworld.
We will be back.
I will never forget my debt to you
for helping me.
Dr. Knocs, thank you very much.
Me, playing at being a doctor now? Me?
Yeah! Who is it?
Good evening, Dad. It's been a long time.
- How are you doing, dear?
- Fine.
We had an errand that brought us
to the area, so...
- You've grown up.
- You've lost some weight, haven't you?
- As have you.
- Is work keeping you busy?
Yeah. Dealing with corpses,
same as always.
No, actually, I treated two live patients
just this week.
It's funny, thinking of me, saving lives.
Dad, I want to become a doctor.
I know that you've been tormented,
ever since you got back from Ishval.
Even so, Dad,
you never gave up being a doctor.
I love you, Dad, for being a doctor.
You jackass...
Come on in. It may not taste very good
but have some coffee.
Wow, what a mess!
Come on, let's straighten up
while your father is making the coffee.
God, if you're out there,
then let this slide.
It's okay for someone like me
to want the happiness
of enjoying some coffee
with his family, right?
Now, Ishval is completely
under armed forces jurisdiction.
Well done, Major Kimblee.
So, how did the Philosopher's Stone work?
It was fantastic.
By ignoring equivalent exchange,
I was able to perform greater
transmutations than I'd imagined.
Very good. Write up the details
in a report, and submit it to us.
We will be taking the Stone back.
What are you doing, Kimblee?
Now then, you are the only ones
who know the whereabouts
of the Philosopher's Stone, right?
Why, you...!
- What was that?
- What happened?
What's going on?
Come on out, Kimblee.
You're being released.
What is the meaning of this?
- Don't ask me any questions.
- Is this an order from above?
Shut up.
How is it that you kill five officers,
and don't get sentenced to death?
What kind of strings did you pull?
None at all. Maybe it's my natural virus.
Don't make me laugh, you mad bomber!
What are the higher-ups thinking,
letting a maniac like you go free?
Mr. Jailer, thank you for taking care
of me for this long while.
Don't ever come back here.
Just my way of saying thanks.
This isn't... Hold on a second!
Don't do this!
Get this off of me, Kimblee!
It's only a harmless toy. Please,
give it to your child, or something.
Well, farewell.
Now then...
Long time no see, Kimblee.
Congratulations on your release.
- It was an order from you guys?
- Yep. We're shorthanded, you see.
You mean, you have a job for me?
Do you remember Doctor Marcoh?
The researcher who created
the Philosopher's Stone?
I remember him well.
Marcoh has run away from us... maybe.
- Maybe?
- We're still not entirely sure.
One of the Chimeras that we had posted
as a watchdog is gone.
Marcoh is an alchemist
who excelled in living transmutations.
It may have taken his place.
And to complicate things,
there's a possibility that he's fled
with an Ishvalan named Scar.
What do you say, as the
Crimson Alchemist who was ordered
to carry out the extermination of Ishval?
Indeed. If he is an Ishvalan
that I should have bested,
then this is inexcusable.
When you find Scar,
you are free to kill him.
But bring Marcoh back to us.
That is the only reason
why you got me out?
Once you nab Marcoh, wipe a town
off the map, to serve as a warning.
- It's a great job, isn't it?
- You fight dirty, don't you?
It's been a long time
since I've been able to use this.
That might not be enough
to wipe out a whole town.
What's this?
Did you use more of the Ishvalans?
That was the men who were doing research
on the Stone under Doctor Marcoh.
You really do fight dirty.
Why did you get me out? I...
I still have some questions to ask you...
about the alchemist named Kimblee.
I don't understand parts of the research
notes that my brother left me.
Research notes?
Before my brother died, he said,
"This country's alchemy is strange."
He must have written about that
in his notes.
You are a shrewd alchemist.
You can make sense of it, right?
This country's alchemy... is strange?
Sir...
The girl has returned to us.
Mr. Scar, you're all right?
Do we have another colleague?
He's not our colleague.
His name is Marcoh.
He's the man who created
the Philosopher's Stone
and took part in the extermination.
The Philosopher's Stone? Immortality!
Mr. Marcoh, you know how
to create a Philosopher's Stone?
How is it done? Please tell me!
- No, it's...
- Stop!
Do not seek that!
I have only destroyed the surface
of your face.
- Stop his bleeding, would you?
- Right.
It will be easier for us
if your face is ruined,
- so people will not know who you are.
- Are you all right?
- We're leaving.
- Where to?
To the place where I hid
the research notes
that I inherited from my brother.
To the north.