- It's true.
- This does look just like her.
My little one is cute, isn't she?
- Definitely not her!
- I know!
For that matter,
we don't have time to be playing along
with such an insignificant joke!
Really...
- Where could she be?
East City! East City!
- New intel on Scar.
- Is he still on the lam?
He never gives up.
Oh, my, I'm so sorry.
Not at all. I'm sorry I wasn't watching
where I was going.
Such unusual clothing.
Are you from another country?
- I'm from Xing.
- Oh, my. Are you here sightseeing?
There isn't much to look at
here in East City.
No, I'm just here transferring trains.
I'm heading north from here.
The train bound for North City.
- Oh, no!
- Departing from Platform.
- Thank you, ma'am.
- All passengers, please hurry aboard.
Take care, okay?
What an unusual kitty-cat.
- Where did he go?
- I know I heard footsteps.
Over there!
He was together with a middle-aged man
who had black hair, right?
Yes, that was the report we got.
This was yesterday.
West, huh?
There were several people wounded
to various degrees here.
Scar must be getting desperate.
I have to say though,
he's being too conspicuous.
Well then, let's get to work.
Well, no matter. It's none of my business.
It looks like a funeral.
Yes, so it would seem.
Such an awful thing.
When you get to be my age,
all you do is wonder
when you're going to end up like that.
Whatever do you mean, ma'am?
You still look quite young to me.
General Grumman, sir?
We were to meet up in front
of General Hughes' grave, right?
For you to use your last-ditch measure,
I figured it had to be something serious.
Just to be safe, I put on this disguise.
Wow, I see why you're famous
for being eccentric, General Grumman.
I wasn't expecting such a disguise.
Eccentric?
I shall take that as a compliment.
So, what do you need?
Alkahestry...
We might be able to find out something
about it from the Central Library.
Yeah.
As long as we can't locate
that bean sprout girl,
we have no choice
but to look into it ourselves.
I hope we can find
even a small clue about it.
I see. The Central senior staff
have all gone dark, huh?
You've lost too much
for the information you gained.
With the men that you can trust
stripped away from you,
you won't get anywhere.
Yes, sir. I don't know what to say.
Even Raven, huh?
It wasn't too long ago that I came
to Central, and Raven asked me
if would I be interested in an utterly
immortal corps of soldiers.
An immortal corps?
I wonder if he meant Homunculi.
Immortality is nonsense.
I told him so, and turned him down.
And then, immediately afterward,
I was shunted off
to the Eastern Command Center.
You were demoted?
As a result, I've ended up stuck
having to clean up
all of the upsetting messes
in the Eastern Area.
Speaking of upsetting, do you remember
the insurrection in Liore?
The incident where the false priest
of Leto's schemes
were uncovered by the Fullmetal Alchemist.
Yes, I remember.
Liore fell into all-out chaos,
but at the beginning stages,
the Eastern forces acted quickly
and kept the uprising under control.
However, the Central forces came in,
and the Eastern forces were dismissed.
- Weren't they?
- Yes.
The peace in Liore quickly disintegrated
after the Central forces moved in.
What are those folks
in Central cooking up?
Mercy's sake!
Can't they keep things peaceful and quiet
until after I retire?
There you go again with the jokes.
General Grumman, someone like you
isn't the least bit satisfied
being the chief
of some provincial territory, are you?
Not when you are in command
of the Eastern forces,
hardy soldiers who are veterans of Ishval.
I figured you'd come crying to me
when you used the note
with my top-secret contact number on it,
but you've called me here
to get me stirred up?
My word, as a result of things in Central
getting interesting,
the embers of my ambition
which had almost gone out,
I have started to flare back up again.
If you get too fired up,
your makeup will run, ma'am.
Oh, good gracious!
Do you have any free time later, sir?
If you like, we could have some tea
somewhere.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I do appreciate the invitation.
It's no use.
Why is there such minimal description
about alkahestry?
We may as well just go over to Xing
and learn the real thing.
On the other hand,
crossing the desert with this automail...
I've found you, Edward Elric.
Major! What are you doing?
Keep quiet inside the library.
I understand you're after a Xingese girl
who has a black and white cat.
Yeah. But how do you know that?
Colonel Mustang told me.
I am running errands
for the colonel today.
Word is that the girl is headed north.
According to eyewitnesses,
she is headed from East City to the north.
North, huh? All right!
Knowing that much, I can act!
Major, thank you.
Thank the colonel for me too.
Hold on, hold on. Don't be hasty.
Take this with you.
What is it?
A letter of introduction.
It may not be of much use though.
First, see her.
See her? See who?
Farther north
from the Northern Command Center
is a general, nicknamed
the Northern Wall of Briggs,
who defends our border with Drachma.
Hurry.
Scar, you can't get away!
Where did they go?
Report this to the command center!
That train is bound for West City!
Damn!
I can't find very many details
about alkahestry at all.
That May girl's long-range alchemy
was pretty incredible.
I sure wish we could use it.
I should have asked her more about it
when we were at Dr. Knocs' place.
Ling said it was a specialized technique
for the medical field.
Are you the Fullmetal Alchemist's brother,
the one in the large suit of armor?
- Yes, I am.
- Amazing!
Thanks. I mean, you should keep quiet
inside the library.
Oh, sorry.
- What is that you're studying?
- Alkahestry.
- Alkahestry?
- It's alchemy from the country of Xing.
Oh, yeah? The country of Xing?
But you Elric brothers
are masterful enough
to earn your state certifications
here in Amestris,
which is a major alchemic power, right?
So why are you looking into
the minor alchemy of a foreign country?
I can't tell him that I'm looking
for a way to get my body back,
or to fight back against the Homunculi.
Well...
They say that alkahestry is tailored
toward medical uses.
I'm researching whether or not
there are any new possibilities
of using it as a technique
to save people's lives.
Wow! Just what I'd expect
of the Elric brothers I've heard about.
Al! Alphonse!
Get everything ready! We're leaving!
Brother, keep it down inside the library.
And where are we going?
I'll fill you in while we walk.
In any case, we're taking off.
Get our stuff at the hotel together.
Who's the kid?
If you're Mr. Armor's brother,
does that mean you're Edward?
- The State Alchemist?
- Yeah.
Wow! You're a teeny alchemist,
just like everyone says!
Hey, you say that one more time,
and you'll go flying
out as far as Neptune!
Wow, you snap when people call you small,
just like everyone says.
- Step away from Master Selim.
- No, don't shoot him.
- By any chance, are you Selim Bradley?
- The F端hrer's son?
Yes, I am.
How did this happen?
We're supposed to be heading north.
- Don't look at me.
- Sorry about that.
He has been in awe of you
for so long, Edward.
- In awe of me?
- Selim, do you like alchemy?
Yes, my dream is to learn alchemy
and become a State Alchemist,
just like Edward.
- In awe of me?
- And then, I want to help out my father.
Do you like your father?
F端hrer King Bradley?
Of course I do.
- What kind of man is your father?
- He's a fine man.
He endures a demanding job
that would make a normal man shriek,
and thinks and acts only
for the nation's people every day.
You don't say.
The F端hrer does seem to be busy every day.
That's true.
He still means to stay on active duty
and work himself ragged.
As old as he is,
he ought to take it easier.
He's been devoted to work since way back.
He could handle his job,
but he never understood women.
He was such a rude man,
I even slapped him.
It must have been fate,
because we started seeing each other
and our first date was something else.
Oh, dear, listen to me going on about him.
- Father!
- My...
- Welcome home!
- Sure, Selim.
What is the matter?
I had some free time for a change,
so I came to see your faces.
And then, I heard that
the Fullmetal Alchemist was here.
- Hi there.
- Long time no see.
We just saw each other at the Central
Command Center, didn't we?
- Oh, so you ran into them at the library.
- Yes.
You're thinking
that he doesn't look like me?
- No, it's not that.
- I have no blood relation to him.
We were unable to have any children.
So, we're raising a relative's son
as a foster child.
He really has grown up
to be a kind, devoted son.
Cut it out, Father.
- You're embarrassing me.
- It's the truth though.
Something on your mind?
No, it's just that we never see you,
except at the command center
so, I mean, you know?
There's what you might call
an "image gap."
I see.
I, too, have a family. Me too.
It may be a little different
from your family though.
Father, are you leaving already?
Yes, it's about time I got back
to my duties.
Please, make yourself at home,
State Alchemist.
Let's go.
- Please, come visit again sometime, okay?
- Yeah, see you later.
Neither the wife nor the son know
that the F端hrer is a Homunculus.
Anyway, north! We're going north!
We'll catch that bean sprout girl,
and get the secrets of alkahestry
out of her.
We'll arrive there in the morning.
Get some sleep.
I see. So he managed
to succeed in escaping?
- This is a map of the West Area, right?
- Yes.
He was last spotted... here.
West City is here.
Scar and Marcoh disappeared
somewhere in between.
You slow down considerably
around curves, right?
Is it possible that they jumped off?
There's no reason why they couldn't have,
but it's very dangerous.
You don't say.
Now then, after they jumped off,
which way would they have fled?
North, or south?
Won't this be the first time
we've ever gone up north?
Yeah, it is.
I wonder if we'll see any snow.
Snow, huh? It never really piled up
when we were in Resembool, did it?