Ed and Al, who are searching for May,
the young girl from the country of Xing,
in order to find out
the secrets of Alkahestry,
obtain information
that she is headed north.
Meanwhile,
Scar has left Central and was headed west
with the Crimson Alchemist, Kimblee,
in pursuit.
However, under the cover of night,
Scar has suddenly gone into hiding.
If he was going to jump from the train,
he'd do it around here,
where there are curves.
The engine would have to slow down
after all.
The question is,
which way did he head from here?
- Any word on any Scar sightings?
- Nothing definite.
That is odd. All the way here,
he made a big show of his movements.
I have something to report, sir.
There was a small boat stolen
from along a river
about 200 meters to the south.
Was it Scar?
There aren't any eyewitness reports
as of yet.
- Look into it!
- Yes, sir!
I have something to report!
An old man who lives nearby spotted
a suspicious pair of men headed west.
Now he's headed west?
Take some soldiers at once,
and detain those two!
Yes, sir!
- Is something the matter?
- No, it's just...
there is a mountain road
heading north on this map.
What is this, here?
It was a logging road
through to the North Area,
but there were too many rockslides,
and it is currently closed to any traffic.
Is there something about it?
There are several other places further on
where giant rockslides have closed
the road, like they have here.
The water's flow has been altered here.
So it would seem.
Does that mean something?
To an alchemist skilled in destruction,
clearing an obstacle of this size
is a simple matter.
- Sir?
- As is destroying the mountain face...
to once again block the road
with a rockslide.
Transmutation marks?
Send the soldiers north.
Snow!
Brother!
Brother, you're so unbalanced.
Shut up!
I just slipped a little, that's all!
Still, all this snow is amazing, huh?
Yeah, you barely ever see this
in Resembool.
Hey, yeah, Al!
Do you remember that heavy snow
we had in Resembool when we were little?
Heavy snow...
I remember, I remember!
We all had a snowball fight!
- And we made a snowman too.
- That's right!
When I was little,
I had no idea we would ever come
this far north.
Yeah, and here we are.
So, what do we do?
There's still some time
before the train to Briggs leaves.
Go have something tasty to eat.
I'm not really that hungry.
Let's go have a look anyhow.
- You're going to fall again if you run!
- Oh, shut up!
- Attention, North Area units...
- The express still hadn't arrived.
- Descriptions of Scar are in document...
- ...as of three hours ago.
Any new information?
We are searching as fast as we can,
but unfortunately, no.
A man fitting Scar's description was seen
at the switchyard one station ahead of us!
You're sure about this?
Positive, he was spotted
getting aboard a military train
that is bound for Briggs.
Was there anyone with him?
A middle-aged man with black hair,
just like in the report.
I will have the train stopped at once.
That will not be necessary.
We can't have him jumping
from the train again after all.
Now then...
From here on, the job is mine.
See that you people stay out of my way.
Get some sleep now.
You won't be able to sleep
in the northern cold, even if you want to.
I'm jumping over, please match our speed.
Roger!
Dr. Marcoh...
I have come to get you.
You cannot run any longer.
Are you alone? Where is Scar?
You don't know when to give up.
I told you, you cannot get away, Dr. Mar--
Who are you?
You're the Ishvalan
I've heard so much about, aren't you?
How am I supposed to stick around
with those monsters?
If I'm going to jump, now's the time!
I can't!
Solf J. Kimblee, the Crimson Alchemist.
Do you remember me?
Yes, I remember you well.
You were in the Kanda District of Ishval.
Was that your family
who was around you back then?
There was a fellow there
who looked just like you, wearing glasses.
He was losing a great deal of blood
from his left side,
and appeared to be in terrible agony.
This is bad.
I've just barely gotten out of jail,
and my movements are still rusty,
while he has been fighting continuously,
even after the end of the civil war.
Physically, I am at a disadvantage.
But since all he can do is destroy...
His left side, right?
I won't give you any time to pray to God.
It's a shame...
That's twice now that I've failed
to stop the same Ishvalan...
It is deeply humiliating
that I would have to run away.
We will settle this next time,
for sure, Ishvalan!
Kimblee!
Damn it, I can't see!
What was that sound a moment ago?
The rear cars are gone!
This is bad!
The military gave us orders not to stop!
It's no use! If we derail,
the question of liability will be on us!
Hey!
What happened to you? Hey!
- Who said you could stop?
- What?
Keep us going! Head north!
Yes, good. Death is closing in.
Those who forge death
are also pursued by death.
They are always side-by-side with death.
It is the work that puts the soul at risk
that possesses beauty.
What worth there is in performing it
on my battlefield!
I wonder
if Mr. Scar and Mr. Yoki are all right.
Judging by the fact
that no one has come after us,
they seem to have been successful
in drawing the MPs' attention.
I do hope they are safe.
- Mr. Marcoh?
- It's nothing.
The northern wind is bracing
against my still-healing skin.
I'm sorry.
I wish I could have healed your face,
so that it looked better.
No, this is the face that fits me.
I am content with it.
May, look at that.
The Briggs mountain range.
These mountains mark the border
with the large country of Drachma
to the north.
We should be getting close
to the location that Scar showed us.
Let's see.
It's right over there.
What? They're not at the hotel?
- Yes, they left yesterday.
- Do you know where they went?
As I recall,
they said they were going north.
They did? Thank you very much.
That dummy!
What's the matter?
Are the brothers doing well?
They said they were heading north
from there.
Oh, my, well then...
...they're gonna die.
Brother, are you catching a cold?
Oh, I'm so cold. That's Briggs for you.
We're here, boys!
If you follow this mountain road...
- ...you'll get to Fort Briggs.
- Thanks.
Oh, and you there...
- Yes, you. Is that automail?
- No.
Oh, okay. In that case, you're all right.
- What was that about?
- Beats me.
Beyond that fence is military property,
so if you leave the road,
you'll end up dead.
Huh?
- Ready to go?
- Yes.
They say that the weather
in the mountains is highly variable,
but I didn't think
it changed this quickly.
What do we do, Brother?
We've completely lost sight of the road.
Relax. Our teacher, Izumi,
said that she got tossed out here
at Briggs Mountain for a whole month
during her training period,
and she made it out alive.
No way!
There's no way she could have
survived in this for a whole month!
But she said she killed some bears!
When the bears around Briggs rear up,
they're taller than six feet!
There's no way she could have killed them!
That's no bear!
Al!
Hey, wait!
That's a military uniform, isn't it?
You have automail too? The ordinary sort.
What about you?
You've got that tacky-looking thing on!
You're a fool not to see
the beauty of this mechanism!
The Combat Automail M1913-A Crocodile!
Surrender peacefully,
unless you want to get torn to pieces,
you miserable Drachman spy!
Spy? What are you talking about? I'm--
Why, you...
Don't you hear me, you big lunk?
Why does that hurt like that?
I can't move my automail very well!
Gotcha!
Brother!
You bastard!
- Listen to what I'm telling you!
- You're still resisting me?
You're kidding!
Wait! Wait! Wait!
Your good-for-nothing automail
is all mine!
Why, you... It's your arm that's mine!
Did you do something?
Whoa, hold on! Hold on! Hold on!
Why didn't my alchemy work?
Isn't this iron?
Brother!
Thank you, Al!
- Are you okay?
- Why, you...
I won't get to die in the snow,
because Winry is gonna kill me first!
Not bad, kid.
You did pretty well with normal automail.
But it ends now.
The Briggs Mountain Guards?
Hey, are we getting guns stuck
in our faces again?
- Brother!
- A wall?
What's going on here, Captain Buccaneer?
I am terribly sorry for the disturbance,
General Armstrong, sir!
Armstrong?
That's who Major Armstrong said
he would introduce to us?
Olivier Mira Armstrong,
Major Armstrong's older sister?
But...
- She doesn't look like him.
- She's not huge.
Who are you?
The Fullmetal Alchemist, Edward Elric!
I am here by referral
of Major Armstrong of Central
to meet the general in charge here!
But first, I would like you
to call off your guards!
Frisk them.
- Hey! I'm not a shady character!
- I don't know that.
Anyone can claim to be someone famous.
- Whoa, he's hollow!
- Why, you...
What's this?
General!
That's a letter of introduction
from Major Alex Louis Armstrong!
If you read that,
you will see that you can trust us!
This is from Alex all right.
What? You're not going to read it?
Letters of introduction
are meaningless to me.
I don't care
about anyone else's appraisals.
I judge people with my own eyes.
Awesome!
It's huge! What is this?
Enter, Fullmetal Alchemist.
Awesome! It's so tall! And huge!
Start walking already, dirtbags,
before I yank out that antenna
on top of your head!
I'll warn you upfront,
I'm not going to treat you like children.
This is the mountain fortress, Briggs.
It's a world of survival of the fittest.
There it is!
So this is Scar's brother's
research notebook.
A fusion of Xingese alkahestry
and Amestrisian alchemy, right?
Could the secret of gaining immortality
be written in here?
I sure hope it is.
Will this book bring hope,
or will it bring despair?
Well, let me start deciphering it.