Donatus,
Poswell, Reinmeir, Gianni,
Collins, Toni, Willard,
Ripley, Mechthild, Mayo...
Forgive me,
but I had to use you years ago.
13 YEARS AGO
You ought to caress them.
They are your sons, right?
I don't want the monster to spread.
Oh, brother.
If you could catch it by doing that,
I would have caught it a long time ago.
Ever since I got this body,
I've seen a lot of death.
But if I thought about it as one part
of the flow of the larger world,
it helped to alleviate
the sorrow somewhat.
Every time I would encounter
something beautiful, or wondrous,
it was okay that I accepted
this body, and went on living.
I thought that for a long time.
That is, until I met you, Trisha,
and had children.
I don't get any older,
but my children age
and grow before my eyes.
Suddenly, it terrifies me.
I realize that I really am a monster.
Dear! Dear, come here a minute!
What is it?
Hello, sir.
A photographer?
Yes. Fix yourself up.
We haven't yet taken a picture
with all of us, right?
This is awfully sudden.
Here, you hold Ed.
Okay.
We're ready. If you please.
Oh, boy.
Okay, look over here. Don't move, okay?
Someday, I'll be a wrinkly old
monster of a woman myself.
Even so, no matter what form I take,
I want to be able to take a photograph
of all of us together, smiling.
So let's always stay a family.
Don't go distancing yourself,
or keep aloof from the rest of us.
And don't put yourself down
with words like "monster."
Okay, I'm taking it.
Smile, dear.
I had planned to accept this body,
and live on and on,
but it's different now.
I want to be with Trisha
and the children...
to grow old and die with them.
That bastard.
That ought to do it.
What are you doing?
Fixing the swing.
That's so unlike you.
I've never been able
to do anything for them,
but I can do this much.
Trisha, I'm going away.
Wait here for me.
Okay.
Don't tell the children about my body.
Okay. Are you sure
you don't want to wake them?
If I see their faces...
You dummy, it's okay to cry.
Goodness,
what are you doing up so early?
Al said he had to go potty.
Oh. You took care of Al, didn't you?
Thanks, Ed.
A little while longer.
Well?
It's no use. It just won't go through.
Now what? We can't contact those above us.
What do we do? Keep going?
There has to be an exit
somewhere to dump out the rubble.
Let's go on a little farther.
Smith, you go back and report.
Yes, sir.
What's the matter?
Fan out!
Would you be interested in a legion
of completely immortal soldiers?
He took the bait.
Never dying, never decaying...
You're interested too, aren't you?
I wanna cut him to ribbons!
It's such an extraordinary question,
I'm not sure how to answer.
Are you interested, or not?
There are only two answers.
It is interesting.
When this day
when it's not just a dream comes,
can you tell me if not just me, but my men
as well, will share in this boon?
When the day comes, I can.
Does that mean there are
no guarantees until then?
If I buy into this,
I will be forced to help facilitate
evil doings here at Briggs.
If I do not accept, I will be
swapped out for some other pawn,
and probably demoted.
So then, which is the best answer?
Excuse me.
What is it?
Begging your pardon, but the
underground tunnel advance team is--
What's this about the underground tunnel?
- It's all right, speak.
- Yes, sir.
There is something the matter
with the advance team.
All right, I'll be right there.
I'm coming too.
All right, let's move.
Just a minute!
We'll need this, right?
What's going on, Buccaneer?
Sir, I am moving the Elric brothers
from the east cells to the west cells.
Who is this gentleman?
Mr. Solf J. Kimblee.
He is General Raven's guest.
Kimblee... The Crimson Alchemist.
By the Elric brothers,
you mean the Fullmetal Alchemist.
I see, just as your second name suggests.
Oh, this one?
It's been a long time since
we've had this exchange.
Pleased to meet you,
Mr. Fullmetal Alchemist.
Hello.
- General.
- What happened?
We've lost contact with the party
that is searching the tunnel.
Immediately afterward, Smith's horse,
and what we presume is his arm,
are all that returned.
Just his arm?
Where's the rest of his body?
Missing, sir.
The horse he was riding is too wound up
to be of any use.
Henschel, organize a rescue party.
That won't do, General Armstrong.
This hole is too dangerous.
Where have you put that immortal
biological weapon you mentioned?
Put him back,
and close up the entrance, General.
- There are still people--
- I am speaking to the general.
That is the law up here, right?
Obey the strong, obey the power,
General Armstrong.
I am Raven, from Central.
I have heard about you
from His Excellency, the F端hrer.
Hello.
It appears that you have
kept your mouth shut.
That was the agreement.
You seem discontent.
It would be strange
for someone not to be discontent
when hostages were
taken on their account, right?
When can we be let out of this cell?
The agreement was that as long
as we don't interfere with you,
you would let us continue our journey.
I will let you out of here soon,
don't worry.
Is that underground tunnel
a part of your plan, as well?
If everyone else finds out...
You needn't worry about that, either.
General Armstrong said she was
going to put the Homunculus
back in the tunnel
and then close up the hole.
The general has come over to our side.
General! Aren't we going to search
for the missing advance team?
Quiet, Henschel.
They might still be alive,
and in need of help!
I said be quiet!
Be quiet and obey.
Obey the power, huh?
Even the impregnable "Northern Wall
of Briggs" yields to authority, does she?
Well, that is the smartest approach.
That's what I've heard so much about?
Good morning, Sloth. Did you sleep well?
Who are you? I'm still sleepy.
Hey, now, you still have work to do.
Pride told you so, didn't he?
Pride?
Such a bother but I have no choice.
What a bother. Why was it a bother again?
It's too much of a bother to remember.
Not to worry. He is a Chimera,
doing work for the Central forces.
He is working
to make this country even greater.
Although, it is still
a top-secret operation.
Now, close up this hole quickly,
men of Briggs.
You are comrades
that now share in this secret.
All the important parts
are written in ancient Ishvalan,
so that it can't be read.
Do we give up?
If Scar were here,
he might be able to read it.
After all, as an Ishvalan monk,
there's a chance
that he knows the ancient text.
Could something have happened
to Mr. Scar?
We've found her.
The girl with the black-and-white cat.
All right, let's go.
Mr. Scar! Mr. Yoki!
Did you find the research notes?
Yes, we sure did!
We're relocating.
The Briggs soldiers
know of this place. Move.
SEVERAL DAYS LATER
This will do.
We, the chosen ones,
will receive near-godly bodies,
and will rule the world.
Smith, wasn't it?
There was nothing we could do
about the advance team.
Are you saying that those who are lesser
will be sacrificed for the chosen ones?
Yes, it's survival of the fittest.
The weak will become
the foundation for the country,
while the strong will flourish above them.
Is that what happened in Ishval too?
Yes. They were part of the plan.
Weaker people have been destined
to perish from the start.
Is that right? By all means, allow me.
Yes.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
You sure are making frequent
telephone calls, aren't you?
Where is General Raven?
I must speak with him.
Gravely injured and near death,
you showed up here,
the same day, fully recovered.
What sort of magic did you use?
That is none of your business.
How did you, after being imprisoned
for killing those officers,
ever get released?
I told you, didn't I?
That is none of your business.
When was this plan set in motion?
I've heard that it was in place
when the country was created.
And now, in my lifetime,
it is to be completed.
I am grateful for your assistance,
General Armstrong.
I shall speak with those above us
about preparing a seat for you.
- That's all right.
- What?
Was Smith's arm the left one?
The right one?
What are you...?
Growing old truly is terrifying, isn't it,
General Raven?
Long ago, you were probably
a young, high-minded soldier,
who had an earnest love for his country.
You can't do this!
You were to be a chosen one!
You were to have a seat!
I don't need any new seat.
You're going to vacate the chair
that your moldy old ass
is occupying, right now!
Meddlesome old goat!
Immortality...
It was right before our eyes...
You're going to literally
become a foundation for the state here,
in this ground, General Raven.
I was going to be immortal...
Buccaneer, contact Miles.
Yes, sir.
The rest of you, carry on!
General...
Make that concrete nice and level.
Yes, sir.
You're riding me pretty hard, aren't you?
Is it because I was a State Alchemist
who served in the Ishvalan War?
What will it take for you to be content?
Do you want to know
how your countrymen died?
Shut up, Kimblee.
Do you want me to tell you?
I said shut up!
Major, may I have a moment?
I have a message from General Armstrong.
She says, "Operation complete.
No need to buy any more time."
Acknowledged.
Well, well, at last, I don't have
to talk to him anymore.
It may have been an act,
but it was still tough.
Kimblee...
Nobody can find General Raven.
Do you know where he might have gone?
He's missing?
What can you do?
This place isn't safe enough
for an outsider to be walking
around on their own.
If anything happens to the general--
I would welcome it.
If anything happens to General Raven,
I am free to act however I see fit.
I have permission
from the F端hrer to do so.
Could I ask you for a car to drive me
to the base of the mountain, Major Miles?
Do you understand me?
Right now, my actions are tantamount
to the F端hrer's actions.
Please wait, sir!
We have to search for Smith and the others
before we completely cover up the hole!
Fullmetal figured this might happen,
and made us this secret passage.
She killed him?
General Raven?
Okay, now you've been told.
Hey! When are you going
to let us out of here?
Who knows? Take it up with the general.
Damn it!
It won't do any good
to get worked up, Brother.
You should let yourself rest right now.
I can't just sit still,
while all of this is going on!
Hello there. Might I have a word
with the Fullmetal Alchemist?
Oh, dear, do you not care
to see me for me for some reason?
I have brought a visitor with me
for you two today.
Visitor?
- You idiot!
- Why did you come here?
Why? You have to switch your automail
for the north country, right?
And for that matter,
what are you doing in a cell?
Nobody asked you to come here!
What's with you? I was worried about you.
A military person contacted me.
The military?
Now, now, you two, His Excellency
the F端hrer was quite concerned.
Kimblee?
Yes.
I heard from a friend
who works as a nurse
at the foot of Briggs.
She said he was admitted
with serious injuries,
but after General Raven came to visit him,
he recovered right away,
and was discharged.
Raven and Kimblee...
That's all the information
I have for today.
Thanks. Let me know
if you hear anything else.
Come on by the parlor again sometime.
Looks like you got
the old heave-ho, young man.
Why don't you buy some flowers,
and go after her?
I'm better off without her. Thanks anyway.
There are some women who leave you,
and some who find you.
I have a message for you
from Olivier Mira Armstrong,
Colonel Roy Mustang.
How about I buy all of your flowers?