Who are those guys?
A few of Kimblee's men,
who were dispatched from Central,
under the pretext of being
Miss Rockbell's escorts.
What are you planning
to do here at Briggs, Kimblee?
If you were going up north,
you should have told me!
I couldn't help it. We were in a hurry.
You guys are always in a hurry!
And what were you doing in that cell?
It is a simple misunderstanding.
They will be out soon.
I will handle the arrangements afterward.
Thank you, Mr. Kimblee.
Please look after these two for me, okay?
Yes.
Hey, don't go trusting Kimblee too much.
Why not? He's a nice man, isn't he?
Miss Rockbell,
your parents were doctors
who lost their lives in Ishval, right?
- Yes.
- I knew it.
It was my squad that recovered
their bodies.
We were one step short
of reaching them in time,
and when we arrived,
it was already too late.
I see.
They followed the physician's code,
and stuck to their convictions,
right up to the end.
I sincerely respect them.
I would like to have met them
when they were still alive.
They were holding a photograph
of themselves
with their dear daughter,
ever so preciously.
You must have been a great
emotional support to them.
It is an honor to meet you,
Winry Rockbell.
Do you know what he did in Ishval--?
All I know about Ishval
is what the lieutenant said to me.
What the lieutenant said...
You love Winry, don't you?
Calm down! Think about something else!
Think about something else!
Hydrogen, helium, lithium,
beryllium, carbon...
- Nitrogen, oxygen, fluorine...
- Ed...?
Aluminum, silicon, phosphorus,
chromium, manganese, iron,
cobalt, nickel, copper, zinc...
Why did I have to go
and fall for a weirdo like him?
Huh? Did you say something?
Nothing at all!
Why, you! I told you,
warn me before you connect the nerves!
Right, right. Now for the leg.
Oh, it's so light!
Is the strength of this still okay?
Overall, the strength
is lower than before,
but the key areas are reinforced.
What are you doing out of your cell?
Who knows? Maybe it's the power
of being a State Alchemist.
You're finally switching
to a cold-weather climate model?
What about you?
This is the one
that I'm most comfortable with!
Wow! The M-light combat automail!
Huh? The claw tips have been reinforced?
Are those diamond stock, by any chance?
Yeah! It's a refitted M, the Mad Bear G!
Hey, Ed, you want something like this too?
No, thanks!
Hey, who is this cute little girl?
My mechanic.
KILL!!!
What did you do that for?
This is turning my stomach.
That was brutal.
I've never seen a northern model!
It's so thrilling.
Oh, yeah?
- In that case, want to see my workplace?
- I do, I do! I want to see it!
- Hey!
- What?
Nothing.
Just don't get too carried away,
and wander around this place too much.
There's all sorts of dangerous stuff
inside the fort.
All right.
If you'd be so kind!
This one is kind of rare.
Wow, incredible!
That's a Crocodile, right?
As enthusiastic about her work
as her parents, I see.
I'm impressed you knew that!
The earmark of this is its design
with respect to the coefficient
of expansion of its material...
Now then, your automail swap
has been completed without incident.
Let's get down to business,
Fullmetal Alchemist.
Excuse me. Why haven't you let me out?
Mr. Kimblee's orders.
We were told to only let
the Fullmetal Alchemist out for now.
- You just stay here and behave yourself.
- Kimblee's men...
He's covering all the bases,
not letting us work together.
Not to mention bringing Winry along,
to emphasize that "she is in our hands."
That just shows how wary they are of us.
I can't rush into anything.
I have to wait for my chance.
The provisions the advance team
took with them were for three days.
A week has already gone by.
That's cutting it pretty close.
I'm concerned
about their mental state too.
If you spend a week
in the dark like this...
Let's have faith in their mental strength.
General, we can't even guess
what might happen in this hole.
If we're not back in hours,
please seal up the hole.
All right, I will.
I'm telling you all, right now,
that the incident with General Raven
is something I did all on my own.
None of you saw anything,
nor heard anything.
If any of this ever comes out,
put all of the blame on me.
Yes, ma'am.
Let's go.
I see. Things appear to be getting
pretty unruly up north too.
Yeah. From here on,
you need to take the initiative.
The Briggs crowd is skilled at defense.
The "first-strike victory" strategy works
when you excel
at both offense and defense.
Thus, it would be best if they teamed
with the Eastern forces,
which are skilled at attacking,
or so Madam Olivier believes.
It's an honor to be chosen
as her tag team partner.
No, it's the strength of the Eastern
forces that Madam Olivier wants.
She said you could just
as well get lost, Mustang.
Oh, is that so?
If I might ask,
what would you do
if I sold this information
to the Führer, to save my own neck?
She said, "Not possible.
Mustang is not that kind of man."
That will be 35,000 cens.
I'm honored.
Ma'am, who are you?
Just an old florist woman,
who has served the Armstrong
family for generations.
Hughes,
the people who understand and support us
are ultimately our old war buddies,
whom we've fought alongside, aren't they?
Now then...
- What's with him?
- What a weirdo.
- What do I do with these flowers?
- Oh, no, he's looking at us!
This is awful.
It looks like Smith's arm.
Even this metal was cut through cleanly.
Watch yourselves.
The enemy might be out there.
There's someone there!
You're all right.
It's me. Do you recognize me?
Lieutenant Henschel?
Thank goodness you're alive.
Is it just you? Any others?
The others...
The others were all torn to pieces!
We have to...
We have to get out of here, quick!
- It's coming!
- It?
No lights! The shadow...
The shadow is coming!
Take it easy! Hey!
The light...
Hey, snap out of it!
The shadow is coming!
- Can you stand?
- Let's go.
Carry them as best you can.
I apologize for coming so late.
I came to deliver these urgent
documents to His Excellency.
Oh, dear, I'm sorry.
He is not home at the moment.
I would like for him
to look these over by tomorrow.
By tomorrow, you say?
All right. I will take them from you.
Well then, if you'd be so k--
Selim, are you still up?
Yes. I heard someone at the door,
and thought that maybe
Father had come home.
This is Lieutenant Hawkeye.
Good evening, Miss Hawkeye.
Pleased to meet you.
Are you still working this late?
Yes. I came to deliver some
documents to His Excellency.
I'm terribly sorry to have awakened you.
Come, Master Selim.
You must retire,
or you will oversleep tomorrow.
Okay.
Such a sharp son you have.
Isn't he? I'm so proud of our son.
If he were our biological son,
you might call me a doting mother,
but since he is adopted,
I can be unreserved in my pride.
Though, since he's the boy
of a distant relative on the Bradley side,
perhaps his good traits come
from my husband's lineage.
He's not one
of your distant relatives?
No.
According to what the colonel said,
King Bradley was raised as a test
subject from the time he was a baby,
and has no family.
He doesn't have a single relative.
Besides which, there was
that sensation a moment ago.
- That boy is...
- You've figured it out?
I don't know what I'm going to do
with my stepmother.
She loves to talk.
Earlier, just for a moment,
I sensed an odd bloodlust.
I've felt it before, somewhere...
However, now I remember it clearly.
It's the same sensation
as when the Homunculus, Gluttony,
surprised me from behind.
Selim Bradley...
Just who exactly are you?
You've got a lot of guts,
asking my true identity,
under these circumstances,
Lieutenant Hawkeye.
You also show keen judgment
in not drawing your gun.
You would be unable to beat me.
Are you a Homunculus, like Gluttony?
No, I sense a pressure coming from you
that Gluttony couldn't hold a candle to.
It offends me that you would even
consider us to be on the same level.
My name is Pride, the First Homunculus.
The First Homunculus,
that's what you called yourself, right?
What does that mean?
Just what I said.
You tried to extract
even a little information, didn't you?
You really are gutsy, aren't you?
Are you sure you won't become one of us?
One of you?
You just want more pawns, right?
I see. That is too bad. Well, then...
I'd rather you didn't make
such empty threats.
There is no purpose
in killing your hostage, right?
How well you understand things.
However, Lieutenant Hawkeye,
I will always be watching you,
from your shadow.
Business, you say?
Yes, as a State Alchemist.
There are three directives
from the Führer.
Number one:
To search for Scar. Just find him.
Disposing of him is my job.
Number two:
Likewise, search for Dr. Marcoh,
who has potentially fled with Scar.
Dr. Marcoh is with Scar?
Again, after you find them,
the rest will be my task.
And number three:
To carve out a crest of blood here
at Briggs.
Carve out a crest of blood?
Like what happened in Ishval.
Kill people, and etch the land
with hatred and sorrow.
There's no way I could...
You became a dog of the military
without the resolve to kill others?
No, the resolve not to kill others.
The resolve not to kill others.
There'd be veracity
if you adhere to that, as well.
Are you working with them,
aware of what they're trying to do?
- They're going to--
- I want to see how the world changes.
Resolve and resolve, will and will.
Life and life.
Humans and Homunculi.
Which one will win?
What will the world choose?
If humans perish under the Homunculi,
who call themselves "evolved humans,"
that would be a historic moment.
I just want to see it through.
How can you, a human,
take sides with the Homunculi?
Because they let me use my alchemy
without any reservation.
You're off your rocker.
I know that I'm a heretic.
However, if someone like me survives,
it means that the world
will have chosen me.
I stake my survival, indeed,
my very existence, on this battle.
There is no life worth living
as much as this one.
I don't get it.
Oh, that's a shame.
I thought that all alchemists
were self-centered.
Well then, I shall speak to the part
that is at your self-center.
You want this so badly, you can taste it.
If you accept this job,
I will give it to you.
A Philosopher's Stone!
Let me talk to Al and Winry.
Miss Winry too?
I haven't told her anything.
Regardless of the job,
I don't want to betray her by lying.
Very well.
I will accompany you,
to make sure you do not tell her too much.
Winry, you are in a hostage
situation right now.
How so?
What is he talking about? Is this a joke?
Listen to me.
I am being ordered from higher up
to go to work as a human weapon.
As such, I may have to assist
in a mass murder.
You have to refuse!
That's why I'm...
Oh, no. I'm serving to shackle you.
I won't cry!
I'm sorry.
I'm upset at myself
for being so happy-go-lucky.
How did this...?
All you guys wanted to do
was get your original bodies back.
About that, if I help with the operation,
I can get a Philosopher's Stone.
A Stone? But...
Kimblee has it.
Not that!
The ingredients for a Stone are--
I know!
- You do whatever you want to.
- Yeah.
That settles it. I'll take the job.
Let me search for Scar first.
Why is that?
Scar killed Winry's parents.
I want to avenge them.
I see. Very well.
Also, I'm taking Al with me.
Him being the way he is,
Scar's bodily destruction
won't work on him.
Oh, that is handy.
Al, are you sure?
A Philosopher's Stone is made
by sacrificing many lives.
It's all right.
Brother doesn't intend to use it.
Right now,
we're investigating the possibility
of using Xingese alkahestry
to get our bodies back.
There's a girl who uses alkahestry
that appears to be working with Scar.
Then, he's going to act like
he's going after Scar
to get to this girl?
- Probably.
- I see.
In that case, I have to come up
with a better-sounding excuse too.
We'll head to the place
Scar was last spotted first.
Very good.
Hey, there! Let me squeeze in!
Al! Move over a little more that way!
What are you doing here?
Miss Winry, please wait at the fort.
- We aren't here for the fun of it.
- I know!
But I just switched his automail, right?
We don't want him
to have any malfunctions,
and if I don't come along
to perform maintenance,
it would tarnish the Rockbell name
if anything were to happen.
You're as earnest about your work
as ever, huh? Workaholic!
You bet I am! We've been a highly-trusted
operation since my great-granddad!
All right, very well.
- I know, you're a family of gearheads!
- I will permit you to accompany us.
"Gearheads" is fine!
There's no telling what will happen.
Yeah.
But I've had enough
of just waiting around.