I will always be watching you
from the shadows.
- Yes?
- This is your neighborhood florist.
What do you want, Colonel?
Sorry.
I got drunk,
and bought a great deal of flowers.
I'd be grateful if you'd take
some of them from me.
What's wrong?
- Has something happened?
- No, it's nothing.
Are you sure?
Yes, it's nothing, really.
I'll pass on the flowers.
I don't have any vases here.
Thank you for taking the time
to call me though. Bye.
How is his timing always so spot-on?
Someone matching Scar's description
was seen on a nearby mountain road.
He was probably headed here.
- An abandoned mine?
- That's right.
Nowadays, Baschool is a ghost town.
- It's a perfect place to hide.
- That will be problematic.
Which is why we're splitting up to search.
All squads, if you spot Scar,
contact us here at once.
Yes, sir!
- We will accompany the Elric brothers.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Could they be our watchers?
- Probably.
- Now then...
- How do we slip away from these guys?
- I just saw someone!
- What?
- This way! This way!
- Hey, hold on!
Hey, wait up!
- They're gone?
- Where did they go?
- They went inside that room, didn't they?
- Damn, they're scampering away from us!
Looks like we managed
to give them the slip.
But this place is...
Too big!
Where could Scar and that girl be?
Unless they come to us,
finding them will be quite--
Alphonse...!
Alphonse!
- Hey...
- It can't be...
Alphonse!
She really did come to us.
What are you doing here?
May! Thank goodness!
We really did manage to find you!
You mean, Al, you were pursuing me?
I wanted to see you again.
Oh, Al...
I wanted to see you,
and learn more about alkahestry.
What do I do? What do I do?
- Am I dreaming?
- Hey now, little girl!
Al is after me!
I've missed you!
You're not getting away again!
Now tell us about your alkahestry,
right now!
Both brothers are after me,
to steal my love!
No, Edward, you are not my type.
Stop playing dumb!
- Hey, Al!
- Sorry, sorry.
- Yow, I bumped my head.
- Alphonse, who is this woman?
How mean, Al! You've already got me!
Oh, she's just a friend from childhood.
And why am I making excuses,
like I was two-timing someone?
May, you shouldn't go so far
on ahead by yourself.
The Elric brothers?!
- Who are you?
- It's me! It's me, Marcoh!
- Eh? Dr. Marcoh?
- What happened to your face?
What about you?
What are you doing here?
- The Elric brothers!
- Who are you?
You can't tell me you've forgotten me!
Not me, Yoki,
the great colliery proprietor of Youswell!
We've forgotten. Or I should say,
we never knew you.
How mean! After what you did to me!
"YOUSWELL"
The coal mining town of Youswell.
I, Yoki, was both military governor
and operator of the coal mine.
Thanks to me,
the people of the town lived in happiness.
"Would you pay your back taxes already?"
"We can't pay since you've been
skimming from our salaries!"
That's when the greatest criminal
of all time,
the State Alchemist, Edward Elric,
suddenly appeared.
"A silver pocket watch?"
"A State Alchemist!!"
"Gold bars!!"
"I want you to sell me the title
to the mine in exchange for this."
However, it was an ingenious trap!
"What is this, alchemist?"
"All the gold bars you gave me
have turned into stones!"
They had set this up together
behind the scenes.
And so, having had the mine
defrauded from me,
I was treated cruelly
by the ungrateful townspeople,
and branded persona non grata
by the military.
Planning my comeback,
I expanded my ventures all over.
But they all failed.
My fallback investments...
...also all failed.
As a last resort,
I went to seek a goodwill loan
from a millionaire family.
If it weren't for them...
If it weren't for those Elric brothers...
That's when I swore an oath.
Yes, I would take my revenge
against the ones who had done this to me!
A vengeance far worse than death!
I won't be outdone
by a thieving hussy like you!
Who are you calling a thieving hussy?
I told you, there's nothing between us.
That's right. So don't get upset.
Can we hurry up and get to the alkahestry?
- You guys listen to me!
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
It must have been hard for you, pops.
- I know how you feel.
- Don't go brushing me off!
Miss Winry is gone?
- For crying out loud, what are you doing?
- Sorry about that.
I will look for her.
Two members from Charlie Squad,
- come with me.
- Yes, sir.
- Major Miles...
- I know. Scar, right?
The moment we spot him, we'll contact you.
No luck here either.
There's not much to speak of.
You're Scar, right?
Mr. Kimblee is waiting for you.
You're coming with us.
You've got pretty sharp noses.
But do you really think
just the two of you can take me?
Well, if we were just ordinary humans,
there'd be no way.
If we were just ordinary humans...
Chimeras, huh?
This should be good!
I've learned a lot since then.
Starting with how to create
a Philosopher's Stone,
as well as the history of this country,
and that there's something odd
about alchemy.
That's why, seeking the possibilities
of Xingese alkahestry,
- we came looking for this girl.
- Impressive.
Actually, there is someone
who realized this sooner.
These are the research notes
he left behind.
We suspect that there are clues
to sorting it out in these pages.
Then, once we're able to decipher
what's written in there...
Yes, perhaps.
However,
we will need Scar's help to do it.
Why do we need him?
What was that sound?
It came from where Scar is!
Is it the military?
Winry, Dr. Marcoh and you guys, hide here.
Al and I will go see what's going on.
Scar...
He's fast for his size.
We know that unless you touch our bodies,
you can't perform your destruction!
We'll just stick with attacking you
from a distance!
We've also studied how you have a habit
of destroying the ground underfoot
when the situation turns on you.
We're gonna beat you senseless
before turning you over to Mr. Kimblee.
We got here in the nick of time again.
- The Elric brothers?
- That voice...
Brother, these are the flunkies
- Kimblee brought with him from Central.
- What?
I see.
You just stay there quietly and watch.
We're just about to round up Scar--
- Strange monsters!
- What are you doing? We're on your side!
I don't know anything
about any inhuman allies!
I'm so scared! They're pretending to be
our allies, but they're out to eat us!
That tubby one behind him has
a huge mouth! He's gonna swallow me whole!
You little brats! Sit still!
This guy is even faster than Scar!
- Brother?
- What's so funny?
They're so light! They're so light!
My arm and leg almost feel like feathers!
How magnificent
this cold-weather automail is!
Why, you... Mess with me, will you?
Huh? My punches are also lighter?
You won't get out of my saliva
that easily!
This is drool? How vile!
- Take this!
- If this is saliva...
If you break it down,
it's mostly water, isn't it?
- It's so cold!
- Take this!
- What are you doing, Brother?
- Stop! My skin is gonna peel off!
"Wet Hands Freezing To Cold Metal
When Touched Attack!"
Stay out of this, Fullmetal Alchemist!
You're supposed to be on our side!
You shut up, pig! I don't know anyone
that looks anything like you!
Any way you look at it, you're the enemy!
If you're really on our side, prove it!
All right. I'm about to transform back,
so watch closely!
- I've been waiting for this!
- Zampano!
You're a fool to put away your weapon
in front of your enemy!
Damn it. Let go of me, you...!
Okay, okay. Lights out for a little while.
He's back in action.
Stay caught already, would you?
It's time to answer
for what you've done, Scar.
Anyone who gets in my way
will be eliminated.
For him to come straight at me
without even thinking...
Your steel right arm... is mine!
Aw, too bad! It's not steel anymore!
Come quietly!
Stop!
You dumbass! Why did you come here?
- Stay back.
- Major Miles.
What are these things?
Those folks in Central appear to be doing
some ungodly experiments.
- Tie them up to that column.
- Yes, sir!
Now then, Scar,
I hate to come down on one
of my own people,
but I can't allow you to go around
doing whatever you please.
Your own people?
Elric brothers, we'll take it from here.
- Winry!
- You idiot! Stay away from him!
It's all right. Let me go.
- How is it all right?
- Miss, stay away from him!
Please, let me talk to him.
I want to speak to him, face to face.
Why did you kill my mom and dad?
Anything I say would only be an excuse.
The fact remains,
I killed the Rockbell doctors.
What was that?
It came from the building
that reported in!
This is bad.
Our appointed hour has passed.
And you know our queen. I'll bet
she really has sealed the hole up.
There's nothing we can do about it.
We groped our way back
without the lanterns after all.
They were adamant that if the lights
were on, the monster would come.
- Welcome back.
- Thank goodness.
Get these two to the medical room, quick.
- Sorry.
- Nothing to apologize for.
I thought you were told
to block up this hole after hours.
Yes, sir, but...
Look, it hasn't been hours yet.
At least not on this watch.
General Armstrong gave it to me.
General!
- Was the advance party safe?
- Only two of them survived, sir.
I see.
- What are you doing out here?
- I'm looking at the mountains.
Winter here sure is nice.
Nothing but black and white.
- I like how everything's very clear-cut.
- Are you sure about that, sir?
If you look up, there's also blue.
Just like a person's heart.
Thanks for showing us a little mercy, sir.
Why, I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Something's coming.
Long time no see.
Forgive me for being so abrupt,
but there's something you need
to give an account for, isn't there?
- Keep back!
- Everyone, stay back!
Damn it!
- Fullmetal Alchemist?
- Kimblee!
Why, you! How come
you didn't keep an eye on Winry?
Mr. Kimblee, up on the roof!