Do you remember, Kimblee,
when we first met?
- The situation is reversed now!
- Don't you look down on me!
Kimblee! Why, you!
Why? Why is Winry here?
Here we've finally cornered Scar,
and now he's taken her hostage!
Stand aside.
You dumbass!
Stop, Crimson Alchemist!
Can't you see Winry up there?
I wish you would keep out of my way.
Just a moment, Scar!
Mr. Kimblee! It's too dangerous
to get close to the building!
Fall back!
- A snowstorm is moving in!
- Hurry!
- That was a convincing performance.
- It wasn't a performance.
I really am seething with anger
at how worthless I am,
having to put on a charade like this.
Why did you kill my mom and dad?
Anything I say would only be an excuse.
The fact remains,
I killed the Doctors Rockbell.
With this hand.
Young girl, you have every right
to pass judgment on me.
Your arm... You're going to bleed
to death if we don't do something.
- Winry.
- I know.
But this is probably
what Mom and Dad did, too.
Mom and Dad saved his life, after all.
I think there's some sort
of meaning in that.
You are forgiving me?
Don't get me wrong.
I'm not forgiving your wantonness.
- Winry...
- It's all right. I'm not going to cry.
I promised you that the next time I cried,
they'd be tears of joy.
Hey, Scar.
That may be what Winry says,
but I still want to beat you to a pulp
and drag you out
to the Rockbell family grave!
- Should we contact headquarters?
- Yeah.
Miles, wasn't it?
- Can I ask you something?
- What is it?
You called me one of your people.
That's right. I'm Ishvalan,
on my grandfather's side.
I wish we didn't have to meet like this,
my red-eyed brother.
Why do you take part
in the Amestrisian armed forces?
In order to change the minds
of the people in this country
regarding Ishvalans from the inside.
I doubt it's going to be so easy
to change minds.
There's no telling how long it will take.
But there's something I can do
because of my mixed blood.
I am an Ishvalan pebble,
tossed into the Amestrisian armed forces,
and in time, perhaps my small ripples
may become great waves.
And ironically enough,
it was a native-born Amestrisian
that made me realize it.
I am the festering discharge of hatred,
born of that civil war.
I am glad that there are those like you.
Major...
Headquarters? This is Miles.
We've captured Scar
in a building in Area D.
Inform Kimblee.
Whatever your circumstances might be,
I cannot let you go.
You must accept the judgment due to you.
- Just a moment!
- Who are you?
May! Dr. Marcoh!
Please don't take that man away.
This isn't looking good, Mr. Kimblee.
The clouds are moving fast.
There's a storm coming in.
Hurry it up.
Deciphering research notes?
It's ground-breaking research
that attempts to fuse
Amestrisian alchemy
and Xingese alkahestry.
But all of the critical parts
are written in ancient Ishvalan.
Scar is the only one who can read it.
So you see...
You're the alkahestry girl, aren't you?
I have orders to bring you back
to the fort.
Me?
Don't worry. You're to receive
a warm welcome.
Well now, if Scar can't be captured
and it would be bad if they found out
that Marcoh is here...
It might be best to hide
all of you together at Fort Briggs.
Hold on a second. What do you mean?
Are you telling me
we're bringing him, too?
We need him to decipher
the research notes, right?
To think that we need this guy's help...
- Just hand him over to Kimblee already!
- The countrywide transmutation circle
and the origins of this country...
I heard all about it
from General Armstrong.
Something is about to happen
that is going to engulf all of Amestris.
Deciphering the research notes
is more important than anything, isn't it?
I heard that the Rockbell girl
is being kept as their hostage.
If we act now, we can disgrace Kimblee
and hide her away.
Scar, if you work with us,
I will postpone your judgment until later.
What do you say?
It appears that I don't have
any other choice.
I promise to work with you.
You're sincere?
I swear it on my Ishvalan blood,
my red-eyed brother.
That's that.
I'm sorry, miss, but you'll have to wait
a short while for him to be punished.
Okay.
Come to think of it.
I forgot about these guys.
- Dispose of them.
- Yes, sir.
Hey!
Just a minute!
You don't have to kill them!
There's no value in leaving them alive.
Kill them.
No, it's not about value.
Isn't there any way to let them live?
Are you showing us mercy? Is that it?
Who asked you,
you sentimental know-nothing?
In the bodies we have,
we know what lies ahead for us anyhow.
If you're gonna kill us, then do it.
Misters, don't you have families
or loved ones?
Sure we do.
But once we got these bodies,
they were told that we were dead.
We haven't seen them since.
Don't you want to see them?
Even if we do, there's no way we can,
in our shape.
Then you don't want to go back
to your original bodies.
You're content with the bodies you have?
- No way we could be!
- Of course we want to go back!
There's your answer, right?
Don't go talking to me
about "anyhows" or "no ways".
Not without investigating the possibility
of getting your original bodies back.
- What could you possibly know about us?
- What possibility is there of going back?
I'm going back.
No matter how many years it takes.
I'm not going to give up.
Major!
- What is it?
- This is bad.
There's going to be a storm.
We can't conduct a snowbound march
with the equipment here.
We won't be able
to reach the fort at this rate.
What do we do?
This is a mining town, right?
Why don't we just use
the underground tunnels?
What? I mean, as large as this mine is,
there has to be a tunnel that goes
beyond the mountain... I think.
- That's it!
- Mr. Yoki!
Give a little credit
to the former mine proprietor.
We can make it.
The tunnels come out past the mountain.
All right. Once you meet some soldiers
from Fort Briggs, give them this.
I've written down what's going on inside,
so they will provide you with shelter.
Thank you.
That leaves the matter of the young lady.
Assuming she comes together with us,
when it comes out that she's gone missing,
the Elric brothers will be the first ones
they suspect, won't they?
We can handle ourselves.
I don't mean to brag, but when it comes
to having a smooth tongue...
No, this is the skeptical Kimblee
we're dealing with.
If you try anything half-cocked,
it will just make him more suspicious.
I hate to be the one
to suggest this, but...
What if I were to be taken hostage
by Scar?
Kidnapped?
So what you're saying is, let him go?
Yes, Scar will run away, carrying me.
Ed, you and the others
will try desperately to stop him,
or so it will look like to those
who are after us.
- How can you do anything so dangerous?
- My life is in their hands!
So unless I risk my life to escape,
I won't get away!
But to go together with Scar...
Yeah! There's no need for you
to risk your life!
You guys, stop, always taking everything
upon yourselves!
Make up your minds quickly.
The storm is closing in.
Soon, we won't be able
to set one foot out of here.
Kimblee's forces are within sight!
Damn it all!
- Scar, if you pull anything...
- I know. I will keep my promise.
Us, too...
Take us with you, too!
I know you don't trust us,
so we don't mind if you take us in cuffs.
Mr. Kimblee is merciless to troops
who can't do their jobs.
One way or the other, we're dead.
Besides, we don't want to give up, either.
You're sure we can trust you?
If you do anything to obstruct us,
the country could be destroyed.
Including your loved ones.
Hold on a minute!
What do you mean by that?
The Central forces
weren't told anything about this!
Tell us more! What's going on?
- You're sure about this?
- Yeah.
You'll be able to rest easier
this way, too.
Scar, give us a good show.
All right.
You keep your oath
on your Ishvalan blood.
Miss, your ear piercings.
They're made of metal, right?
If you don't take them out,
you'll get frostbite.
Ed.
You hang onto these.
I'll be waiting for you at the fort.
Kimblee! Why, you!
How come you didn't keep an eye on Winry?
I'm worried about Zampano and Gerso.
Either Scar did them in
or they're trapped out in this storm.
Scar won't be able to move, either.
He must be somewhere in this town.
Let's make arrangements for our next
search operation now while we can.
Man, this storm really saved our hides.
Please let them reach the fort, quickly.
Major Miles,
Briggs is on the line for you.
This is Miles.
What?
So then, you're the daughter
of the Rockbells?
You knew my parents?
There isn't a doctor
that went through Ishval
that doesn't know their names.
They stuck to their physician's duty
without any regard for themselves.
I'm not forgiving your wantonness.
You must abide this.
And forgive what the armed forces
have done?
"Forgiving" is not "abiding".
You must not forgive
the wantonness of the world.
As a man, you must be indignant at it.
But you must abide it.
You must sever the chain of hatred.
If negative feelings come together,
the world will be caught
in a stream of negativity.
On the other hand, if positive feelings
are brought together,
we can also make the world
a positive stream.
That's the reason
why I'm learning alchemy.
Oh, here it is, here it is.
What is this place?
The mine's staff room.
In here should be...
Here it is.
See? A detailed map of the tunnels.
Looks complicated.
I can't tell what is what.
We need to go through here,
here, and here.
- Ho, you're amazing.
- Keep the praise coming.
At this rate, we should get
to the other side of the mountain
quicker than we thought.
Say, Dr. Marcoh, are there any hints
in those research notes
about how we can get
our original bodies back?
There is a possibility.
After all, it is an alchemy
that we know nothing about.
We've got great expectations, Doc.
I can't wait to see my family again.
And as henpecked as you used to be.
It's only your daughter
you miss, isn't it?
What about you? You were such a drunkard.
Your son can't stand you, can he?
You think you can face him now?
You would have to say that.
- Is something wrong, May?
- No.
Back in my country
my clan is waiting for me,
but when I think about when I go back...
The Philosopher's Stone
is made from living people.
No one should be allowed to seek it.
Even without the Stone,
if he knew how to make one,
His Highness, the Emperor
wouldn't hesitate to try it out
and sacrifice a great deal of people.
Just how does one obtain immortality?
It's possible that the answer to that
is written in these research notes.
Let's hurry to the fort
and carefully decipher them.
- Right.
- The fort is no longer safe?
General Armstrong
was summoned back to Central.
There are Central forces
entering the fort in great numbers.
No doubt at Kimblee's behest.
When we were at the fort, he was making
calls pretty frequently, after all.
Hold on. If the general is gone...
A commander affiliated with Bradley
will be posted in her place.
Then, what about Winry and the others?
Hiding them just became difficult.
In fact, if they're not careful,
they'll fall into enemy hands.
We have to warn Winry
and the others somehow.
It will be impossible
to catch up to them in this storm.
So are we just going to let them go?
I'm going after them.
Don't go belittling the storm, rookie.
You'll lose all your strength
in no time flat and freeze to death.
There is a way.
A person with a body
that doesn't get tired
and won't freeze to death.
This is worse than I imagined.
Let's see. The marker, the marker...
There it is!
Everything is white. I can't see anything.
What was that just now? My body?
How did...
It's inherently impossible
to stick someone's body
together with a different soul.
A body, which by all rights
shouldn't have a soul in it...
It's being rejected.
My body is pulling on my soul?
Snap out of it! Snap out of it!
I have to hurry.
Alphonse Elric...
Edward Elric...
And...
Van Hohenheim...
Izumi Curtis is also a possibility.
That leaves one more...