You're saying that General Armstrong
is linked to the disappearance
- of General Raven?
- Probably.
However, she wouldn't be so foolish
as to leave any evidence behind.
- Indeed.
- No matter.
Our job is to hold this fort
while that vixen is surrounded
by the pack of tigers in Central.
Well, well, General, sir...
To think that you'd be posted to Central.
- What connections do you have?
- Oh, it's all merit, you know?
That's rich, coming from such a greenhorn.
What brings you here today?
His Excellency, the Führer called me here.
I may not be able to go back north
for a while.
You can't go back? Well then,
by all means, let's have dinner sometime.
Your treat? I'm in, if you don't mind me
eating you into bankruptcy.
Never mind about dinner.
Oh, so you're a man
short on money and nerve.
How would you like some flowers, instead?
- There are many fine florists in Central.
- Are there?
- Enter.
- Yes, sir.
Now then, General Armstrong,
let me ask you
about General Raven going missing.
- What have you done?
- I won't be able to hide it all.
Excellency,
how is it that someone like you
could have someone
so thoughtless at your side?
Is that why you disposed of him?
You didn't need him, did you?
Having someone so talkative on your staff
is not good for you, Excellency.
- What did General Raven say to you?
- A legion of immortals...
The history of this country,
Your Excellency's true identity...
He told me all sorts of things
without me even asking.
And you responded to my summons,
having heard all of this?
Yes, sir. I came to take the seat
that fool was occupying.
That makes it all the more interesting!
Very well. I will give you a seat.
In return, my men will control
Fort Briggs. Agreed?
As you please, sir.
I have seen that my soldiers are hearty.
I am sure that Your Excellency
will find favor with them.
I am pleased. Struggle well, human.
You can't steal a tiger's cubs
without entering her den.
I guess the general herself
entered the tiger's den, huh?
Yeah. This place is theirs, too.
However, they do not know one thing.
Although our master may be gone,
we are still one giant monolith,
acting together as with one will.
Such is Fort Briggs.
From here on, the bears and tigers
will turn on one another.
Is this spot taken?
Be my guest.
- How is your work going?
- See for yourself.
I have to work through meals,
or I'll never keep up.
- How about you?
- I'm keeping busy myself,
with so much to remember.
However, His Excellency works quickly,
so that helps.
Best of all, he doesn't slack off.
Sounds like this is going to be
a dull conversation.
Now that you mention it...
I heard that Scar was in the north.
The Elric brothers are also up north.
I see.
My former classmates Lucy and Ian
are up north right now,
- and tell me lots of things.
- Oh, yeah?
As I recall,
this spring, the north and the east
- will be conducting joint exercises.
- Yes.
Major Miles and Captain Buccaneer
outdid us many times, huh?
Miles... Buccaneer...
And then York,
Ida and Sugar spoke to her...
Havoc, Oscar, Mike, Uni, Nora,
Charlie, then Uni and Lucy again...
Then came Uni, and finally Sterling...
"Selim Bradley is a homunculus."
Impossible...
But then, there's no such thing.
Just what on earth
is about to happen here in Central?
Young man...
Say, you there!
- Oh, no!
- It's all right.
Over here, over here.
- I see.
- Hey, now.
How about acting surprised, or something?
Will you give me something
if I act surprised?
Hey, I like how you aren't scared.
- What's your name?
- No. 23.
Not your number, tell me your real name.
Don't have one. I'm a slave.
A slave? You mean a person not given
any rights or freedom,
but trafficked and deeded as a possession?
- Deeded?
- That's when property, rights,
and so on are transferred to another.
- You're not too smart, are you?
- Buzz off!
I have no idea how I was born
from someone like this.
You are the one who gave me blood, right?
Come to think of it, he did say
he would use it in an experiment.
Because you gave your blood,
I have been born into this world.
Thank you. Let's see...
"No. 23" is a bit brusque.
I will give you a name.
- Who do you think you are?
- You'll want a fine one, right? I know...
- Theo... Theophrastus Bombastus.
- Too long!
Oh, right, you're not too smart,
so you can't remember
- anything too long.
- Don't say I'm not smart!
Well then, Van...
How about Van Hohenheim?
Van Hohen, huh?
I can remember something like that.
It's spelled... oh, right.
Do you know how to read and write?
I can still work
without being able to do that.
Slave work.
Don't you want freedom and rights?
Do you intend to live out
your life as a slave
without obtaining the rights of man?
In that case, you're no different
than being inside a stuffy flask.
Let me give you some knowledge,
Van Hohenheim.
Hey...
What are you?
What do I call you?
Why don't you call me
the Dwarf in the Flask, Homunculus?
All things are made from the one
and return to the one.
In other words, one is all.
All is of the one.
All is within the one.
If all is not included in the one,
then all is nothing.
You pass.
You are now a fine alchemist, Hohenheim.
But still nothing beyond assistant level.
I'm nowhere near close
to your skill, Master.
- I'm grateful to you.
- For what?
Because of the knowledge you gave me,
I can now live as well as I do.
I'm also happy to be held
in Master's esteem.
Now, getting married
and having a family someday
is more than just a dream.
A family, huh?
Sure is inconvenient for you humans.
Unless you form communities,
and breed yourselves,
your species can't continue to exist.
Don't say "breed."
And while it might seem silly to you--
As far as humans go,
we find happiness in things
such as family and friendship.
Well, if you say so.
Okay then, what do you find happiness in?
Well, I don't want to ask too much,
but I think I would be happy
if I could leave this flask.
Immortality...
Why is it that one who has attained
the height of power and prosperity
- would move toward that?
- Watch your tongue!
You are in the presence of His Majesty!
If you continue your insolence,
I will smash your flask!
You would destroy a source of knowledge
to which you are ignorant?
Enough chatter. Immortality--
Is it possible or isn't it?
Impatience, owing to old age?
How lamentable, King of Xerxes.
Very well. I will tell you
the way to gain immortality.
- What are you building?
- Irrigation canals.
The king has ordered canals
to be dug throughout the land.
That's the King of Xerxes for you.
- He even thinks about us commoners.
- That he does.
- Remember! Leave no one alive!
- Yes, sir!
Hurry! Quickly!
Quickly, carve out the crests of blood!
The village to the north was attacked?
I heard they were killed to the last man.
Before that,
it was the village to the west.
- Who could be doing this?
- What a terrible tale.
Sure is tragic.
Your Majesty, your long-anticipated
transmutation circle is complete.
That took a long time. At last...
Now it is ready, right?
Yes. You can now become immortal.
Amazing.
The king is going to become immortal.
This is a moment of the ages.
This is immortality, is it?
What is this?
You said no harm would come
to those of us at the center!
What? What's going on? Hey, Homunculus!
The true center
of the transmutation circle is here,
- where you are standing.
- What?
I've used your blood, which is within me,
to open the doorway.
Hohenheim, my blood kin,
right now, you and I
are at the center of everything.
Your Majesty!
Master...
He's dead.
Is anyone there?
Willard... Mechthild...!
Reinmeir! Toni! Mayo!
Somebody... answer me.
It's no use. They've all had
their souls taken out of them.
Your Majesty!
- Are you all right?
- Well?
How does that body feel?
I'm over there...
I created a receptacle for myself
based on the information in your blood.
Well, well, I can finally walk
on my own two legs.
Are you Homunculus?
What is this? What have you done?
To thank you for your blood,
I've given you a name,
and I've given you knowledge.
And now, I've given you a body
that will live forever.
- Live forever?
- Focus your attention within yourself.
You hear them, don't you?
The voices of all the people in the land
who were offered in exchange
for your immortality?
Although, I did take half of them.
I appreciate your cooperation, Hohenheim.
Mr. Hohenheim?
I knew it.
Wow, imagine,
you being Ed and Al's father...
And you, being my sons' teacher...
I'm sure they must have been
a handful for you.
Oh, no, don't let it concern you.
- Mrs. Izumi...?
- Izumi, are you all right?
- I'll get your medicine.
- May I have a look at her?
- I know a bit about medicine.
- Okay.
- I'm all right. This always happens.
- You are not all right.
Mr. Sig, please find us a car!
- Hurry!
- All right.
Mrs. Izumi...
you've seen the truth, haven't you?
What did you sacrifice?
Please be truthful with me.
My insides were taken away.
I was trying to bring my dead child
back to life.
I see.
Please excuse me...
Izumi! Hang on! Izumi!
- Take it easy, dear, I'm all right.
- Your belly has been run through!
- But my breathing is easier...
- Show me!
- There's no wound.
- That's impossible.
The organs that were taken away
are testament to your sin,
and cannot be brought back,
but I did rearrange the inside
of your belly somewhat,
and improved the flow of blood.
Mrs. Izumi, you must not fall just yet.
Hohenheim, who...
are you, exactly?
I am a Philosopher's Stone,
in the form of a man named Van Hohenheim.
"The Sage's Stone,"
"The Celestial Stone,
"The Grand Elixir"...
Just as the Philosopher's Stone
is called by many names,
its form is not necessarily
that of a stone.
The one Dr. Marcoh had was semi-liquid.
The one Kimblee has is like a crystal,
and it's about this big.
You say it has tremendous energy,
so I thought it would be something larger.
I've never seen one larger
than pebble-sized.
Then again, if you had
a huge Philosopher's Stone,
it would mean using an incredible amount
of people as material.
If possible, I don't ever want to see one.