It's almost like a maze in here.
- Be careful not to get separated.
- Right.
- Are you all right?
- Sorry.
What's this?
- Dynamite.
- You're kidding!
No, these are completely soaked through.
Relax, they won't explode.
Hey, don't dawdle around.
There's no telling when someone
might come after us.
Right.
It looks like the storm is over.
- Get things ready.
- Yes, sir.
Kimblee and the men he brought
from Central...
When you get an opening,
take out all three of them.
Yes, sir.
We'll carry out the mission
with only those of us who are here.
This is top-secret, even to the soldiers
from Northern Command.
Hold on. Major Miles, by "take out,"
- do you mean kill?
- Of course.
I can't go along with killing them.
Better to keep him from using alchemy
and getting intel from him.
Do you think that guy
is going to freely tell us anything?
- It's too dangerous to keep him alive.
- Then what about his men?
They've been turned into Chimeras
and maybe they have no choice
but to obey him, you know?
You're right.
But ultimately, that's still a "maybe".
You're going to kill them
just because you're suspicious of them?
I mean, even in General Raven's case,
there was no other way!
Do not forget the law of Briggs.
"If you get careless, you're dead."
Your sense of mercy could cost you
or your friends their lives.
We don't need anyone careless
in these parts.
We're going to dispose of Kimblee
and the other two.
- He's still a child after all, huh?
- Yeah.
But in this world, it's naive to stick
to the idea of not having to kill anyone.
Then again,
I went through that phase myself.
So did I. But at our age,
after living through a number of wars,
you learn some things.
Like letting someone live
is harder than killing them.
The Elric brothers have chosen
the more difficult way.
- They are pretty arbitrary that way, huh?
- Yeah.
But I'm kind of envious of them too.
What's this "rasayana" here?
It's a miracle drug
from which one gains longevity.
The Philosopher's Stone maybe? Let's see.
"Changes all metals into gold and returns
the elderly back to their youth."
- What's "aurelian" here?
- That means gold.
It's all about immortality and gold.
That's because Mr. Scar's brother,
who wrote these notes,
was influenced by Xingese alkahestry.
How do you mean?
In Xing, we call an immortal a shinhito,
a "true person".
It means that they are a perfect person.
And since gold is the perfect metal,
a shinhito is sometimes
also called a "kinhito".
I get it. So a perfect person
is a gold person then?
In a sense. The person
who brought alchemy to Xing
was an immortal man
who had golden hair and eyes.
So that's apparently
how they got to be called that.
Gold hair and eyes. Sounds like Ed and Al.
Hey, everyone! Over here! The exit!
Wow, it's so bright.
We made it safely through the mountain.
The weather is nice.
Let's head for Briggs now while we can.
All right, men, follow me--
- Hey, help me!
- The snow is pretty deep.
- Miss, hop on my back.
- Hey, guys, is anyone listening?
- We'll stomp it down
and make a path for you
- so you can follow behind us.
- Thanks.
Hey! Hey!
Help me! Somebody!
- Al?
- Alphonse!
- Oh, no! Oh, no! I'll save you!
- Al, are you all right?
I'm saved.
I got stuck here where it became deep
- and then got buried by it.
- Al, what are you doing here?
I crossed over the mountain
to get to you first.
You crossed over the mountain?
In that snowstorm?
I see. You came straight here
without taking any detours.
Why would you do something so reckless?
- I have an emergency message.
- Emergency message?
Central's forces are inside Fort Briggs.
General Armstrong
was apparently summoned to Central.
As such, it's too dangerous
to go to the fort now.
What do we do? We can't very well go back.
- We'll just have to hide someplace else.
- Someplace else like where?
- Follow me.
- Where are you going?
There's a village called Asbeck
that shouldn't be too far from here.
I've heard that some of my people
are taking refuge in the slums there.
An Ishvalan slum?
We don't appear to have any other options.
Good going, sir. Let's go.
- But are you sure that's a good idea?
- What?
Al, if you disappear all of a sudden,
won't Mr. Kimblee be suspicious?
It's okay, it's okay.
Brother will take care of that.
- Squad 3, three men.
- Squad 4, five men.
All right, that's everyone.
Okay, each of you,
commence searching your areas.
- Sir.
- Yes, sir.
- Let's go.
Hey now, Alphonse.
You mean "right", don't you?
Man, I tell you, it's hard
to move around in this, Edward.
Please manage to somehow.
Come on, Kimblee is watching.
- Just a minute, Brother!
- Walk faster.
Hey, where are Kimblee
and the others searching?
There's that huge mineshaft
in the center of town, right?
He said he was going in there
to search the tunnels.
He said he couldn't trust
the northern soldiers,
so he was only taking the men
he brought from Central.
He's caught on, has he?
We'll head him off.
- Secure sniping positions near the shaft.
- Yes, sir.
Search the entrance to the tunnel.
If there are multiple sets of footprints,
- then there's no doubt.
- Yes, sir.
- Can you do it?
- Yes, at this distance...
What's the matter?
- It's Edward.
- What?
Kimblee, if you're going
to check out the tunnels,
shouldn't you leave that
to the Briggs soldiers?
It runs pretty deep in there.
The fact that you're intentionally
stopping me proves they're here.
What do you mean?
I want to get Scar as fast as--
Or are you buying time
until the snipers get into position?
You knew about that?
With as much bloodlust
filling the air around us, I knew.
I didn't survive the Ishvalan War
because of my good looks.
It looks like they're talking
to each other.
What do I do?
- Can you target just Kimblee?
- Yes, sir.
- Take careful aim and fire.
That bastard!
He's using the snow to obstruct the view!
Damn.
Kimblee!
Why, you--!
You fellows are Chimeras too?
That bastard. I can't see anything.
But then, the other guys can't see either.
The odds are even--
Come quietly, Fullmetal Alchemist.
You can't escape from our sharp noses
in this poor visibility.
Shut up.
Fullmetal!
What's going on? Where are you? Answer me!
Major Miles? There are Chimeras here!
And they're accustomed
to fighting in poor visibility!
Don't come inside the snow cloud!
Damn it. I'm gonna be even shorter.
"Dynamite?" That's a mine for you.
Don't come too close!
You know what this is, right?
- You idiot.
- That stuff is too damp
to be of any help to you.
Fellows, do you know
what dynamite is made of?
Nitroglycerin?
Nitroglycol, wood flour,
ammonium nitrate and so forth?
Okay, and what is
the ammonium nitrate made of?
That's easy. Nitric acid and ammonia.
Ammonia?
Pee-yew!
- What is that smell?
- Ammonia.
Having a too sharp nose
can be a problem too.
These guys aren't any use to you anymore.
This is what happens,
the moment your hostage concerns are gone?
Whatever do you mean?
I'm just trying to get you
to spill everything you know.
Well, well, aren't you
the hot-blooded one?
Facing a youngster like you while
I'm on the mend will be quite taxing.
I don't have time to mess with you either.
How about I make use of this?
He brought it out on his own.
He's fast.
Too slow!
He has no Philosopher's Stone
and he can't use
his transmutation circles.
- Now I've--
- You've won.
That's what you're thinking, right?
The resolve not to kill.
It is a fine policy. However,
on the battlefield, it's something
that can be taken advantage of.
You should have finished me off just then.
That sense of mercy
will be the reason for your defeat.
I fell down the mine shaft?
Why, that rotten-- He took us down too.
Damn it. Where did Kimblee go?
Hey, you're kidding, right?
- Al, what's the matter?
- Alphonse!
Al.
Yikes... I'm being pulled away again.
- What do you mean "pulled away"? Al.
- Hey, what's the matter, armor guy?
My soul...
is being pulled over.
Al! Al.
- His soul is being pulled away?
- Alphonse.
Miss, has anything like this
happened before?
Alphonse, stay with us.
- I don't know. Al.
- Alphonse!
Al, wake up.
No. Al, Al!
What do we do? What do we do?
Ed!
I can't make her cry
over something like this, can I?
Damn that Kimblee.
Hey, Fullmetal, are you alive?
Why did you save us?
You're more seriously injured
than we are, aren't you?
Don't get me wrong. I need someone...
to pull this thing stuck in my side...
out of me... or I've had it...
You want us to pull that beam out?
But we're the enemy.
Yeah, please.
Well, we don't have any orders
to kill you or anything.
- Here.
- But as soon as I pull that out,
you're gonna lose a lot of blood
and then it's lights out.
The moment you pull it out,
I'll close it up with alchemy...
before I lose too much blood.
What? Do you have any experience
in performing medical alchemy?
Long ago, when I tried to perform
human transmutation,
I researched it briefly.
Briefly? Your internal organs
are probably all torn up.
Without a Philosopher's Stone
or something like Mr. Kimblee has...
I'll use my own life...
in place of a Philosopher's Stone.
It may shorten my life
a little bit though.
- Are you sure about this?
- This is no time for debate.
If this is the outcome
of my sense of mercy,
then I've gotta wipe my own ass.
I'm not sure how you mean
but this is no time for debate.
I'll pull it out.
Okay, pull it.
Think of your life
as a sort of energy form.
The same as a Philosopher's Stone.
That's it. Right now,
I am a one-soul-sized Philosopher's Stone!
Remember... how it felt... back then!
How it felt... to use... life!
Is he dead?
Don't go writing me off.
Oh, it worked?
I'm not completely healed
but I spliced together a working system.
And for now... this jury-rigging
has at least stopped the bleeding.
Then you need
to have a doctor look at you.
No. There's no time for that.
Hey.
I have to go after Kimblee
or the others will be at risk.
Fool, there's no way you can fight
and win in your shape.
What is it?
A Philosopher's Stone?
That's the one Mr. Kimblee had.
We don't need to call
that freak "Mister" anything.
Not after he got us tangled up
in this too.
You're right.
What do you say we bid
that bastard farewell now?
Yeah. We'll let him think we died here
and become free men.
So, what do we do about him?
We can't just let him die, right?
We owe him our lives after all.
Yeah.
Once we get outside, we'll have
to find him a doctor right away.
Yeah.