Here's that expression again, May.
That word must also mean "gold", huh?
What are you doing?
We're checking to see
if there is a hidden code.
Code?
In order to make sure regular people
can't decode their notes easily,
alchemists use metaphor and allegory
to conceal their content.
However, in the case
of these research notes,
there doesn't seem to be any of that.
So, because of all the phrases
that mean "gold" and "immortality,"
we thought we might change our way
of investigating them.
- So have you figured anything out?
- Nothing.
- Where am I?
-Al!
- Al!
- Thank goodness!
I didn't know what I would do
if you didn't regain consciousness.
Sorry. I must have worried you.
By the way, why have I been taken apart?
So there you have it.
You were too big for us
to move with one of us carrying you.
So we dismantled you.
Sorry. I guess I put you all out.
Has anything like this
ever happened before?
Once, before coming here.
Well, it can't be very convenient
for you to be taken apart.
Let's put you back together.
Yes, please do.
Would you hold onto this for a bit?
Let's see.
- This part goes...
- That's his right arm, right?
Right. Can't have him matching up
the wrong way, after all.
In pieces...
Matching up...
May!
How could you pull it apart like that?
By changing the way it matches up...
I was thinking,
what if I tried overlapping the parts
of the phrases that mean
"gold" and "immortality"?
"Golden man."
This phrase was over there.
"Immortality..." overlaps here.
"Perfect person..."
There it is, there it is.
Give me those pages, Marcoh.
That one connects over here.
- Is there a "golden person"?
- Yes, there is. Right here.
This is the last one.
I wonder if...
Is that...?
The countrywide transmutation circle.
What good does it do, finding this now?
What does this mean?
Does this mean that the research notes
are no help at all?
You've gotta be kidding me!
What's gonna happen to us?
No, the whole country?
I'm sorry. I was naive to think
that the way to take
this critical situation
and turn it around would be found
in someone else's research.
Brother, is this what you wanted
to tell me?
Brother, knowing you, didn't you arrive
at anything beyond this?
There's still something here.
We didn't realize
that we needed to pull it apart.
If there was still something...
still something hidden,
it wouldn't surprise me.
Hey, what are you thinking?
It's not my fault it's so cold!
And even without it,
I'm sensitive to the cold.
Who cares?
You can't even tell which side
is face-up or down anymore.
- You've flipped these over like crazy.
- That might be it!
Take the critical situation
and turn it around.
Face-up and face-down!
Take what we just had
and flip the pages upside-down!
Well?
That was it.
This is a new Amestrisian countrywide
transmutation circle
that incorporates alkahestry.
There doesn't seem to be any trace
of anyone passing through here.
Perhaps I've come the wrong way.
I guess I'll go back.
So that's it.
This place must have been used
to remove the rubble
from the tunnel that Sloth is digging.
You are the Crimson Alchemist, right?
Pleased to meet you. I am Pride.
Did you need something from me?
- How is the Scar matter coming?
- I am pursuing him now.
Deal with him later.
Carve out the crest of blood
at Briggs first.
Forgive me for saying so,
but the monolithic nature and strength
of Briggs' soldiers
are quite considerable.
- It is not going to be an easy task.
- Make use of their strength.
The tunnel that Sloth
is digging is almost complete.
Very well. I will carve out
the crest of blood for you
at Fort Briggs.
- We've been expecting you.
Any change to report?
Not especially. Never mind us.
I heard that Kimblee went missing.
Is that true?
Yeah. There was an explosion,
big enough to collapse the tunnels.
Kimblee and several others are missing.
We did a thorough search, but ultimately,
no one's body turned up.
Were the "several others"
Briggs' soldiers?
No, they were Kimblee's two men...
and the Fullmetal Alchemist.
I see. Chief Fullmetal?
- I hope he's all right.
- Yeah.
How are things in the west?
What can I tell you?
The border war at Pendleton
was a real mess.
The way they were fighting,
I can only guess
they were intentionally
racking up the KIAs.
The military seems to be taking
the initiative in making this bloody
so they can create the transmutation
circle, just like you said.
Have you gotten any word
from Sergeant Fuery, in the south?
A little while ago, by phone.
He said they were exchanging fire
with the Aerugo forces,
down in southern Fotcett.
Run, Thomas! Don't let up! Thomas!
Damn it!
I'm gonna survive!
I'm gonna survive, no matter what!
Is that right?
That's how it is for us redheaded
stepchildren from Mustang's old squad.
Are you in touch with the colonel?
Yes, we're using a messenger
with ties to the Armstrong family.
Okay. Sounds like it's rough up north too
so watch yourself.
Yes, you could say it's rough.
Their men are up here, working steadily
to turn this country into a hell on earth,
and there isn't a single thing
we can do about it.
I've connected...
Can I stop working now, Pride?
It's almost time.
The day is nearly at hand.
Everyone! Time to eat! Please line up!
Rose, I'd like to have meat pie sometime.
I'll make some,
once I get the ingredients.
I can't wait.
I haven't worked, but would you give me
some for these children?
Of course. Have some as well, ma'am.
It looks so good.
Rose, a heaping helping, if you please.
I can't do that.
Everyone gets an equal portion.
Excuse me...
May I have some too, please?
Wow, you saved me.
Thanks, that was delicious.
Where did you come from?
I didn't come from anywhere.
I wander around here and there.
What did you come
all the way out here for?
You do know about the disturbance
that took place here, right?
There isn't anything in this town anymore
because of it.
Despite there being such delicious food?
I'm flattered that you would say so,
but this is about the extent
of what I can do.
I wouldn't say that.
A hot meal and a young lady's smile
give strength to everyone.
Right.
I hate to ask after imposing
so much already,
but I'm looking for a church.
Church?
Yes. The home of Letoism,
which was the cause of the disturbance.
It's just what you see.
You go in there now,
and there's nothing left.
Would there happen to be a passage
that leads underground?
Yes, there is.
What's this?
Toxic water.
It happened before anyone realized it.
It's all set up so that no normal person
can go any farther, is it?
- Let me see.
- Wait!
You'll die if you go in there.
It's a miracle.
No, it isn't. It's alchemy, isn't it?
I'm going to go a little farther in.
Would you wait there for me?
It's huge.
They went all-out in making this.
Found it right off the bat.
Oh, my, didn't even slow you down.
In that case...
let me try to contain you.
Oh, dear.
I don't know what to do now.
What's the matter?
Aren't you coming after me?
Your appearance... You're Van Hohenheim?
It would seem that your receptacle
only comes this far.
If you leave here, you'll die, right?
You'll die if you transgress
some fixed line, won't you?
Just like the flask, way back when.
It looks to me like you can only act
within the heart of Central
and in these tunnels.
How about it?
Did I guess it right?
What's the matter?
Why don't you say something,
you shrinking violet?
Are you angry?
Anger does not exist within me.
And it isn't just anger.
I left all of my unnecessary emotions
within my father.
My name is Pride.
Pride. I see. The Arrogant.
They say that man
is possessed of seven sins.
Lust,
greed,
sloth,
gluttony,
envy,
wrath,
and pride.
So that makes you, "Pride,"
the first one he cut loose from himself.
To think that he would take the care
to cut you loose
with an appearance similar
to when he was in the flask.
That is the very form
of his proud, arrogant self.
It's the essence of your father.
Would you like to come
to where my father is?
Don't be in such a hurry.
I will be coming, invited or not.
Give him a message.
Tell him Slave No. 23
will be coming to see him soon.
Tell him to sit back in his chair
in Central and wait for me.
Yes, I am waiting for you,
Van Hohenheim.
He's coming back!
Did you find something?
Regular people shouldn't go near there.
It's too dangerous.
Please tell everyone not to go in there.
What did you do in there?
Made a declaration of war.
You're relieved.
We've been waiting for you.
This snowstorm has been terrible.
Now then, I think I'll go
get some lousy coffee.
Good work--
- Hey...!
- That couldn't possibly be...
It's Drachma!
Drachma has declared an outbreak
of hostilities from the north!
All personnel, prepare for combat!
Repeat, Drachma has declared
an outbreak of hostilities from the north!
All personnel, prepare for combat!
Lucky for us,
the Northern Wall of Briggs isn't in.
Mr. Kimblee?
Additionally, many of our own men
are inside the fort.
Once the fighting starts,
they'll turn on them,
and then there will be chaos
inside the fort.
After not being able to cross Briggs
for so long,
today is the day that Drachma
will capture it!
Now, to decree war.
What do you say we launch
our fireworks in style?
All cannons, prepare to fire!
Fire!
Yeah. My name is Zampano.
I'm one of Kimblee's men.
Dr. Marcoh is hiding in the slums
of Asbeck Village.
You were right to tell me this, Zampano.
I will guarantee your safety.
Marcoh!
This is starting to get interesting.