Where are you, Mr. Kimblee?
This isn't what we agreed to.
You said that if we attacked,
there would be turncoats at Briggs!
Cease fire!
- An overwhelming victory, huh?
- Yeah.
It's like...
A crest of blood.
I told you.
In alkahestry,
you read the dragon's pulse.
And I'm telling you,
I don't know what that means.
You have to sharpen your senses.
And go! There, I sense it.
- I told you, I can't!
- Yes, you can!
Explain it to me more academically!
- You have to go whoomph!
- They sure are lively.
- I don't know what you mean!
- Sorry to have to hide out here.
Don't worry about it.
We're getting something out of it, too.
My hair! Stop that!
The children have someone else
to play with.
Help me!
Tell Zampano that I'm going off
to the mountains to get some firewood.
Damn it!
What a terrible predicament!
Everyone else is working,
so where did that bastard Zampano
go off to?
Hey!
This way. I'll take you there.
Please do, Zampano.
I understand you've found out about Selim.
Yes, sir.
- And my own true identity, as well.
- Yes, sir.
As one of this country's people,
how do you feel about its leader
and his son being Homunculi?
I think it's sad that the family
in whom I've trusted is fictitious.
You're a make-believe family.
Pretending to be the humans
that you sneer at as fools.
It's true, my "son" was given to me
from someone higher up.
Everything, from my position as Fuhrer
to all of my men were given to me.
You might say I'm a make-believe
potentate.
However, my wife, at least,
is someone I chose.
- Is the tea ready yet?
- Oh, yes, sir.
Delicious.
Oh, yeah, Doctor?
You were one of the bigwigs
at the Fifth Laboratory?
I was no bigwig.
I just had some men working under me.
I wonder how they are doing now.
Hey!
- Who is that gentleman?
- A drifter that I met this morning.
He says he wants to get examined
by you, Doctor.
That's enough, Zampano.
You can stop with the third-rate acting.
Good day to you, Doctor.
What might you be doing
in a place like this?
You maggot.
Trying to put one over on me
was wishful thinking.
What is this?
Zampano!
I can stop
with the third-rate acting, right?
Our goal from the outset
was to lure you here.
As nasty as you are,
I knew that if you found out
I was still alive,
you'd come after me all on your own.
What can you three pieces of trash
do to me?
No matter how many of you gang up,
trash is still trash!
They're like landmines.
Alchemy evolves day by day.
There's no such thing
as this kind of alchemy.
Damn it! If these are landmines,
then if I trace your footsteps,
I won't set them off.
How?
They only respond to Homunculi.
Thanks to the snow,
you can't tell what's waiting
in store for you.
Well? How does it feel
to be made a mockery of
by someone you treated like scum
and trash?
We've got him fooled, don't we?
It's just remote transmutation.
Why, you...
Scum should do what scum is told to do.
Don't act so cocky,
you worthless piece of crap!
Doctor!
- That was a close one.
- Thank you.
As tubby as he is, he's fast!
Don't sell us pieces of crap short!
Damn it!
You think this two-bit attack
is going to work?
No, huh?
Well then, how do you like this?
Did he get him?
I caught you.
- Doctor!
Don't you move. I'll snap him like a twig.
Now then, I'll have to give you
your punishment.
I told you, Doctor. You try anything
and I'll wipe out the whole village.
I won't let you do that.
You're still resisting?
You really are an idiot.
All right. I'm going to lay waste
to that slum.
Stop!
But simply crushing them
won't be much fun.
Maybe I'll take them back to Central
and use them as ingredients
for Philosopher's Stones.
Why, you!
Are you still having those things
made there?
Let the researchers there-- Let my men go!
Huh? No can do.
After all, we've turned them all
into a Philosopher's Stone.
What? Not my men, too...
Huh? You mean I didn't tell you?
But Doctor, there's no need
to mourn them now, is there?
I mean, you've made so many
Philosopher's Stones, haven't you?
And used people's lives to do it.
Yes. I've sacrificed many people's lives
to make Philosopher's Stones.
I know better than anyone else
in the country
how to make Philosopher's Stones.
And knowing how to make them
means I know how
to destroy them, as well!
What is that?
It's coming from the hill
where the Doctor and the others are.
It hurts! It hurts! It hurts!
No! This can't...
This can't...
No, this can't...
This can't be happening to me, Envy.
There's no way you lower creatures
can beat me.
No. Not the Chimeras, too.
Don't look at me.
Don't... Don't look at me.
Don't you look down on me, humans!
Don't look at me, you worms, you filth.
Don't look.
This is the guy that was manipulating us?
We beat him, Marcoh.
Oh, they're coming back.
Dr. Marcoh! You're hurt! What happened?
What's that?
You were up to something that amazing
without us knowing about it?
That's what you get
for going against us humans,
you little... you little...
Dr. Marcoh,
why would you do something so rash?
Up to now, I've always done
whatever I was told to do.
But this time,
I wanted to settle things myself.
To think and decide for myself.
Like your parents did.
- Still, don't be so reckless, okay?
- Yeah.
Hey! Ouch!
- Mr. Yoki?
- Help me.
I've taken this guy's body.
Stop this, you monster!
I can't move my body!
No, you can't!
Now, everyone,
if you want me to spare his life...
Nah, do whatever you like.
He's not one of us, after all.
Mr. Yoki, it's been nice knowing you,
even for this short time.
I won't forget about you.
Scar, sir,
you'll take my side, right? Right?
Don't you look away from me!
- Sir, I had faith in you, at least.
- Why?
- I had faith in you.
- He's one of you, isn't he?
Save your breath, Envy.
We've taken the gloves off now.
If you get in our way,
we'll destroy you and that man together!
Damn it!
- He came off.
- Really?
Nice performance.
Bluffing isn't my strong suit.
Damn it all! You guys are not my friends!
I'm through with you!
I'm severing our relationship!
Damn.
Well, I think it's about time
we asked you about your plans.
I don't know anything.
What was that? Spit it out!
Spit it out, you little worm!
Go! Let him have it, Zampano!
After I tell you,
you're just gonna kill me, aren't you?
- You expect me to talk, you fool?
- Damn you!
Come to think of it,
isn't the Fullmetal pipsqueak here?
Brother? He should be back
at Briggs right now.
I heard he's gone missing.
What? What are you talking about? Tell me!
Apparently, the mine shaft
in Baschool caved in.
I wonder if he's still alive.
That's not true.
What do we do? Head back to Baschool?
No. Knowing brother, at a time like this,
I'm sure he would trust
that the other was all right,
and decide to move forward.
That's why we're moving on, too.
There's still hope.
I will go my separate way for now.
There's something
I was thinking a little earlier.
I'm not out to just hold a grudge
against this country for rejecting Ishval.
But to change it...
For that purpose, Marcoh,
I will need your assistance.
All right. I will go with you.
In order to change this country...
Actually, there's a town
I'd kind of like to go to, as well.
Oh, and where is that?
A town called Liore.
If my guess is correct,
that tunnel will be there, too.
- I'm thinking, it'd be the fastest way...
- May, take this.
- ...to destroy it.
- And go back to your land.
- That would buy us some time.
- Hold on, sir!
- And let us figure out how to set up...
- It's what's left of a Homunculus...
- the reverse transmutation circle.
- that doesn't die when you kill it.
- By "reverse transmutation circle"...
- It may be enough to save your clan.
- You mean that diagram...
- But if I go home...
- we found earlier, right?
- who will teach you about alkahestry?
Is this any time to be concerned
about someone else's country?
Is that the resolve you had
when you came to this country?
If you lose the power struggle,
are you going to apologize to those
who have entrusted their fate to you
by telling them you
weren't able to save them
because you were involved
in some other country's affairs?
Go on. This country's problems
will be dealt with
by this country's people.
Thank you very much.
May, take care.
Once I get through the basics
of alkahestry,
I'll come to you to learn some more.
Oh, Al.
Al, I...
Thank you so much, everyone! Goodbye!
Take care!
There she goes.
- Well then, we should be going, too.
- Yeah.
Mr. Greed.
It's no use. Izumi Curtis went on a trip
with her husband
and no one knows
when they are returning.
There's nothing we can do.
For now, I guess we go back
to Fuhrer Bradley and report in.
Bradley.
You're coming with me, Greed.
Let's get him to provide us
with replacements.
Yeah.
If I follow them,
I'll find Mr. Greed, but...
Would you mind moving your foot, sister?
- Address me as General while we're here.
- Yes, ma'am!
Same old gutless mug as ever, I see.
I hear the fight against Drachma earlier
was a complete victory.
Of course it was!
The countrywide transmutation circle
is about to be finished, isn't it?
I don't care.
Right now, we should be keeping
the peace and security of this country.
If there is a foe that threatens that,
even for a moment,
we must bring them
to overwhelming and utter defeat!
My word, how ferocious.
If you keep this up, you'll never have
anyone ask for your hand--
You are short on fighting spirit!
You scum. I'm going to catch
your cowardice by being around you.
Oh, here you are, General.
Is this your brother?
I hate to think of him as my brother, sir.
Not some coward
who would desert from Ishval.
Come with me.
There's something I'd like to show you.
Do you know the three grand restrictions
of State Alchemy?
As I recall,
they are "do not oppose the military,"
"do not create gold,"
and "do not fashion people."
That is correct.
"Do not oppose the military"
should go without saying.
"Do not create gold" is there
to avoid financial disorder.
But what about "do not fashion people"?
Why does the state prohibit
the creation of people?
Because it is unethical, I suppose.
I've heard that even among alchemists,
it is implicitly forbidden
as sacrilege against God.
That's not why.
Ethics is something that varies over time
and among individuals.
That is not where the reason lies.
It is to prevent the individual
from possessing
a powerful military force, General.
This is awful.
Is there anywhere we can get
something to eat here?
Let's see. I know it's around here...
Rose! How have you been?
How are you, Al?
What ? Are you traveling again?
- Oh, you know her?
- Well, yeah, somewhat.
Al, where's Ed? Isn't he with you?
Ah, Brother isn't here today.
That's too bad. I really miss him.
- Oh.
- What?
Oh, I was just wondering
what that subtle expression
on your face was.
Don't go talking crazy!
Hey, Rose, I'm finished washing the pots.
Do you have anything else for me to...