Long time no see, Al.
I heard from Pinako
about your body and whatnot.
Ah, here he is.
Mr. Ho, could you give us a hand
for a bit?
Sure. Well, we'll catch up later.
The radio that you guys fixed
has been working fine ever since.
It's not even picking up static now.
I'm sorry.
It's all because we stuck our noses into
Cornello's business that everything...
Don't worry about it.
It's because you revealed
his underhandedness
that the town has regained its senses.
Sure, we had some violence and stuff,
but look at us now.
Sounds good, doesn't it?
The whole town is involved
in our reconstruction.
With all of our hard feelings left behind.
I'll be back in a while too.
Rose, can you take care of Winry?
Well, why don't we help too?
- Let's go, Yoki.
- What about supper?
It will taste better
if we work before we eat, right?
- Come on, you.
- Hey, let me go! Oh, the food!
That was your son back there?
Oh, dear,
maybe we shouldn't have called you.
You've been apart a long time, right?
Are you sure you should leave him alone?
Oh, I left home many years ago so...
He probably doesn't trust me
as his father,
and I have no idea
what to talk to him about.
Dad!
Well... I'll work too.
I'll carry that.
Here.
- Miss Winry, how is the water?
- Terrific!
I can't remember
the last time I had a bath.
I'll leave a change of clothes
here for you, okay?
Thank you very much.
Miss Rose is such a nice person.
I have to say, it's great
how you're an automail artisan
and so independent, as young as you are.
Are you the one who made Ed's leg?
Yeah. I guess you could say
it was out of our childhood friendship.
That's amazing. So you're the one
who made the leg that Ed stands on.
Then in a roundabout way,
you got me to stand up again.
So, Miss Winry, I am in your debt as well.
I believed in a miracle cure
that was supposed to bring
my dead boyfriend back to life,
and fell into Letoism.
It was then that Ed and Al
came to this town,
and exposed the priest's trickery.
Everything I had clung to up to then
vanished, and I lost hope.
Then Ed got angry at me.
He told me to stand up
and walk on my own legs.
I'm sorry! He's always like that.
I wonder why he can't be a little nicer.
He was being nice. That was Ed's kindness.
You understand it too, right?
Because of him, our eyes were opened.
Both mine, and the whole town's.
We're all trying to get back
on our feet on our own,
without relying on miracles.
And it's because of Ed and Al.
Ed...
Tagging along with the military guys
is one thing,
but it looks like I've found
a hell of a place to get lost in.
Mr. Greed...
Ethics is something that varies over time
and among individuals.
That is not where the reason lies.
It is to prevent the individual
from possessing
a powerful military force, General.
They aren't people.
- Are they dummies?
- That's right.
Receptacles shaped like people
to which souls are bonded
and soldiers created.
The greatest of soldiers
who will fight as we command them to.
An immortal legion, as it were.
- May I ask you a question?
- What is it?
Where do you procure the souls
that are to be bonded to them?
From those whose lands
we have ravaged or will ravage?
The battlefield is a hunting ground
from which we obtain
large numbers of souls.
Central is scary, awful, and appalling!
There's no way Mr. Greed
would be in a place like this.
An underground tunnel?
I want to check to see
if it runs under this town.
If it doesn't... No, I'm sure it does.
I'm going to--
Hold on a minute.
Let's go someplace where we won't be seen.
You're saying you came to Liore
to prevent the countrywide
transmutation circle from activating?
And when I saw you here, Dad,
I was surprised.
But at the same time, I feel lucky.
We saw someone who looked
just like you, Dad,
underground in Central.
I doubt you two have nothing to do
with each other.
I'll bet you know who he is. Don't you?
Are you sure you want to know, Alphonse?
What if I'm someone on their side?
As gabby as you're being,
it didn't occur to you
that I might leak it all to them?
Thanks for trusting me. I'm quite glad.
Even this boy can see me as his father,
and trust me.
Now then,
I suppose I should also trust my sons
and tell them everything.
This is going to take a long time
to explain.
I'd like to have Edward here
to hear it too.
Actually, Brother...
has gone missing.
Next, please.
I would like to withdraw some funds
from State Alchemist Edward Elric's
research expense account.
- And are you he?
- I am his representative.
I have a letter of attorney
and his signature.
Thank you very much.
This is Banks Bank, northern branch.
We have just had a cash withdrawal
from State Alchemist
Edward Elric's account.
The man claims to be his representative.
Yes, I would describe him
as a large, brawny man...
Here, this is for his medical expenses.
All right. I accept payment.
Oh, my, what a rip-off artist.
What are you talking about?
When you factor in the hush money,
it's reasonable.
Well, I guess it does help
that you're not asking
any questions about us.
Darius!
They're onto us, huh?
Yes, coming!
Ah, soldier, are you not feeling well?
We're looking for someone.
You just have the one patient?
Have you admitted anyone else?
There's one more inside--
- Are you the only patient here?
- Yes, that's right.
Do you need something?
You're the man who was at the bank,
aren't you?
Don't move!
Halt! Are you with this clinic?
Slowly bring your hands out
from under your covers!
Have you seen a stranger
enter or leave the clinic recently?
He's described as...
Well? Put your hands up!
...wearing a red coat, having blond,
braided hair, and being short.
What's going on?
- Harris! Snap to!
- Who got you? Hey, Harris--
Cohen! Harris!
What happened? Answer me!
You took them all by yourself.
Don't overexert yourself.
You still haven't recovered, have you?
Don't treat me like I'm an invalid.
I'm up and revving at full throttle now!
Thanks for everything, Doc.
Never mind the thanks.
Just hurry up and go.
We can't afford any more trouble.
They're searching for a red coat
and the braid, huh?
Looks like I'll be better off
in this getup for a while.
Freeze! Drop your weapons!
Fresh troops, huh?
Place your hands over your heads!
Do it now!
You there, it's too dangerous there!
Get away from them!
- Don't you move!
- You want us to blow this kid's head off?
- I'll get us some wheels!
- Okay!
Mr. Gorilla, they're after us!
- Don't call me a gorilla!
- They're catching up!
They're from the northern forces!
We'll never outrun them on snowy roads!
- That was close.
- Hey, how's it look behind us?
- It's no use! They're gonna catch us!
- Damn it!
Turn right here! Cut through there!
- What?
- Just do it!
I don't know what you're up to--
Once we're in there,
turn us around, quick!
Don't let them get away!
Where did they go?
I bet they turned at that corner!
We managed to give them the slip.
Hey, next time, transmute us
into something a little more plain.
What do you mean?
This looks cool as hell, doesn't it?
Just change it, okay? Please, change it.
What, you've got a problem
with my sense of style?
- It's too much!
- Once again, we've got no place to go.
- Yeah.
I've gotten held up something awful,
all because I dropped my guard
around that Kimblee bastard.
I wonder if Al was able
to safely rendezvous
with Winry and the others.
Hey, Fullmetal, are you listening?
What do we do now?
Right now, I need some information,
no matter what it is.
I have to get together
with Al and the others.
- So, where are they?
- Where should we go to meet up with them?
If I were Al, where would I go?
Think... Think...
Are you listening?
So, Dad, you were a slave
and you're a Philosopher's Stone?
Right.
You really don't believe me, huh?
Well, I can understand that.
If someone was told
my story out of the blue
and they bought it,
they'd have to be touched in the head.
If so, I guess I must be
touched in the head.
- You accept it? That was fast.
- To tell you the truth, I'm stunned too.
Then again, maybe it's because
I'm in this body and all.
Say, what does it feel like to never die?
How does it feel?
There's a lot about this body
that comes in handy.
But I hate how those dear to me
always die ahead of me.
Like Mom...
Say, Dad, if you're a Philosopher's Stone,
then you don't have a regular body, right?
So then, does that mean that we're...
Not exactly regular people?
It's all right.
The Philosopher's Stone
may be fused to my soul,
but ultimately, at my core,
I'm still the person that I am.
However, that guy in Central...
He's like a guy in a leather bag,
patterned after me.
- Leather bag?
- Yeah.
So, if we can destroy that leather bag,
we should be able to defeat him.
Defeat him... Oh, yeah!
They're about to use this country
to recreate what happened in Xerxes,
aren't they?
We have to stop them right away
or it will be disastrous!
Not bad. You've already figured
this much out, have you?
This is a
reverse transmutation circle, huh?
The quickest way is to destroy
the underground tunnel.
- It goes under here, so that's why--
- No, don't.
There's a real monster
of a Homunculus named Pride
lying in wait underground.
But if we don't act soon,
their transmutation circle will be...
- It could already be completed.
- Then that's all the more reason.
- It's not yet That Day.
- That Day?
Alphonse, don't just look downward.
Look up as well.
Do so, and something will come into sight.
Up? The sky? The Sun God Leto?
He is awaiting the "Coming Day."
What? What did I do?
Good. I love it when they're energetic.
Standing guard underground is so dull.
Folks like you are more than welcome.
The Ultimate Shield?
Not to mention that speech pattern
and way of laughing...
Damn it. Imitate Mr. Greed, will you?
That's right. I am Greed.
I'm impressed you knew that.
The Avaricious?
That's right.
Everything in the world is mine.
I want money, I want women,
I want status, and glory--
And everything else the world has!
- It can't be. But then again...
- Who are you?
Mr. Greed? Is it you?
How is it that you look like that?
I asked you, who are you?
It's me! Bido from Dublith!
Have you forgotten your friend's face?
Dublith? Oh, I see, I see.
You remember me?
Sorry.
That was probably the previous Greed.
- You mean...
- I don't know you.
Mr. Greed... we're friends...
My job is to eliminate intruders.
I'm sorry. I really am.
What?
Hey, hey, hey!
You really have sunk to a new low, Greed.
What's the idea,
killing one of your own friends?
He wasn't my... friend...
Then what are these memories?
Are you telling me
that what that Bido guy said
was cooked up too?
Those are the last Greed's memories!
Not mine!
Then why are you suffering so much?
Get a hold of yourself.
Steady on your feet, or my soul
is going to take my body back again.
The last Greed's soul
had his memories wiped clean!
- I've forgotten my whole past!
- There's no way you can forget it!
Friends are connected by their souls!
You can't just rinse out something
that has been deeply instilled
into your soul!
Look!
Their souls are crying out, aren't they?
You've cast away your soul family
and abandoned them!
Greed, is that what you call the avarice
that has to have everything?
How about this one?
I read it when I was just about your age.
It's the story of an adventurer
who travels the world.
What is it?
Who is it?