- Dear!
- Stay back.
Well, what's the meaning of this, Wrath?
It won't go away!
My head is pounding over this!
Why are you, King Bradley,
showing up in there?
What did you do to my stuff?
Your Avarice, huh?
You're a fool
who never gets rid of anything,
and craves even the past.
Damn it!
Sir!
Ma'am, are you and Master Selim
all right?
Yes.
I'm terribly sorry. The security patrol
was helpless against him.
Oh, don't worry about it.
He had quite formidable skill.
Yes, sir.
Father, go into retirement.
Olivier!
Here you come home
after being away for so long,
and what do you say to me out of the blue?
To transfer responsibility
over the family to me,
and spend the remainder of your years
at your leisure.
I was going to have Alex be my successor.
That pantywaist?
Why don't you leave everything to me
and take a long vacation
in some foreign land?
Alex would only drag
the Armstrong family name
through the mud.
Sister! You've returned home, have you?
- Oh, Alex, you're just in time.
- Yes, sir?
Fight Olivier.
Whoever wins gets to head the family.
Is that acceptable, Olivier?
Yes. I could ask for nothing more.
Olivier told me to retire
and go somewhere else, you see.
What? What insolence
to show to Father, sister!
Very well!
I will employ my whole body, soul,
and muscles to face you.
You've got some nerve, Alex.
I will show you just how callow you are!
Well then, let's be off.
- All right.
Where shall we go on our vacation?
What about Xing, dear?
I've heard that they have delicious food.
Then let's go there.
Is that all right with you, Catherine?
Yes, Father.
No! No!
- Wait!
- No take backs!
- Are you trying to kill me?
- You're just now figuring that out?
Good luck, brother.
What sort of souvenirs
shall we get for those two?
How about elephants?
They are huge and strong.
If they're getting elephants,
I want one too.
No!
That settles that.
The entire Armstrong family is now mine.
Sister, I heard that recently,
you have become quite chummy
with the military senior staff.
The senior staff is--
I make my judgments with my own eyes.
And having seen for yourself,
have you sent Father and the others away
so that they cannot be taken as hostages?
Get out, loser! This mansion is now mine.
Young lady, where are you going?
This is the farthest town east.
There's nothing but desert ahead.
I was about to go back to my home country.
- Home country?
- Yes. Xing.
- Across the desert?
- Yes.
- A girl crossing the desert by herself?
Hey, everyone!
All of you chip in.
Food, or anything else you've got.
- There's no need to...
- Don't worry about it.
Why don't you spend the night,
and leave tomorrow?
Come over to our place
and have a bath first.
Are you hungry?
Steve, you've got a lot of rooms, right?
Put her up.
Yeah, sure.
My oldest daughter's room is available.
You mean Emmy,
who went off to college in Central?
She turned out pretty good
for being your daughter.
Didn't she?
We'll have to get something
for the little kitty too.
- Oh, my, she's hungry, isn't she?
- She thinks you're her food.
Oh, don't be ridiculous.
That isn't true, is it, little kitty?
There, she says you look tasty.
Nice folks, huh?
You're going to just leave them behind?
Well, that might be for the best too.
Then again, if you go home carrying
a half-dead Homunculus like me,
I don't think it's going to do you
any good.
But if you go to Central,
you'll be able to learn the true method
of gaining immortality.
You might be able to save
these folks as well.
Oh, well, with you going back
to your home country,
they aren't any business of yours,
are they?
Everyone, thank you all for your kindness!
Where are you going?
There's something I've left undone,
so I'm going back to Central!
Fool! Once you get to Central,
you're all mine.
If only I had a Philosopher's Stone,
I could transform again.
If only I had a Stone...
- Where are we?
- A hideout that I've used before.
This is where your brother is, right?
Yeah. I know him like the back of my hand.
Al is definitely here.
Hey, there's no one here, is there?
You can't bank on this older brother.
We busted our tails fleeing from the north
and this is what we get?
Ling? I mean, Greed?
I'm hungry.
It's Ling.
I feel like myself again.
Thanks, that was good.
Same old overeating dumbass as ever.
- Our emergency rations are all gone.
- Are those guys your pals?
- Mr. Gorill...
- It's Darius!
I'm Heinkel.
We're former military,
but as circumstances would have it,
we're working with the kid here.
- Who is this guy?
- Let's see...
I'm not sure how to explain it to you.
- I'm a Homunculus.
- Hom--
- Hey, now, don't spill it so easily!
- Seriously?
It would take too long to lay it all out.
And what are you doing here anyway?
Greed went his separate way
from the Homunculus gang.
I took advantage of his agitation
and gained control of my body back.
I was looking for someplace near Central
where I could hide, and ended up here.
What's wrong?
This is bad. Greed is coming back.
Hey! Hey, hey, wait, wait, wait! Hold on!
Don't let him overcome you!
Keep your wits about you!
Listen to me! Ed...
That "Father" guy
that lives beneath Central
will open the doorway on "That Day,"
which is to come.
In my layman's opinion,
if you two brothers jump into it then,
you might be able to get
your original bodies back.
No, wait. That might be true, but...
in order to open the doorway,
a toll is required.
For what reason is he opening the doorway?
This "Day" which is to come...
Is there a set day
on which he's going to open the doorway?
- Well, I--
- Ling? Hey!
Damn it. Don't come back yet.
The message...
- Did you give Lan Fan the message?
- Message?
Al gave it to her. Lan Fan is all right.
We don't know where she is
right now though.
- Okay. Thank goodness.
- Ling?
Sorry. That's all for me.
Damn, lousy Xingese prince.
He talks far too much.
- Is that you, Greed?
- Yeah, that's right.
Give it up, you can't kill me with that.
Sorry to bother you.
Hey! You're gonna just let us skate?
Skate, nothing.
He told you earlier, right?
That I have washed my hands
of the Homunculi?
My memories got all jumbled up
and I attacked Bradley.
If I go back, there's no telling
what they'd do to me.
So I've gone and flown the coop,
and will live however I want to.
By myself.
You want to pal up with us?
If you've got nowhere to go, come with us.
Pal up? Pal up with you? That's rich.
Up yours! Everything in the world is mine!
Then again, if you wanted to work for me,
I wouldn't mind palling around with you.
Bye now.
Pal up? Even with all these souls
I have inside me....
I'm all alone, aren't I?
In that case, you should pal up
with Ed and the others.
If you don't like that idea,
give me my body back.
I'll become the emperor of Xing
and fill that emptiness.
- The king of the whole land, huh?
- That's a big deal, right?
What a brat. That's still small potatoes.
If I'm going to be anything,
how about becoming the king
of the whole world?
The world?
Hey, Ling, wait up!
What? You're such a pest.
Remember, I'm Greed.
I don't care who you are anymore.
It's too much of a hassle,
so I'll just call you Greeling.
- Hey, who are you calling Gree--
- I'll work for you, Greeling.
I said, I would be one of your men.
Which means that the Chimera fellows
that are with me now work for you too.
Hey, kid!
You can't go deciding that for us!
Don't get carried away,
you little beansprout!
Pipsqueak! Pee-wee!
Now that I think about it,
the moment I decided to become
a dog of the military,
I lost all pride
and everything else with it.
So wagging my tail
is no big deal to me anymore.
Besides, I can't very well let
any information slip away
or pass up this chance just because
I'm caught up in my emotions, right?
Not this one chance in a million.
How foolish.
Are you going to give yourself
over to your passion
and lose this precious information?
What a hoot!
To work for me is to become an outcast.
- Make sure you won't regret it later.
- Give me a break.
When it comes to having regrets,
I've got the inside track!
- What does that mean?
That settles it then.
So that means you're my men as well.
Whatever, suit yourself.
I don't care who I follow
as long as I get fed.
What kind of Chimeras are you?
- I'm part gorilla.
- I'm part lion.
Hey, that's pretty cool, huh?
I've still got her piercings.
It doesn't look like I'll be seeing
Winry or Al for a while.
"The day which is to come," huh?
I can't wait.
I've told you time and again,
please don't come here!
When Mrs. Izumi gets back,
I will contact you.
I can't get any work done
with you coming here all the time.
Yes, Curtis Butcher Shop.
Ah, thank you for calling.
About your order...
We'll be back.
Come by as a customer once in a while,
if you wouldn't mind!
MEAT DAY
Sorry, some military folks
were just here. Yeah.
You have a message from Alphonse
and a man named Hohenheim.
Yeah, got it.
SUBURBS OF NORTH CITY
The Promised Day, huh?
I see. That's a pretty big deal.
Briggs Mountain.
BRIGGS MOUNTAIN
Contact headquarters at once!
This is Point P! We're under attack!
- Who is it? Drachma?
- We don't know!
- What are the enemy's numbers?
- Just one!
Just one? Who is it?
Hey, I asked you who it was!
Point P! Who is it?
A housewife!
FORT BRIGGS
It's the same as those incidents
20 years ago.
An attack on a Mountain Guard
by a mysterious woman?
To be wiped out by a single woman...
Once General Armstrong gets back,
she's going to kill us.
- Major Miles.
- Good work.
PRISON CELL
An Ishvalan with dark glasses
and notches shaved into his hair
and a great big soldier with a mohawk.
Just like they told me.
I've been waiting for you two to show up.
Who are you?
I told you, I'm just a housewife
who is passing through.
I've brought a message from Al.
Can we talk someplace privately?
OUTSKIRTS OF NORTH CITY
Yes, sir. A message from Alphonse Elric.
It concerns "The Promised Day."
EAST CITY, GRUMMAN RESIDENCE
"The Promised Day."
Your timing is perfect.
This is starting to get interesting.
EASTERN COMMAND CENTER,
RIFLE RANGE
Hey, Rebecca!
I see your aim is as fine as always.
And so is your tushy.
Lt. General Grumman, what are you doing?
You can't go leaving yourself vulnerable
on the battlefield.
Incidentally, you and Lieutenant Hawkeye
are friends, right?
CENTRAL
- Hey, Riza!
- Long time no see, Rebecca.
There has been a change of plans
for the joint exercises
between the Northern and Eastern forces.
You know, because of that exchange of fire
between Drachma and Briggs.
They're going to change locations
and hold them in the east.
I heard so from the Fuhrer.
First, Colonel Mustang,
and now the Führer.
You have to set me up
with a nice guy from Central too.
Okay. Here's a nice guy.
Hayate, your master
is a cold-blooded skinflint!
Just you watch though.
I'll catch me a nice guy,
resign, and stay at home.
Yeah, yeah. Good luck with that.
Be sure to give my regards
to Lieutenant Havoc.
- Roger that.
- See you later.
"Be sure to give my regards
to Lieutenant Havoc," huh?
Once my condition stabilizes,
I'm thinking of transferring
to a hospital in the east.
Oh, yeah? We'll sure miss you.
In that case,
I wish I had brought you a proper gift.
These are for you. One per day, okay?
Thank you. I just barely ran out.
- All right, I'll come see you later.
- Thanks.
- Rebecca was concerned about you too.
- Sure, sure.
When the colonel comes by,
tell him I said hi.
Okey-dokey.
You heard her, Colonel.
There's no need for you to hide.
Both of us are being watched.
Any private, unwarranted contact
will draw suspicion.
Yum. Colonel, care to have one as well?
- No, I'm...
- Oh, come on. Just one.
"After the new year, in the spring,
on the Promised Day,
the north and east will make their move."