The Promised Day which was to come.
There were those who moved forward
their preparations
for this day that would shape
their destiny.
And so, time moves on, until the spring.
The Promised Day was about to arrive.
Is this a festival?
It's the Spring Sheep Festival,
a Resembool institution.
Sorry to interrupt you on a day like this.
We'd like to replenish our water.
Sure thing. Take as much as you'd like.
All right. Unload the tanks!
Looks like no one's home.
We're here, miss.
It smells like home.
There's automail all over the place.
Don't touch any of the pieces
in progress, okay?
It's so dusty in here.
What's wrong?
Edward Elric?
Intruders!
- What are you guys doing?
- Ling?
You guys are Kimblee's men!
You guys are from Briggs.
You've pursued us all the way here?
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
Lower your guns!
- You lower yours first!
- Ed, what in the world is going on here?
- It's a really long story.
- Where did you guys come from?
Is Kimblee with you?
And what are you doing in my room?
Kimblee's got nothing to do with us!
I like looking outside while I eat.
- Hear us out!
- You expect us to believe you?
Whatever. Just put your guns down!
Don't shout!
Shut that dog up.
This is a girl's bedroom! Get out!
I was worried.
Yeah... I'm glad you're okay too.
Isn't Al with you?
Ed, Al is at the train station
together with Mr. Miles.
They're leaving before long.
If you hurry, you might make it in time.
What's wrong? Aren't you going?
We're wanted men in Central.
It wouldn't be good if anyone saw us.
Yeah, but...
The sheep festival? That takes me back.
- We're just about ready to leave.
- Right.
I sure hope the next time
you come back here,
you'll have your original body.
Right.
Winry?
Welcome home.
I'm back. Sorry to have worried you.
I see we have some more
foul characters about.
We're terribly sorry
for all the commotion.
We are soldiers from Briggs.
We've been assigned to escort Miss Winry.
Ling, it's you, right?
Are you one of this guy's friends?
I'm Greed. Pleased to meet you.
And so, these guys are now working for me.
Why did you come here?
To get ourselves ready.
His automail needs maintenance.
- I want him in tip-top condition.
- Have a look at him later.
You're the one who made his automail,
so I can't do any of the fine tuning.
Okay.
Is that right?
Liore is getting back on its feet.
Good. That's been bothering me.
So, how come Al is with Major Miles?
The folks from Briggs
are going to be doing something
at some training ground in the east.
Al thought he might be able
to help out there, so he volunteered.
I see.
Ed, your father went to Central
a little before we left.
I hear he's in some slum named Kanama,
so go see him
and get the full story from him.
The Promised Day is almost here, right?
I heard about it from Greed.
The day is a chance for us
to get back to normal,
but it also could mean a huge tragedy
for the country.
- Listen...
- What?
Take Granny and Den,
and run away to some foreign country.
What do you mean, run away?
What good is having
only those close to you get away?
Can't you do anything to stop the country
from getting messed up?
I'm gonna stop it!
I'm going to stop it,
but there is that one chance in a million!
Don't give me one in a million,
or even a billion!
Those guys are about to do
something awful, right?
So slam the door shut on it,
and protect the country!
And then, Ed,
both you and Al come home
with your original bodies!
I'll do anything to make that happen!
You make it sound so simple.
What is this?
It's not like you to get discouraged.
- Hey, Ed!
- The girl doesn't know when to shut up.
Ed!
Nice girl you have there.
She wants to have it all.
Nothing good comes from wanting
something too badly.
Look here, I wanted someone
who was dead, and this is what I got.
Are you sure?
"I want to see someone who died,"
"I want money," "I want women,"
and "I want to defend the world,"
are all things that the heart wants,
or in other words, desires.
If I had to say it,
greed is neither good nor bad.
You humans get tripped up
because you presume to assign
value ratings to greed.
You're leaving at this hour?
We planned to leave today,
even if we hadn't run into you.
Thanks for servicing my automail.
If you happen to see Hohenheim,
give him the message from Trisha.
Okay, okay.
- Ed, I...
- You make sure you keep yourself hidden.
We're going to put an end to all of this
on the Promised Day,
and then come back home.
So bake us some apple pie and wait for us.
I put in a good day's work today.
Then again, are you sure
we should be doing this?
The Promised Day is almost here.
What else are we supposed to do?
Mr. Marcoh and Scar haven't come yet.
For Pete's sake, where are those two,
and what are they doing?
- Doc!
- Oh, it's you guys!
Don't "Oh, it's you guys" us!
Where have you been
traipsing around all this time?
All right... Let's head off for Central.
You know, it feels kind of funny,
doesn't it?
Imagine, us former soldiers
working together with an Ishvalan.
Yeah, yeah, for us,
Amestris is the land we were born in.
Our families are here.
But now, Scar, who rebelled
against this country,
is now taking action to save this country.
Think of it.
Don't get me wrong.
I'm not saving the country.
I'm changing it.
I'm acting to make this country
which rejected the Ishvalan people,
acknowledge our presence.
In order to change the world,
you must first be changed yourself.
That is how it is, Amestrisians.
- Ishvalans?
- But how?
We haven't just been "traipsing around"
for all these months.
These are friends
who share the same purpose.
I look forward to this again
this year, sir.
Well, happily, our exercises
are being held here this time around.
Having joint exercises in the north
is quite a pain.
- Everything is in place.
- We are all set up as well.
However, there is one small problem...
Problem?
Of all things,
Bradley has come to watch us.
The Promised Day is so close,
I was ready for them to send
someone to watch us, but...
Well, I guess we'll just have
to do something about it.
Not again.
The intervals where I'm being
pulled over there
are gradually getting shorter.
We have to hurry.
If I don't get back to my body soon...
I smell him! I smell him!
That's the smell
of the Fullmetal Alchemist's brother!
You're running away?
This is bad!
I can't fight him very well in my shape!
What is this?
Not now of all times...!
You're going to take it easy
until the Promised Day,
Alphonse Elric.
Hello there, General.
I've got no tea to serve
to the likes of you.
I may be able to invite you out
to dinner soon.
You've decided to deliver
on your promise from earlier?
I must say, you have a large mansion.
Just what you'd expect
of the Armstrong family.
You could fit a company,
no, a whole battalion in there.
If anything were to happen to me,
I could let you have the entire mansion.
It won't fit inside a casket after all.
You're not going to leave it
to your brother?
If it came down to giving it
to you or him,
I'd still rather give it to you,
but only by a whisker.
I'm honored.
Belated though it may be, congratulations
on becoming head of the Armstrong family.
Hyacinths.
"Selim Bradley is a Homunculus."
Do you know what hyacinths represent
in the language of flowers?
No.
Ladylike appeal.
You mind your own business!
Well then, I must be going, sir.
Little punk...!
THE DAY BEFORE THE PROMISED DAY
This is so stifling.
What do you say we avail ourselves
of the commotion
and blow the building Bradley is in
away with our cannons?
- Sir, please don't do that.
- Major Miles...
You still can't figure out
where Alphonse Elric is?
No, sir. The search is still ongoing.
But you don't think the other side
caught him, do you?
And here, the Promised Day
is tomorrow too.
Your Excellency...
General Hakuro.
Excellency, there is something
I would like to inform you
concerning General Grumman.
He's going to use the Eastern forces
to stage a coup d'état?
If so, it's what I would expect of him.
No, sir, the north and east
joint exercise is a decoy.
Excellency, with Central
under lighter guard
while you are here in the east,
the Ishvalan remnants
will carry out terrorist acts there.
Then General Grumman
plans to invade Central
under the excuse
of putting down the terrorists.
And working in concert
with Colonel Mustang,
he will take advantage of the confusion
and take control
of the Central Command Center.
Just as General Hakuro's
intelligence suggests,
for the last few days,
Ishvalans have been moving
into the areas around Central.
I am returning to Central.
You take over here.
Yes, sir.
That miserable Mustang! How outrageous!
And here, after we've defanged him
by stripping him of any usable pawns too!
- We've stopped.
- What's going on?
- Sheep.
- And us, in a hurry.
- Hey, only the engine has started moving.
- What?
What's going on? Hey, stop them!
We've cleared off the sheep
from the tracks.
We're headed to Central as planned.
- Let's go. The colonel is waiting for us!
- Yes!
Damn it!
They played you like a fiddle,
General Hakuro.
The train that His Excellency was in
has been blown up!
Tomorrow, everything goes into motion.
Let's do what we have to.
Lieutenant Breda, Sergeant Fuery.
Knock it off
with that "Lieutenant" business.
Right now, I'm just an ordinary deserter.
Aw, the way ahead is as murky as can be.
Once this is all over,
we'll get the colonel to answer for us.
- The Führer?
- Imagine, King Bradley, dead...!
- We still don't know that it's true!
- What's going on with the search?
The troops haven't reached the site yet!
As soon as their head is gone,
they're like this.
- Get them moving!
- Don't yell at me!
Besides, that's not my job!
- What a squawking rabble.
- Yeah, but...
- Is this any time to talk like that?
- Our commander-in-chief is missing!
- We know that!
- This could be my chance to act.
It is an honor to have you come here.
Calm down, everyone.
I am still here, in Central.