On the day before the Promised Day,
Alphonse Elric hid himself
at the East Area training grounds.
However, the Homunculi Gluttony
and Pride appear, and capture him.
Alphonse.
Wake up, Alphonse.
Who are you?
It's too soon for you to die.
There's still so much use
we need to put you to.
Excuse me, is this Kanama?
Mr. Ho.
You have a visitor.
So you've come, Edwa--
Ah, that feels better.
You didn't have to haul off
and slug me out of nowhere, you know!
And with your right hand too!
You've made some more friends. Whoa...
It just works out
that we're all in the same boat.
And incidentally,
I'm the boss of these guys.
Well, well, thank you
for looking after my son.
Not at all.
- And a damn sassy son he is.
- Shut up!
That's an unusual tattoo.
Ah, this?
I suppose there's no sense in hiding it.
Pops, don't keep back anything
from us either.
Tomorrow is the "Promised Day," right?
Yeah. I'll tell you everything.
I guess you can't accept this
as readily as Alphonse did.
You talked to Al too?
Yeah.
He probably has his own take
on some of it, but he accepted it.
I am the Philosopher's Stone
that you wanted.
- Will you use me?
- Don't be ridiculous!
Those are the lives of people
that have nothing to do with this!
There's no way we can use you,
when it's our own fault
we lost our bodies!
I'm glad my son would say so.
Tomorrow, there will be an eclipse.
He is planning to exploit it.
Exploit the eclipse?
Edward, will you help me
put a stop to his scheme?
Help you? Don't get the wrong idea.
I'll knock that bearded bastard's
block off
without teaming up with you!
It's just that right now,
it looks like banding together
assures our victory,
which is the only reason
why I'm listening to you!
Good.
Whatever your reasons are,
you'll still fight alongside me.
Granny Pinako asked me
to give Mom's last words to you.
"Sorry I couldn't keep my promise."
And "I'm dying first."
There, I told you!
Don't you think you should talk more
heart-to-heart with your old man?
Yeah, yeah. At least call him "Pop."
It sounds like there's been a lot
between you in the past,
but he's not the sort of man
who would abandon his wife.
I'm sure a lot has happened to him.
Go on, hear him out.
Aw, geez, shut up!
A lot has happened to me too!
Like what?
I'll bet you're just being stubborn.
You're not sure how to sort out
your feelings, huh?
I can't blame you.
He's a Philosopher's Stone,
in the form of a live person.
And what's more,
he also happens to be your father.
It's not just that.
He's not quite who I was expecting.
Someday, I'll be
a wrinkly old woman myself.
Even so, no matter what form I take,
I want us to be able
to all smile together.
So let's always stay a family.
Trisha, I'm going away.
Wait here for me.
Okay.
I'll wait for you.
"I'm sorry I couldn't keep my promise."
You've passed away first, huh?
I may not have been able to grow old
and die with you like you wanted,
but you always believed
that I would be coming back
to you later on.
Tomorrow, Trisha.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
What are you doing with that?
Are you planning to wear something
that flashy again?
Why does it have to be red?
This will probably be our last battle
against them.
I have to make sure
I'm all fired up for it.
Look, you guys don't have
to tag along with me.
I think it might be better for you
if we parted ways here, fellows.
Hey, now, you can't decide that
for yourself.
You work for me.
Or, do you, you know, want to get
your original bodies back, or...
I don't know.
There's a lot about these bodies
that comes in handy.
I wouldn't really mind staying like this.
That's more like it!
So then, why?
Well, you know,
we don't have anywhere else to be.
My animal instincts tell me
that if I stay here,
something good will happen to me.
What about you?
Didn't you say you'd split
from the Homunculi?
Are you asking
why I've returned to Central?
I'm not telling.
What is it?
Al!
Oh, it's you. Don't scare me like that.
I'm glad we managed to link up again.
How have you been?
- Brother, you're all right too.
- Huh?
I thought you were together
with Major Miles.
Is everything all right with them?
I need to speak to you about that.
Come here a minute.
Okay.
Al, is something the matter with you?
Why do you ask?
No reason, it's just that...
- Ed!
- Ling?
Get away from him!
That's...
He's...
What is this?
So you've gone over to their side, Greed.
To think you'd let the human
take you over again.
Your soul is too weak!
The Führer is still missing?
They say they've only found the body
of one of his subordinates downriver.
It would be a miracle if he's still alive.
I'll enlist the cooperation
of the Northern forces,
and direct the search myself.
You, personally, General?
I won't be able to rest until I see
his corpse for myself.
You're not going to make for Central,
as we first planned?
There's not much choice.
I'll have to let Colonel Mustang
have the bigger bite of Central.
The current Bradley administration
is still functioning
without any great difficulty.
If either Colonel Mustang
or General Armstrong starts anything now,
they'll be treated as rebels.
And if that happens,
that is when I step in.
After they are held up as the villains,
General Grumman will come riding in
on a white horse.
I'll let the youngsters
pull the chestnuts out of the fire,
so that I can take charge
of this country with little risk.
That's probably what the old fox
is thinking.
We've joined forces
with the Promised Day ahead of us,
but I can't let my guard down
until it's all over.
- Al!
- It's Pride.
Pride?
Yeah.
I guess you could say
he's our oldest brother.
A Homunculus?
You're going to betray us,
no matter what, aren't you, Greed?
At this point, you are nothing
more than an obstacle to us.
Damn it, how did you know I was here?
How dare you disguise yourself as Al?
It is not a disguise.
This is, indisputably,
your brother's body.
You bastard!
I'm going to deal with Greed now.
Fullmetal Alchemist,
would you be so kind as to come with me?
Hey, Mr. Gorilla, you guys run--
Whoa, you guys sure are fast!
Our animal instincts are telling us
not to fight with that thing.
Are you going to be all right?
I'll be fine.
They need Al and me,
so they won't kill us.
But I can go all out against them!
I won't hesitate to take them down!
You are correct. I will not kill you.
I might slice up two or three
of your limbs, though.
I can't afford to run toward the slums!
Guards won't work against this guy!
That was close!
Now then, I have captured your friend,
as well.
What will it be?
Will you do as I say
if I capture the slums' people, as well?
True to form, he goes right
after the last thing you want.
I can't stand to keep losing my fights.
- What's that?
- A blackout?
Hey, what's going on?
I can't see anything...
but then, his eyes have disappeared too.
- Greed.
- Is that you, Heinkel?
What is this? What's going on?
Oh, you only get shadows
when there's light.
When it's pitch-black,
he can't materialize,
and just like us, he can't see anything.
So he's gone, then?
He's just lying in wait.
When the lights come back on,
he'll return.
Hey, what do we do?
Heinkel, did you see
Alphonse's shadow earlier?
Yeah, with the snaky,
tentacle-looking things.
Not those.
He always kept near a large shadow, right?
His main body is somewhere
in the forest shadows.
Main body?
The suit of armor wasn't his main body?
No.
He has a specialized container
that he uses to go out in.
What kind of container?
The moon and stars are not out tonight.
The others cannot act
in this darkness either.
I'll just wait for the slum's lights
to come back on, and...
You're not getting away!
You're pretty good,
attacking me in this form
without even flinching.
Sure, I might hesitate to lay
into a little kid.
On top of which,
my animal instincts
are screaming at me!
They're saying that if I don't beat
this guy, I'm in deep trouble.
Ed.
- Hey, Ed.
- Is that you, Mr. Gorilla?
Where's your brother?
He hasn't moved.
Whenever he moves, he clanks.
All right, for the time being,
let's move away from here.
And leave Al behind here?
I know how worried you must be,
but what if we get close to him,
and it's a trap?
We have to stick together,
at least until Heinkel deals with Pride,
so we can avoid attacking each other.
That sound is the lion guy fighting?
When it's dark, leave the fighting
to the nocturnal animals.
Lousy Pride.
How did he know where we are?
Does he have that sort of ability?
Get down!
I smell the Fullmetal Alchemist,
I smell Greed.
- That voice, it's Gluttony!
- Him?
I get it.
So they used Gluttony's sense of smell
to track us down.
Sniff, sniff...
I also smell someone I don't know.
I can eat them, right?
You're up, Darius. He's a Homunculus too.
How am I supposed to handle
a monster-class opponent like him?
He's only relying on his nose
to move around.
If you take him now,
you'll be evenly matched, won't you?
My animal instinct is telling me not to.
But, hey, a man's gotta have nerve!
Victory favors he who strikes first!
And another!
That was brutal, Mr. Gorilla.
I thought we were sticking together
so we could avoid attacking each other.
Sorry.
I guess in the dark, we don't have
the upper hand against Gluttony.
But once the lights are back on,
there's Pride.
This is going to be tough.
Hey, Greed!
Is that you, Ling?
Switch with me.
I'm able to sense a Homunculus' presence.
I'm the one who realized Pride
was out there, right?
I can maneuver around better
in the darkness!
Don't go running off with this body!
Don't be ridiculous!
It was my body to begin with!
Time to eat--
There you are!
Oh, nice one. I'm glad I paired with you.
Thank you.
- Is that you, Ling?
- Yeah!
I'm mad, I'm hungry,
but you won't let me eat you right away!
So I'm gonna swallow you all!
- I sense something bad.
- Bad like what?
- Something's coming.
- Something like what?
It's the same as that time earlier.
Hey, what is it you guys are looking at?
Explain it to me, the normal guy!
What?
Huh?
- What?
- Hold still!
- Is there someone else out there?
- I don't know.
I don't know, but that's...
That smell...
I know it.
Thank goodness you're all right.
I've been waiting for you, Lan Fan!