Geez, because of you,
I'm dying again and again.
Look out!
Young lord!
Exchange greetings later.
Let's pour it on.
Right!
Let me eat you already--
You're overwhelming him!
You're quite the stud,
having a fine woman like her hidden away.
Thanks a lot!
As dark as it is here,
how do you know where I am?
The ruler of our land of Xing
has control over the dragon's pulse,
or chi, by which he governs the kingdom.
Those of us who serve our ruler
are also able to read the flow of chi!
Moreover, our role being what it is,
we can see well at night.
That voice...
Long time no see, kid.
It's old man Fu, all right. But how?
How did you know where we were?
We'd snuck into Central for a while
to see what was going on.
When we detected several large chi
moving toward here, we followed them.
There are two huge chi clashing
with each other right nearby.
That would probably be Greed and Gluttony.
Greed, the one who swallowed up
the Young Lord.
And then, there's another huge chi
out there in the forest.
My companion is fighting a Homunculus
right now, named Pride.
Hmm...
And finally, there's one more,
in the nearby settlement.
There's something unparalleled
about that one.
That's probably Ed's old man.
Him?
Your father is not human?
For now, we can leave him alone.
First, we have to do something
about these Homunculi.
Don't worry about Gluttony.
Let Lan Fan take care of him.
Let her take care of him?
She's only had her automail
for six months, hasn't she?
That's crazy, old-timer!
If we don't go help her,
she'll be in hot water.
Don't worry, hand-to-hand combat
is not our only weapon.
Give us some warning before you use those.
What was that? An explosion?
- What was that?
- From inside the forest?
- Aren't the lights back on yet?
- Hey, bring a lamp over here.
Geez...
Well, if that's the case,
I guess we can relax.
Old man Fu,
what else do you have besides bombs?
Hmm? All sorts of things.
Tear-gas bombs, flash bombs, flares.
The lights in the slums
have started to come back on.
Those snaky things
are going to start appearing again.
If we don't do something fast,
Heinkel will be in deep trouble!
Yeah.
Old man Fu, would you take me
to where Pride is?
There's something I'd like you
to help me out with.
As you wish.
Ed.
You watch yourself.
Remember, Pride,
the guy Heinkel is fighting, is...
Die already, would you?
You were right, Roy.
Selim Bradley is not,
strictly speaking, human.
These are old photos.
Twenty years ago...
This one is from 50 years ago.
In each age, he's with the government.
I checked into the town that the Führer
is supposed to be from too.
While there are records of him
being born and raised there,
there isn't a single person
who has ever seen the Bradley family.
The mansion at the address listed
was a dummy
and it goes without saying
that there are no relatives.
Thank you, Madam Christmas.
It must have been tough
to investigate all of this.
Yeah.
But the moment I found out
that Selim wasn't human,
all my fatigue just disappeared.
I have to wonder why
this has never gotten out before.
Because he is the son
of the man called King,
the top man in our military state.
They can fabricate anything they want to.
- You, bastard!
- Hey!
Who's there? Is someone there?
It's a monster!
Oh, no! That child!
Damn.
All I need is this much light
to make shadows.
Goodbye, Mr. Chimera.
That was a close one, pops.
Imagine, this little kid
being a Homunculus.
You had me fooled, Selim Bradley.
Outward appearances are only symbolic.
Isn't that right, my little alchemist?
Where is he? Where is Roy Mustang?
He's still inside.
It's been a long time,
for being his usual bar.
That woman in there, Madam Christmas,
her real name is Chris Mustang.
She's his foster mother.
Damn it!
Ah, my poor chateau.
Forgive me. I'll buy you another one.
Well, then, okay.
I have to go underground
for a while, anyhow.
Are the girls in the bar all right?
Don't you worry.
By now, they're under the skies
of a foreign land,
enjoying themselves,
and have long since forgotten about you.
Never mind them.
You should be thinking
about what's going to happen tomorrow
in this country.
If the next time we meet,
you're inside a body bag,
branded as a rebel,
you'll have to answer to me.
Thank you, Madam.
I will make sure to repay you.
You'll remember me
when you've made it big.
In that case, I'll really look forward
to the next time we meet, Roy.
I wish she'd stop treating me
like a little boy already.
Now, then, I guess I should start moving.
You're late, Colonel.
We almost left without you.
Your wry comments sound
so reassuring to me now.
- Did you make sure you weren't followed?
- Yes, sir.
If anything were to happen,
this little guy would react.
Okay.
We'll be counting on you.
What are the Bradley family's activities?
I've got the schedule for all
three of them for the next three days.
The Führer went to the training grounds
in the east.
Selim went along with him.
Regarding that,
the train that the Führer was riding in
plunged to the bottom of a ravine.
You don't say.
Old man Grumman
takes some drastic measures, huh?
The watch level will be elevated now.
It might make what we're doing
more difficult.
What about our mission?
Will the Eastern forces be coming
into Central, as planned?
The Führer is missing.
Is this a once-in-a-lifetime chance,
or are we walking into a trap?
Even if it is a trap,
we've got no choice but to move forward.
Your orders?
Right now, we're holding a one-way ticket
to the battlefield.
Win or lose,
there's no turning back from this.
The reason being that once
this primary mission is over,
we still have the great task of rebuilding
this nation, with me as its Führer,
waiting ahead for us.
Which means that you've only got
one order to obey.
Don't die.
That is all.
Yes, sir!
Why? Why can't I cut through him?
Looks like keeping my northern automail
was the right decision.
This carbon fiber is proving quite useful.
Carbon reinforcement?
He's copying Greed, is he?
In that case...
What's the matter?
Is that all you've got?
Sure enough, I'll have to...
Al!
Using your brother to fight you
should give me the advantage.
Old man Fu!
A flash bomb!
Oh, no!
I've had enough of those guys.
What?
Lan Fan, what's wrong?
Lan Fan!
- Mr. Gorilla!
- Right!
Al!
Mr. Gorilla,
take Al and get away from here.
You're sure he's not still possessed?
The parts that get cut off
from the Homunculus' main body
disperse and disappear.
Now that Al's insides are cut off
from the main shadow body,
Pride is no longer in there.
You won't get away!
Here's another one!
Say, what was that light before?
- It hurts, it hurts!
- You've really done it now.
You're a real mess, aren't you?
Well, it's because that girl and Greed
were acting funny.
They knew where I was,
even when it was so dark.
They what?
Perhaps she is the warrior from Xing
that Wrath mentioned,
the one who could sense
the presence of Homunculi.
So you've turned yourself over
to the Xingese prince,
and he's using that ability, then?
Miserable Greed.
Gluttony, how many times
have you been killed?
I don't know.
I've been killed a lot though.
I've been beaten up pretty badly myself.
The way things are headed,
we could be wiped out by them.
Then, we could have Father fix us--
No.
No, Pride.
No! Don't eat me.
It hurts. Help me, Lust.
He devoured his own kind.
Ah, this is more convenient.
I can detect your scents quite well now.
I could do without the feeling of hunger
that comes with it though.
That scent.
Are you nearby, Hohenheim?
Mustang appears to be using
his former subordinates
and is sneaking around somewhere.
If the explosion of the train
that was carrying the Führer
and the many Ishvalans
that are coming into Central
turns out to be tied to him...
And with this timing, of all things...
You are all more familiar
with the way he thinks than I am.
What will be his next move?
If it were me,
I would first take Mrs. Bradley
into my custody.
You mean as a hostage?
That would be futile.
He's going to take a useless hostage,
and brand himself a traitor?
Humans are absolutely impossible.
Hey! What are you doing?
Roy Mustang?
I'm terribly sorry for this,
at such a late hour, ma'am.
Lieutenant Hawkeye?
Why are you doing this?
Please forgive this abrupt offense.
If you would be good enough
to come quietly with me,
I have no intention
of bringing any harm to you.
Please, come with me.