Ed fights alongside Lan Fan, now back,
against the Homunculus Pride.
As the difficult battle carries on,
Ed successfully works out a plan
to safely get Al back from him.
However, Pride takes in
his partner, Gluttony,
and obtains his abilities.
Elsewhere, Mustang joins up
with Hawkeye and the others.
They kidnap the Führer's wife,
and hold her hostage.
Al, wake up.
Hey, Al! Can you hear me?
Alphonse!
That smell...
Edward Elric!
If I capture you, Hohenheim will be forced
to come forward.
Ed!
- Young Lord!
- Afraid not.
I'm Greed.
Why, you...
Give the Young Lord back his body!
That's something I'm afraid I can't do.
Here he comes!
Are you all right?
Who asked you to help?
Shut up! Your arm
still isn't at its best yet, right?
That's none of your affair!
Right now, you just worry about yourself.
We're going to need your help
down the road.
- Keep going!
- Sorry, I couldn't bag him.
Don't worry about it.
Can't fault you
for not being able to defeat him.
He's a monster, even by my standards.
Wake up...
Alphonse!
Dad?
Yo.
If you're here, Dad, then is this Kanama?
That's right.
How did...? When did I...?
Oh, right! Pride!
Dad, the Homunculus Pride
came inside my body.
I heard all about it from Mr. Gorius here.
That's "Darius."
Rats.
It was like he was interfering
and it felt icky.
Those guys are almost like clones
of a clone of me.
As my son, it might be easy for them
to interfere with your blood seal.
Old man Fu.
Would you see to caring for this man?
What's the situation like over there?
- Are you Edward's father?
- Yes, I am.
The shadow monster
devoured the one named Gluttony,
and he's beyond our control.
Greed and Edward are fighting him,
but the situation is not good.
This is all my fault.
Everyone is in this mess
because Pride caught me.
The fires have created
too many light sources
and I've run out of flash bombs.
The same tricks won't work any longer.
This is bad.
The way things are headed,
the people in the slums are going
to be caught in the middle of this.
Dad...
You're a big-time alchemist, right?
Yeah, I'm not half bad.
I have a favor to ask,
and I'm counting on your skills.
There.
The view is much better now.
It won't do any good
to hide behind anything.
Your smell gives you away.
Damn! Hey, you still alive?
More or less.
Is this any time to be worried
about others, Greed?
I wonder how much longer it will be
before you are dead?
You monster...
That's a rather rude thing to say
about your brother, Greed.
May I eat you now?
You eat me
and you'll upset your stomach, brother.
You're finally making an appearance...
Hohenheim.
Heroes always arrive late, you know.
Hero? Are you saying
you mean to defeat me?
No, I couldn't do that.
You really are a fright, after all.
What is he thinking?
Is he after something?
Here he comes!
Oh, what a pathetic strategy.
You don't know when to give up.
Al!
To think that you would come back here
to be my hostage.
What a curious boy your son is.
Don't you put...
my son down.
Hohenheim!
Amazing.
He confined him.
What is this?
You trapped Al in there, too, you know?
What are you thinking?
It wasn't my idea.
Al suggested we do this.
It worked!
You can't use your abilities like this.
Is this any time to be laughing?
You can't get out of here, either.
The instant you open up a crack
trying to leave,
I'll use my shadows to--
I never meant to leave here
in the first place.
What do you say
we have a test of endurance, Selim--
Or rather, the Homunculus Pride?
My body is just fine with having
no oxygen, or light, or food.
All day today, until the Promised Day,
you are going to stay put right here,
together with me.
It's too difficult to try
to defeat Pride right now.
However, the way things were going,
there would be too much damage done
to the surrounding area.
So instead of fighting him,
we used me as a decoy,
and pinned him down.
Now we've bought ourselves some time
to put together some countermeasures.
So without even discussing it with me--
He said, "If we tell Brother,
he'll definitely be against it."
This is what came of him
thinking up a way for everyone to survive.
Try to understand.
Now, let's get these fires out.
Al!
Brother!
I'm sorry.
Here we were finally reunited, too.
But then, I was the reason
why all of this happened to begin with.
Besides, I only have to put up
with this for one day.
I'll be fine, Brother.
Lust is gone, Envy is gone,
and Gluttony is out of commission.
Wrath is at the training ground
in the east, and Pride is stuck here!
Right now, the only ones here in Central
are Daddy and Sloth.
Greed, what are you thinking?
I told you.
I'm going to be king of the whole world.
Doesn't it seem like lately,
there are more Ishvalans in Central?
Yeah, yeah.
There seem to be quite a few of them
around those abandoned buildings
in the west.
Speaking of Ishvalans,
I wonder how that X-scarred fellow
who was here before is doing now.
- Hey, it's the X-scarred fellow.
- Speak of the devil, here he is.
I'm looking for the Kanama slums.
Kanama is in the woods,
on the outskirts to the south.
Oh, yeah? Thanks.
Come to think of it,
isn't that girl with you?
You know, the girl who had
that black-and-white cat with her.
She came back here a little while ago.
- What?
- She didn't go back to her home country.
What is she doing?
Hey, you guys have finally done it!
What do you mean?
You're the ones who blew up Bradley
in his train out east, right?
Blew up?
- You mean you weren't?
- It's news to us.
Oh, and here I was sure you grouped up
with the other Ishvalans
and pulled it off.
Yeah, that business about them
pulling terrorist acts
is just hot air, that's all.
They have not come together
to do anything like that.
They're important friends
who are trying to change the country
without terrorism.
There are limits as to how devoted
one should be to his work.
The new suit I went and had made
has gotten dirty.
The main event doesn't start
until after the sun goes up, either.
It's no use.
I doubt my dad made it such that a chi
could do anything about it.
This is what happens
when you deride humans so much.
You guys don't understand
a single thing about us humans.
You shouldn't think that everything
is going to go your way.
That plan of yours, for example.
The way I see it, it was perfectly sloppy.
Sloppy?
Yeah. It sounded
like there were sacrifices to it
and you were going to use us
to try to do something.
But if we were to run away
to some foreign country,
at that point, your plans
would have gone up in smoke.
It's true, there are humans
that only think about themselves.
However...
Yes, Wrath's wife, for example.
Once, in town, there was an incident
where I was nearly hit by a car.
When it happened,
she risked her life to try to save me.
Even though she didn't know
I was a Homunculus,
I was unexpectedly thrown for a loop
by her rashness.
I have a father, but I did not have
what you would call a mother,
so to be honest,
I have been most intrigued by her.
I wondered if this was what
having a mother was like.
Wrath's wife...
You mean Mrs. Bradley, right?
Yes, that's right.
I can't believe
you tricked that nice woman.
It's true,
I was just playing house with her.
However, living life with her
was enjoyable,
and I did like it.
- So then...!
- There are humans...
There are humans, like Wrath's wife,
who will throw away their own lives
to protect what is dear to them.
And then there are you guys,
that were chosen to be sacrifices,
who have even stronger spirits.
There's no way you could have abandoned
this country and escaped.
In fact, you came back here
just to fight me.
So in no way were our plans sloppy.
Colonel...
It's almost time.
Yeah.
Let's go, Lieutenant.
What is this?
What in the world happened?
And what's with that mountain?
Well, if it isn't Jerso and Zampano!
Darius!
Are you here under orders from Kimblee
to kill all of us?
What are you talking about?
We quit being Kimblee's servants
a long time ago.
So you say, then you'll wait for us
to lower our guard
- so you can kill us, right?
- As if I would do that!
I don't trust you.
I'll bet Heinkel is hiding nearby,
about to attack us, isn't he?
Dr. Marcoh!
- Get over it already, you idiot.
- Edward.
You wanna go at it, you swine?
- And Scar is with you, huh?
- What did you say?
I hate to ask when you just got here,
- but we have to get set up.
- Shut up!
Hey, you! Piggy, tubby, and gorilla,
stop fighting!
Why, you! You want a fight, do you?
Oh, so you really have quit
as Kimblee's men.
Working under him,
it was obvious that we were expendable.
I know what you mean.
And, as a result,
we've ended up as fugitives,
but it sure feels good.
Yeah. What's more...
these guys aren't going
to run out on us.
It's finally gonna start,
once the sun comes up.
Yeah.
I sure hope everyone lives
through this all right.
Looks like they're done talking.
Where did the old guy go?
He went to go check out the city.
- By himself?
- Yeah.
He said he was the only one among us
whose face hasn't been shown to the enemy
so it would be better for all of us
that way.
He said he would also get a handle
on Colonel Mustang's movements.
He's probably also wondering
what Lin is up to.
Ah, that makes sense.
Is your meeting with Scar
and the others over?
Yeah.
We've set up our mission.
You have, huh? Then it's almost time.
Your younger brother
is a real piece of work.
Staying in the darkness
with that monster like that.
If it were me, I'd be flipping out.
Al's really giving it his all, huh?
The rest...
is up to us to do.
The Promised Day has started.
Brother! Brother! Hey, Brother Denny!
Pipe down!
What is it?
Hurry and get up. It's about to start.
What's about to start?
The eclipse!
Eclipse?
Okay, look,
what time do you think this is?
It's not yet time
for the eclipse to start.
Hey, don't look at the sun!
You'll ruin your eyes!
I know that much, at least.
Brother, come here, come here!
There's smoke rising from the city!
Don't you guys go outside today!
Cedi Squad in the western sector
has discovered and engaged
Mustang's group in Sector C75.
However, they have taken
the Führer's wife as a hostage,
so we're having trouble handling him.
- No matter. Attack.
- Sir?
All we need is to keep Roy Mustang alive.
The wife has no practical value.
Have his men eliminated.
Don't move!
Are you going to shoot?
You're free to shoot everyone
but Colonel Mustang!