You're free to shoot everyone
but Colonel Mustang!
They're free to shoot everyone
but Colonel Mustang?
They're free to shoot the missus?
Those are words that I wanted to hear.
Have I...
I mean, has my husband
been forsaken by this country?
Or has my husband forsaken me?
I do not know.
However, I promise you,
we will protect your life.
To prove to you,
once everything is over,
that we were not wrong.
Reinforcements coming in! Hurry!
We've spared your lives.
If we had been Briggs soldiers,
you'd be dead.
What?
Colonel, long time no see.
Good work. Where is General Grumman?
Finishing up with the train accident.
You haven't told the missus
about the Fuhrer going missing?
No, if she faints or anything,
it will be harder to move her.
This place is teeming with them.
You're quite popular, Colonel.
You got that right.
Haven't you dealt with him yet?
What are you doing?
There are only five of them!
- The enemy force has increased!
- There's a platoon's worth of them now!
- What are our losses?
- Fifty-nine men injured, zero dead.
Zero?
- Damn it! Are you all right?
- Yeah, more or less.
That guy's the Flame Alchemist,
a hero of the Ishval Civil War.
But he doesn't seem all that impressive.
You're right.
He's made nothing
but harmless explosions.
Jess! Parky!
Damn, that blew my eardrum out!
- What's the toll?
- Five wounded, none dead!
We're lucky nobody got killed.
They've got both the Hero of Ishval
and the Hawk's Eye.
It's strange that none of our men
have been killed.
Unless...
No doubt about it! They're...
They're going easy on us?
Yes, sir. We have many wounded.
But there's zero fatalities.
Even those who have been shot
have been hit in non-critical areas.
They're mocking us.
Send Dimitri Squad and Kim Squad!
Stack up the bodies of Mustang's men
right here, immediately!
Hasn't Mustang been caught yet?
What is General Cremin doing?
They aren't killing our men,
but instead,
they're whittling down our forces.
There's no way they can keep up
their crafty little charade.
Colonel Mustang is too soft.
Absolutely. What is he thinking?
And nothing is softer
than the Central forces
who can't defeat him.
They're almost like children playing.
What was that?
Come to think of it,
there was a single rebel
who nearly froze
the command center, right?
Ever since the nation's founding,
there hasn't been a large enemy force
that has attacked Central.
The lack of experience
is painfully obvious.
Their offense may be good,
but their defense is awful.
How about it?
Why don't you let me have
a few of the Central forces?
Don't get carried away, Armstrong!
Do you think you're in your position
because of merit?
You're just being detained here.
We know there's a strong connection
between you and the Briggs' forces.
That's why keeping you detained here
is a powerful deterrent against possible
rebellion from the Briggs soldiers.
You people don't know a thing about us!
I've told them to abandon me
if there is an emergency.
The law of Briggs
is survival of the fittest.
Even if I were to kick the bucket here,
they are a force that can
just write me off as being weak
and keep on moving.
That's who the Briggs soldiers are.
Don't speak about the men I've trained
as if you know who they are!
Colonel Mustang is exchanging fire
in the manufacturing quarter
on the west side.
There are many soldiers
being dispatched there.
We're moving out.
You can kiss this cellar goodbye.
Sink your teeth into the windpipes
of those Central pantywaists!
See? Here they come.
They are men of valor,
who are more than a match
against the bears of Briggs Mountain.
I wonder which is stronger,
them or your vaunted dolls?
Damn!
New forces?
Impossible! Where did they come from?
They just suddenly appeared
in the middle of town.
What is this sorcery?
How did they do that?
You guys head in there, too!
- What are the enemy numbers?
- Unknown.
However, judging from their gear,
I believe they are Northern soldiers.
From Briggs?
Inside the Armstrong mansion?
Yeah, using the repairs
to the mansion as a cover,
we moved soldiers and weapons
into the cellar.
Just how huge is that house?
- Charlie, give me some ammo.
- Sorry, but I'm out, too.
What do we do?
Isn't the supply unit here yet?
Did they get captured?
Listen, if it comes to that,
leave me here and go.
Roger that!
Don't you mean,
"We'll stay with you until the end"?
I'm not going out surrounded by men.
I've got a wife waiting for me at home.
Ah, you don't say!
They've all but stopped fighting back
with their guns.
Could they be out of ammo?
All right, we're moving in on them!
Round up everyone we have left!
- Yoo-hoo, Riza!
- Rebecca, you're late!
Sorry!
I've got some nice presents
for those of you who've been waiting!
- Awesome!
- It's not just ammo, either!
Way to go, Rebecca! I love you!
Shut up! Men without money
don't get to flirt with me!
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
Long time no see, Colonel Mustang.
Second Lieutenant Maria Ross,
returning without orders!
Why aren't those guys charging in here?
We've got the Flame Alchemist with us,
so they have to be careful
about approaching.
But we're in the middle of town,
so the colonel can't get too wild
with his flames.
Oh, dear, I came to Central
to snag me a nice man,
but you're all a bunch of wusses!
Damn it!
It's a tear-gas bomb from Xing.
It's got extra pepper spray.
By any chance,
did you get all of this from Xing?
I didn't know that you were part
of this operation.
Did you procure these weapons
all by yourself?
Or did someone else order this?
Would you like to speak
to them personally, sir?
Okay!
Here you go.
Some dignitary from Xing?
This is Colonel Roy Mustang
of the armed forces.
I am honored to be able to...
Man, you sound so respectful!
Let's just talk
in our regular tone, Colonel.
In your hearts for 80 years,
with everything from underwear bands
to armored vehicles,
delivered to you, anytime, anyplace,
just a phone call away...
We're your neighborhood
Havoc general store!
Havoc!
So, who's footing the bill?
I'll pay you when I've made it big.
Start a tab!
There's smoke rising in the city.
I can hear sirens, too.
Looks like the colonel
and the Briggs guys are on the move.
Central is in chaos right about now.
We should get going.
Yeah, the nationwide
transmutation circle counter is in place,
but it's best to keep it
from activating in the first place.
He's still inside a flask.
He's just gotten a lot bigger.
If we smash his container, he'll die.
We can also free the souls of people
that he has trapped inside him.
But how do we get to where he is?
We use the underground passageway
that I took with May earlier.
There will be a ton of vicious Chimera,
but we should make it through.
- Heinkel, hold down the fort here.
- Yeah, I owe you one.
Don't worry about it.
Dr. Marcoh,
don't let the military find you.
Yoki. You stay behind, too.
Gladly!
- Al.
- What is it, brother?
I'm going to pop out for a bit
and kick that underground bearded guy.
Be careful.
Yeah.
The city sure is in an uproar, huh?
We should hurry.
Father is about to show off
the secrets of immortality.
I know!
We'll cordon off this area!
Don't let Mustang's squad
or the Briggs soldiers
get past this point!
Tell your soldiers to pull out!
You're the ones who stole the command
of Briggs away from me, right?
Do you think you will get away with this?
What about you?
You must have heard of that "Father" guy.
What he's going to sacrifice
and what he's going to obtain.
Yeah, I heard.
Those of us who were chosen
will rise even higher,
while Amestris changes the world!
The pain that accompanies this change
cannot be avoided!
Why can't you understand that?
You guys are hopeless.
What?
Scum like you, who watch the battlefield
from the comfort of a safety zone,
make pain out to be something lofty
and exploit it.
You're going to turn traitor?
Who knows?
Once this is all over, I might be a hero.
However...
You'll find that I'm not as merciful
as the Hero of Ishval!
Wait!
- What?
Sir!
Major Armstrong!
Sergeant Brosh.
Isn't this your day off?
I saw the smoke from my house.
What's going on, sir?
Colonel Mustang and his former men
have taken the Fuhrer's wife hostage
and are fleeing through town.
What?
How cowardly of him!
First, he kills
the innocent Lieutenant Ross.
And now, he has Mrs. Bradley!
The man's the devil in disguise!
Major!
General Armstrong
just shot General Gardner
in one of the command center
conference rooms.
She killed him?
Things are progressing faster
than I imagined.
I have to find the Young Lord soon.
Then again, I can't trace his presence
because the gigantic flow of chi
from underground is interfering.
My word...
It feels like the underground presence
has spread itself out since yesterday.
This won't work.
The military is using it
as a rallying point.
We can't get near it.
Looks like it's going to be hard
to force our way through.
There is another way in!
The Third Laboratory!
Al and the colonel broke inside
that place before
and fought that Homunculus!
There are three guards at the entrance.
Well, then, let's have a go at them.
No, a situation like this
calls for me to use my title.
Hey, Mr. M.P.!
I'm Edward Elric, the State Alchemist.
A State Alchemist?
Please help me! I'm being chased by Scar!
The man on the wanted list!
Don't move!
That was pretty mean of you.
Shut up. Let's go.
Excuse us, coming through.
I'm sure it was right around here...
Here it is!
- Should we split up into two teams?
- Yeah.
I'll go this way.
Edward and Scar, you go that way.
What?
Why do I get stuck with him?
Call it "distribution of alchemic power."
Besides, when he used
his alchemist-stopper technique,
Scar could still use his,
but you were helpless, weren't you?
Okay, that settles it.
These two are a pair. Anything else?
I'm a bit beyond standard,
so I should be fine on my own.
However...
As long as she's here,
why don't I take the Xingese young lady
along as my bodyguard?
All right, once we find him,
we'll smash him with all our might.
Roger that!
Are you sure you'll be okay
with just the two of you?
Yeah, I'll be fine.
This old man would be happier
with just the young lady.
- Dirty old man.
- Come on, let's go.
You need to search
for the Xingese prince, right?
Go on.
But...
Don't worry about us.
He's dear to you, right?
Thank you very much.
Seriously, what a pathetic bunch.
They can't even handle
those Briggs Mountain monkeys!
Please wait!
The multiple soul-bonding tests
haven't been--
Shut up!
If we don't use them now, when will we?
We worked so hard
to make these Philosopher's Stones
for a time like this, right?
Now, move! Dig into those rebels!