- It hurts!
- Save us!
- I'm hungry!
- It hurts!
- Big Brother!
You say that the multiple-body tests
aren't done yet?
This is your test and it was successful!
Undying, obedient, mighty soldiers
who will fight however we order them to.
The Immortal Legion is born.
Papa?
Yes, I am your father.
Now, listen very closely
to what I'm about to say.
There are multiple renegade elements
that are trying to take
this command center.
Papa.
You men are to--
- It hurts.
- It hurts!
That sure is a huge doorway.
The air here seems nasty somehow.
- Are you sure this is it?
- Yeah.
- It's just like Al told me.
- Huh?
Who is this?
Number 66, Barry the Chopper.
He was Slicer's partner.
Come on! Come on!
Damn it, how do you open this?
Step aside.
Oh, it opened?
Tell the Central soldiers
that are fighting with Mustang
and the Briggs soldiers to pull back.
Whoa, are you going to open fire?
Your subordinates aren't
all that disciplined, are they?
Pull them back now.
The Briggs soldiers will not hesitate
to continue fighting them.
Do you want to lose
every last soldier you have?
Close the north, south, east,
and west gates
of the Central Command Center!
Don't let a single one of Mustang's
soldiers or the Briggs soldiers inside!
Oh, it seems you have some guts after all,
however rotten they might be.
Don't be too full of yourself, woman!
We will crush all of you
Briggs Mountain monkeys!
What?
Oh, over there.
No, he told me to kill you.
What a pain.
Ha! Another seat opens up ahead of me!
You have my thanks, Homunculus!
Now, I don't have to sully this sword
that was passed down through
the Armstrong family for generations
with his despicable blood!
You bastard!
They don't die?
It hurts.
Mama.
- So hungry.
- It hurts.
- It hurts!
Big brother!
It can't be.
These mannequins have human souls
possessing them?
Damn it, they just keep coming!
What are these things?
How should I know? And why won't they die?
This is bad.
If these things get outside...
- Did something happen?
- Beats me.
Word is that Colonel Mustang
is leading a coup d'état.
What a dangerous affair.
There, there, don't cry.
What do we do?
Damn you!
No! They're going to get out!
Sorry, I blocked the exit.
Don't worry about it.
If you hadn't done it,
I would have busted the exit open.
Now, we can brace ourselve for the worst.
Okay, then,
now that our outside concerns are gone,
this is our chance to show our stuff!
- Mama!
- It hurts!
- It hurts.
- Help me!
How could they create these things?
We have to go through them
if we want to reach the bearded bastard!
This a real pain in the ass!
Mustang is fleeing in an ice cream truck!
Seal off the main roads!
It's disguised as a civilian truck,
but it's loaded with weapons
and ammunition!
Look sharp!
A bear! A bear with a mohawk!
Transmission was cut.
A bear with a mohawk?
That's Captain Buccaneer,
from the Northern forces.
Colonel, it looks like it's going
to be hard to get into town.
You're right.
An ice cream truck, huh?
I wonder if the guys are doing all right.
It sure is aggravating
not being able to fight with them.
Who knew that just sitting around
could make you so restless?
I've been hearing that sound
ever since yesterday.
Hey, Alphonse! What's that sound?
Selim is playing around with my head.
Whatever he may be on the inside,
he's still just a kid.
Stop him, Alphonse!
Stop him from making that sound!
That's dot-and-dash,
a military communications code!
He's signaling this location--
Hey, thank you very much
for coming to get me, Kimblee.
Good grief,
please don't give me extra work.
Please forgive me.
I won't let my guard down again.
What is this? You tricked me, Envy!
I didn't lie to you!
Immortality is farther inside!
Damn you, you twit!
I made it!
I've come back to life!
Thanks for bringing me this far, squirt!
What are soldiers doing
in a place like this?
Are they here to serve
notices of eviction?
What do we do now?
We don't have anywhere else to go.
What is this? You don't suppose
they caught wind of where we are, do you?
Not good. Alphonse is...
Hold on, Doc!
What if they discover
that you're Doctor Marcoh?
But we can't just sit here and watch.
Take it easy.
If you get taken prisoner or anything,
it's just going to make it
that much harder on Alphonse!
We can't afford to move carelessly.
Just sit still, okay?
You're alone?
I heard that Gluttony was here, too.
I ended up consuming him.
You ate him?
Your own kind?
He is not my kind. We are a collective.
We are both born from the same father.
All we've done
is go back to being one form.
Is that how it is?
Mr. Heinkel!
Oh, you're still alive, are you?
That's a Chimera for you.
Your life force is strong.
Mr. Heinkel!
Damn it!
Let me go!
You're not getting away.
Why, you...!
Stop your useless struggling.
Don't run away.
What?
I should have known that wouldn't work.
That's far enough, General Armstrong.
We have orders to shoot you, a traitor!
Aim!
Fire!
You idiot.
This isn't the time to be divided.
Take a little damage, would you?
Got you.
This time, I won't mess up.
Kill the woman general.
Big Sister!
Are you all right?
Who do you think you're talking to, Alex?
I'm glad you're all right!
By the way, what might that be?
A Homunculus.
Bullets have no effect against him.
-Cannon-class fire is just barely enough.
-What?
That's my field of specialty, you know?
What do you say you leave this to Alex,
your younger brother?
Come, monster!
What a pain.
Don't worry about me.
Get out of here. Quickly!
- No way!
- Don't talk back to me.
At this rate, we'll both be beaten.
If you leave me behind,
you might be able
to save yourself, at least.
I said, I'm not going!
Now, think about something useful instead,
like staying alive!
You dumbass!
Look at our situation!
We're facing Kimblee and Pride!
Now, leave me here and get going.
Don't give up! I swear, I'll save you!
Damn it!
Move it, legs!
We can't afford to be beaten here!
Mr. Heinkel, grab on!
Don't give up!
You brothers really take the cake.
How is it that you can try
to help someone else
when you're falling to pieces yourself?
I made a promise.
I promised my brother
that I wasn't going to let
anyone else die, no matter what.
Right, I guess it was Kimblee
who said that to survive was to win.
Which reminds me,
I've got something nice here.
Mr. Heinkel, why do you have that?
I picked it up when Kimblee
abandoned us at that mine up north.
A Philosopher's Stone.
With this, we just might win.
But...
Yeah, I know.
These are made using human lives, right?
Your brother also told me
that you'd rather not use one of these
to get your original bodies back.
In that case...
In that case,
use it not for your own sake,
but to save the world.
I'm asking you this because, even though
they've turned into this stone,
you still recognize them
as being people's lives.
I can tell.
No matter their appearance,
they want to fight to protect
what's important to them.
Let those guys fight, as well.
All right.
Give them hell.
Alphonse!
Let's fight, together.
What an annoying dust cloud.
- Shall I blow it away with a blast wave?
- No.
Those two are still inside the dust cloud.
He can't escape with those legs--
Well, well.
I don't think he's running away.
Good!
Very good, Alphonse Elric!