- A Philosopher's Stone.
- Where did he get one of those?
Dust in our eyes again?
I won't fall for that again.
A flash bomb.
It was a decoy!
That's a Philosopher's Stone for you.
From one trick to the next...
Indeed, the power of a Philosopher's Stone
is something to behold.
I've used one myself, so I would know.
Which is why I'm puzzled.
Why do you not use that power
to get your own body back?
With the stone, it would be an easy matter
for you to flee from us.
And once you've gotten away,
you could use the stone,
and the two of you could return
to your original bodies.
Then your journey would end, wouldn't it?
If I did that, I couldn't save everyone.
So it's to fulfill
your earnest wish, then.
In order to obtain something,
you have to discard something else.
Tell me.
Why are there only two choices?
It's not right that I can only choose
between "return to our original bodies"
and "save everyone."
Why isn't "return to our original bodies
and save everyone" among our choices?
What about the Law of Equivalent Exchange?
I think that seeking possibilities
without being bound by laws
is necessary for mankind to advance.
I see. So you're saying
that if it comes to pass,
it will be acknowledged
as a new law by the world.
Is that right?
In that case,
there is one other possibility.
"You don't get back your bodies
and you don't save everyone"
must be one of the choices.
I'm not through yet!
Good. Under his skin, he's vulnerable.
I'm dying. What a bother.
Dying is a bother.
What a bother.
- Fighting all-out is an ultra-bother.
- What?
General Armstrong,
throw down your weapon and--
What is that huge thing?
What was that?
I missed.
What speed.
- Sloth the Indolent.
- Sister.
He grazed me slightly.
- Did you see him just now?
- Only the blur.
For him to move with that speed
as heavy as he is...
No way, that's below the belt.
Yes, I am the fastest Homunculus.
Alex!
He's too fast
to be able to control himself.
Oh, no--
Finally hit you.
Mm, I love that sound.
Is there anything that strikes
a more beautiful note
than the sound of two strong wills
colliding with each other?
- Alphonse Elric is still close by.
- Indeed, he is.
It will take more than that to kill him.
There!
Dust in our eyes again?
How artless. It won't work.
I told you, I can tell where you are
by your smell.
Checkmate.
I'm not so sure.
This is the part where we humans
show off how tenacious we are.
Even with a Philosopher's Stone,
there's no way you can win
all on your own.
I'm not alone!
Where is the stone?
It can't be.
The purpose of this smokescreen
was to let him know
the direction of the wind?
He's set something up downwind
where my sense of smell won't work.
An attack from behind?
Impossible. How can he be mobile
with those injuries?
Doctor Marcoh!
It was an ice cream truck, right?
Yeah, don't let it get past you.
Alchemy really is handy, isn't it?
Changing the outer appearance
of the vehicle is no trouble at all.
We can't get in here, either.
North, south, east, and west,
the command center's gates are all closed.
What do we do? Force our way in?
No, leave the overt, heavy-handed stuff to
the Briggs fellows.
- We'll take a more covert route.
- Yes, sir.
We'll split up here.
You guys accompany the missus
- and head for you-know-where.
- Roger that.
It's a good thing I'm so beefy.
That's the Philosopher's Stone for you,
I guess you could say.
The legs! Go for the legs!
What?
- Alex?
- Oh, it's just dislocated. You, sister?
Just some fractures.
Sister!
Kill you quick and then sleep.
You stopped?
He's reluctant to stab through Kimblee.
But that's not like him.
I see.
The humanity you speak of is tenacious.
However, you still cannot win.
Not as long as our father is over there.
But then, before we get to that,
you must do something
about the situation you're in now.
Who's that?
I got you. I got you!
- Yoki?
- All right, way to go, fuzzy-lip.
I never expected you to show up.
No way am I letting you guys
be the only ones to play hero!
Let me have a chance
to show off too, damn it!
How about that?
I, Yoki, just landed a shot
on the strongest Homunculus!
I popped him good!
Where did you get the car?
It's the one Kimblee rode here in.
The guys who were driving it
are taking a little time-out.
Nice going, Doctor Marcoh.
Move it!
Shut up and drive! Floor it!
I don't feel like fighting
that monster head-on.
Head for the city limits.
We'll join up with Ed
and clobber that "Father" guy
before that thing catches us.
Those brave, stalwart humans
sure are easy to dupe.
Good. You're still alive.
Your suit has taken on a nice color,
hasn't it, Kimblee?
They're called the kings of beasts
and rightly so.
He followed the law
of survival of the fittest
and easily bit right through
your windpipe.
Sure enough, humans are beings
of little consequence in this world.
You were always saying
how you wanted to see
what the world would choose, huh?
And so, for you to perish in a place
such as this must be fairly humiliating.
But not to worry.
You will go on living, inside of me.
What just happened?
Alex.
I knew he was going to come
charging in all on his own,
so all I had to do was wait for him.
Sister, can you stand up?
Come to think of it,
there are orders out to shoot me.
What? We can't have that.
I will be the one to inherit
the Armstrong household,
so I can't have you die
until the paperwork is in place.
You need not worry about that.
If I die, the mansion goes to Mustang.
You made that promise
without even consulting the family?
He's still one smidgen more preferable
than a good-for-nothing like you.
Is that any attitude to have
towards someone who came to save you?
What is this?
- An enemy attack?
- It can't be Mustang's squad.
What are they?
- They won't die when we shoot them!
- Are they Briggs soldiers?
You idiots!
Don't you compare my robust men
to those puny tenderfoots.
They're probably the same as this guy.
The one who gave you your orders
must have sent them out.
We don't know anything about this!
Apparently, they don't care
whether or not you knew.
What will it be? My brother and I can deal
with these monsters.
But...
Well, what will it be?
Are you going to shoot us
then fall prey to these monsters?
Or are you going to work with us
and shoot the monsters?
Make up your own minds!
Why, you--!
Not again!
It's no use.
These mannequin soldiers have been infused
with Philosopher's Stones.
You can't kill them that easily.
See? That's what you get
for running away from me.
I've absorbed some more
and grown even stronger now, haven't I?
You don't get it.
When those mannequins come
in large numbers, that spells trouble,
but running away from you is simple.
Silence!
These mannequins have been infused
with Philosopher's Stones.
That's why they don't die.
Their immortality comes
from the Philosopher's Stones, all right.
To save my clan, immortality will be mine.
- It hurts.
They're still coming?
There's no end to them!
- I'm gonna run out of quills!
- My saliva is starting to go dry, too.
Damn it!
- Oh, crap!
- Ed!
Things are always rowdy wherever you are.
Would it be okay
if I lend you a hand, Fullmetal?