What in the world is going on?
- What is happening?
- I don't know.
Rumor has it that Colonel Mustang
is up to something.
- Are you sure?
- It's just what I've heard.
Hey! The radio! Turn on the radio!
- To Radio Capital!
- Radio Capital?
- Yeah. Something amazing is going on!
- That station is so boring.
Just do it! Hurry before the military
shuts down their broadcast!
Is that what you were saying,
Mrs. Bradley?
Yes, the Central forces...
attempted to kill me.
You mean, they pointed guns at your head
and demonstrated intent to shoot you?
That is right.
They said, "You're free to shoot her,
along with Colonel Mustang's men."
Fuhrer Bradley has gone east
to conduct an inspection
and is not currently in Central.
Yes.
So then, somebody centrally located
was waiting for His Excellency to leave
- so they could stage a coup d'état?
- That I do not know.
- Is that really Mrs. Bradley?
- I've heard her voice before.
- Be that as it may, Mrs. Bradley...
- It's really her.
...under the circumstances,
it's a good thing your son
is somewhere other than Central.
I have not been able to contact my son.
- You haven't? That's just--
- You're kidding.
- Poor thing.
- I wonder if little Selim is all right.
Please try to keep your composure,
Mrs. Bradley.
A coup d'état?
- Thank goodness that you are safe.
- Can anyone run this country?
Truly, if Colonel Mustang
had not saved me,
I don't know what would have become of me.
I see. So Colonel Mustang
saw this coup d'état coming?
Mustang?
So, then, could you please tell us...
- the exact circumstances of your rescue?
- Yes.
You haven't told her...
- ...that Selim is a Homunculus yet?
- When the guns were pointed at me...
- We couldn't tell her.
- ...I closed my eyes and prayed to God.
- She doesn't know the Fuhrer is missing.
- When I heard the gunshots,
I thought it was all over for me...
but then--
The madam hasn't been told this yet,
but the truth is, yesterday,
the train that the Fuhrer
was aboard in the east
was blown up by someone.
His Excellency is now missing.
Mrs. Bradley!
Are you all right?
Mrs. Bradley does not appear
to be feeling well right now,
having been overwhelmed
by all that is happening.
Still, what do you mean
His Excellency, the Fuhrer, is missing?
Colonel Mustang has harbored suspicions
about the senior staff.
Since before all this,
they suspected they would do something.
Now, with the bombing
of the Fuhrer's train
and permission being given
to fire on Mrs. Bradley,
matters have become clear.
There is a faction among the senior staff
attempting to eliminate His Excellency.
You fool! Shut down
that broadcast immediately!
You know what will happen
if you don't do so!
It doesn't matter what you say, I can't.
They have taken hostages
and they're pointing guns at us, too.
We can't move a muscle here.
There are so many perpetrators here.
We can't do anything.
Give me Mustang!
I will speak to him directly!
The... colonel?
Don't shoot me!
Forgive me, I beg you!
- So, how was I?
- Perfect.
All right, don't stop broadcasting!
- Yes, sir!
I'm not about to let this story
get away from us!
Now, continuing on, here is a message
from one of Colonel Mustang's men
who helped rescue Mrs. Bradley.
So Colonel Mustang
isn't staging a coup d'état?
Those of us who support Colonel Mustang
may not be all that powerful,
but we will carry on,
- His Excellency...
- That voice.
...the Fuhrer's will, and we are prepared
to use all our strength
to bring down those cowardly men
in the name of justice.
Thank you very much. Now, then,
I would like to sum up all the events...
Oh, Mustang.
- ...that have transpired up to now.
- You're using Bradley's absence
and using the Fuhrer's influence
any way that you like?
And in the name of justice.
I sure do hope the people will buy it.
You sure sounded like a pro.
And way to work in an ambiguous,
frivolous little word like "justice."
It's all right.
Everyone loves justice after all.
Yeah. Whoever invokes it first
comes out on top.
What exactly is going on?
Apparently, this isn't the doing
of Mustang and company.
- Are you sure?
- Roy Mustang is telling the truth.
We just got here from the east,
and there's a big fuss back there
about the Fuhrer's train being bombed.
You folks in Central
don't know about that yet?
The nation's top man is missing.
So why don't it's citizens know
anything about it?
- Then it really is a coup d'état?
- Who's behind this?
If Radio Capital were to get raided
and Mrs. Bradley were to die,
then there's no doubt
that the senior staff is behind this.
- Selim! What about Selim?
- I'm sure he's been taken prisoner.
I sure hope he hasn't been killed.
What is the garrison doing?
Sir, the enemy apparently possesses
far more weapons than expected
and are putting up a difficult fight.
Weapons? There's only a limited amount
they can carry, right?
Transmission from the garrison!
Go ahead, sir.
You're late checking in!
What's happening there? Over!
The Briggs guys even have one of those--
Hey!
Is everything all right?
This gate isn't going
to fall to them, right?
Of course not!
Sheesh, ridiculous.
As long as they don't bring in
a tank or something, we're--
What?
Would it be okay
if I lend you a hand, Fullmetal?
Colonel?
It would appear that you have
some more new friends.
Scar?
You know, this place
takes me back, Lieutenant.
I remember seeing your tearful face here.
I'd like to see
those honest tears again sometime.
I thought you hated moisture.
It renders you useless.
Save the chit-chat for later! Fight!
Don't you order me around.
Acknowledged. We just need
to beat these white guys, right?
That won't work, Lieutenant!
You can't beat these guys using bullets.
Not again.
It's all we've been dealing with.
Are they Homunculi?
No, they aren't self-repairing.
But they won't die either. Is it the power
of the Philosopher's Stone?
They are the enemy, Fullmetal.
Why, you--! Stop scampering around!
It would seem
that he doesn't want me to go this way.
The presence is stronger
that way, too. I knew it.
May?
Envy!
You guys...
Fool! Why didn't you go back
to your home country?
But... I mean... I mean...
- Never mind! Don't cry!
- I'm sorry, Mr. Scar!
Geez. This is why you humans
turn my stomach.
I have to admit though,
you've really done a number here.
The Fullmetal Alchemist,
the Flame Alchemist, not to mention Scar.
And the filthy Chimeras,
who I owe for up north, are here with you.
Now, then, which one of you
will I deal with first?
You're Envy, are you?
The Homunculus who can change
his shape, as I recall.
So you know.
Pleased to meet you, Colonel Mustang.
Are you sure about this, Scar?
This is one of the State Alchemists
that turned Ishval into such a hellhole.
You're right.
You're acting chummy? You're no fun.
Let me see you guys act
more rumbly-grumbly.
It's so much more fun when you maggots
are shouting at each other.
We don't have time
to entertain your boorish interests.
Boorish? Then let me ask you this.
You humans love
watching others' misfortune
and watching fools run around
in circles, don't you?
Isn't that why you're always at war
with each other?
Indeed. It is delightful to watch fools
get worked up into a frenzy.
And watching fools who are Homunculi
go into a frenzy is especially enjoyable.
I have answered your question.
Now, why don't you answer mine?
Who was it that killed Maes Hughes?
Answer me, Homunculus.
It was Maria Ross.
The one you burned to death.
No. It wasn't her.
Then you burned an innocent girl alive.
Nice work. You're awful.
So how did you break it to her family?
Did you cry when you apologized?
Or did you keep quiet because you were
too afraid of them getting mad at you?
Would you quit working your mouth,
you idiot?
I have become sick and tired
of asking you Homunculi this question.
Now, tell me the truth right now,
you idiot!
Who was it that killed Hughes?
Congratulations, Colonel Mustang.
You've finally arrived at your answer.
I doubt a moron like you
would be able to take Hughes.
Moron?
A moron...
is what you call someone...
like Hughes
for falling for a trick like this.
Your face has gone pale!
I like that expression.
The look on Hughes' face
when I killed him was terrific, too.
The look on his face...
The despair of being shot dead
by someone with his beloved wife's face.
It was terrific!
That settles it.
You're the one who killed Hughes.
All I needed to know was that fact.
You don't have to say anything else, Envy.
I'll start by burning out...
the base of your tongue.
Scar, Fullmetal, let me take this one.
He is my quarry.
All right. Then we'll leave this to you
and go on ahead.
Who says you're allowed to go?
I have to pay you back in full
for what you did up north--
Are you sure you can afford to talk
to anyone else while facing me?
I would say that nimble tongue of yours
has gotten nice and greasy.
It burns so well, doesn't it, Envy?
Lieutenant, are you sure
just the two of you will be--?
Go on, Edward.
We can manage.
- But...
- Go, Edward Elric.
You have something else you have to do.
- Come on, let's go, Ed.
- Hold on!
Damn it.
The colonel will be fine.
That Homunculus will be
a pushover for him.
That's not what I'm worried about.
What do you mean?
Yes, you've been pursuing the one
who killed Hughes for a long time.
Such a beautiful friendship!
Stay back, Lieutenant.
In deference to your beautiful friendship,
I will fight you all-out.
I can't really pull my punches
in this body,
so it's not my fault what might hap--
How does it feel, having the fluid
inside your eyeballs boil?
I'll bet it hurts beyond imagination.
Damn you!
I'm surprised you'd intentionally
make my target bigger for me.
Did you think being bigger
would let you beat me? Idiot.
Get up, monster.
Hurry and regenerate yourself.
I'm going to let you relive that pain
over and over until you die.
Yeah, that's right.
He's the man who burned Lust to death.
- Hold it!
- Colonel!
Lieutenant, you wait here!
I'm going to take care of him myself!
This way. It's probably this way.
- Creepy.
- These things are like veins.
It almost feels
like I've been having heartburn.
I'll bet you are.
There's a powerful mass of chi deeper in.
Mass of chi?
If I said it feels like
an incredible number of people writhing,
would that make sense to you?
I don't know what it is,
but I do know that it feels creepy.
I sure wouldn't want to run
into the enemy here.
Scar, do you have a minute?
Is this about the Flame Alchemist?
Having once lost myself,
burning in the flames of revenge,
I understand it all too well.
The way he's going,
he's going to burn his own heart up
in the flames of hatred.
- Where are you, Envy?
- Damn.
If you don't come out, I'm gonna hit you
with an even bigger explosion!
Yo, Roy.
You're only human! You'll get mixed up!
You'd burn up your best friend
without any hesitation?
Hughes is dead. He's gone.
Your actions have only poured
more fuel on the fire!
Damn it! Don't get so carried away!
Not again! My eyes! My eyes!
You fool. Did you think I wouldn't use
heavy firepower right next to me?
Unfortunately for you,
I can do pinpoint aiming.
Don't you sell my technique short!
Colonel, I'm disobeying your orders.
He got away again.
You've disobeyed orders, Lieutenant.
I'm sorry, but I couldn't
just sit there and wait.
Where's Envy?
I lost sight of him.
It's almost like a maze in here.
Do not leave my side, Lieutenant.
Now that you're here,
you're going to help me out.