1909: THE CONCLUSION
OF THE ISHVALAN CIVIL WAR
Aren't you going back?
You'll be left behind.
A war buddy's grave?
No. It's an Ishvalan child.
One who was left dead by the wayside.
Let's go home. The war is over.
The Ishvalan War is still not over
within me.
No, it will never be over
for as long as I live.
I am the one who believed in you
and entrusted my father's research to you.
I am also the one
who entered the military academy,
in hopes for the happiness of the people.
And even if that did come
to an unwanted result,
I cannot escape the truth.
There is no way I can atone
for what I've done.
I have a favor to ask, Mr. Mustang.
Please burn... and deface my back.
- There's no way I could do that!
- At least...
If I can't atone,
I, at least, want to destroy
the secrets on my back
so that no other Flame Alchemists
can be produced!
Can you do that?
If so, then please release me
from my charge.
Please set me free from the burden
placed on me by my father
through his alchemy.
I beg you.
All right.
I will burn you,
leaving as little trace of it as I can.
Thank you very much, Mr. Mustang.
What are you trying to pull, Lieutenant?
Who do you think
you're pointing your gun at?
Who? Don't make me laugh.
When it's just the two of us,
the colonel always calls me "Riza."
- That's how close you two are?
- I lied.
Thanks for falling for it, Envy.
Now, die here for me.
That hurts!
Damn it.
You're taking the potshots too far!
I'll dump you in front of the colonel
like a worn-out dishrag--
Colonel.
What are you doing to my dear subordinate?
Don't do anything rash, Lieutenant.
I told you I was going
to take care of him.
Damn, human. Don't you look down at me!
Damn it.
Not this again.
Is that your true body?
You're ugly.
Envy, your name means "jealous," right?
That makes sense.
No. Don't!
And jealousy...
is an ugly thing.
No, I don't want to die!
- No! No!
- Be gone...
from my sight!
What do you think
you're doing, Lieutenant?
That's enough, Colonel.
I will deal with him from here.
One more blast will finish him.
Put down your gun.
I cannot obey that order, sir.
Please put your hand down.
Stop screwing around! I said put it down!
Fullmetal.
Let me have that.
I'll ask you one more time.
No.
I must give him the worst of all deaths.
Give him to me! Or I will burn him up
along with your right hand!
Fine with me!
I'll fight you like I mean it!
But before I do,
take a good look at your own face!
Is that the face you plan to wear
when you're the nation's top man?
That's not what you...
Colonel, that's not
what you're after, is it?
Those below me
will protect those below them.
We, tiny humans, should be able
to do that much, at least.
This could be interesting.
I'll take a piece of that action.
I want to see how your naive idealism
changes this country.
Are you going down the path
of the beast, given over to his passion?
You can if you want to.
If you're going to live for revenge,
I won't stop you.
Hey!
I have no right to stop another
from taking vengeance.
But I do think it would be a sight
to see what sort of world
a man who is held captive
by his own hatred,
at the head of everyone else,
would create.
Colonel, I cannot allow you to kill Envy.
That being said,
I do not intend to let him live.
I will dispose of him, sir.
I finally did it! I finally ran him down!
I know!
But still...
But still, what you are about to do
is not to help the country
or your friends!
It is to vindicate your hatred.
That is all that consumes you.
I cannot allow you
to descend to that level!
If you wish to shoot me, then shoot me.
However, after you shoot me,
what will you do then?
I have no intention of living on
by myself, free of care.
Once this fight is over,
I will remove my body,
along with its maddening flame alchemy,
from the face of the Earth.
I can't have that.
I can't...
afford to lose you.
What kind of situation is this?
Scolded by a child, lectured by a man
who once came after me as an enemy,
causing you pain, once again...
I'm just a big fool.
I'm sorry.
What are you, dense?
Just flowery words
and make-believe empathy?
It's turning my stomach.
Are you humans really that over-the-top?
Just do whatever you want to,
like your gut tells you to do!
Colonel Mustang! Have you forgotten?
Scar was out to take your life.
As I recall,
Scar is also the one who killed
the pipsqueak's friend's parents.
Yeah, yeah.
And the girl-and-dog Chimera in East City.
Isn't Scar the one who killed her, too?
And as for you, Scar,
what happened to all that hatred
over your countrymen killed in Ishval?
And the woman,
all full of herself,
called the "Hawk's Eye,"
she shot your pals left and right!
You'll never get another chance like this!
Well, go get them!
This is a prime opportunity!
Hate and weep. Kill and be killed!
Thrash around! Grovel in the dirt.
Teaming up together as friends
is something you scum
couldn't possibly do!
Right, pipsqueak? Right, Hawkeye?
Mustang? Scar?
How come?
How come? How come? How come?
Envy...
You're... jealous of humans.
Humans are supposed to be
so much weaker than you Homunculi.
And yet, even when we're beaten down
and get discouraged
or seem like we're about
to go astray and fall,
we still stand up to the challenge,
again and again.
Those who are around us pick us back up.
And you...
you're envious of humans like that.
If you forsake the smaller part,
the greater will be saved.
If you think about it just a little,
you'll see that.
You can't shoot like this, huh, human?
But then again, that's just the way
you humans are.
But, as long as I'm going to transform,
something young and cute
would be better, huh?
You humans really are such fools.
You risk your lives
over the most pointless things.
Only human, all right.
Humans?
Humans...
Hey, you! Don't run away!
Hey, hold on a second!
You idiot, if you squeeze yourself out...
Wait.
He won't last much longer.
It's so humiliating,
ending up like a worn-out dishrag...
walked on by you humans,
you loathsome beings.
What's worse,
of all the scum out there,
the scummiest pipsqueak
had to be the one--
Damn it. Damn it. Damn it.
How humiliating. How humiliating.
Me, Envy, jealous of you humans?
Me, Envy?
Me, Envy, being understood by this kid?
That's the ultimate humiliation.
We'll see how long
those flowery words will last.
Best of luck with that.
Bye, bye, Edward Elric.
He terminated his own life?
Cowardly bastard.
His wounds are healing.
He's a monster.
Hey, what is that thing?
You're here just in time! Give us a hand!
Give you a hand?
We have orders to shoot General Armstrong.
General? And you, too, Major?
You're just in time.
From here on out, I'm running the show!
Just help us out, now!
Hey, what are those things?
Get your heads down!
Bullets don't have any effect on them.
Smash in their upper jaws.
At least, we won't have to worry
about being chewed to death.
Attack in pairs, and make sure
to take out at least one each.
Show me the valor of the Central soldiers!
Let's see. What was I doing?
I remember.
Kill the woman general.
No, you don't!
Let go!
It sure is hard
only being able to use one arm.
- Major.
- General!
He's gonna beat him to death!
If someone doesn't get in there
to help him out!
Leave him!
My brother...
has trained himself better
than to be killed like that!
This...
is the end.
Major!
My shoulder has popped back in!
All right.
This artistic muscular
and artistic alchemic collaboration...
is excellent and elegant!
Yes, sir. The Armstrong estate
is completely empty!
Damn it. Is this where
they assembled that tank?
This is the gate commander
calling Operations!
We're taking fire from what
we believe to be a Briggs tank.
- Come in, Operations!
- Stop shouting! I can see!
No matter, return fire!
But the civilians
haven't finished evacuating.
If we wait for them,
we'll lose the main gate!
Contact the command center
and main gate batteries--
Damn it. What was that?
You were going to fire on an urban area?
You want that to go out
over the radio, too?
Why, you...
This is Briggs equipment!
How did you get in here?
A man formerly stationed
at Central Command Center,
one with a sharp memory,
remembers exactly where this location is.
All that was left was for someone
to single-handedly
dig a tunnel
from the urban area to right here.
Is there anyone able
to pull something like that off?
- Yes, there is. Right here.
- Who?
When anyone asks who I am,
I tell them I'm a housewife.
That is only proper for me.
But, today, why don't I identify myself
as something else?
I'm an alchemist!
You're alone?
I thought you would bring
those brothers with you.
I don't need to bring
a bunch of others along
to chastise a bad little boy, do I?
Dwarf in the Flask, Homunculus?
Slave No. 23,
who gave me a part of his body...
Now, you will become a part of my body.