That's strange. I'm sure it was this way.
- No, that way?
- Are you lost, Fullmetal?
Los-- Shut up!
If I hadn't come back to make sure that
a certain nitwit wasn't goofing around,
this wouldn't be happening!
Nobody asked you to come back.
Get out of here!
If it weren't for me and Scar,
you definitely would have lost your way!
Don't you patronize me.
It was thanks to the lieutenant that
I was able to regain control back there.
What?
Keep it down. The enemy will find us.
Scar, I want to offer my thanks now,
while I can, for persuading the colonel.
I know that it probably
just upsets you Ishvalans
to have someone like me say thank you.
But you may have brought him back...
to who he once was.
Thank you.
Your words of gratitude are not needed.
Yes, sir! Yes, sir! Copy that!
Hey! We can stop shooting! Cease fire!
Attention, Central soldiers!
Briggs forces have taken
the Operations Center!
- Curse those rebels!
- We have 13 men in our custody,
including General Cremin. Repeat.
Briggs forces have taken
the Operations Center!
All Central soldiers,
cease hostilities immediately.
We have General Cremin in custody.
So, the reason you were blasting away
with your tank
was to cover the sound of you
digging your hole with alchemy?
That's right.
What was that? I didn't copy!
- What? Are you sure?
- What is it?
The Operations Center
has fallen to Briggs forces!
They've apparently
captured General Cremin!
Operations Center, is Buccaneer there?
Captain!
There are a large number of pale,
one-eyed, humanoid monsters on the loose!
Not only are they hard to kill,
they are man-eaters.
No matter what happens,
do not open any of the gates!
We cannot allow a single one
of those things to get out into the city!
Exterminate them within the walls
of the command center!
Yes, ma'am.
For the love of... What is Cremin doing?
From here on out, I am in command!
As of right now,
this is the Operations Center!
The Fuhrer's chair.
If we get through this crisis,
I will be...
There are still more of them coming out?
General, what in the world
are these things?
They're called the Immortal Legion.
They were created by placing
human souls inside mannequins.
Soldiers who have no fear of death.
Someday, you recruits
will probably end up as one of these.
He's still moving?
How many times does he have to be killed?
In that case, once more!
What tenacity.
No!
- Major!
- General Armstrong!
Stay back!
We are the ones he is after!
Keep your distance!
Kill... the obstinate... woman general.
Pull!
Dig in!
Both of you, please run while you can!
This way, sirs, quickly!
Come, Major!
You would have me run away?
You would have me flee
from the battlefield once again?
There is no way
that I could do such a thing!
You're determined not to run. Nice.
You're a fine man. But then again,
my husband is a hundred times finer.
Who are you?
A female officer.
That must mean you're General Armstrong.
Your subordinate, the one with the mohawk,
asked me to come help you.
Who asked him?
What a bother...
Coming at you, dear!
Right!
- Who is that gentleman?
- My husband.
Valor a hundredfold!
Muscle a thousandfold!
Ow...
He's still moving?
I'm... dying... dying.
What is dying?
Too much bother... to think...
Too much bother... to live.
Too...
- Major!
Those scrawny guys
are all that remain!
Give it all you've got
to exterminate them!
Yes, sir!
Sorry, I need a little breather.
Yes, ma'am.
Please let us take it from here!
I don't know who you are,
but I'm grateful for the help.
My pleasure.
You must be
a well-renowned martial artist.
Me? No, no.
Just a housewife and an alchemist.
You know the Elric brothers, right?
We're as close as family.
Then you must be Izumi Curtis.
- That's me.
- Are the Elric brothers here, too?
Yes, they should be here.
Now, then, shall we take care
of the remaining mannequin soldiers?
- Can you stand, sister?
- Of course I can.
Hold on, now. Sit back down.
With your injuries...
We adults can't very well
be caught lying down
while the youngsters are fighting.
What if we adults,
who carry the burden of this world,
failed to show the youngsters,
who will carry the burden of this world
after us, the way to live?
Well, then,
why don't we give you a hand, as well?
Oh, thank you.
The two of you together
have the strength of a hundred men.
Oh, no, don't expect too much.
Apparently, I'm what
they call a "sacrifice."
After I've done a limited amount
of fighting, I'm flying the coop...
before the really bad guy catches me.
This is an emotional reunion.
Why so sullen?
You're no fun anymore.
Long ago, you were full
of feelings and interesting.
Lust, greed, sloth,
gluttony, envy, wrath, pride.
They say that man has seven sins.
Sure, excessive appetites
will ruin a person.
But, at the same time,
each of those feelings are imperative
if one is to understand humanity.
Why did you sever yourself from them?
Sheesh. Watch it.
Listen to me!
You're kidding!
Cut it out. I'm not very good at fighting.
Answer me!
Why did you create the Homunculi,
keep them at your side,
and have them call you "Father"?
When you were still in your flask,
you even put down
the community of a family!
When, actually,
you wanted a family,
like humans have, didn't you?
Where is he? Is he...
planning to stay withdrawn
until the nationwide
transmutation circle is activated?
I do not wish to become human.
I wish to become a perfect being.
I will have the Philosopher's Stone...
that is inside you!
Your expression has finally changed.
What did you do?
I just did what you wouldn't.
You probably don't understand.
You've cast aside something else important
besides your feelings.
Something important?
Don't think you're going
to win so easily. Not against us.
It's no use.
The tire is completely caught.
What are you doing, fuzzy-lip?
If we don't hurry,
the eclipse is going to start!
Shut up! Hurry and lift the car out!
Good grief.
Mr. Marcoh, please keep back.
Mr. Heinkel and I can handle this.
Yes, but...
We're fine. Let us take care of it.
Okay, then, here we go.
- One, two, three!
Turn yourselves in
to the Operations Center! Move it!
- Right!
- Thank you very much!
You know,
with these mannequin soldiers taking out
so many of the Central troops for us,
taking control is no sweat.
Let's keep on going
and take the main gate!
Yes, sir!
We're not even going to get a chance.
Why, you... Why, you...! How come?
I thought you were created
to obey our orders!
Does this mean
the good gentleman lied to us?
Stay back!
I'm not one of the ones
who were supposed to die here!
I don't know who you are, but well done!
Join my security detail,
and I will give you special--
I wonder if you might tell me more
about this "good gentleman"?
This place is a mess.
Are you going to take command here?
I can't fathom why anyone would sit
in a place where they would be
so easily shot at.
- Let's go.
- Yes, ma'am!
Sister!
Where does this passageway go?
It appears to lead downward
for quite a ways.
Is that the opening from which
the mannequin soldiers came?
If it is, it might link up underground.
Yes. Yes. Acknowledged.
Sir, Buccaneer Squad
has taken control of the main gate!
There was little resistance
and our casualties are few.
We also control the main entrance!
They've secured tanks
and are taking up positions.
Buccaneer Squad,
maintain your current status.
Please be absolutely sure
not to open the gates
until every last mannequin soldier
on the grounds has been expelled.
Copy that.
This is the west gate.
Briggs' White Squad has taken control!
North Gate. Black Squad now has control!
Blue Squad controls the east gate!
Yellow Squad has secured
the weapons depot.
You heard them, General Armstrong!
Briggs forces now control nine-tenths
of the Central Command Center.
We are victorious!
We won!
The colonel didn't get here in time.
Hip hip hooray!
Gentlemen, I'm back.
Things have been quite astir
while I've been away, haven't they?
As of now,
I am personally taking command
and will oust these rebels.
All available Central forces,
give me a hand.
King Bradley!
He's alive?
Where is he? Where is he attacking from?
All salute His Excellency, the Fuhrer!