Take it easy. I want to talk to you.
Just hear what I have to say.
Then you talk to me, too.
Yes... that's right.
You aren't alone.
Blond hair. He's from the west, isn't he?
Well, I suppose
we should at least bury him.
Whoa, he's alive!
- You've gotta be kidding!
- Stay with us!
Hey, are you all right?
Water! Bring water!
Don't drink it all at once.
Take little sips.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
We're merchants from Xing.
Where were you trying to go?
No place to return to, no place to go.
Ran away, too scared to stay in Xerxes.
I'll bet.
I'm sorry. I couldn't stop him.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, Sergence.
Sergence, the master carpenter.
He often came to the palace to do repairs.
Do you remember?
His son, Dzur, respected his father,
and was working hard
to follow in his footsteps.
Kaya, the florist lady.
A kind, compassionate woman.
Sari, the stable hand,
sure did love his liquor.
I get where he's coming from.
Tami's boyhood dream
was to become a scholar.
Gidarouche was a cook.
He was once fired for feeding a traveler
who had no money for free.
Andal, my fellow slave,
saw me as his enemy
because I found favor with the master.
Suhl, the incorrigible criminal,
who was awaiting execution.
He said he wanted one last shot at you.
A shot at me?
They are the souls
who have now invaded you.
They are working with me
for the sole purpose of defeating you.
Your Philosopher's Stone
has individual wills.
Which are working with you?
Those mere energy forms?
You think that's impossible?
It's true, I thought dealing
with these raging souls one-on-one
was going to drive me crazy.
But I had plenty of time
to converse with them,
all thanks to this undying body
you gave me.
You conversed with them?
Yes. That is what you would not do.
I have completed conversing
with all 536,329 people who are inside me.
Why... you...
Go back to where you were born,
Dwarf in the Flask, Homunculus.
Forgive me, but we are going
to destroy your container.
Once your leather bag is torn through,
it will be as though
your flask were broken.
You will turn to dust.
Realize the pain of those with whom
you were so condescending!
You're the one being condescending,
aren't you, Hohenheim?
You can still live outside of your skin?
Don't go thinking that
you're the only ones who have advanced.
I told you I was going to become
the perfect being.
- What?
- A frontal assault?
Is there some reason why I should come in
through the back door,
when I'm entering my own castle?
Infantrymen, keep back!
- Wha...?
- Impossible!
Did we get him?
- Take over driving!
- Yes, sir!
Damn it! Where is he?
The bastard took out
a whole tank single-handedly.
Captain!
Captain Buccaneer!
What's the matter?
The master has returned.
Open the gate.
Open it, Falman.
I'm sorry, Colonel Mustang...
I... might be dying here.
Hey, you! Don't go trying to act brave
with such a pathetic look on your face.
You're not going to beat me out
when it comes to manly pride.
I can still fight!
What rubbish.
This is what people call foolhardiness.
You are correct.
Nothing good comes of giving in
to the heat of the moment.
And yet, for some reason,
I just can't bring myself
to leave them high and dry.
Damn. As soon as the Führer came back,
they regained their momentum.
If they get through us,
they'll take the main gate!
We have to hold, no matter what!
Yes... Yes.
Are you sure?
Mrs. Bradley, His Excellency,
the Führer is all right!
He is alive!
Thank goodness.
Are you all right?
Yes, I'm all right.
Thank goodness, he's still alive.
Is he at all hurt?
That we do not yet know.
His Excellency is sweeping out
the Briggs soldiers
at the Central Command Center.
We'll have to pin this on Briggs.
But...
It's in order to protect Colonel Mustang.
First, it's great to hear
that His Excellency is okay.
Yes. I do hope that Selim is safe as well.
If he is fighting Briggs' soldiers,
it would appear that General Armstrong
is leading this coup d'état.
Armstrong? Ah, the lady general
that recently came to Central.
The question is,
how much of the senior staff
is wrapped up in this?
He's alive?
I guess that's what you'd expect
of a Homunculus.
It looks like siding with the Führer
has backfired on us.
Imagine, having to paint
General Armstrong as the villain.
It's starting to get dangerous
around here too.
Yeah.
I wonder what will happen to us.
I don't know.
For now, since we've claimed
to be on the Führer's side,
it won't be that easy for them
to attack us.
But once Bradley
takes back full command...
- We could be crushed right away?
- Even with his wife here?
Do you think that bunch
has that sort of sentiment?
Long time no see.
You should have just fled and kept quiet.
Unfortunately, my avarice knows no bounds.
I want your life, too, Wrath.
Is he our backup?
Word all over town is that you died
in a train accident.
How did you survive it?
My eyes are too sharp for that.
I was able to evaluate in an instant
where among the rubble
to run to get out of there.
However, the years take their toll.
My body won't keep up like it used to.
His body isn't at its peak,
and he's still capable of this?
Ling Yao, right?
Yeah! Haven't seen you since I hid out
in that run-down apartment, huh?
Been a long time, Warrant Officer Falman.
I'm a lieutenant!
I owe you for the stay and the meal,
so I'll give you a hand.
Although the truth is, we both have
a personal grudge against him!
Moving into my blind spot?
My partner inside me
taught me how to fight you.
Did he?
Then I will do this.
- He's gaining the upper hand!
- This is bad, isn't it?
Fire! Fire! Fire!
You fools! Stay out of this!
Why, you!
Captain!
You've got some tough abs.
Now you can't use
your fancy swordsmanship.
Don't do anything crazy, you dumbass!
Then again... nicely done!
Well, well...
I may not be as accustomed
to these weapons, but still...
Now you've done it, old man!
His Excellency has returned?
Yes, sir. He is currently fighting
against an unidentified man.
Send in more forces at once.
We're going to drive out those
Briggs nobodies and save the Führer!
Replenish our weapons and troops.
Retake the main gate!
Yes, sir!
Go! Go! Go!
Oh, no!
The Central soldiers
are coming around again!
Sorry. I have my hands full
dealing with him.
You'll have to handle it.
Eh? Handle it? As outmanned as we are,
what are we supposed to do?
Just do something!
- Just do something?
- Captain, be strong!
I guess I've got no choice.
Hey! You guys get Captain Buccaneer
to a safe place!
- Yes, sir!
- Come on, we're going to move that!
Yes, sir!
Damn! For us to be pinned down
by just a couple of machine guns...
The high ground is against us!
Are there any forces
inside we can contact?
Have them force open the door
from the inside!
Yes, sir!
This is the 3rd Sovereign Battalion.
Central Command Center Garrison, come in.
There are still mannequins
at the East Gate.
What? What are you talking about?
Give it here.
This is Gamelan of Sovereign Battalion.
We are at the main gate.
Can you open the command center gate
from within?
Negative.
There are mannequin soldiers here,
and we can't open the gate.
Mannequin soldiers?
What are you talking about?
What happened? What's going on?
What's that? A new player?
What in the world is happening down there?
Not bad, old man.
Thank you! You saved me.
I didn't save you.
I saved the Young Lord's body.
Oh, I see.
Your sickening chi is emanating
from the Young Lord's body.
But then,
that's why I was able to find you.
So? Who is this man,
upon whom neither you nor I
could leave a scratch,
even with our skills?
King Bradley.
This is the first time
I've seen him for myself.
This is the man who took
my granddaughter's arm, is it?