The Fuhrer has returned?
Word is that he destroyed
a Briggs tank at the main gate.
Take that, lousy Briggs mountain monkeys.
Let's round up the remaining soldiers.
We're going to retake
the Operations Center!
The Fuhrer is at the main gate?
Ho, this is the first time
I've seen him for myself.
This is the man who took
my granddaughter's arm, is it?
Oh, yeah? So you sacrifice
the general population,
so that you top officials
can gain immortality
and unite the whole world, huh?
And Fuhrer Bradley is also aware of this?
He was created to be
this country's leader to that end.
Why would we hesitate?
We were creating a world without war!
But to do so,
it would have to perish first?
No, not perish, be reborn.
What you alchemists
would call reconstruction.
We would not be giving death
to the general population.
They will live on forever, inside us!
And together, we will bring
the world together as one!
All is one and one is all!
We, the chosen ones of Amestris,
will act as one to bring everything--
There you have it. What will you do now?
These guys are only in this
for themselves.
Will you leave them to it?
You men, follow me.
Do so and I will put in
a good word for you.
W.C
I am a soldier so I must obey
the orders of my superiors.
However, to be honest,
I'm not sure what to believe anymore.
You still can't make up your mind
after everything that's happened?
Following a superior
that you have no faith in
is not what I'd call loyalty.
It's merely self-deception.
Believe in yourselves.
You just have to choose to live,
so as not to bring shame
on your own soul, right?
I have a family in the city.
Me too.
As do I.
Brigadier General, sir...
this is our answer.
Operations, what's the situation?
Not very favorable.
The Central soldiers are getting
their second wind all over.
Where are you right now, ma'am?
In the Fuhrer's office.
Any survivors?
We can't contact any of our allies
near the office.
There's a good chance that
it has been surrounded by Central troops.
Understood. If things get too
dangerous there, get yourselves out.
Leave me here.
Yes, ma'am.
Well, once again,
this place is full of the enemy.
It's only a matter of time
before the Central troops regroup
and start setting foot in here.
Which will mean...
When we get down far enough,
I'll dig an escape tunnel
like I did on the way here.
Escape?
Care to come with us?
You could use a chance to regroup, right?
- We're close.
- You think so too, huh?
Can you guys sense his presence?
I'm getting a bad feeling.
I guess you could say
my uglier old wounds are aching.
Well, well, to think that I would have
a gallery watching.
You're going to make me nervous.
- Who are you?
- Who, me?
The man who created King Bradley...
I guess you could say.
The Fuhrer?
Which would mean, you're on their side.
Oh, it's you. I thought you were
at the radio station
but you've come all the way
down here for me.
Thanks, that will save me
some trouble, Mustang.
You guys, take them on for a bit.
Who are these guys?
Mannequin soldiers?
No, they move decidedly differently
than those things!
These are the men that might
have become King Bradley.
Men who were brought together
as soon as they were born
and given specialized education
and training
for the sole purpose
of becoming the Fuhrer.
And on the 12th trial,
King Bradley came into being.
Then these men are the leftovers.
But then,
they have received a great deal
of combat training.
They're not as strong as King Bradley
but they are strong.
Damn.
Miserable rebels.
Whoops, I passed out.
- Captain.
- Oh, right.
If I pull it out,
I'll just bleed to death.
Bradley.
Watch it, old man!
I didn't do it on purp--
I mean, I didn't mean it!
Why, you--
I do feel more comfortable
with a weapon like this.
You move well
for someone even older than I am.
However...
this is the end for you!
Old man.
The Xingese prince, huh?
Damn it, Ling!
Don't go popping up on your own!
It's just like the time
with that girl who lost her arm.
Once again, you risk your life
for something
you are unable to leave behind.
Young Lord, cast aside this old man,
no longer able to fight.
Don't be absurd!
Are you telling me to be like what he is?
A king is to be for the people,
and there is no king without his people!
He is about to forsake
the people of his own nation.
That is not what I've set out to be!
A man worthy to be the king?
You must overcome--
Don't talk. You just rest.
Yes, you're right. Rest.
I will go to my rest now.
Harden yourself, Greed!
Protect the Young Lord's body!
Young Lord...
become the king.
This old man now goes to his eternal rest!
You stupid fool!
I'm taking you to hell with me!
Bradley!
Even with my life on the line,
I cannot even lay a scratch on him?
Young Lord, forgive my shame.
Even if you do have godlike eyes,
there's no way you can dodge
an attack you can't see coming!
Old man,
I'll accompany you down to hell!
Oh, you have my gratitude.
Grandfather!
Sheesh. You get us stuck in a ditch
then run into a lamppost.
You're just a lousy driver, fuzzy-lip.
Shut up! Just be grateful
that piece-of-junk car made it this far!
We've come this far, let's not fight!
Just hurry up and find us
a way underground.
Is that...?
Could that be Colonel Mustang?
I sure hope he's doing all right.
Brother.
Let's hurry.
I know they're supposed to be superhuman,
but come on!
You've left your back wide open, Colonel.
I'm letting my subordinate cover it.
It happens.
The gateway of truth.
When an alchemist commits
the taboo of human transmutation,
they end up opening the gateway of truth.
They also pay the corresponding toll.
You mean, the way the Elric brothers
sacrificed their bodies?
And you?
Part of my insides were taken away.
But after going through all that,
what I learned was, in fact,
that human transmutation could not
be successfully performed.
Oh, my, I suppose this topic
might not be of interest to soldiers, huh?
Not at all.
The people who open the gateway of truth
are the ones they refer to as sacrifices.
That could be a clue as to what
the enemy is planning.
There was someone you wanted
to be reunited with so badly
that you would open the gateway of truth
and sacrifice a portion
of your own bodies?
And you?
Is there someone whom you would pay
any price to see one more time?
That is indeed a topic of no interest
to soldiers.
It is pointless to have attachments
to those who are dead.
All we can do is fight
to keep them from dying.
I suppose that's true.
However...
I do understand
what you're saying somewhat.
Edward Elric.
When I first met him,
I intimidated him into telling me
everything that he knew,
but he did not say a word about them
holding a childhood friend of his hostage.
All he said was...
You'll have to guess.
"You'll have to guess."
The look in his eye
was not that of a soldier,
nor was it that of an alchemist,
a so-called Dog of the Military.
If I had to describe it,
it was the look of someone trying
not to lose anything else
that was dear to him, no matter what.
The eyes of a difficult child?
I'd be lying if I said I wasn't moved
when I looked into his eyes.
However, I'm not sure
if his naivete of thought
is going to find us a way
out of this fight,
or if it will work against us.
That will do.
Now then, shall we get started?
No. 16, No. 17, No. 21,
No. 23, No. 26, come here.
What?
Here goes!
What have you done?
Oh, this is just the first stage.
Do you know
how many alchemy laboratories there are
under direct prefectural control
here in Central?
There are four of them
currently in use within the city.
No.
The Fifth Laboratory... five of them.
A five-cornered transmutation circle.
Don't tell me
that curved underground passageway
connected the laboratories
together in a circle.
What the...?
What's the matter, Mr. Heinkel?
Izumi.
Yeah, it looks like this is our cue.
I'm going to dig us a hole
to escape out of through this wall.
Stand back a bit.
Well then, this is where we part ways.
We must remain here and keep fighting.
From here on is probably where the heart
of the enemy will be.
We aren't about to pass up
our chance to storm them.
You guys...
You've been a tremendous help.
Thank you, Izumi Curtis.
Thank you, General Armstrong--
What?
Alphonse!
Izumi!
Fullmetal.
Why, you--