Fullmetal!
He's gone.
What did you do?
He's just been carried off to the place
where you will also go, in time.
What is this?
It feels like... Oh, right!
Like it did when we opened
the gateway of truth!
Damn it. Why, you--
You...
You dumbass! Never mind us!
It is our job to protect the Young Lord.
This much weight is too much
for your automail to support.
You look after the old man!
It's too late for him.
Briggs soldiers, give me a hand!
Right!
Bradley! Take this!
Fu!
Someone get a doctor!
Is there a doctor around
who can use alchemy?
I have a Philosopher's Stone right here!
Use as much of it as you want!
Somebody, please!
This is Amestris,
a major alchemic power, right?
Is there nobody?
Why?
Young Lord!
You monster.
Why?
I've obtained immortality
and yet I can't save
a single one of my subjects?
Damn it!
Captain!
Captain, stay with us!
- Captain!
Captain!
Fire!
Thanks to you,
Bradley received a lethal blow.
You saw that Fu's death was not in vain,
and yet I can't do a thing for you.
- Give me some ammo!
- That's the last of it!
Damn, I'm out over here too!
- All of you, fire back with your rifles!
- Yes, sir!
Ling Yao.
Greed... whichever.
If you feel indebted,
would you do a favor for me?
We are to keep this gate from opening
until we receive orders from our queen.
Please defend it for me.
With your power, you can do that, right?
No, you're the only one who can do it,
if you would.
Greed.
I want your power. Let me have it.
Sure. There's still a little time
before my engagement.
- Lan Fan, you protect the men here.
- Yes, sir!
You'll do it?
Yeah, I promise.
And people from Xing...
always keep their word.
Fire! Fire!
Who is that guy?
Listen up, you guys!
Anyone who doesn't want to get hurt,
anyone with a family
or a lover, keep back!
Also, women!
I'm not the sort who fights women!
Impossible.
Fire!
Amazing. Is that Ling Yao?
Or is it the Homunculus?
It's a good thing for us he's on our side.
Captain! Captain!
Captain, please stay with us.
- He's fighting for our side?
- Yes, sir.
Now I can cash it in in peace.
What are you talking about, Captain?
General Armstrong is about to win!
Just a little bit longer!
Captain, we need you to do even more
than you already have here in Central!
The sooty air of Central
doesn't agree with me.
Farewell, comrades.
I'm going on ahead...
to someplace even higher
than the summit of Briggs.
Captain Buccaneer!
What was that light earlier?
There have been no reports.
What's going on
at the military command center?
Are there any updates from Radio Capital?
No, nothing.
What about other stations?
They're just informing us
to stay in our homes.
Mama!
The radio said
we weren't allowed to go out,
so let's forget about going over
to Tabitha's, okay, Elicia?
We can still watch it from here.
It's about to start.
You can watch the eclipse
together with Mama, okay?
Izumi!
Where are you? Izumi!
Alex, do you know what's going on?
Hmm, the Elric brothers
once told me about this.
They said that when they performed
human transmutation,
they were dragged
into the gateway of truth by black hands.
What is the gateway of truth?
I do not know.
What?
Have you gotten through?
Sir, headquarters is safe.
Good. So do they have any information
concerning Ms. Izumi?
- No, sir.
- I see.
Anything else?
Captain Buccaneer,
along with several of his men,
were engaged by King Bradley...
while defending the main gate...
and were killed.
The captain was working together
with those from Xing,
inflicted a mortal wound on Bradley,
and pushed him over into the moat.
Impossible!
Impossible, impossible, impossible!
King Bradley cannot be killed that easily.
He is a superhuman--
What about the main gate?
They're still defending it.
The Homunculus named Greed
has come over to our side,
and has mowed down
the Central troops at the main gate.
A Homunculus?
Impossible.
A Homunculus would not turn
against the good gentleman.
They said that Captain Buccaneer died
with a smile on his face.
I see.
If he died with a smile,
then we can't let ourselves weep over him.
- Let's keep going!
- Yes, ma'am!
Mr. Sig, let's go.
- We have to go find your wife as well.
- Yeah.
Oh, Teacher.
- Ed?
- Are you all right?
Yeah, more or less.
Teacher, what are you doing here?
That's what I'd like to know.
So where are we?
I don't know.
I just suddenly got whooshed here.
Al!
- Al, snap out of it.
- Al too? Could it be...?
- What's wrong with you, Al? Hey!
- That the sacrifices are being gathered?
One, two, three...
Four of you? That's one short.
Could the last one be being made now?
What is that monster?
Hohenheim!
Edward... And he caught Alphonse too.
Oh, as well as Ms. Izumi.
You'll have to excuse my sorry appearance.
What in the world...?
There's nothing to it.
Mind yourself.
I will drain the Philosopher's Stone
from inside you later at my leisure.
Hohenheim, what is that black thing?
A copy of me.
The one the Homunculi called "Father."
Wha--?
You're telling me
this is that bearded bastard?
That's right.
I destroyed the leather bag
he was in, but...
You keep your mouth closed, Hohenheim.
Now, greetings, my sacrifices.
Welcome to my castle.
Al, wake up. This doesn't look good.
Al?
Hey, Al. Alphonse!
My word, the people up there
are so unreliable.
To think that they can't even get
five sacrifices ready for this day.
But then, they only managed
to assemble those who took the bait
of something small like immortality.
I suppose it's no surprise
they didn't get the job done.
Why, you--!
Wha--?
All right, good, hold him there.
Now then, Mustang, we are out of time.
I would appreciate it if you would proceed
to cooperate with us.
Could you perform
a little human transmutation
and open the gateway for me?
What?
It doesn't matter who.
A parent you've lost, a lover, a friend...
The one you were so close to.
What was his name? Hughes?
He will do too. I will get things set up
for you over here.
I'm one of the sacrifices?
Yes. Those who have opened
the gateway can become sacrifices.
That's why the Elric brothers were chosen?
Yes, it is.
They told me that human transmutation
could not be done.
What kind of fool would perform it
knowing it would fail?
Yes, you're right.
You see, all you have to do
is open the gateway and return.
No way!
I won't perform human transmutation
nor will I open the gateway!
I told you, we are out of time.
Lieutenant!
Lieutenant. Lieutenant!
Now, why don't you try opening
the gateway, Mustang?
Why, you--
Lieutenant, can you hear me?
Answer me!
Now, perform human transmutation
and become the fifth.
Come on, if you don't hurry,
the woman will lose her life.
Ah, I know. Would you like
to transmute her after she dies?
That would be okay too.
I won't die.
You see, I am under orders not to die.
If people could obtain
an immortal body like that,
it wouldn't be very sporting.
Mustang, what will it be?
Your precious woman is about to die.
If you do nothing,
she will soon bleed to death.
However, I am a doctor
that can use alchemy
and I even have a Philosopher's Stone.
Which is to say,
I would be able to save this woman's life
with all certainty.
But if she dies
before you make up your mind,
then there will be nothing that I can do.
Oh?
She sure has grown quiet. Has she died?
Colonel...
there is no need for you
to perform human transmutation.
You'll do it, won't you, Mustang?
Well?
All right.