Colonel.
There is no need for you to perform
human transmutation.
You'll do it, won't you, Mustang?
Well?
All right.
Oh, you're going to do it?
All right, Lieutenant.
I will not perform human transmutation.
You're going to forsake her?
How cold of you.
Forsake?
As someone who treats
these men as sacrificial pawns,
you're the last person
I want to hear that from.
They are happy to serve
as sacrificial pawns.
I fed these men, who were
abandoned by their parents,
and would have died
if I had done nothing.
I gave them a first-rate education.
I gave them a reason to exist.
These men are grateful to me.
Which is why you let yourself
be caught off-balance.
What do you--?
He vanished?
Yeah, we're grateful. After all,
I was able to nab you like this.
Let me go!
Let everyone loose, right now!
Or else...
I'm the only doctor who can
use alchemy here right now!
If you kill me, you'll never save
the woman! Do you understand?
Heh, don't give me
that third-rate line, Doctor.
A Philosopher's Stone!
Out of my way!
Lieutenant! Stay with me!
Lieutenant, open your eyes!
Lieutenant! Lieutenant! Lieutenant!
Are you all right?
If I can just get that...
Don't you die!
Lieutenant, stay with me!
This comes first!
Let me take care of this!
Lieutenant!
I've stopped the bleeding for now,
but you have to get her
to a proper doctor.
Thanks, I owe you one.
Colonel, I'm sorry...
Don't speak. Just rest.
I'm so glad...
...you understood the look I gave you.
It's because we've been
together for so long.
Besides, you were glaring at me
with that look that said,
"Perform human transmutation,
and I'll shoot you."
That's the last one, huh?
Thanks for your help, everyone.
Hey, no problem.
Oh, right! The Philosopher's Stone!
King Bradley...
His wounds aren't regenerating.
Long time no see, Mustang.
Long time no see, sir.
It would be difficult for me to say
that you're looking as good as ever.
Bradley! Take this!
Knowing you, I thought that when
someone dear to you fell before your eyes,
you wouldn't hesitate to turn
to human transmutation.
I might have done so, a little while ago.
However, right now,
I have people who will stop me
and show me the right path to take.
Here I thought you were pathetic
creatures who would never learn,
but there are those like you
who can change
in a short period of time.
The thing about you humans is,
it infuriates me when you don't act
the way I think you will.
What's wrong?
He's under us... He's right under us.
Why, you... I won't let you interfere
with the good gentleman.
Give it up, old-timer.
I'm not letting you--
Gerso!
Shake it off!
Run!
This is bad!
Something's coming. Something terrible.
Sorry, but look after the lieutenant.
Colonel!
Well done, Bradley.
That's the boy I brought up--
Colonel Mustang, you are the fifth.
The last one.
Not again.
What's with all this racket today?
Ah, the eclipse has begun, huh?
I didn't want to have to resort to this
but there is no choice.
We are out of time.
We're going to force you to open
the gateway, Colonel Mustang.
I won't perform human transmutation.
It doesn't matter if you don't want to.
An alchemist who has knowledge
of human transmutation
has been assimilated by Pride.
He has the constructional formula.
He is pinned. Move back, Wrath.
Well now, I wonder what
you'll have taken from you.
- Colonel!
- No! You'll get caught in it!
Colonel!
The human transmutation is complete.
That old guy with the glasses?
Where is the colonel?
Relax. Right about now,
Mustang is with our father.
I can't vouch for
his physical integrity though.
Now, you see what sort of shape I'm in.
Who will take down
the Fuhrer of Amestris
and claim fame for themselves?
A Chimera?
The outsider?
Mustang's dog?
Or perhaps...
you'll all come at me at once?
What is this?
I don't feel like we can win
against this broken-down old man.
Right under us...
Beneath that hole...
As soon as May said
he was right below us,
the old guy in the glasses said
that he wouldn't let us interfere
with the good gentleman.
Apparently, he didn't want us
to go down there.
Ho, so that's where the center is?
That's right.
There is an incredible mass
of chi right below us.
In that case...
Colonel!
Here is the fifth, Father.
- Hmm, that makes all five...
- Are you okay, Colonel? Colonel?
- ...or so I would say.
- Wake up, Colonel!
But Alphonse Elric has not arrived.
Are you okay, Colonel?
Fullmetal?
Where are we?
The ringleader's hideout. Colonel,
what in the world happened to you?
I was flung into a white space,
before a large gateway.
Gateway?
You don't mean
something was taken from you?
But your arms and legs are there!
Fullmetal,
I'm surprised that you can tell
my condition in all this darkness.
What are you talking--?
It's pitch-black. I can't see anything.
The lights...
Where are the lights?
Don't tell me...
You can't see, then?
That is good.
Your abilities are quite honestly
the most problematic
among all
of the State Alchemists right now.
Now wallow there in your grief.
Colonel, you performed
human transmutation.
Fullmetal,
do you think I would do such a thing?
We forcibly had him open the gateway.
It all worked out in the end.
Now, the combat abilities of
the most irksome Colonel Mustang
have been reduced to as good as nothing.
The truth is cruel.
For those who tempted fate,
and sought their mother's warmth
by bringing the dead back to life,
one lost the leg upon which he stood,
as well as his only family.
The other had his entire body taken away
to be replaced with one
that feels no warmth.
One who sought her child
was given a body
that could never again have children.
And then, the one who looked forward
to the future of his nation
had his eyesight taken from him.
Now, he can no longer see his future.
It gives humans proper despair,
so that they do not become boastful.
Such is the very thing
that you humans call your god...
Truth.
I don't buy it!
I'd get it if he did it on his own,
like we did.
But to force someone who doesn't
want to do human transmutation
to be caught in the middle of this,
and have his eyesight taken...
Is that what you call proper?
I don't accept any truth
that's so unreasonable.
You're planning to interfere with Fate?
What is your real name?
I have no name.
I cast it aside.
What a coincidence.
I don't know my real name either.
It might be interesting
if we fellow nameless ones
killed each other.
May!
There he is!
For her to put a hole
in my home like that...
That little girl...
His outer appearance may have changed
but his presence is that
of the immortal ringleader.
Oh, Alphonse! What's happened to you?
I don't know. He won't wake up.
Oh, no!
Alphonse! Alphonse!
Please, wake up!
Alphonse!
My body...
That's my body.
I've been waiting a long time.
Welcome home.
What thin arms you have.
Nothing but skin and bones.
It's all you can do just
to stand up, isn't it?
I can't...
I can't fight in a body like this!
Everyone else is fighting, though!
You don't want to become one with me?
It's not that at all!
For a long, long, long time,
I've thought about getting
my original body back.
And yet...
I can't right now.
That body isn't going to cut it.
You want to go back there?
You want to go back there, in that body?
If you do, I won't stop you.
I'm sorry! I'll be back!
Just hang in there a little while longer.
I swear, I'll be back!
Absolutely! I promise.
Al!
Al! Are you all right?
- Alphonse!
- Al!
Teacher, Brother, May!
Then this is...
He left behind the body he's been
searching for all these years,
so that he could help his friends.
My noble soul.
As your vessel, I am proud of you.
But with your return,
the world just might become filled
with despair.
Alphonse.
That makes all five.