What's the matter?
The guys outside say
they want to negotiate.
Just one man. He's coming to you.
Don't shoot, all right?
Hands above your head.
Any false moves, and we will shoot!
It's all right.
Let him through. He's a man we can trust.
Lieutenant!
Is there any way
that I can see my husband?
You can't!
There's no telling
what will befall you if you go.
We can't completely rule out
the possibility
of military forces being in the hands
of the anti-Bradley faction.
Please, be patient
just a little while longer.
Yes. Yes, you're right.
You say you don't accept the truth?
Yeah, that's right!
And you! You might think you've won
because you've got all your sacrifices
but we aren't going to be so easily used.
Your words are futile.
Can you stand? We're getting out of here.
No, you can't get away.
You are already inside my belly.
What is this?
Is the good gentleman, or Father,
or whoever it is, in there?
Right about now,
Mustang is with our father.
I can't vouch
for his physical integrity, though.
- May!
- Beansprout girl!
You there, with the eyes all over you.
You're immortal, aren't you?
You're not denying it?
Alphonse, I will be taking that one.
Just a minute.
He's too much for you alone.
No, I have my alkahestry.
Sure, even if our alchemy is bound,
you can still use alkahestry, but...
I will leave the smaller Homunculus
to the two of you!
You make it sound so simple.
They forced the colonel's gate open?
If you can use such a strong-arm move,
why haven't you done it before now?
Fullmetal...
when I was caught up
in the transmutation, he said,
"I didn't want to have to resort to this,
but there is no choice."
So it carries some sort of high risk.
Probably.
Let's give it a shot.
All right! We can use our alchemy!
He ran? Up to now, he's always
deflected us with his black shadows.
We might be able to take him now!
You've messed up my home yet again.
What am I to do with you?
Immortality will be mine!
You are someone I do not need here.
Away with you.
No, young lady!
He doesn't have to move to--
May!
What in the world is going on?
There's still no contact
with the command center.
Reporting in!
The city is infested with Ishvalans.
Several MP squads have been--
Why, you--
Excuse me! There's no time to explain.
No! No!
Help me! Help me! Help me!
Excuse us, ma'am.
We won't harm you, so please tell us...
This house is right here, correct?
Whoa, it's getting darker
right before our eyes.
I wonder if the others
are doing all right.
This is the place, right?
Yeah, no doubt about it.
All right.
Now then,
it's up to you, Scar.
It's nice to face death
directly like this, isn't it?
The only thing I feel is a pure sensation,
telling me to "fight to the death."
Rank, personal history, birth,
race, sex, name...
I don't need any of it.
To just fight
without being bound to anyone,
or on behalf of someone...
it feels so good.
I've finally arrived.
What's wrong? Is that the best you've got?
It's not good enough!
Entirely not good enough.
Let me see you try to destroy me,
human with no name!
Unbelievable.
That's the look on your face, isn't it?
Yes, that I would use something like this?
Up until a little while ago,
I wouldn't have imagined it either.
I considered for a long time
what I could do.
And this is what I came up with.
The reconstruction transmutation circle
that I got from my brother's research!
You miserable humans
never give up the struggle.
May!
Damn! Al, go help May!
What about Pride?
Let me handle him.
I can take him by myself!
All right.
Young lady!
You keep still, Hohenheim.
Alphonse!
What's the matter? What's the matter?
Your attacks are pretty lackluster,
aren't they?!
Please do not misunderstand.
Until you have fulfilled your purpose...
You have to keep me alive, huh?
Then all I have to do is defeat you all
before that happens!
Defeat us? Please, do try.
You are short,
so you've always fought those
who were bigger than you.
Put another way,
you have little experience
fighting those who are smaller than you.
Dad! I apologize if I hit you!
Why, you...
You're right, I've fought nothing
but opponents bigger than me.
Which is why...
...I know the attack patterns
a runt will have!
Sensei!
His no-motion transmutations
are a real problem.
It's just about time.
We are done playing around.
Time to get to work for me, my sacrifices.
Ah, it's completely dark.
Hurry...
Hurry and get us to the center
of the transmutation circle.
Hurry! We won't make it in here!
Stop acting up!
Take me to the center! Do it now!
We'll be swallowed up!
Hurry!
The time has come!
Have you ever thought
of this planet as a life form?
Or perhaps I should say a system,
rather than a life form.
A system that can retain
a vast amount of information
about the universe,
incomparable to the amount
of information a single human has.
Once one opens that gateway,
how much power would they gain?
Have you ever thought about that?
Right here, right now,
using you sacrifices,
I am going to open that gateway!
That's where the center is, huh?
Greed!
The center of the world is mine!
I am going to lay hold on the world!
He got him.
I thought you might be coming,
my son, Greed.
You are the avarice
that was born of me, after all.
Anything I want, you will want,
as we are the same.
Ed!
The center of the world
is here!
Damn it!
What?
What is this?
Yes, fight each other, gateways!
Repel each other!
What magnificent energy!
It's all I can do just to contain it.
With this power, I will open up
the gateway of this planet!
What is this?
Winry...
Ms. Pinako, what is this?
Hohenheim, when you come back,
I'm gonna slug you.
Ed... Ed...
God!
Respond to the cry of my soul!
Come to me!
Yes, come to me! I will continue
to be bound by you no longer!
I shall drag you down to the earth,
and make you a part of me!