The sun is a he.
It represents masculinity.
The moon is a she.
It represents femininity.
When the sun and the moon intersect,
it means both genders in one.
In other words,
it represents a perfect being.
I wonder if by "perfect being,"
it means immortality.
Or something even more incredible?
Even more incredible?
Like say, God or something.
Yes, come to me!
I will continue to be bound
by you no longer!
I shall drag you down to the earth,
and make you a part of me!
Is everyone all right? What happened?
Well done, my sacrifices.
You actually did it!
Yeah.
I have acquired... God.
God?! How can that be?
It's possible, given a large enough
amount of energy.
Energy... a Philosopher's Stone?!
It can't be...
you mean, everyone was turned
into a Philosopher's Stone?
Just how many people were sacrificed...?
The population of this country
is about 50 million.
You bastard!
Damn!
Your alchemy is bound.
Farewell, gentlemen.
What are you doing?
Now that I have obtained God,
it is even possible for me
to create suns in the palm of my hand.
Shall I turn it loose in here?
From the moment
that you obtained God or whatever,
we had already started
turning the tables on you.
Over many long years,
I calculated and calculated,
arranging the Philosopher's Stones,
the friends inside me,
in preparation for this day.
The time has come.
He has done that which must not be done.
There are no longer bodies
for us to return to.
However, the people of Amestris
do have bodies to go back to.
Yes. Let's return their souls
back to their bodies.
It is what Hohenheim asked of us.
You just drove in Philosopher's Stones?
But they are merely points.
Without a circle, they will not activate.
That is a fundamental of alchemy.
But we do have a circle.
Something with such enormous power,
it would activate on its own,
even if something were to happen to me!
The shadow of the moon,
cast upon the Earth by the eclipse!
We're going on ahead, Hohenheim.
You would block me,
no matter what, Hohenheim?
That is the reason I came here,
Dwarf in the Flask, Homunculus!
- Winry, are you all right?
- What was that just now?
Did we all lose consciousness?
- Ms. Pinako, you too?
- So it would seem.
But that was...
How would you even describe it?
It was like...
It felt like we were inside
a vortex of anguish.
Did it work?
The souls of the people of Amestris
have each returned to their own bodies.
And with just the souls
of the Xerxesians that he already had,
I doubt he can keep
what he calls God suppressed.
I can always create
another Philosopher's Stone.
Using a hundred million
or even a billion!
There is no shortage of the energy
that humans are!
May!
Reading the flow of power in the ground
and making use of it
is an alkahestrist's stock in trade.
What's more, the greater the power
the other side has,
the greater my own power becomes.
Mister, dead ahead!
Damn. I don't have what it takes
to cancel out his energy!
Please hang in there, mister.
My defensive array is crumbling!
It's no use!
- Dad, hang in there!
- Come on, you bastard! Stay focused!
What can I say?
I'm just a foolish old man,
but now I want to show off what I've got!
If this doesn't end soon,
the Philosopher's Stone
inside Dad will run out!
Aren't you done yet, Scar?
Ishvalan!
I thought that alchemy,
the construction of matter,
was blasphemy against Ishvala,
the creator of all things!
Have you abandoned your god?
Is that all that your god is...
to you people?
Nay!
During the Ishvalan Civil War...
when you were steeped in despair...
you must have thought,
somewhere in your heart,
that there was no god
anywhere in this world!
I never believed in fate or God,
but I suppose it can be said of this
that Providence has taken
no favor with me.
The heavens have sent me
a rather dashing visitor.
Here to avenge your grandfather?
Very well.
- Any last words?
- None.
Such a sad life, King Bradley.
Didn't you love anybody?
Your friends? Your wife?
My wife?
Are you saying
you have nothing to say to her?
When she finds out
that you are a Homunculus...
Do not befoul yourself
with such trivial words
as "sad" and "love," young lady.
Do not mock me.
She is the woman that I chose.
There is no need
for any last words between us.
That is what it is to be the wife
of a king.
While engaging yourself
in pointless questions,
you've missed your chance
at vengeance, young lady.
My life was lived on the rails
that were laid down for me,
but thanks to you humans,
it was, to some degree,
a good life, one worth living.
I'm sensing life.
It's a Philosopher's Stone.
This?
Are you all right?
- Take me over there.
- The transmutation circle is broken.
No matter!
Over there is where the center is.
All right.
Brother...
To tell you the truth,
the hatred inside me is not gone,
and yet I am about to help Amestris,
the object of my hatred.
Brother, you spoke of positive streams
and negative streams...
but as I paradoxically carry
both of them...
I wonder which way I will flow.
Here it comes!
Take that! The seat that you
so arrogantly reclined in is now rubble!
You've been so self-indulgent,
you bastard.
I'm gonna kick your ass,
right along with that damn truth!
Was that alkahestry just now?
No, it's what my brother came up with.
My brother researched alchemy.
As he expanded beyond it,
he began to research alkahestry too.
Alkahestry is an art that uses
the flow of chi through the Earth.
The alchemy of this country
uses tectonic energy.
However, my brother realized something.
Alchemists weren't able to use it
to full measure.
There was an inhibiting component
between the alchemist
and the tectonic energy.
I felt it when I entered this country...
a sensation like people
were crawling around under the ground.
Yes.
That was probably
the Philosopher's Stone
that stretches out underground
throughout the land.
Take that! And that!
Mister, you created a transmutation circle
that returned everyone's souls?
Yeah, and it worked.
The reverse transmutation circle
which Scar activated
is there to correct
the alchemy of this country.
After all of Scar's brother's
long research,
he was skeptical
about this country's alchemy...
and went on to discover the existence
of the nationwide transmutation circle.
And so, using it as a base,
he superscribed it in alkahestry
and developed
a reverse transmutation circle
that would render
the Philosopher's Stone ineffective.
Now we can use the tectonic energy
inhibited by the Philosopher's Stone
to its full extent.
Keep pouring it on!
Make him use his Philosopher's Stone!
At some point, he will run out of energy!
But when?
I don't know!
I don't know, but you have to keep it up!
Take this!
That takes me back.
If it isn't the tub
I took a bath in earlier!
You have one too, Daddy, sir.
Move it, Greed!
Don't move!
Take it nice and easy.
- Lieutenant Hawkeye?
- Major.
What the...?
That rat.
He went to go make a Philosopher's Stone.
- After him!
- Right!
And we'll get you to a safe place
while we're at it.
Sorry.
I didn't expect to be so useless
at such a critical time.
Brother!
Al! Go on ahead!
He appears to want something from me.
Al, let's go!
Don't you let yourself get beaten, Ed!
Right!
Dear!
Izumi!
This is no time to relax.
Look after the colonel.
Right.
Colonel!
There's someone up there
that we have to eliminate, so we're off.
- Are you injured, Colonel?
- My eyes have had it.
Lieutenant, what is the status
of your injuries?
You're doing it again!
Please, worry about yourself. Your eyes...
Can you still fight?
Yes, sir!
- Young Lord!
- It's Greed.
Sheesh, you tagged along all the way here?
Wrath...
Oh... he's dead.
He looks so content. Pisses me off.
Greed, it's pathetic
that you would throw away your honor
as a Homunculus.
Why are you guys so obedient
to that father of yours?
What a senseless question to ask.
It's only natural that we would obey
our own father, isn't it?
You're the one who's senseless.
"Only natural," you say?
You're just a mindless punk
who doesn't try to think for himself!
I don't get it.
Why are you his willing lapdog?
You've been worn as ragged as you now are,
and you don't even care.
So what?
Please don't go applying
your human sensibilities
onto us Homunculi!
This container won't last much longer.
However, since you, like my father,
are of Hohenheim's blood,
we are virtually brothers.
Edward Elric, give your container,
your body, to me!
What?
You cannot have it.
Indeed, you cannot have it,
Homunculus Pride.
Kimblee! It can't be!
There's no way
you could maintain your individuality
among this tempest of souls!
Tempest? Please, don't make me laugh.
These voices of bitterness
are like a lullaby to me.
Why are you interfering, Kimblee?
Yes, well, if you had kept your honor
as a Homunculus as you fought,
I would have done nothing.
You speak of your pride
or honor as a Homunculus,
but the moment any danger befalls you,
you try to escape
into the container of a human,
the lower life form
that you look down on.
Quite unbecoming of you.
He's going to kill me!
You do not understand Edward Elric.
Selim!
Impossible. He's turned himself
into a Philosopher's Stone,
and now he's forcing his way inside me?
I've caught you, Selim!
Stop.
Please stop!
So that's your real body, huh?
Once this is all over,
I'll have to go apologize to Mrs. Bradley.
You wait right there, Selim, you fool!
Mama.