Why, you...!
I won't let you have any more!
Dad!
He was trying to create
another Philosopher's Stone.
The humans should just turn
into the Stone.
Why do you treat them
like lower life forms?
Philosopher's Stones
are made from humans.
Homunculi are made
from Philosopher's Stones.
So, what do you make from Homunculi?
What do they produce?
Can you call a being
that only brings about destruction a god?
You may think you've become
a perfect being,
but you've reached a dead end!
Have I? Then I will produce humans.
I have obtained immortality.
I am... still... alive...
King Xerxes!
A body!
- I've gotten a body.
- I finally got a body.
No! Stop it!
- We're human again.
- This is...
- We suffered for so long.
- This isn't right!
Look! We have bodies.
Hohenheim...
Everyone...
Damn you!
Oh, no--
What's this? What's happening?
- Damn it!
- Greed!
- Gorius!
- Are you all right?
Perfect. Let me hop on too!
You need someone
who knows the situation, right?
Yeah. What the hell is going on?
Father, the first of the Homunculus,
is running amok.
At this point, we should leave behind
anyone who can't fight anymore.
Hey, the frog with the two women, get off!
You're hurt, right?
Don't be ridiculous!
If I don't lead our forces, who will?
Who cares? Get off, now!
This is no time to be talking
about who's in charge!
- I'm not taking orders from--
- Sir!
Transmission from headquarters.
Operations, it's me.
What's going on there?
Sir, half of Central Command Center...
Has been blown away.
What?
We can't establish contact
with the northern gate.
That's the magnitude of his power.
What sort of monster is he?
By all appearances, he's an ordinary man.
However, he has thousands of souls
in the Philosopher's Stone inside of him.
And with that energy, he has obtained
what he calls the power of God.
You alchemists understand
how serious that is, right?
A Philosopher's Stone...?
You regular humans, get off here.
My men are still fighting out there.
I am their commanding officer.
Sir, headquarters wishes to speak to you.
What is it?
Don't worry about it, sir.
Have you forgotten that we Briggs soldiers
are a force that can act
without missing a beat,
even when without our boss?
Yellow Squad, at the weapons depot,
are you still there?
East gate, Blue Squad, come in!
From what I gather,
you're injured, aren't you?
Please, stay back and watch.
- Alex!
- Yes, sir?
Take the radio with you.
Make sure you win.
You don't have to tell me that!
All right, let's go, Lieutenant.
Hey now, the two of you are hurt,
aren't you?
I'm going to burn up
his Philosopher's Stone.
I need the lieutenant's help to do so.
Whatever, let's hurry and get going.
My job is to protect the young lord.
Take care of Izumi and the others.
Okay then, here we go!
So this is where you died.
You're the one who defeated him?
He was already covered
in wounds when he came here.
If he hadn't been,
it would have been a close call.
Captain Buccaneer,
working with the man from Xing,
inflicted a mortal wound upon Bradley.
Well, Bradley?
My men are strong, aren't they?
Shao May, you're all right.
Thank goodness.
Alphonse!
May.
Thank goodness you're alive.
Alphonse, your body...
Alphonse!
Oh, no! You shielded me, and...
Alphonse! Alphonse!
Sensei!
Sensei! Sensei!
I'm alive.
Mr. Hohenheim protected me
in the nick of time.
Hohenheim!
Hey, shake it off! Hey--!
I'll start with you two.
Stop!
Target the long-haired blond man.
Do not hit the Fullmetal Alchemist!
Yes, sir!
East gate, Blue Squad, hurry!
West gate, White Squad,
take position in front of the west wing!
Roger!
Sensei!
Fire!
Yo, Fullmetal, are you okay?
It's no use!
That won't even make him flinch!
You're kidding me!
Don't give him a chance to hit back!
Yes, sir!
Damn! He's not even breaking a sweat!
Copy that. Patch me to all units.
Yes, sir. Are you sure?
Cease fire! Get down!
- Did I hit him?
- You were off by just a bit.
Adjust targeting to 12 o'clock!
I can't see,
so I can't throttle the flames.
You don't have to throttle them at all!
Range 50. No, 53!
This clapping transmutation
just feels weird!
Incoming attack, dead ahead!
Nicely done.
Oh, this is handy.
Fire! Fire! Keep firing!
Don't give him the opportunity
to hit back!
Keep making him use
his Philosopher's Stone!
Awesome!
With that kind of power,
I could conquer the whole world!
Hey, Greed.
Is this what you meant
when you were talking about
obtaining the whole world?
Yeah, once I get that,
everything in the world will be mine!
That just might fill the emptiness
inside me!
It could quench the thirst I've had
ever since I was born!
How despicable of you, Greed.
What you really want is something else.
You keep quiet, you little pissant.
I am Greed the Avaricious!
Whatever I want, I get!
Roasting time!
No effect whatsoever.
We have to do something
about his defenses.
We're running out of ammo!
Bring in some more!
How futile.
You humans cannot lay a finger on me.
If humans can't,
then how about a Homunculus?
You're just in time, Greed.
Such an obedient son.
I happened to need
another Philosopher's Stone.
I'll be taking yours.
Just kidding!
You can't take my Philosopher's Stone
unless you drop your barrier, huh?
But you didn't think that you could have
your godly powers taken from you, did you?
I will be taking all of it!
Greed!
Don't give up!
He defended himself with his arm.
He's at his breaking point!
He can't keep God or whatever
under his control anymore!
Stone... Stone!
Philosopher's Stone!
Get out of there, Edward!
Brother! Run!
Brother!
Stop!
Damn it!
Al!
Stop! Stop!
Let Brother... Let Brother...!
Let Brother...!
May, I need a favor.
Brother sacrificed his right arm
to bring my soul back.
So the reverse should be possible.
Alphonse...?
Just clear a path for me.
You can do that, right?
But if you do that, Alphonse--
There's no time! Please!
You're the only one I can ask to do this.
Stone...
Human...
Give me...
Edward!
...your energy!
What do you think you're doing?
No! Don't!
Al!
Beat him, Brother.
Stop!
Are you ready now?
Now we put our faith in Brother.
Yo, your soul has entered you, huh?
Will he be coming to get you back?
He will. Absolutely.
I can't wait to see what
he will sacrifice.
You dumbass!
It's working.
He's doing it. He's doing it!
- Go!
- Kid!
Go!
- Let him have it, short stuff!
- Lay him out!
- Edward!
- Ed!
Edward Elric!
Go!
Greed.
This is what you wanted so badly.
Am I right?
Edward!
Go!
Fullmetal!
Yeah, you're right.
What I wanted...
was to have friends like these.
Get up, benchwarmer!
I'm gonna show you
just how out of our league you are!