Don't you want freedom and rights,
Hohenheim?
Do you intend to live out your life
as a slave,
without obtaining the rights of man?
In that case, you're no different
than being inside a stuffy flask.
Why?!
All right! Clobber him, Ed!
Why, when I have acquired God...
...can a mere human...
...alchemist...
...bare-handedly...
He did it!
-He did it!
-We won!
Get hold of yourself, would you?
What are you letting yourself
get knocked around for?
Sorry.
Stone...!
Philosopher's Stone!
Give me your Philosopher's Stone!
This is bad!
Greed!
You dumbass! Let me go!
You'll be dragged in!
No way! I need to have you within me
if I'm going to be emperor!
That's impossible!
I was originally born of dear old Dad.
The power pulling me that way
is greater than that of Ling Yao's body,
and there's nothing I can do!
Don't give up, Greed! Tough it out!
Yikes!
My body!
Damn it all!
Being the emperor of Xing is quite a bit
lower than being king of the world,
but I guess it's not too bad.
Let's fight together, partner.
That's more like it--
What are you...?
This is where we say goodbye.
There's no need for you to be
sucked in by dear old Dad, too.
Hold on a second, Greed!
You just said we would
fight together, didn't you?!
Sucker-punching me like this is just...
I thought your creed was to never
tell a lie! To end it like this...
And you fell for it hook, line and sinker,
you little pissant!
That was my first and last lie ever.
Lan Fan has a Philosopher's Stone.
Take it and go home, kid.
Wait...
Wait, Greed!
Get over here, Lan Fan!
Later.
Greed!
Why, you...!
I managed to separate myself
from that annoying kid!
Greed! Why do you turn on your father?!
Call it a delayed rebellious phase,
Daddy, sir.
With the carbonizing ability you gave me,
I'll transform us into the weakest,
most fragile carbon there is!
Crafty devil!
Away with you, fool!
Greed!
Ah, damn... this is it, huh?
What are you looking at me
like that for, pissant?
Friends are connected by their souls!
There's no way you can forget it!
You want to pal up with us?
If you've got nowhere to go, come with us.
Sheesh, both Ling and the little runt
took a pretty cocky attitude with me.
Enough...
Yeah, that's enough.
I don't need anything more.
See you later, my soul... friends.
Guys...
My Stone... My Philosopher's Stone.
What...? What is this?
Go back to wherever you were born,
Dwarf in the Flask, Homunculus!
Why?!
I wanted to know everything
about this world!
Without being bound by anything!
Free, in the vast world!
I...!
Why?
Why wouldn't you become mine?
God! What is it you didn't like about me?!
It's because you didn't
believe in yourself.
You stole your power from others,
and despite being born of a person,
all you ever did was cling
to what you called God.
You yourself haven't grown.
Did you think that by detaching
yourself from your seven desires,
you would be able to surpass humans?
Don't make me laugh!
I wanted to be the perfect being!
I wanted to know everything in the world!
What's wrong with wanting that?
What's wrong with desiring that?
What's wrong with wishing for that?
What? What are you? What is your name?
Who do you think you are?
I am what you call the world.
Or perhaps the universe, or perhaps God,
or perhaps truth, or perhaps all,
or perhaps one,
and I am also you.
What gives you proper despair,
so that you do not become boastful,
is truth.
It gives humans proper despair,
so that they do not become boastful.
It is truth!
And so, I will give you despair as well!
No! I don't want to go back!
Stop! I can't bear to go on
being bound in there!
No! No! No!
Despair to those who become boastful.
What should I have done?
This is the outcome you desired.
You must have seen the answer.
What? What happened? Did we win?
Yes, sir.
However, Alphonse has not
returned from the other side.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
It's not your fault. It was Al's decision.
Ed! I've got the toll!
Use it. It's a Philosopher's Stone.
Get Al back with it.
I can't.
I promised Al that we wouldn't
use a Philosopher's Stone
to get our bodies back.
There must be a way.
There has to be! Think.
Think it through.
Keep the thoughts coming!
Edward...
Use my life, and bring Alphonse back.
There's exactly one person's
worth remaining.
You dumbass, there's no way
I could do something like that!
It is our own fault, as brothers,
that we lost our bodies!
I am adamant that I will not
use human lives to get Al back!
And why should you need
to put your life on the line?
Because I'm his father.
This isn't about need, or reason.
You are dear to me.
I want you to be happy.
By neglecting you, I do bear
some responsibility
for your bodies ending up
the way they are.
I'm sorry.
I've lived long enough.
At least let me act like a father
at the end.
Don't be ridiculous, you rotten father!
Don't ever say anything like that again!
I'll lay you out!
I'm sorry, Edward.
Think! Think! You're the youngest
State Alchemist in history, right?
You've seen the truth,
so you can transmute
without transmutation circles!
There has to be a way!
There must be!
There must be many people who
are waiting for the day to come
when you get your bodies back.
If the possibility is there,
you should move forward!
That's right. Don't give up.
There has to be something. Something...
Something...
Al...
Al... Al...
May is weeping that much over Al?
Zampano, Mr. Gorilla,
the guys from Briggs,
the major,
Ling, Lan Fan,
Teacher,
our old man.
May, stand back a bit.
That's...
...a human transmutation circle!
I'll be right back.
This is the Fullmetal Alchemist's
final transmutation.
-Ed!
Edward Elric!
You're here to bring your brother back,
are you?
But how are you going to pull
a whole person out of here?
What price will you pay?
Will you offer your body?
I've got your price right here.
This huge thing.
This is my gateway of truth.
Which means it's up to me
how I use it. Am I wrong?
Is that what it's come to?
Are you sure about this?
If you lose your gateway,
you'll never be able to use alchemy again.
You're right.
It's true, beyond this gateway
lies everything about alchemy.
However, I've been manipulated
because of it.
After having been shown
the so-called truth,
I was convinced that I could
solve everything with alchemy.
But I was wrong. That was just arrogance.
You would lower yourself to
become just a normal person,
unable to use alchemy?
"Lower myself," nothing. I've been
just a person from the start.
An insignificant human
who couldn't save a little girl
who had been made into a Chimera.
You're sure you'll be okay without it?
-Ed!
-Fullmetal!
-Edward!
-Ed!
Edward Elric!
-Mr. Edward!
Ed!
Ed...
Even without alchemy, I still have them.
That is the right answer, alchemist.
You have beaten me.
Take it with you. All of it!
The back door is over there,
Edward Elric.
That was a crazy thing to do.
You too, Brother.
Now, let's go home. Together.
Oh, he's coming around.
Are you all right, Alphonse?
Mr. Zampano, Mr. Darius, all of you...
Dad...
Welcome back.
I'm home.
It's so warm.
Al...
Alphonse!
May!
I was... I was...
Oh, right, sorry. That was
a hard thing to put you through.
Thanks, May.
Listeners of Radio Capital,
today, a force led by General Armstrong
and Colonel Mustang
took control of the Central
Command Center and the Assembly.
This was done to put a halt
to the actions of the military's
senior staff.
They were undertaking
a large-scale alchemic experiment,
which would have sacrificed
the majority of the nation's population.
Two of the masterminds behind
this nefarious experiment,
who took advantage of
His Excellency the Fuhrer's absence,
General Cremin and General Edison,
have been arrested,
and the forces led by the two generals
have been disarmed.
His Excellency, Fuhrer King Bradley
and his dear son Selim lost their
precious lives amid the turmoil.
Colonel Mustang announced that he
would carry on the Fuhrer's wishes
by maintaining the nation's security
and conferring with all those
taking policy measures hereafter.
You are the one who gave me blood, right?
Don't you want freedom and rights,
Hohenheim?
Okay then, what do you find happiness in?
Well, I don't want to ask too much,
but I think I would be happy
if I could leave this flask.
You're right, Dwarf in the Flask,
Homunculus.
You were born of my blood.
I...
Mr. Hohenheim...
Your sons have both been
admitted to the hospital.
Ah, thanks. I'm grateful.
No, I am the one who is grateful.
Without those two boys,
Edward Elric and Alphonse Elric,
this nation would be no more.
Thank you very much.
Thanks.
I'm home, Trisha.
Edward called me "father."
Though he did say "rotten" before it.
I always thought that living
so much longer than others
was a hard thing to bear.
But after coming across you and our sons,
I've sincerely come to feel
happy to be alive.
It has been a fulfilling life.
Yes, it has been enough.
Thank you, Trisha.
Ah, but still...
Sure enough, I don't want to die.
There really is no help for me, huh?
Hohenheim!
Oh, you came back, did you?
You imbecile.
What a happy look on your face
to die with.