- Which room is Colonel Roy Mustang in?
- Let's see...
May I ask your name?
My name is Knocs.
I'm a private-practice doctor.
If you relay that to him,
he'll know who I am.
- Hey, young lady.
- It has been a long time.
Who is this gentleman?
Oh, it's kind of a long story.
You might say he's my big gun.
Well? Is he letting it get him down?
The crops that will be planted
in the Ishvalan region
- will primarily be double-cropped.
- Okay, that's a mistake.
It's not double-cropping,
it's dual-cropping.
There's no way you're going
to earn their trust like this.
- I know!
- Okay, okay.
So what two crops are they raising?
- Wheat and cotton.
- Correct.
- See? You are getting this, aren't you?
- Give me some credit.
I've been looking into this
since before it all started.
He said he was going
to solve this Ishvalan problem
- before he became F端hrer.
- Solve it?
For that matter,
become F端hrer, in the first place?
That voice... Is that you, Dr. Knocs?
Hey, what can I say,
you're doing all right, huh?
Yeah, these guys are pests.
They won't give me any rest.
- No, not that, I meant your eyes.
- Yeah.
Apparently, this is the punishment
that truth gives
to those who dream of the future.
Are you okay?
Well, who can say?
But I can't just stop dead in my track.
So, F端hrer?
Or before you get to that, Ishval?
The Ishvalan War of Extermination.
That's where this all started.
Yeah. Both for you, and for me.
- Now it's time to come to terms with it.
- Come to terms?
First, I'm going to open
the closed-off Ishvalan areas.
Then, I'm going to return
the Ishvalans living in the slums
back to their holy land.
There's still a lot to be done.
It was because of Scar
and the other Ishvalans
that we were able to make it
through all of this.
We have to return the favor
for all that they've done.
Colonel, I brought the materials
you requested.
This won't blot out our sins, but we would
like to start with whatever we can do.
Good grief, all of you.
Hey, Marcoh, looks like they'll save us
the trouble of asking.
Marcoh? Doctor Marcoh?
Colonel Mustang...
I have a Philosopher's Stone here.
Might we not be able to return
your eyesight with this?
Yeah.
This Stone was one
that I once created using Ishvalan lives.
I think it would be presumptuous
of me to ask,
but if it were to aid
in the reestablishment of Ishval...
No, I am not able to hear their voices
so this will be a request from me,
personally.
I would like to heal you with this Stone.
For the sake of Ishval!
They might be upset over this,
Fullmetal, too.
But I will use it anyhow.
I will devote all my efforts,
on that basis.
Before I do, however...
...there is someone who needs
that Stone more than I do.
I will go after he does.
Yes, in your hearts for 80 years,
your Havoc General Store!
Hey, Breda. What's up?
What? To Central? Now?
I'll find out when I get there?
All right, you...
How are your injuries, Scar?
- Why did you save me?
- At first, I did it
because it would let me get
your alkahestry,
but then the circumstances changed.
Mustang told me to let him have Miles
to help with his Ishvalan policies.
So I thought I'd take you with me.
Not as Scar, of course,
but as an Ishvalan.
What do you say?
Will you work with me to reestablish
the teachings of Ishvala?
We cannot allow our historic religion
and culture to die out.
The death of a culture
is the death of a people.
By your hand,
rescue our people from death.
A reason why I was kept alive.
Are you telling me to live on
and keep looking, Brother?
All right. I will work with you.
You may take this body of mine
with you wherever you go.
All right. Miles, you handle it from here.
- Make sure everything goes smoothly.
- Yes, sir.
Mustang, once you find out
that Scar is still alive,
I'll bet your knuckles will turn white.
Scar, what is your real name?
I've died twice now.
I'm someone not of this world.
I don't need a name.
Call me whatever you like.
Okay.
I'll see you later, Ishvalan.
Are you okay?
I didn't think my muscles
had atrophied so much.
Want me to carry you?
No, that's okay. I'll walk on my own legs.
I'll come back at my own pace.
Brother, you go on ahead.
No. We left home together,
and we're gonna return home together.
Okay then, let's go home together.
Yeah.
- Brother, your leg...
- Yeah.
I haven't maintained it for a while, so...
- Thanks.
- Huh? What for?
- Nothing.
- What's with you? You're acting weird.
Come to think of it, I wonder if Ling and
the others have made it back to Xing yet.
It's been two months already.
They've probably made it by now.
I hope May is okay.
Don't worry about it. Leave her to him.
- May.
- Al.
- What's the matter?
- Oh, it's nothing.
Hey, princess of the Chang family!
Ling Yao!
Hey now, don't make that scary face at me.
You've been a fool, too,
getting mixed up in the troubles
of a foreign country like this.
You didn't even end up
with a Philosopher's Stone, huh?
The Yaos will be the next emperor, then.
But don't worry.
The Yao family will take it upon ourselves
to protect your family.
I even accepted the Homunculus Greed.
I will accept those of the Chang family
and all the other families, as well.
What kind of face is that?
Don't worry, the people of Xing
always keep their word, right?
Accepting everyone is too greedy,
Ling Yao!
Ah, maybe he rubbed off on me.
- Now then, let's go home.
- You're leaving?
Yeah. I want to bury Fu as soon as I can.
See you later.
Yeah! Later!
- A lot has happened, huh?
- Yeah.
Especially for you, Alphonse.
You seem to have become quite fond
of May Chang,
- the princess of Xing.
- She really is a nice girl, huh?
But never mind me, Brother,
are you sure about Winry?
Den, it's me.
Do we have visitors?
Den, you're tickling me!
Welcome home, dummies!
- Yeah!
- We're home!
TWO YEARS LATER
I'm not very good at this.
I guess that won't work.
- Oh, well.
- Brother, aren't you done fixing it yet?
I'm worn out from making
all those courtesy calls.
Winry is such a slave driver about that.
I mean, after all--
Winry says that once the apple pie
is done baking, we'll have a snack.
- Oh, okay.
- Wow.
- You can see especially far today, huh?
- Yeah.
- It's so vast.
Brother, I've been thinking
about something for a long time.
I've probably been thinking
the same thing.
How are things going with work?
Oh, well, the problems keep piling up,
and it's made me an old man overnight.
Although, Mustang is working hard
in the East,
and Armstrong
is working hard in the North,
so this old man can manage
to keep himself in the F端hrer's seat.
I am glad for that.
You are not going to leave it
to younger men?
Not quite yet. I won't trust this
to those whippersnappers.
Oh, my. That sounds like something
the late Bradley would say.
He was devoted to his work, as well.
Oh, no, I'm about as...
...frivolous as they come.
Oh, Selim, what's the matter?
The little bird is hurt. Help him.
Oh, my, how terrible.
Have Gramps call a veterinarian.
Can they fix him? Can they fix the bird?
It'll be fine. Now, off you go.
- He's grown up to be such a kind boy.
- Yes.
When I made up my mind to raise him,
everyone else was against it,
but he's been growing up well,
without any worries.
We're going to watch over him
for a little while longer.
If the boy starts showing anything
out of the ordinary...
You understand what will happen.
I'll see that he doesn't show anything.
Homunculi and humans...
Will we ever truly be able
to relate to each other?
New possibilities are exciting,
no matter how old you get.
Isn't Edward bummed out
about his left leg?
He's all right. He said he was okay
with leaving his leg as automail,
as an admonishment to himself.
Besides, he says that Winry
would get all melancholy without it.
Oh, now he's just carrying on!
I sure am glad you're back to normal.
I'm sure he's thrilled, too.
We were afforded a lot of happiness,
a lot of happiness,
in a lot of places by a lot of people...
Including Mr. Hughes.
And so, now, we feel it's our turn
to return the favor.
Is that equivalent exchange,
like the alchemists say?
No, by taking ten, and giving ten,
it all ends up the same.
So we take ten, put something of ourselves
on top of it, and return 11.
It's not much,
but it's a new principle we've hit upon.
Now we have to go and prove it.
There's something you want to do, then?
There was a girl we were unable to save.
We will never be able to forget that girl.
Welcome!
- Mr. Gerso, Mr. Zampano.
- Hey.
- There's plenty. Dig in.
- Okay.
Excuse me, could you bring some milk,
- and a sandwich?
- Sure.
- So you're done paying all your regards?
- Yes.
- So then, it's just about time.
- Right?
We're going to Xing.
I plan to study alkahestry
in full swing from May.
And not just Xing. I'd like to travel
around all the eastern countries,
and study all sorts of things.
I want to see many different sites,
learn many different things,
and meet many different people.
- So then, you're really coming along?
- Of course we are!
If we tag along with you,
good things will follow.
That's what our animal instincts
are whispering to us!
Alphonse...
We're going to find a way
to get our original bodies back.
You're the one who told us not to give up.
To act for ourselves,
and not leave it to others.
Your brother isn't going to Xing?
I'm going East, and Brother is going
to obtain more knowledge.
And then, by bringing the knowledge
of East and West together,
we may be able to keep the tragedy of Nina
from ever happening again.
However... Brother and I
are doing more than just that.
We want to see just how big the world is.
- Remember to oil it every day.
- Yeah.
Be sure to check
that the screws are tight, too.
Be sure to wipe off the water
when you get out of the tub.
- Right.
- Hey, are you listening?
- Yeah.
- Geez.
Here it comes.
Good grief, you're going to break it
and have to come back again like that.
Yeah, yeah, I know.
Whenever you need maintenance,
- be sure to call for an appointment.
- Sure.
Appointment?
What?
Winry...
What? Come out and say it.
Equivalent exchange!
I'll give you half of my life,
if you give me half of yours!
Why do alchemists have to be like this?
The principle of equivalent
exchange is all nonsense, isn't it?
- What did you say?
- It really is nonsense.
Never mind half, I'll give you all of it.
Okay, not all of it!
Ninety percent... No, 80 percent.
Seventy... no, that won't work. Okay, 85.
Yeah! I'd be willing
to give you that much.
What? Ed!
Sorry!
Ed!
You really are amazing!
You turn equivalent exchange
on its ear so easily!
What do you mean?
- Are you making fun of me?
- No, I'm not!
You've cheered me up. Thanks. I'm off.
Come back soon.
Well, well, Edward is off on a trip, too?
- They ought to just settle down a while.
- They're better off this way.
Men that sit around doing nothing
are no fun.
There's no point to lessons
that don't bring with them pain.
People can't gain anything
without sacrificing something, after all.
But once you've successfully
endured that pain,
you gain a heart that is stout enough
not to be overcome by anything.
Yeah, a heart made fullmetal.