Onii-chan!
Come on, how long are you going to stay in bed?
It's morning already.
Breakfast will get cold if you don't get up.
I made it for you and everything.
Take off your shirt, I'll put it in the wash.
You're a fake.
You see, my sister would never wake me up or cook breakfast or do my laundry.
In fact, she completely looks down on me and treats me like an idiot, or outright ignores me!
She doesn't listen to a word I say!
There's no way she'd come into my room like this to wake me up!
Onii-chan?
Basically, what I'm trying to say is...
There's no way my sister can be this cu—
sonna yasashiku shinai de donna kao sureba ii no
Don't be so nice to me, I just don't know how to react
tsumikasaneta kotoba de mienaiyo kimi no yokogao
With all these words piling up, I can't even see your face
dokodakke? nakushita kagi ha mitsukaranai mama de
Where is it? I lost my key, now I can't find it
tameiki surechigai ni iji hatte tsukarechau
Sigh, I'll burn out if I keep acting like this whenever we miss
hon no sukoshi chikaku kimi to no kyori ga
Maybe we're close? I just can't figure out
umaku tsukamenainda ato chotto na no ni
Just how far away I am, even though you're right there
sonna yasashikushinaide hora mata kizutsukeatte
Don't be so nice to me, see? We hurt each other again
tsumikasaneta uso demo ugokenakunatteru
With all these lies piling up, I can't even move
sugu ni ai ni ikitai kedo kotoba ha mitsukaranai shi
I want to see you now, but I don't know what to say
saigo no ichi pe-ji kai? kimi ni ha egao misetai
Is this the end for our story? I want you to see my smile
There's No Way I Could Love My Sister
All right, here's yours.
Where's Kirino?
She left already.
She has morning practice today.
I see.
She broke her record again.
They say she might be going to a big tournament soon!
I see.
Thanks for the food.
"I see" is all you say these days!
Morning, Kyou-chan!
Kirino-chan had morning practice?
It's hard living in the shadow of an overachieving little sister.
She's smart and pretty too.
Everyone in the shopping district talks about her.
So I'm being shamed at a town level?
I just want to live my life out quietly...
Normal is best for us humans.
Mundane, ordinary, or like the majority.
By that definition, you're perfect.
If there were a Miss Normal contest, you'd easily take first place.
The Normal Queen.
Really? How embarrassing...
No, that wasn't really a compliment.
Take your seats.
We're starting homeroom.
"Bring me a tree of sleet, will you, Kenji?"
This line is from Miyazawa Kenji's "Morning of Final Farewell", which was written for his sister.
It means “Please bring me a tree of rain”.
Biographers of his life say that his sister was a major influence in his life.
...his younger sister.
Good, now in Japanese.
"Instead of George driving was his little sister."
And so Ono no Imoko was the one who delivered Prince Shoutoku's famous "Son of Heaven from the Land of the Rising Sun" letter.
Bye bye!
What the hell was with today?
Some international little sister appreciation day?
What?
Nothing.
See you tomorrow!
Yeah.
Yeah, I went there too!
That place is crazy!
But don't you think the service sucks?
They ignored me the first time.
You too, Ayase?
Yeah, the one with the fat legs!
What? That's so dumb!
I'm back.
No way, the other one!
You know, the place Kanako told us about!
Oh, what was it again...
Yeah!
Yeah.
You don't remember?
We went there together after the shoot!
Wasn't it in May?
Yeah...
Yeah.
That's okay, I'll take you there.
Oh, it's today?
Sorry.
Don't touch it!
I'm going out.
What the hell.
What?
Why is her hair pink?
I'm home!
What's wrong, Kyousuke?
What's with the fetal position?
Don't mind me.
I just felt like a change of pace.
Oh?
I almost died as a member of society there...
So whose is this?
Dad's?
Mom's?
Kirino's?
None of them seem to fit...
Make Love with Little Sister! — Limited First Edition
Stardust Witch...
Little Sister...
Meruru...
Make Love...
Limited Edition...
R-18...
I make some pretty crazy mistakes!
I grabbed the nearest case while I was putting away this CD and switched the contents!
What the hell?!
Make Love? With Little Sister?
Like hell!!
What the hell do you want me to do?!
And R-18?!
This is an eroge, dammit!!
Kyousuke! Weren't the dirty magazines you hide under your bed good enough for you?
You're kidding me. That's seriously gross.
Die.
This is seriously bad...
If I'm caught with this...
Kyousuke!
Are you study—
—ing?
Did I come at a bad time?
Never mind me!
I'm just training my voice box!
And knock next time!!
Sorry!
I am definitely going to find out who the real culprit is!
What are you doing?
Huh?
None of your business.
That so?
At this moment, the suspect is obstructing justice by maintaining silence.
I'm going to the convenience store later. Need anything?
Get me some ice cream.
The culprit is among us!
Oh yeah, a friend of mine got really into this anime aimed at girls recently.
"Stardust" or something.
What are you talking about?
Well it sounded interesting, so I thought I might try it.
Isn't that what those "otaku" people watch?
They talk about them on TV sometimes.
Don't become like them.
Right, Dad?
Right.
Don't go polluting your mind with that filth.
Okay.
I guess that reaction rules them out.
Which means...
What's wrong, Kirino?
Thanks for the meal!
No way...
All right then...
I guess I'll head to the convenience store...
No way...
No way!
Hey.
What are you doing?
Who cares what I'm doing?
I care!! This is my room!
Move.
Answer my question.
Move!
This is what you're looking for, right?
So it is yours!
What are you talking about?
There's no way I'd watch an anime like that!
Your actions don't match your words!
If you weren't looking for this, what were you doing in my room?
I was...
Here, take it.
I said it's not—
Then throw it away for me.
Huh?
Sorry, I guess I misunderstood.
It's not yours then.
I don't want to carry it around though, so throw it away for me please.
F-Fine...
Do you think it's weird?
I said, i-if this were actually mine,
would you think that's weird?
Why would I think that's weird?
Really?
Yeah.
It doesn't matter what hobbies you have.
I wouldn't make fun of you.
I see.
What's with her?
Oh crap, I forgot about the ice cream...
What are you—
Be quiet.
Wh-What are you doing?
I-I need to talk to you.
Come to my room.
Can this wait till tomorrow?
No.
Don't stare at everything.
I'm not staring!
So, what did you want to talk about?
Hurry up or I'm out of here.
You said earlier...
Even if I had stuff like that, you wouldn't make fun of me.
Huh? Yeah...
Like, really really?
No questions?
Once is enough. I won't.
If you're lying, I'll kill you.
She'll kill me?
Uh—
—eling.
What? I didn't hear that.
I want some life counseling!
Life counseling?
You?
From me?
You have a closet?!
This room was originally Japanese-style.
It's probably left over from the remodeling.
So I turned it into this.
Y-You... th-this—
Wh-What is this?!
Oh, that's the PC version.
It originally came out on PS2, but it turned into a completely different series after the port.
It's a masterpiece, but it's a bit hard, so I wouldn't recommend it to an amateur.
I didn't ask about that!
By the way, I have everything before it too.
And what's that about amateurs?
Are you a pro? A professional?!
Here we go...
This is series 3, Super Sister-in-Law.
Series 2, Playing with Younger Sisters.
Series 9, Tengen Toppa 12 Sisters.
Series 16, Saishuu Heiki Imouto.
Are these all PC games?
Right.
Why are the boxes so big?
There are small ones too.
My Younger Sister Is Mai Waifu, Welcome to Younger Sister Land, Sister Collector: Imoking ~Sorry to Trouble You Every Sister~.
But these are the ones that go mainstream.
They're a completely different experience on the screen.
They catch your eye even if it's only by mail order.
Eroge are a race against the release.
Sorry, I have no clue what you're talking about.
What's this?
A special edition anime DVD box.
Special edition?
A re-edited complete version of the TV broadcast and unaired episodes on bonus disks and stuff!
And special booklets and mini-dramas and limited edition figures!
Amazing, right?
That... Stardust Meruru whatever thing?
Stardust Witch Meruru!
It's insulting if you don't get it right!
To who?
This is the broadcast version, this is the popular box, R1 version, R1 popular box, and Blu-Ray.
Why did you buy this many copies of the same thing?!
As an offering!
I seriously don't get anything you're saying.
Okay, calm down.
Try to understand this situation.
This is my sister's room.
I'm so proud of my collection!
My sister is in front of me,
along with a mountain of eroge and anime DVDs.
Aren't these things expensive?
Kind of, I guess.
This was ¥41,970, and this was ¥55,000.
That's hella expensive!
You're a middle schooler!
Where did you get that kind of money?!
Royalties, obviously.
What?
You're a model?
Yeah.
I had no idea...
Isn't this a major magazine?
Are you like, amazing or something?
It's not a big deal.
Really.
And so?
What do you mean, "so"?
What do you think?
About my hobby.
Surprising.
Anything else?
What else can I say?
Is it weird for me to have things like this?
No, I mean,
it's unexpected, but you're buying it with your own money.
What you buy is your choice.
You think so?
Really?
Yeah.
You don't have to care about what people think.
I'm just surprised.
I'm not making fun of you or anything.
I see. You're right.
You say good stuff sometimes!
Come to think of it...
Why are all these eroge the little sister love type?
Why do you think?
No clue...
Why are you backing away?
Well, you...
When you look at this package, don't you think it might be good?
What do you mean?
Look at it! Isn't it really cute?!
In other words, you have all those games...
...because you like little sisters?
Yeah!
Little sisters are just so cute!
Like in these galge, they call you "Onii-chan" or "Aniki" or "Nii-nii" or "Nii-chama"!
They all love me and have their own names for me!
It just makes me go crazy!
I-I see. That's nice...
Well, I've never been called anything like that,
and rather than going crazy, I'd get irritated...
In this one, I love this girl!
Younger sisters have to have black hair and twintails!
They look so pure, you just want to protect them, or hold them tight!
Your hair is brown.
You're pointing out your own problems yourself!
They're so lovely!
She's hopeless.
But why?
It's normally guys that buy things like that.
Why would—
Why do you like them?
I don't know.
You don't know?
I really don't know why!
I can't help it.
I fell in love with them before I knew it.
Even I know that this isn't a hobby normal girls have.
That's why I've been hiding it all this time!
But I really love them.
I Google them and try out the demos and before I know it I just have to buy them!
No matter how many times I try to stop, this cuteness just drives me crazy again!
Every news site keeps announcing new information every day and makes me want to buy them.
It's all KarzuSP and AkibaBlog's fault!
I don't really get it, but you could just stop reading them.
I wouldn't have any problems if I could.
Hey, what do you think I should do?
What you should do?
Maybe I should tell Mom and Dad—
Don't do that!
You wouldn't be worried if you could.
There will be big trouble if Dad ever finds out.
I don't even want to think about what would happen.
I see.
I get it. I'll help you out.
I'll make sure no one finds out about your hobby.
I don't know what I can do, though.
You will?
Sure.
If you need anything, just ask.
Anything that I can do, anyway.
R-Really?
Then I guess I will...
It might be a real help if you did.
I just want to confirm one thing though...
You play these little sister eroge because you love little sisters, right?
Huh? I said that, didn't I?
You don't have any ulterior motives?
Gross!
No way I would!
Get away from me!
This year's grossest!
Look here... in your games, the younger sister loves her brother, right?
Are you stupid?
Don't mix 2D and 3D!
No way any sister would love her brother in real life!
That's more like her.
We're done here, so get out now.
Yeah, yeah.
I guess I'll sleep.
Not cute at all.
What!
More life counseling.
Kyousuke
Wha... Sh-Shiori......?
Shiori is sleeping next to me. I...
Hug her gently and closely
Slip out of bed without waking her up
Screw that, kick her out of my bed!
Kyousuke
What the hell are you doing?!
Same to you! What are you making me do?!
You're unbelievable!
How can you just kick your cute sister out of your bed like that?!
Is she seriously saying that to me,
after slapping me awake in the middle of the night?!
I'm not in the wrong here!
This is definitely her fault!
Where in this world is there a brother who would play a game about loving a little sister with his little sister?!
I-I'm sorry! I'm sorry Onii-chan!
See? Don't you feel sorry for Shiori-chan?
What do you have to say for yourself?
Little sisters should treat their brothers with more respect—
Huh? What was that?
Nothing.
Now hurry up and carry on!
When I said I'd help you, I wasn't referring to this...
Huh?
You said to ask you if there's anything I need help with!
I was talking about keeping this a secret from Dad!
Why do you need me to play through an eroge with you?
Y-You just need to!
I want someone to give me an objective viewpoint of this game!
I want an actual opinion.
How can I be objective about this?!
Come on, look at it from my perspective.
Half a day ago I didn't even know this sort of game existed!
Isn't throwing me into a situation like this is a bit much?
So you're making fun of me after all.
You're all talk in the end.
You're prejudiced against this hobby!
That's not it!
This is just awkward!
It's like sitting together in the living room watching a drama and it suddenly gets to a kissing scene!
That's what it's like!
What? You're not making any sense.
This is an R-18 game, right?
"Those" kinds of scenes are going to happen, right?
Are you really okay with watching a scene where a brother and sister do that kind of thing with me?
Gross!!
Idiot!
Pervert!
Why are you actually thinking of that kind of thing?
It'd be more of a problem if I weren't!!
Fine.
I'll take out the all-ages version just for you then.
You should have taken that out from the start!
And you really don't get it!
You can only fully appreciate the story if you play the original release, though.
If you want to talk about that stuff, ask your friends.
Stop blabbing and take it.
It's pretty late already, you know...
How about you lend me your laptop?
Then I'll play the R-18 version when I have some free time.
Well, if you insist...
This is your homework then.
Clear this before next week.
Yeah, yeah.
Exit the game?
Onii-chan!
Let's play again!
Bye bye!
kimoi! kimoi! tte, sonna kakkou de atashi no tonari ni tatanaide yo
Gross! Gross! Don't stand by my side in public!
majisaitee! datte, kocchi jirojiro minna! kono baka aniki!
You're the worst! Don't stare at me that way! Stupid brother!
Chou rori - Chou moe - Chou rabu - Chou Puripuritii na imouto wo kudasai
Super loli - Super moe - Super love - Super pretty, give me a little sister like this!
chiisaku tte kirakira shiteru
Small and shining
atashi dake no suitto enjeru
a sweet angel for me alone.
atashi ni kawaii imouto wo...
Give me a cute little sister...
Hitori de nemurenai kara, issho ni netemoii?
I can't get to sleep alone, can I sleep with you?
...nanchatte, aa maji shiawase maji yabai! yabaissu!
... just kidding. Ah! I'm really happy. It's just awful! Awful!
tte haa? be, betsu ni koi na koto kangaeteru wake janai shi
What? I-It's not like I'm thinking about love or anything!
yume miru no wa ii janai
It's not good to wish for it
kuusou kurai noo puroburemu
but there's no problem when it's just a fantasy.
manneri na mainichi ni, chiisana shigeki no essensu
In your daily need, do you need
anata ni datte hitsuyou desho?
any bit of motivation?
itsuka kitto wakaru hazu
One day you should understand
taisetsu na mono ga nanka tte
what is the most important thing.
imouto ga hitsuyou tte koto!
I need a little sister!
zettai ni!
I really do!
There's No Way I'd Go to an 0000IRL Meetup with My Sister
Next time:
There's No Way I'd Go to an IRL Meetup with My Sister