Got tickets for the premier showing?
Nope. Radio Taikan was completely out.
And it was over after only two shots at the raffle.
I went for back-row seats from the start, too.
It looked a lot easier based on the time and energy it would take.
And there's Summer Comiket too.
We'll need to save up the Perika.
Note: Currency in Kaiji
Note: Famitsu points sytem, similar to Xbox live points
Man, I have plenty of Gabasu...
Kirino!
Let's go.
Yep.
Let's take a break.
Kirino, are you free this Sunday?
I've got work in the morning, but do you want to go out somewhere after?
Sorry, I've got stuff to do...
Oh? Are you working that day?
It's not work...
Ah, your club?
Well...
Sorry! I just can't do that day!
It's fine...
Lately you seem kind of distant though...
O-Of course not!
Don't tell me you've picked up a boyfriend?
No way, no way!
Not a chance!
sonna yasashiku shinai de donna kao sureba ii no
Don't be so nice to me, I just don't know how to react
tsumikasaneta kotoba de mienaiyo kimi no yokogao
With all these words piling up, I can't even see your face
dokodakke? nakushita kagi ha mitsukaranai mama de
Where is it? I lost my key, now I can't find it
tameiki surechigai ni iji hatte tsukarechau
Sigh, I'll burn out if I keep acting like this whenever we miss
hon no sukoshi chikaku kimi to no kyori ga
Maybe we're close? I just can't figure out
umaku tsukamenainda ato chotto na no ni
Just how far away I am, even though you're right there
sonna yasashikushinaide hora mata kizutsukeatte
Don't be so nice to me, see? We hurt each other again
tsumikasaneta uso demo ugokenakunatteru
With all these lies piling up, I can't even move
sugu ni ai ni ikitai kedo kotoba ha mitsukaranai shi
I want to see you now, but I don't know what to say
saigo no ichi pe-ji kai? kimi ni ha egao misetai
Is this the end for our story? I want you to see my smile
Come to think of it, it's just ridiculous.
Elena
That's why we should go to the beach!
The beach again?
The setting and story are a complete failure.
Might you be talking about Maschera?
What else?
You practically begged me to watch it the other day, remember?
I don't recall asking you any such thing.
Oh?
Well, I went and bought all the DVDs at once.
I finished watching them...
Let's take a bath together!
Isana
So to start with, why are their lines so freaking annoying?
Yaaaaaay!
Kushina
We have to wash our hair...
Isana
Yeah...
Kushina
What do you mean?
But it hurts my eyes.
Isana
Like "Observe!" or "Your lamentations into mad screams!"
It's like I have to use a dictionary for every other word!
It's sad that your vocabulary isn't even at that level.
Ah, wait a second.
Use a shower cap
Don't use a shower cap
What should she do?
What?
Use a shower cap
Don't use a shower cap
What should she do?
And saved...
Use a shower cap
Don't use a shower cap
What should she do?
Anyway, don't you think his outlook fits precisely because of the way he talks?
Let's go in then.
Wow! My eyes don't hurt!
Isana
Kushina
A victory for science!
His life is already full of discord and on its way to ruin.
The lines are fit for someone who has left their life to that—
Ah, wait a second.
Use a shower cap
Don't use a shower cap
What should she do?
Save loaded
Use a shower cap
Don't use a shower cap
There we go.
Let's go in then.
It huuuuurts!
Isana
Because you got sand in it.
Kushina
Wait, are you playing a galge while talking to me?
It's an eroge, not a galge.
I have to get all the CGs.
You're living quite the otaku life, aren't you?
Must be nice.
Anyway, what about you?
Have you watched Meruru?
There isn't a chance in hell that I'm spending any of my allowance on Meruru.
What the hell?
You're really annoying.
She came to me for something like life counseling.
She went to you for life counseling?
Why do you look so surprised?
I-I would never do something so thoughtless!
Wait, how did you know?
Can you see me??
I can't, but I got that feeling.
Though, it wasn't really counseling so much as just me listening to her.
I seriously didn't expect—
I'll tell you the details on Sunday.
Catch you later.
Ah, okay.
Good night!
Yeah.
I'll bring it on Sunday then.
Do you have a Blu-Ray player?
If I had to choose between whether I do or don't...
I'd say I don't.
Just say that from the start!
Then I'll bring the DVDs.
Is the first season enough for now?
Just bring the part with the smooth story.
Smoothly.
That's just rude to the staff!
If you don't watch it from the start, you'll only get half the experience!
Fine, do whatever you want.
Ah, I need to go help my little sister take a bath.
Fine then.
I'm hanging up.
Yeah, I'll catch you tomorrow.
Later!
What am I missing?
Coming!
Thank you very much.
Morning.
It’s not morning.
Oh, come on. It’s Sunday.
Where’s Kirino?
She went shopping with a friend.
She’s been doing this a lot lately.
I see.
It’s rare to see you concerned about Kirino.
That’s not it!
Kyousuke.
Don’t talk back to your mother.
Fiiine.
I’m gonna head out, too.
Manabi Station.
Oh?
What about lunch?
I should be fine for lunch.
That’s right, dear.
Her new magazine came in.
Already?
The elusive ImoFes version!
I have to buy this!
You're pretty simple aren't you.
Shut up!
We came all the way to Akiba, so if I don't buy it here, I can't buy it anywhere!
Any purchase is once in a lifetime.
Let it go once, and you'll never get a chance again.
In this world, we do say "Leap before you look, buy before you think."
How very Bourgeois.
Excuse me!
Could you open that one please?
Yes! This one!
Thank you!!
So I guess it's working out for her.
School is school, and the other stuff is the other stuff.
That's good to hear!
So she doesn't need to consult you anymore?
Yep, it's great!
I can finally return to my peaceful life.
I see...
I really wonder what it was all for...
Man, I didn't get enough sleep.
K-Kyou-chan!
G-Go ahead!!
And what?
You idiot.
Why are you angry?
Because you're dumb.
Let's get going.
I'll treat you to anything you like as thanks for the advice.
You don't have to...
It's fine.
I owe you for helping me study too.
Okay!
What should I get?
Could you not drool over your eroge so brazenly in public like that?
I'm free to do what I want!
I'm holding myself back from going home right now to play this.
Be more appreciative!
Appreciative of what now?
I understand how you feel, Miss Kiririn!
I get to read the doujins I worked so hard to find later...
Or maybe I'll read them tomorrow...
Pushing it back a day is another kind of pleasure.
Oh, right...
Here's the DVDs, as promised.
I don't remember agreeing to anything...
Oh?
Weren't you begging me to lend you the Meruru DVDs earlier?
What kind of image do you have of me, exactly?
It's good to see how well you two get along!
I actually recorded Meruru but never got around to watching it...
After hearing you talk so passionately about it yesterday, I figured I should give it a try.
What?!
You're missing out on life if you haven't watched it!
Go and watch it immediately!
Understood!
When I get the chance.
By the way, why Akiba?
We could have met somewhere closer.
Well, I have some stuff to do here...
And we can't hang around home, right?
Haven't you been keeping this hobby a secret from your parents?
There's no way I'd be able to keep it secret...
Huh?
How does that work?
It just does? I just live normally.
It's stupid to care about what other people think.
Didn't you take a shot at me for looking at my eroge earlier?
Shut up.
I'll put a curse on you.
I'm the same way.
I don't really get any hassle for it.
As long as I do everything else properly, it doesn't really matter what hobbies I have.
I see...
That makes sense.
So where are we going after lunch?
I absolutely have to see Uchimizukko Event!
What's that?
Crap...
Kyou-chan?
Mr. Kyousuke,
Our happy couple are acting just like one.
I have sent you a photograph.
You're doing well.
What's wrong, Kyou-chan?
Nothing.
Alright, let's keep at it a little longer.
I'm back.
I didn't see exactly what happened,
but apparently she bumped into Dad when she came back and dropped that DVD.
And inside it was... what do you call it?
Something very indecent, and Dad caught a glimpse of it.
You don't look surprised.
Did you... know?
Huh? What?
That Kirino had that kind of thing.
Yeah, I knew.
Why on earth would she have that?
It's been a long time since I saw Dad so angry...
Who knows what'll come of this...
Kirino!
Kyousuke, go after her!
Okay!
She's fast!!
Dammit, what kind of flag is this?
Damn!
If this were an eroge I'd have found her already!
What the hell!
Damn! Damn!
Damn! Damn! Damn!
This damn...
Stupid! Stupid! Stupid!
You stupid, damn...
You're the stupid one.
Oh, it's you?
Why are you here?
Because you just ran out!
I came looking for you!
Gross.
This, huh?
This is what you came home with all ecstatic over?
Got a problem?
So what did Dad say to you?
I have no complaints about your makeup, flashy clothes, or bags.
You worked and paid for them yourself.
But this is different.
Even the news says that this is a bad influence on children.
Of course, I take it with a grain of salt,
but they label people who do these things at this age "otaku".
It can't possibly have any good influence.
If you intend to indulge yourself in such a worthless hobby, I must correct that before you go completely astray.
He called them worthless...
My favorite anime and games and the meetup I went to today...
All of it! All of it!
Even though they aren't... they aren't...
But... I...
I couldn't... say anything back...
Dammit...
Hey, am I weird?
Is it wrong for me to like those things?
Dad will say that.
Any normal parent would think so.
And then there's the social consequences.
You already know, right?
That's why you didn't tell any of your school friends or fellow models.
But Dad found out.
So now you have to choose.
Are you telling me to stop?
If you did, everything would be just peachy.
Dad would relax, and you wouldn't need to sneak around to do all this.
You're a star athlete, an honor student, and a graceful beauty.
Get rid of this, and you're perfect.
I know that already!
But I won't stop.
I definitely won't.
I love them. I really love them.
I can't stop it.
No matter how much you love them, it's just a worthless hobby to Dad.
He might force you to stop.
Even then...
I won't stop. I won't stop loving them.
Working hard at school and as a model, and getting completely absorbed into anime and games...
They're both a part of me.
If I stop either one, I won't be me anymore.
Even if he forces me to throw away my anime and games,
it won't change who I am right now.
So I definitely won't stop loving them!
I see.
Not a bad answer.
Kirino.
Leave it to me.
Is this all you need?
Yeah.
Kirino will be back in around half an hour.
Can you leave me and Dad alone until then?
Okay. I'll go buy some beer or something.
Thanks.
Who'd have thought?
What?
Never mind. Good luck.
Dad.
Where are your manners?
I'm home.
I need to talk to you.
About Kirino.
It looks like you knew she had these things.
Yeah...
And so?
I want you to let Kirino keep her hobby.
What kind of joke is that?
I'm serious.
I won't let you get rid of her hobby or throw away anything she's hidden.
She's hiding things?
Anyway, just don't take anime and games away from her!
Why are you covering for her?
Tell me that first.
You can be stubborn after that—
She knows perfectly well that her hobbies are weird.
That's why she's been enjoying them in secret until now.
But she still wanted someone she could talk to about them.
She finally found someone and worked up the courage to meet them, and she finally found friends.
And this was only recently!
She met those friends today, too.
Kirino worked hard and found friends!
Don't call them worthless before you know them!
I've seen what she holds dear with my own eyes!
I've met other people who love them just as much!
Sure, they're completely weird, but they're not bad people at all!
I mean, it's stupid how excited they can get.
They'll make a scene, yelling at each other even though they've only just met!
I kept wondering just how much they love those things.
For Kirino and them to get that mad, it can't be something worthless!
They get that absorbed into what they love!
They were already friends that could talk to each other about anything!
Is that bad? What's bad about something they can get so absorbed in?
I said nothing about her friends.
I'm talking about bad influences from playing games like this.
Where do you see it?
What are these perfect grades and this pile of awards?
Your daughter's amazing!
That is part of our agreement.
That's why I let her wear those clothes and work as a model.
It's no concern of mine.
Stop being so stubborn!
At least let her have a weird hobby!
This is part of raising a child.
Is that all?
No! There's more!
I asked Mom to get this for me.
She said that it was your treasure.
No concern, you said?
Look how much effort you put into keeping your daughter's pictures!
It's my daughter's job.
I have to keep tabs on it.
That's all there is to it.
And what do you think?
I have no worries about it.
Then what about this?
What's this picture?
It's a picture Kirino's friends sent to me.
Do you think you need to worry about this?
This is what Kirino managed to find!
Everything here is part of Kirino!
If you take any of it away, she won't be her anymore!
If you can look at all this and still say you won't let Kirino have her hobby, I'll beat the crap out of you for her!
I understand what you're trying to say.
I will take back saying that they're worthless.
I will let Kirino keep her hobby.
Really?
But this is different.
I can't allow her to have something so indecent.
It's not a question of good or bad.
What do you think this symbol means?
So it came down to this after all...
This is where Dad is completely right.
I do have a plan for this, but...
I'm going to Kirino's room.
She will throw away these at the least.
Obey Dad
Fight Dad
Apologize to Kirino
Obey Dad
Fight Dad
Apologize to Kirino
Today, I...
Obey Dad
Fight Dad
Apologize to Kirino
Obey Dad
Fight Dad
Apologize to Kirino
Obey Dad
Fight Dad
Apologize to Kirino
Obey Dad
Fight Dad
Apologize to Kirino
Obey Dad
Fight Dad
Apologize to Kirino
Save Kirino
Fight Dad
Apologize to Kirino
Save Kirino
Fight Dad
Apologize to Kirino
Save Kirino
Fight Dad
Apologize to Kirino
Save Kirino
Fight Dad
Apologize to Kirino
Save Kirino
Fight Dad
Apologize to Kirino
Save Kirino
Fight Dad
Apologize to Kirino
Save Kirino
Save the "Little sisters"
Apologize to Kirino
Save Kirino
Save the "Little sisters"
Apologize to Kirino
Save Kirino
Save the "Little sisters"
Apologize to Kirino
Save Kirino
Save the "Little sisters"
Apologize to Kirino
Save Kirino
Save the "Little sisters"
Apologize to Kirino
Save Kirino
Save the "Little sisters"
Apologize to Kirino
Save Kirino
Save the "Little sisters"
Obey Dad
Save Kirino
Save the "Little sisters"
Obey Dad
Save Kirino
Save the "Little sisters"
Obey Dad
Save Kirino
Save the "Little sisters"
Obey Dad
...am completely messed up!
That...
...doesn't belong to Kirino.
What are you saying now?
That is a game for a computer.
Kirino is the only one with a computer in this house!
Like I said, this is mine!
I asked Kirino to hold it for me!
I borrowed her computer and played it!
Oh?
You were in your sister's room, using your sister's computer to play a game about doing indecent things to your sister?
It was really amazing.
Got a problem with that?
What's wrong with a high schooler having eroge?
You know Mom's seen all my porn!
I'm not throwing this away!
I'll defend this to the death!
Listen up, Dad!
I like anime and eroge with a passion!
I can say that I love them!
If I throw this away, I won't be me anymore!
Eroge are my soul!
You hear me?!
You worthless son!
Do as you will!
I don't care anymore!
Morning.
Kyou-chan, good morn—
Y-Your face!! What happened?
Well, uh... stuff.
I see. Stuff happened.
Yeah. Stuff happened.
Good job, Kyou-chan.
Sounds like you did well.
I guess.
I'm back.
What? Did you actually watch it?
How did you come to that conclusion then?
She might have changed a bit now.
I can't believe you.
This is why no one cares about your pretentious opinions.
Looks like she's doing fine without me.
Maybe I'm really done now.
Enough. Whatever.
You really need to get out of that teen complex stuff.
See you.
Hey.
Thanks, Aniki.
Wait, what?
Impossible...
There's no way...
There's No Way My Little Sister
0000can be This Cute
There's no way my little sister can be this cute!
Moshimo negai kanau nara
If my wish could come true,
Zutto soba ni ite ne
I just want to be with you.
Mada tooi kaerimichi
It's still a long way back.
Hanasenai himitsu wo
I'm still holding this secret
Pocket ni shimatta
tightly in my pocket.
Taisetsuna kimi no koto
I still let go of you
Hanasanai de itanda
because you're so important to me.
Wasuretai koto bakari da ne, doushite?
Why is it all the things I want to forget?
Mawari wo ki ni shiteru dare datte
Everyone cares about their surroundings
Hora ochikonde mimi fusagu
I drown out everything in my depression.
Sou ne kitto kudaranai koto de Zutto nayanderu desho tte
You laugh it off saying,"Yeah, you're worrying over something stupid again, aren't you?"
Waratte sumaseteru kedo chigau no
But it's really not like that.
Moshimo kimi ga inakute
If you weren't around
Zettai kimi ga aenaku tte
and I never met you
Sonna mirai ha IYA dakara
I would hate life.
Himitsu ni shite ite ne
Keep it a secret okay?
There's No Way My Little Sister 0000would go to Summer Comiket
Next time:
There's no way my little sister would go to summer comiket