Halloween?
Yeah, Halloween!
Your place sells Japanese sweets...
That's got nothing to do with Halloween.
Actually, we decided to hold a fair and make Western-style Japanese sweets.
Then those are Western sweets...
You think so?
Anyway, they're already made, and the fair is tomorrow, so I was thinking maybe you could come try some?
After school maybe?
Yeah, sure...
Great!
It's really something, so look forward to it!
Tamura-san!
Okay!
I've been wondering for a while, but are you and Tamura-san going out?
No. Do we look like it?
That's how I see it.
In fact, I can't see it any other way.
That's not how we are.
We're close of course, considering how long we've known each other.
But you're saying there aren't any feelings beyond that between you two?
Right?
Akagi...
Let's say for example you had a very kind old Grandma.
Where's this totally unrelated example coming from?
One day, that Grandma gets magically transformed into a 15-year-old girl.
How would you feel about her, keeping in mind that she practically raised you?
I don't think I can imagine how I'd feel in such a messed up situation.
We're pretty much like that.
You lost me.
Well, I don't really care if you understand or not.
Basically, you're not going out, and you never intend to?
Why are you asking me this?
So if some guy made a move on her, you wouldn't care?
Of course I would!
There's no way I'd allow that!
I'd beat the crap out of anyone messed up enough to do that.
So basically...
She's nothing more than a childhood friend to you...
You're not going out with her...
You have no feelings for her...
But you wouldn't allow any other guys to go out with her?
Yeah, so?
So what did you do last night?
That's a secret!
sonna yasashiku shinai de donna kao sureba ii no?
Don't be so nice to me, I just don't know how to react
tsumikasaneta kotoba de
With all these words piling up,
mienaiyo kimi no yokogao
I can't even see your face
dokodakke? nakushita kagi ha mitsukaranai mama de
Where is it? I lost my key, now I can't find it
tameiki... surechigai ni iji hatte tsukarechau
Sigh, I'll burn out if I keep acting like this whenever we fight
hon no sukoshi chikaku kimi to no kyori ga
Maybe we're close? I just can't figure out
umaku tsukamenainda ato chotto na no ni
Just how far away I am, even though you're right there
sonna yasashikushinaide hora mata kizutsukeatte
Don't be so nice to me, see? We hurt each other again
tsumikasaneta uso demo ugokenakunatteru
With all these lies piling up, I can't even move
sugu ni ai ni ikitai kedo kotoba ha mitsukaranai shi
I want to see you now, but I don't know what to say
saigo no ichi pe-ji kurai kimi ni ha egao misetai
If this is the end for our story, I want you to see my smile
There's No Way My Childhood Friend
Can be this Cute
I'm back!
Welcome home.
A package arrived for you.
What did you buy?
A dakimakura!
I mean... something I found online that relieves stress.
Oh?
If it works, let me know.
Sure.
Can't let her know...
I see... sure is Halloween.
Are you going to get customers with this?
Of course!
We're doing an event for the first day too.
Event?
We're going to invite the kids from around the neighborhood and show them how to make sweets and hand them out.
The workers are going to be dressed up as monsters too.
I'm back!
You mean your Grandparents?
The rest of the family too.
So I'll be help—
What's wrong?
Grandpa!
Grandpa, you okay??
Hey!
He's cold!
Call an ambulance, Manami!
Okay!!
Grandpa...
Oh, it's Kyou-chan. Welcome!
Grandma!! Grandpa has...
Oh?
He's playing dead?
No wait, he really is dead!
His body's gone cold already!
He got into the shop refrigerator a little while ago.
So this is what it was for...
But he doesn't have a pulse!
He's always had a weak pulse.
Why does he smell like a corpse?
That's his natural body odor.
But... wait...
Grandpa, if you don't cut it out, I'll pull the hairs out of your head one by one.
Dang, you're one devil of a wife.
How could you even think of harming what little hair I have left?
See?
Happy Halloween, Kyou-chan!
Trick or... what was it again?
Has your brain started to rot?!
Kyou-chan!
What's the number for an ambulance??
Like I know!
I'm so glad you're still alive, Grandpa!
Ah, sorry about that!
I got a little carried away...
I want to punch him in the face!!
What's up, Kyou-chan?
Why were you playing dead?
I was just practicing my costume for tomorrow.
My zombie impression was great, right?
Actually, you seemed more like a normal corpse.
Any kid who sees you will get traumatized.
I don't think you should let them see that.
He's right, you know.
Is that right...
Well fine then.
Not like I care anyway.
Don't bother consoling him.
If you play along with him he'll just go overboard again.
Understood.
I'll go get some of the Halloween candy then.
I'll go help her.
You seem to be popular with the grannies.
That doesn't make me happy!
And why was that plural?
Have you done it yet?
Done what?!
And of course we haven't!
Hey, it's An-chan! Been a while!
Yo, long time—
What happened to your hair?
I cut it all off!
What do you think?
Skinheads are popular nowadays!
That's a monk's buzzcut, you know...
No skinhead looks like that.
No way, An-chan!
The barber said, "Right, skinhead. Skinhead."
then cut it with his clipper.
He even asked how short I wanted it.
That's a totally different hairstyle.
You're supposed to use a special razor for that.
Not that I know much about it...
No way!!
That barber ripped me off!
I thought so!
Ever since you came back with that I've been wanting to say,
There's no "skin" there!
for the longest time!
You should have just told him...
You cut your hair on a whim so you got what's coming to you!
Stupid Rock!
"Rock"?
Hey, get this!
When he got back from the barber he was all like,
"Check out my awesome hairstyle! From now on you can call me Rock!"
Your name's Iwao though...
Tamura Iwao...
Adults are all liars!
Don't trust those over-50s!
These are really elaborate...
Right?
P-Please go ahead and try some!
S-Sure...
It's great!
Really?
You put actual pumpkin inside?
Yeah! You can tell?
Did you make these?
Why?
Well, you wanted to know what I thought...
Yeah, I made them...
I'm so glad you like them!
Yeah...
Why don't you two just get married already?
Grandpa!
Sometimes even he makes sense.
Oh, stop that you two!
Kyou-chan, let's go to my room.
Sure...
Woo! Getting hot up there!
That's so old...
Oh, really?
Wait here a second.
You need to hide something?
Oh, come on!
Yeah, I guess this isn't her we're talking about.
What was that??
I knew it!
Nothing's really changed here...
Stop staring!
It‘s embarrassing...
Um... what should we do?
Sleep.
I think I've been staying up late studying too much these days.
I feel like just relaxing and taking a nap.
That okay?
So that's what you meant...
No studying allowed.
I even left my textbooks at school.
I see...
Let's just relax then.
I'll go get some tea.
‘Kay.
Don't you need to help prepare for the fair?
Yeah, but that'll be after the shop closes.
The whole family will be working on it.
I'll lend a hand then.
Really?
That'd be a great help!
But aren't you tired?
It's fine.
Don't worry about me.
Thanks so much!
It's not exactly payment, but you can have dinner here then.
Look, a tea stalk is standing.
Hey, neat.
You bought a dakimakura...
You really have no intentions on stopping, do you?
Huh?! I worked hard to buy my things!
Moreover, a pillow is an everyday necessity.
You have no right to tell me what to do!
It's not really a necessity, is it?
It's just to satisfy a delusion for that little girl.
She's not a little girl!
Meru-chan is young lady.
A MA-GIC-AL GIRL..
Now, now. Calm down.
Anyway, Kiririn-san, what was your brother Kyousuke's reaction to it?
Well...
I thought I'd let him look at it.
But he still hasn't come home.
Seriously, whenever you need that guy, he's never around.
He probably felt the aura of a succubus in the house and feared for his life.
I don't blame him.
I think he went to the library with that plain girl.
The one he's always talking about.
Not that I really care.
Onii-sama is into that kind of girl?
I'm shocked. It didn't seem like him.
Huh? He never told you?
I'm hearing it for the first time.
So, what's she like?
She's a childhood friend, wears glasses, and is an airhead.
What the? You're keeping a lot to yourself.
Tell us everything.
I see.
You eat breakfast every day with him, so it's obvious you know more.
I don't really understand their relationship,
but everything about her is so...
plain.
Woah, this is heavy!
Ah, thanks.
What the heck are you doing?
An-chan, I understand now.
Rock isn't how you look...
It's a way of life!
There's little difference between a skinhead and a short buzz!
Tomorrow, I shout with all my soul!
And why are you playing a shamisen?
That's more like a biwa player than a rocker.
We don't have a guitar—
Help out.
Fine.
Man, I'm tired.
Good work, Kyou-chan.
Um... do you want dinner first or a bath first?
A bath?
It's been a while since you visited, so Grandpa and Grandma and Dad said you should stay over.
Oh, I see.
Grandpa and Grandma and Dad are really happy to see you again.
Grandpa's—
Grandpa and Grandma—
Gra—
Grandpa had Grandma—
I get it, I'll sleep over.
Are you sure?
Well, yeah.
Tomorrow's the weekend.
It's been so long since you slept over.
I guess you're right.
I used to come over all the time too.
It might be because, you know...
You're that age now, so you get nervous staying at a girl's house.
Why would I get nervous staying at your place?
You don't?
Of course not.
It's more relaxing here than at home.
Huh?
What's wrong?
Nothing, I just thought it might be better that way.
Where is he?
He's staying at the Tamuras'.
Honestly, he's always acting like a little kid.
Did you talk to the parents?
Of course.
They said it'd help with their Halloween.
Halloween?
Thanks for the food.
Yes.
Thanks for the meal.
An-chan, how do you play a C minor?
There aren't any chords on a shamisen, you know...
Kyou-chan, Dad's about to get out of the bath. Do you want to take one next?
I can go last. You take one first.
I'm fine going after you.
No, you take one first.
Then how about taking one together?
Kyou-chan, you're blushing!
Alright! Let's take one together!
Seriously?
Super serious!
You already invited me.
You can't take it back now, can you?
An-chan, you're a real man!
I know, right?
Damn! So cool!
Let's go, Manami!
I'll show you my hyper-weapon!
Grandma, what do I do??
Kyou-chan wants to take a bath with me!
Don't go telling everyone!
So take one with him.
Wha—it was a joke!
You so want to, too.
I don't!
Idiot.
Thanks for the bath.
Anytime.
I put your futon in your usual room.
Thanks.
I guess I'll sleep then.
I'll go back to my room.
Hey, Grandma!
Teach me how to play this!
Sure.
What do you want to play?
Something rock.
How many years has it been since we were up until bedtime together?
Four years, I think?
Good night.
Yeah.
Kyou-chan! Kyou-chan!
My futon is...
Huh? My futon?
Apparently...
Wh-Why is it here?
And right next to yours?
Did you do this, Kyou-chan?
Like hell!
Calm down, calm down...
Analyze the situation.
Ah, so basically... I did it!
Kyou-chan, calm down!
Grandpa!
What are you doing?
Just a little something with my heart...
What the heck are you doing, Grandpa?!
It's trauma from the War.
If you don't sleep there with Manami, my chest gets wracked with pain.
What kind of trauma causes that?!
Oh, the pain!
Grandma's calling for me from across the River Styx...
Grandma!
Grandma's downstairs.
This is just weird!
We can't sleep together at our age!
I don't think she—
I'm...
I'm okay with it...
If you're okay with it.
Well, there you have it.
What?! Wait, you damn nutjob!
It feels like we're kids again.
We used to sleep like this all the time back then.
I never thought we'd do it at this age.
This is all that old codger's fault.
And Grandma... maybe some other time.
I'm going to sleep.
Good night.
Good night, Kyou-chan.
Still awake?
Still awake.
Um...
It'd be nice if we went to the same college.
Yeah.
I wonder how things'll be if we graduate and go to the same college.
How what will be?
Everything.
I don't think it'll change much.
Maybe.
Hey, Manami...
Yes?
What if someone told you they liked you?
What would you do?
Wh-Wh-What?
"What if"!
It's hypothetical!
That kind of fantastic guy might never appear!
If... I don't know what if.
Figured...
Sorry.
Kyou-chan?
If someone told you they liked you, what would you do?
I'd turn them down.
Why?
I like leading a peaceful life.
Things are fine the way they are right now.
Being able to relax in this kind of home is enough for me.
I see...
We've still got a long way to go.
Spoken like a true Grandma.
Well, you're talking like a Grandpa.
Kyou-chan...
Maybe next time...
Um... er...
Sorry... never mind.
Next time...
Want to come to my place next time?
Um...
Yeah, I'd like that.
Sometime soon then.
Okay.
Good night.
How many times is that now?
I'm going to sleep.
Fine, don't come back.
Idiot.
nagaku chikaku ni iru to mienakunaru mono
When you’ve been together for so long, sometimes you just forget about it
itsuka dokoka de mitsukete watashi ha kawatta
Sometime, somewhere, I found it, but I had changed
nee anata ha kawaranai ne dakara modokashii no
Hey, you never seem to change, that’s why I’m so upset
demo tabun sou iu toko fukumete suki nanda
But I think that’s part of what I like about you
mata futari de kaeteyuku yo
We’ll just keep changing together
zutto konna kankei ga tsudzukeba ii no ni
Even though it would be so nice to stay like this forever
kyuu ni sunda kono maegami mitai ni
Just like my bangs that I suddenly cut short
mezameta omoi ga mou modoranai kara
My feelings all came up, now I can’t go back
jimi na watashi dakedo sono mama de ii
I might be so plain, but that’s all okay
anata no kotoba atsuku atsuku nokotteiru
Everything you said still warms me deep inside
There's No Way My Little Sister
Could Write a Novel
Next time:
There's No Way My Little Sister Could Write a Novel