I'm home.
It's just you?
Well, I'm terribly sorry to disappoint.
Were you waiting for a friend or something?
Nothing to do with you.
And I thought it came too, since I heard a motorcycle...
She's been kind of restless the past few days...
The next life counseling will be the last one.
She hasn't said anything since that, either.
What's she thinking?
I'll leave your dinner in the fridge.
Mom and Dad said they'll be back around 10, so eat it whenever.
Hey, are you listening?
Dammit, I want to play it already!
Damn you people who got it on the first day!
She's not even listening...
It's here!!
It finally came!
You're so late!
I've been waiting so long for you!
What is that?
An eroge.
Ah, I see...
sonna yasashiku shinai de donna kao sureba ii no?
Don't be so nice to me, I just don't know how to react
tsumikasaneta kotoba de
With all these words piling up,
mienai yo kimi no yokogao
I can't even see your face
dokodakke? nakushita kagi ha mitsukaranai mama de
Where is it? I lost my key, now I can't find it
tameiki... surechigai ni iji hatte tsukarechau
Sigh, I'll burn out if I keep acting like this whenever we fight
hon no sukoshi chikaku kimi to no kyori ga
Maybe we're close? I just can't figure out
umaku tsukamenainda ato chotto na no ni
Just how far away I am, even though you're right there
sonna yasashikushinaide hora mata kizutsukeatte
Don't be so nice to me, see? We hurt each other again
tsumikasaneta uso de mou ugokenakunatteru
With all these lies piling up, I can't even move
sugu ni ai ni ikitai kedo kotoba ha mitsukaranai shi
I want to see you now, but I don't know what to say
saigo no ichi pe-ji kurai kimi ni ha egao misetai
If this is the end for our story, I want you to see my smile
There's No Way My Little Sister
Can Play Eroge Like This
It's so slow...
Game start!
Good morning.
It's almost time for lunch.
Good morning...
This looks good!
Where's Mom?
Everyone went out.
Then it'll be just the two of us all day?
Yeah, I'll be home all today.
Well, maybe I should more often.
Manami
I wonder if she plans to go out anywhere...
You're my brother?
You've got to be kidding me.
This is the worst...
So this is Rinko-chan...
Nice to meet you, Onii-chan.
And this is Miyabi-chan?
This might be pretty good...
Which route should I do first?
Who is it now?
Oh, work...
Sensei, thanks for taking care of Ayase today.
Oh, no problem.
I wonder what Kirino's doing?
The number you have called is unreachable because the phone is either out of service or turned off.
Oh, right...
She turns it off when she studies so she can concentrate.
That's so Kirino.
I should learn from her, too.
Rinko-chwan~
Gross! Don't act all friendly.
Come on, don't say that...
Shut up! You're so annoying!
Are you stupid?
Cut that out already!
Bear with it......
You're not mad even after all I've said?
What a pitiful guy.
What do you want me to do?
You should really just die.
There's no point to someone like you living anyway, right?
Th-This damn game...
You've got a pretty big mouth!
Who brought you up like that?
Aren't you the little sister?
Shut up! Who do you think you are?
Stop acting like you're my brother!
Wh-Who do you think you are?!
Now you've gone too far!
I don't have to sit here and listen to you mouth off!
Who the heck is she arguing with?
Dammit!
Dammit! Dammit!
I'll do your route later!
An eroge?
What are you drawing?
Meruru!
I see...
Do you want to watch Meruru on TV?
Yeah!
I'm sorry, Onii-chan.
Please don't get mad at Rinko.
I'm sure she feels happy deep down that she got a big brother too.
Really?
Yeah. Rinko's pretty shy about these things.
She's not even on that level.
She's 100% tsun and 0% dere.
I bet this character was just made to make fun of the players.
She's a ridiculous heroine.
Can't she show the slightest bit of a cute side?
You know, Onii-chan...
I'm really glad that I got to meet you.
I'm sure Rinko feels the same way.
I can tell, since we're twins.
I love you, Onii-chan!
Oh man, oh man!
You're too cute, Miyabi-chan!
Are you trying to make me fall for you?
I love you, Onii-chan!
This is a godly game!
What the hell is she doing?
Now I'm tired...
We haven't even started!
Go! Meteo Impact!
Is it fun?
Yes!
I see...
Pomecha-kun, watch out!
W-Why are you here?!
That's my line!
I made a promise to go on a date with Miyabi-chan, so why are you here?!
No way, you too?
Huh?
D-Dammit, Miyabi tricked me!
What's with this plotline...
Did I miss the branch point?
This one was straight to a bad end, so...
That means...
Geez...
Maybe I picked the wrong choice last time...
No way, Miyabi-chan!
Fine, whatever.
Since I came all the way here, I'll just put up with you.
That is not cute at all...
I-It's not a date!
You're gross, so don't come any closer!
I'm spending my time on you, so you'd better appreciate it!
Fine, I'll finish your route first!
You'd better appreciate it!
Yes?
I'm here to deliver an item you had ordered the other day.
I've been expecting you.
What do you think?
My, it's perfect.
This is excellent.
It's a pleasure to serve.
With this height, I can't cosplay without an order-made outfit.
How about these?
We made them with the sizes you gave us the other day.
Thank you.
Are you going to an event with your friends?
Yes, I'm planning a party where everyone can have a lot of fun.
I'll think up a reason for the party later.
Now then, how will I get them to wear this special outfit?
Children are pretty simple-minded, getting excited over something like this.
Kousaka Kyousuke
Hello?
Yo.
Why the sudden call?
Well, it's nothing in particular, but...
What are you doing right now?
I was making a cursed magical artifact.
That figures...
So does that mean you're busy?
N-Not really.
With my magic, I can do this with one hand.
What about you?
Your 2nd year winter's almost over.
Do you have the time to be calling me?
That seems rather lax of you.
I can't really deny that, but for some reason I just can't get into a studying mood.
So I just called to see how you've been doing.
Please don't use me as an excuse to procrastinate.
Ah, my bad.
By the way, I heard there's a Maschera event soon.
Yes. I plan on attending, of course.
I see...
Then how about we—
Finally, her dere side!
You're so cute, Rinko-rin!
Did I just hear a bizarre scream of some kind?
There's a monkey making a ruckus next door. Don't worry about it.
Must be hard on you too.
Stupid Aniki.
Come here...
H-Hey...
Be gentle, okay?
W-Wait a second!
Let me go shower first...
Why are you in such a hurry?
Who cares?
Hey.
What?
What is it now?
You dropped them.
Huh? W-Wai—
Die, you pervert!
Just... Just die!
H-Hey...
Be gentle, okay?
Alright. Alright!
Alright! Here I go!
Sorry for the wait, Rinko-rin!
I'm all ready for you now!
What's she getting so worked up about?
Sheesh...
Woah, Rinko-rin!
That's pretty hot!
Oh wow, oh wow!
That is so hot!
Are you sure?
This really sucks.
It's been a while since I've felt this awkward.
Why do I have to sit here and listen to my little sister playing eroge?
What kind of punishment is this?
Oh, wow!
This is too much!
So hot!
Shut up already!
In case you haven't realized, I can totally hear you!
Wh-Wh-What's with you?!
You pervert!!
Eavesdropping on your sister's room??
What's wrong with you?
I'm not eavesdropping!
I can hear it without even trying!
You don't have to yell like that just because Mom and Dad aren't home!
I can do whatever I want!
At least be a little more considerate!
Hearing my sister's moaning from the other side of the wall is beyond awkward!
D-don't tell me you recorded it?
You aren't recording it, are you?!
You're the real pervert for even coming up with that idea!
That stuff you said about not caring about H-scenes was a total lie!
That's totally different from this!
I was just enjoying Rinko-rin's ero-cuteness with completely pure motivations!
Where's the difference?!
Everything's different!
Ring ring. Click.
Yes, indeed. I know.
We must break Belvegolle's spell in order to save him.
We must free him from the chains of his previous existence.
Impossible!
You're saying the Angels are making a move?
It's starting to get interesting now...
I am the fallen angel, Kuroneko.
From the day I received the protection of the night—
I'm sorry, Aniki...
You got hurt because of me.
They say we can't see each other anymore...
Since we're siblings...
We can't be together...
Why did things have to end up like this...
This isn't how it was supposed to be...
Did I pick the wrong choice?
I've actually always known about you, since long ago.
I'd always wondered what kind of person my brother was...
I got curious, so I went to meet you...
Do you remember?
When we were little, we played together in the park.
That was me.
Goodbye, Aniki.
I always, always loved you.
Are you stupid...
Kuroneko's Diary
A Moment in Isolation
Clamor in the classroom.
A flock of fools wearing masks, laughing.
My world, disconnected.
Light and darkness.
All in passing.
What is the real me?
Sickening.
kiririn@miyabichanismaiimouto
I read up to "I was lonely this week too."
I've been able to decrypt this person's jibberish lately. Kinda scaring myself lol
kiririn@miyabichanismaiimouto
I read up to "I was lonely this week too."
I've been able to decrypt this person's jibberish lately. Kinda scaring myself lol
Saori
If you have time again next week, shall we go somewhere?
Nee-sama, please read me a book!
In a bit.
I'm talking to the denizens of the world of darkness right now.
Are these people the denizens of the world of darkness?
No.
Those people are...
Friends that live in the same world as us.
I guess I'll wait until tomorrow to go for the good end.
*Rinko Route* A new scenario has been unlocked
Kirino! Hurry up and take your bath!
Okay!
Taking another bath?
Ow...
What the hell was that for?!
Gross! Don't act all friendly.
You know...
Shut up! You're so annoying!
Are you stupid?
What's with you?
What are you so mad about?
Shut up! I'm just annoyed, that's all.
Yeah, yeah.
You're always like that.
Stop acting like you understand me.
Sure, sure.
Hey, Kirino.
Good night.
gakugyou yuushuu spootsu bannou na ue
Perfect grades, and an ace athlete
youshi tanrei kanpeki na atashi
With unmatched beauty, look, I’m perfect
demo ne ano ko ni muchuu na koto naisho na no
But don’t tell anyone, I’m actually crazy for this girl
imoutogee anime konpu zumi yo
I played the imoutoge and watched the anime through
shouganai ja nai suki nandamon!
I just can’t help it, I love her!
unmei no itazura? soretomo wana??
Is fate being mean? Or is it a trap??
dame to iwaretatte kono omoi tomerarenai!
I can’t stop these feelings even if you say no!
suki yo suki yo suki nandamon!
I love her, I love her, because I love her!
zutto suki yo suki yo suki nandamon!
I love her, I love her, because I love her forever!
There's No Way My Little Sister
Can Cosplay Like This
Next Time: There's No Way My Little Sister Can Cosplay Like This