Take off her glasses
Don't take off her glasses
Kyousuke!
Could you go out shopping for me?
Oh?
Are you looking at porn sites on Kirino's laptop again?
What are you talking about, dear mother?
Look at this screen, with its clear skies as clean as my heart!
Thank god for the emergency escape key!
And wait, why do you know about the porn site thing?!
"Who browses porn sites on his little sister's laptop?"
"That's so gross!"
sonna yasashiku shinai de donna kao sureba ii no?
Don't be so nice to me, I just don't know how to react
tsumikasaneta kotoba de
With all these words piling up,
mienai yo kimi no yokogao
I can't even see your face
dokodakke? nakushita kagi ha mitsukaranai mama de
Where is it? I lost my key, now I can't find it
tameiki... surechigai ni iji hatte tsukarechau
Sigh, I'll burn out if I keep acting like this whenever we fight
hon no sukoshi chikaku kimi to no kyori ga
Maybe we're close? I just can't figure out
umaku tsukamenainda ato chotto na no ni
Just how far away I am, even though you're right there
sonna yasashikushinaide hora mata kizutsukeatte
Don't be so nice to me, see? We hurt each other again
tsumikasaneta uso de mou ugokenakunatteru
With all these lies piling up, I can't even move
sugu ni ai ni ikitai kedo kotoba ha mitsukaranai shi
I want to see you now, but I don't know what to say
saigo no ichi pe-ji kurai kimi ni ha egao misetai
If this is the end for our story, I want you to see my smile
There's No Way My Little Sister
Can Be A Maid
Dammit, using people like this...
It's pretty rare to run into you here.
I know, right?
What are you having for dinner tonight?
As you can see, curry yet again.
How many times is that this month I wonder?
I wish Mom could learn even half of your repertoire.
You're good at making sweets and meals right?
Oh yeah!
Mom's going to be out for our next day off, and she was wondering how to deal with lunch.
How about you come over and make lunch?
Go on in.
Sorry to intrude.
That was Kirino-chan... right?
Crap.
G-Good afternoon, Kirino-chan!
Do you remember me?
I used to come ov—
Who might you be?
I guess you don't remember...
Then once again, I'm Tamura Manami.
Pleased to meet you!
And why are you here, anyway?
Hey, stop tha—
Come here for a second.
Wait!
What do you think you're doing, bringing a girl over when Mom and Dad aren't home?
That's so gross!
There's no ulterior motive!
I wasn't trying to sneak her in or anything!
I just brought here to make lunch!
I wonder about that.
And even if it weren't just for lunch, that'd have nothing to do with you.
You bring your friends here all the time, too.
I don't want to hear that from you.
So you're saying if I brought over a boyfriend,
and h-h-had s-sex in the living room...
y-you'd be okay with it?
How'd it turn into that?!
We're not doing anything like that!
That's a totally different ballpark!
Um...
You shouldn't fight...
I'm sorry for showing up so suddenly, Kirino-chan.
I heard your Mom wasn't going to be home,
so I thought I might help out a bit with cooking and cleaning.
I'll go home right after!
No good?
I wonder.
In that case, clean up the living room before you make lunch.
Hey, what do you think you're doing?!
Please leave it to me!
Huh?
This looks amazing!
I didn't know how far I could go, so I couldn't get every corner...
No, this is more than enough!
I'll make some tea, so have a seat.
Okay! Thanks!
Kirino-chan!
We're taking a break after finishing cleaning.
Would you like to join us?
So this is the best you can do?
What are you, some mother-in-law?!
Also, you've cleaned everything up so much that I don't know where anything is anymore!
It looked messy before, but I knew exactly where I put everything.
You overdid it.
I'm so sorry!
Where are my fashion magazines?
I left them here so I could find them easily.
They're right here!
Oh, I see...
What about the pedicure box I left here?
That had stuff inside it, so you'd better not have thrown it away.
I tidied it up for you.
Did we always have a box like that?
I re-used an empty tissue box!
That's so ghetto!
Well?
Any other complaints?
Go away, then.
If that's all you came down to—
Wh-What is it?
Remember this!
This isn't over.
What's wrong with her?
Hey, lunch is ready!
Manami's asking you to come eat with us.
I'll come down after I'm done with this call.
Oh, okay...
Did she calm down?
Thanks for the meal.
It was delicious.
Oh, thanks!
I can do that!
I can handle it.
Hear that? She said she liked it.
That's good...
My room?
It's nothing special, so don't get your hopes up.
Well, come in.
Kyou-chan's room...
Why?
Why?!
I already gave this back to Kirino!
Why is it here with an eroge on?!
Who set up this trap—
Kirino...
It must have been her! Dammit!
That's why she was in a good mood!
Evil! Pure evil!
What's wrong?
Nothing, really!
Really!
It's nothing... nothing...
Kyou-chan! Your eyes are rolling around...
Are you feeling okay?
No, wait! Wait!
Oh! I can just hit the emergency escape key!
Wait! Wait!!
Kyou-chan?
Emergency escape key!
Sorry to surprise you like that, Manami.
Wow...
Why are they out?! I put those away earlier!
They're supposed to be in a box under my bed!
Is this another one of Kirino's traps?!
Dammit!
Don't look at those!
It was all girls with glasses...
That's not it!!
Well, they are, but that's not it!
This is a trap!
My heart is as clear as the blue skies—
Huh?
Stare.
M-Manami-san?
"Onii-chan is a pervert who only gets turned on by little sisters!"
Don't read that!
Why did it come back?!
Ah, I see...
An ero CG might sometimes  pop up at random when you hit the emergency escape key...
Oh, those jokers at the game company...
I see...
Um... Kyou-chan...
Um...
Would you like me to call you "Onii-chan" from now on?
Rental Rooms
Kirino's Anime Celebration Party
Super Miss Kiririn
Miss Kuroneko
Mr. Kyousuke
Myself
Super Miss Kiririn
Miss Kuroneko
Mr. Kyousuke
Myself
Ah, whatever.
Excuse me, is there a reservation under Saori Vageena here?
Yes, may I have your name please?
Kousaka.
Kousaka Kyousuke?
Yeah.
It's room 301.
Ah, okay.
Thanks.
Kousaka Kyousuke's Personal Harem Party
Welcome home!
Master.
Miss Kiririn!
Welcome home, Master.
Ah, geez!
I can't take this anymore!
Lowering my head to this guy is just wrong!
What is this?
Just a taste of entertainment!
What do you think of my maid look?
Burning with desire?
Hell no.
That's strange, I was told you had a glasses fetish...
Who told you—
Your little...
Maybe some sexier clothes were in order?
Look, when it's you and my sister doing it—
Ouch! Ouch!
What's with your attitude?
I do all this and that's how you act?
This is painful in more than one way!
Wait...
Where's Kuroneko?
It's not what you think.
I said it's not what you think!
No, no! You look lovely, Miss Kuroneko.
Don't you think so, Mr. Kyousuke?
Y-Yeah...
I don't need your flattery.
I hate to admit it, but that's really cute!
Hey, where do they sell these ears and tail?
I made them myself.
Seriously?!
Oh man, that cosplay is just...
Damn... someone like her...
That ends my turn for now.
That means you're next, Miss Kuroneko.
Wait, turn for what?
Entertainment for Miss Kiririn's anime party, of course.
We'll go around and each do something.
I-I see...
All right.
This is a manga I wrote for today.
Manga? You?
I look forward to this!
Watch and be amazed.
Wait right there, you!
What's wrong?
Why does this character look exactly like me?!
And this one kind of looks like me.
Of course they do.
You two are the models for them.
But don't worry.
I only used your appearances and the siblings part.
I've got a bad feeling about this...
Well, whatever. Keep going.
Thank you.
"This is Onii-chan's underwear... Gulp."
Sniff sniff!
Stop right there!!
What's wrong?
You know exactly what's wrong!!
There are limits to what you can and can't do in manga!
Why are you getting so angry?
My only intention was to write a fictional story.
When you react like that, you make it seem as though I may have accidentally reflected reality.
Don't tell me you really do sniff—
I don't! This is just in a manga!
I'm glad you understand.
Then let's continue.
Rustle rustle. Rustle rustle.
"It's all girls with glasses!"
"Why doesn't he have any little sister ones?"
I'm confiscating this!
What are you doing?
The greatest holy war in human history is about to begi—
Shut up!
I want to go home...
Now then, today's main event!
Miss Kiririn's turn!
Go on!
Miss Kiririn?
Pass!
Pass?
You idiot.
Don't you understand why you're here in the first place?
Now, now, Miss Kuroneko.
Miss Kiririn needs time to prepare herself too.
Perhaps we should have a pleasant little chat before the main event?
I guess we have no choice.
Hey, what's going on?
You guys know what Kirino's doing?
It doesn't matter.
So what did you think of my manga?
The house plan felt scarily real.
I did some detailed research.
But one part was wrong.
I've never been called "Onii-chan" or anything.
Then what does she call you?
Nothing really.
Oh, shut up.
Stay out of other people's family matters.
That must be lonely for you.
Then why don't I call you that?
What?
H-Hey, what?
You don't need to hold back, Nii-san.
Wait, something's not right here.
What's not right, Nii-san?
Wait, you, uh—
That hurt! What the hell!
You don't need to ask!
Stop being so gross!
Wai—Idiot!! Not that!
Getting all embarrassed like that... So shameless.
After being so depressed, all it takes is something like that to get you back on your feet?
You're so simple, I'm almost jealous.
What?
Look here.
I've been really depressed recently because of you.
It's not that Manami has been making fun of me or anything.
She's not that kind of person in the first place.
She's been trying to be nice instead.
But that weird feeling is just wrong for us!
And you're the reason for it!
Do you understand?
But we were going to celebrate today, so I thought I would set aside my own problems and celebrate.
But I come here, and then what?
The receptionist stares at me, you start yelling for no good reason,
and it looks like you're hiding something from me.
How could I possibly have fun like this?
We didn't mean to do that...
I'm not blaming you.
But it's about time for you to explain yourself.
Mr. Kyousuke, please listen. We—
Wait.
I'll take my turn now.
What?
Miss Kiririn.
You understand, right?
I just have to do it, right?
Here, take it!
What?
I said you can have it!
I don't get it!
Oh, figure it out already! I'm giving you a present!
A present?
Right.
I'm sorry I did all that.
Thanks for everything.
Um... Did you hear me?
Y-Yeah...
Oh, really?
Good then.
This party was something we planned to cheer you up.
It was also meant for Miss Kiririn to apologize to you.
It's our fault you were upset.
We're sorry.
Is that why...
Hey, you know...
You probably can't figure it out unless I tell you, so I'll tell you now.
What?
I'm really thankful for everything you've done for me.
If you weren't there for me, I wouldn't have been able to convince Dad.
And I wouldn't have made up with Ayase.
And I wouldn't have met these two.
Without anyone to talk to about games or anime, I'd be depressed, all alone.
I don't know how things would be now.
So... um...
That's how it is!
What are you crying about?!
Idiot! I'm not crying!
Stop that!
It's seriously gross!
Not like it's something to cry about!
Come on! Are you stupid?
I've...
I've done all sorts of things to help Kirino.
But those were all things I decided to do myself, on my own terms.
Even if she isn't cute, or if she makes me irritated, or if I'm jealous of her talents...
I'm her brother, so I can't help it.
It's so natural, I can't help it.
That's why I don't need thanks, and I don't want any, either.
That's what I thought. And that hasn't changed.
That can't change.
But for some reason, the tears won't stop...
It's just not fair!
Sneaking in an ambush like this...
Thanks, Kirino.
I'll take good care of this present.
Sure, sure.
But don't say that yet. You haven't even opened it.
Oh, right. Can I open it?
D-Do what you want.
Okay.
What is this?
That's a seriously godly game!
You'd better play it!
Man, you...
Think of it as me and take real good care of it.
What?
What are you laughing about?
Is he broken?
No, I think that's the right reaction.
I see. So you're that happy?
I guess...
Thanks, Kirino.
atama no naka guruguru mawaru
My head is spinning like a top
sekai koukei ha karafuru
The world is just so colorful
nousaibou shigekiteki do-pamin ha koborechatta
Brain cells, all excited, dopamine overflowing
donichi no ofu taiki de uzu uzu
Waiting, twitching, on my weekends off
shousoukan komiageru
Impatience growing
hayaku aitai yo
I want to see you now
minna issho ni sukumizu tabeyouka-
Let's all eat some school swimsuits!
me wo tojietemo nioi de wakaru
Even with my eyes closed, I can smell it
rui ha rui wo yobu
Birds of a feather flock together!
akihabara dansu nau!!
Akihabara Dance Now!!
jidai no kage de furoa wo wakashiteiru no yo
The floor's boiling with the shadow of the age
gyutto gyutto dakishimete
Hold me, hold me, hold me tight
kamatte kunnakya ekishou he DIVE
If you don't watch, I'll dive into the LCD!
Into LOVE!
Into love!
yuganda ai wo tsutsundeku
Into this messed-up love!
kono chikara ha
This strange power is
yuitsu muni dakara kuse ni naru no
Unstoppable, that's why I love it
suki na mono darake no
Jump into life
mainichi ni Jump! nagekissu!!
Full of what you love! Blow a kiss!!
suki na hito to mae-!!
Go with the ones you love!!
There's No Way My Little Sister's
Life Counseling Can End Like This
Next Time:
There's No Way My Little Sister's
Life Counseling Can End Like This