Wh-What's the deal with this guy?
Don't tell me he's...
a parasite?
No, he's human.
I can tell that much, somehow.
But... Migi...
He's asleep!
Parasyte
The Maxim
In Cold Blood
What's the deal with that guy?
He's acting like a completely
different person now.
This is who he truly is.
Is he human?
Is he?!
It's not like...
It's not like I think I'm all that special.
Why can I tell humans and monsters apart?
Well, let me think...
Maybe it's because I played
around a lot with humans.
So, basically...
I know more about all the qualities
this life form possesses than anyone else.
This toy's pretty fragile.
I sure played around...
But isn't this ability of mine
something most animals have, anyway?
It's just about telling your
own kind apart from others.
When I first found one of them,
sure, I was shocked.
It's not every day you see an alien being
walking in a crowd wearing human clothes...
If watched a crowd for a while,
I'd be lucky to see two come
through in a given hour.
It was weird that no one
around me seemed to notice,
but that "thing" also didn't
seem to give a damn.
I didn't really approach them.
Even I thought it'd be dangerous.
I guess you could call it my animal instinct.
I was kind of looking forward to finding out
what these strange beings would do, but...
It amounted to nothing.
It wasn't all that different
from the kinds of things I did.
Wow, what a mess.
You should clean up your toys when
you're done playing with them...
Don't move!
I-It's not what you think!
It wasn't me! You've got it all wrong!
I'd never...
He's taking his sweet time.
Hirama-san, we can't drag
this out much longer.
Look at Izumi Shinichi.
He kept his cool during our questioning,
but even he seems to be afraid this time.
Uragami.
No.
What?
What do you mean?
Well, he might have potential.
But what caught my attention
wasn't anything like that.
It just distracted me, that's all.
What distracted you?
It turned out I was just imagining it,
but I thought I saw something
not entirely human deep within his eyes.
What?!
Idiot.
Don't yell right into my ear.
I told you I was just imagining it.
When I took a good, long look,
there was nothing to it.
So, you will be staying at a hotel
for a few more days, at least.
We will have someone accompany you
any time you want to visit your home,
so be sure to contact us first.
Oh, that's really unnecessary...
No, I insist.
Um, Hirama-san?
About the baby...
If you're referring to the one Tamura
Reiko was holding in her arms,
it still needs to undergo testing.
After all, the child was
being raised by a parasite.
So once you're sure the baby
is normal, what then?
Well...
The child will be raised in appropriate facilities.
Why do you ask?
Does the child concern you that much?
No.
Well...
If you were to say you're
Tamura Reiko's relative,
I'd ask if you'd like to have custody.
What?
I was kidding.
Deep within his eyes, huh?
I have no way of telling.
Shinichi, need the bath?
You go ahead.
All right, thanks.
Who was he?
Just thinking back gives me chills,
even though I've seen so
many man-eating monsters.
Shinichi, it appears that you
are not only tired in body,
but also exhausted in spirit.
I met someone really scary
while you were asleep.
A human?
Yes...
But I think he was a killer.
I don't know what to think anymore.
There are humans who are
unfathomable and terrifying,
but that man-eating parasite, Tamura Reiko,
saved me.
She healed the hole in my heart.
I still cannot comprehend her behavior.
We are two halves of the same whole.
We and humans are one family.
Conference Room
Regarding the "Legal Analysis of Critical Response
and Operation Planned to
Mitigate Massacre by Parasites."
Technically, the government
has approved this operation,
but keep in mind that
there are many gray areas.
I look forward to working with you,
Inspector Hirama.
I'm only an assistant inspector.
But there's talk that you may be promoted
straight to superintendent
by the day of the operation.
Surely you're joking.
He's been assigned to command the
ground forces during the operation—
I'm Yamagishi.
As you have already heard,
Hirama-kun will be supporting this operation
by overseeing all the support functions,
and Yamagishi-kun will
oversee the core operation
with regard to identifying
and eliminating the enemy.
Director General,
the man named Uragami I spoke of previously
may be a great asset,
depending on how we use him.
I believe it'd be best to incorporate him
as an integral element in our core strategy.
I appreciate the thought,
but regarding this "super ability" of his...
I hear he's a mass murderer.
Having such a foreign element working
with our tactical forces in an operation
may result in mishaps at a critical point.
No, he doesn't need to be a
part of the tactical force.
I'd just like him to function as a pair of eyes.
Eyes, eh?
But we have a sensing system
in place for that purpose.
They are not a flock of sheep
who can be herded by dogs.
You seem to give their possible
humanity too much credit.
This is not intended to be a manhunt,
but an extermination of pests.
I have lost contact with Tamura Reiko.
The same goes for Kusano,
Hikawa, and Maesawa.
Three mangled bodies were found
in a construction site within the city,
and a female thought to be a parasite was
shot to death the following day in a park.
Not to mention, all the bodies were
retrieved by a specialized agency,
and their identities have not been revealed.
Kusano had always borne
animosity toward Tamura Reiko.
He must have plotted to kill
her without our consent
and been killed by her instead.
Then the one who was shot dead
in the park was Tamura Reiko.
Most likely.
Now that a parasite task force
agency has been created,
I no longer receive any information.
That means the government is beginning
to treat this as a serious issue.
It appears so.
Izumi-kun!
Murano.
I'm sorry I made you worry.
It's okay.
Oh, wait.
Here are all the notes
I took while you were gone.
Thanks.
I'll return them once I make copies.
Oh, look who's back!
So you can come back to school starting today?
Huh? Oh.
Yeah.
Listen up!
This is your last timed run in high school!
Give it all you've got so that
you won't have any regrets!
Idiot.
Everything he says is so over the top.
Izumi!
I've always wanted to tell you this.
You never take any of this seriously!
This is your last chance, so try for once!
If it were only that simple...
Last time in high school, huh?
Set!
10... 10.5 seconds?
Wow.
It'd be easy to break 10 seconds.
Why're you getting changed in the
corner like you're hiding something?
Huh?
Don't be so shy! You're a dude!
Sorry.
It's fine.
Ow!
Idiot.
Hi-yah!
We'll be graduating in three months.
Yeah.
A lot of things happened in high school, huh?
Way too much.
But there were good things, too.
Yeah.
I should study.
Huh?
Are you actually going to take
university entrance exams?
What's that supposed to mean?
You know, when I go to uni—
Let's go.
We will win!
I'm 99.9% certain,
but I feel like we're just
missing one last thing.
I don't know what that is,
but there is something missing.
I'd like your help.
Why...
Why is it always Izumi-kun?
Izumi-kun isn't the only one affected.
Everyone here is trying their
best to forget what happened!
We were all supposed to be
leading perfectly normal lives,
like normal high school students.
But just a little step off the track,
and there's blood everywhere!
He seems to be a high school student.
He's the witness I told you about.
Ah.
I hear you saw Hirama-san and his
men put down one of them recently.
Higashi Fukuyama
City Hall
Yamagishi
Yes.
Outer Riot
Police Unit
I understand that you are a civilian,
but I'd like to hear your opinion as to
what weapons might be effective against them.
Higashi Fukuyama
City Hall
Yamagishi
Flamethrowers, for example.
Against things that can move that fast?
Of course, fire won't be enough.
But I think it'll be effective.
Basically,
it'll startle us,
and just the "us" on the surface.
We have intellect on par with that of humans,
and we do not fear fire.
But should flames suddenly come near us,
there will be a disconnect between
our "outer" and "inner" selves.
In short, we'd be startled.
Huh.
Goto's body hosts several parasites
that are controlled by one mind.
So if that one mind becomes startled,
it should unbalance him greatly.
I see...
A flamethrower?
Ah, forgive me.
Well, it may not be a bad idea.
But no matter how many parasites
may reside in one body,
there is only one heart.
Today is the day.
Huh? What's going on?
What's this, a military coup d'etat?
Looks like the riot squad, but...
It can't be.
Sensors ready.
Commence operation.
This is an emergency.
We repeat: this is an emergency.
To everyone in this building:
we have very important information.
Please listen carefully.
I am Mizushima, a detective with the
Higashi Fukuyama Police Department.
A man armed with a rifle
has entered the building
and has concealed himself somewhere
on the building rooftop.
Mutsuki and Kisaragi squads are to
rendezvous in the main entrance hall.
Yayoi squad, cover the annex.
Uzuki squad, cover the second
floor and seal off all exit points.
Satsuki squad, protect the sensing system.
Minazuki squad, neutralize the foxes.
To all workers:
please move to the entrance
hall on the first floor.
Information and Reception
They're claiming they're the police?
My bet would be that none
of them are from the police.
So you're really moving
forward with this, humans?
This is where the real game begins.
The foxes will be stripped of their disguises
and lured to the hunting grounds.
The armed suspect is on the
north side of the rooftop!
We will have you evacuate
through his blind spot,
but he may notice if large
groups evacuate at once.
Thus, we'll have you evacuate in groups of seven.
I don't know, okay?
I'll have to actually see them in person.
Not through a screen like this.
Anyway, this is impressive.
It's like a war.
Am I even going to be needed?
Huh?
Oh, it's you.
So calling in the cavalry wasn't enough.
You had to recruit a killer and a minor for help.
You're in quite a bind, huh?
Enough! Keep your mouth shut!
Well?
Are there any?
I'm not sure.
If we can at least identify
the deviant with multiple parasites in
one body, the one you said you saw...
"The deviant"...
And regarding the other one,
the mayor, Hirokawa...
That's right.
Hirokawa is the key.
What was she trying to say about him?
We're to evacuate in groups of seven.
Mayor, you should go first.
Of course not.
Please prioritize children and the elderly,
as well as women.
City workers should wait as long as they can.
Here comes the first seven.
HQ to all squads.
Should foxes attempt escape
or retaliation when fired upon,
engage safeguards immediately.
Roger that.
Removing materials that do not contain
human DNA from the sensor image.
No hits.
Bring the next seven.
No hits in this batch, either.
Migi, you can't tell how many there are?
We're a fair distance away,
so I can't be precise,
but there are quite a few.
There!
That one!
So the first hit is a woman.
Crime and Punishment
Next time:
"Crime and Punishment."